The short flashes, and not streaks, they're associated with things that are extremely flat and extremely reflective.
Wow.
Like mirrors.
This is from the Palomar Observatory before we had satellites in space.
How many of these transients did you find?
Our original sample is around 105,000 transients from just the northern hemisphere.
Dr. Beatrice Villareal holds a Ph.D. in astrophysics.
She's won the L'Oreal UNESCO Prize for Women in Science.
She's currently an associate professor at Stockholm University, where her research runs the gambit from active galactic nuclei to transient phenomena in the search for intelligent life.
If I look at everything that I learned in the last years, I will be fair.
I don't think we are alone.
I think we have company.
In other words, Dr. Villareal is someone who really knows her s**t when it comes to the night skies and cosmos.
My name is Beatrice Villareal, and I'm a very curious person.
And it's precisely these illustrious mainstream astronomical accomplishments which make her latest paradigm-shattering results all the more shocking and threatening to the establishment.
Dr. Villareal has found over 100,000 light-reflecting unidentified objects on the plates of the Palomar Observatory, the most prominent observatory in use in the 1950s.
The only thing is, she detected these objects before the first satellite, Sputnik, ever orbited Earth.
You heard me right.
A conventionally renowned astronomer has detected over 100,000 UFOs before humans ever put anything in space.
And the debunkers are flailing in their attempts to take her down.
Do you feel like the world is ready to accept this?
In this exclusive long-form interview, we address it all.
We stress test her results and even speak to a Ph.D. from Vanderbilt, Dr. Stephen Bruel, who's followed up on Beatrice's study and correlates these UFO appearances with nuclear tests.
The transients correlate not only with nuclear testing, but also show a small but statistically significant correlation with UAP reports from the general public.
Whoa.
If you've seen our show or read the work of the great Robert Hastings, you'll know that the nuclear-UFO connection is widespread, ongoing, and global.
We've even interviewed a top presidential advisor at the end of his life who admitted to holding UFO material that came from a nuclear detonation in the Marshall Islands in late 1963.
You know what, you said Hamlin.
That's amazing.
But this is unprecedented.
We've never correlated those anecdotal sightings with the astronomical record.
What's even more is that all of this work has received peer review in mainstream astronomical journals.
In other words, she has finally caught the white whale in UFO science.
Academic validation.
And then they can get their own ontological shock.
Why should only I have it?
So strap yourselves in, leave the Earth's atmosphere behind, and prepare to never see the night sky the same way again,
as we welcome this week's returning Swedish alchemist, the amazing Dr. Beatrice Bioreal.
Beatrice Bioreal, thank you so much for being here, a return guest on American Alchemy.
I couldn't be more excited to have you because you had discovered some amazing things the last time we spoke.
But this time, you have discovered things that I think are so ontologically shocking and are hard to kind of compute for the average person
because they wholesale change our worldview and our understanding of the Earth, its place in the cosmos, objects surrounding the Earth.
And so I'm just so grateful for you.
Thank you for being here.
Thank you for spending time with us in Stockholm.
Well, it's a pleasure, and it's a pleasure to have you here in Stockholm.
Walk me through the day that you saw that there were maybe, you know, all these transients,
these objects that we're basically calling UFOs surrounding the Earth.
What happened that day?
Well, I've been working with transients for a while.
I think a lot of people know about this transient work.
We have been looking for, like, multiple transients and images.
Sometimes you can see multiple of them appearing and vanishing within half an hour.
What is a transient?
So imagine a light flash or something that changes in the sky.
You have all these stars in the skies.
You have galaxies.
But some things change their luminosity, and sometimes they change it on a short time.
And in our case, we saw things that appeared and vanished within half an hour.
And we had two such examples that are statistically significant.
One is five objects on a narrow band, and it's from the 27th of July, 1952.
And then my colleague Enrique Solano in Spain, he discovered another such really beautiful example
with three super bright, beautiful stars.
It's the most beautiful example of all we have.
This one is from the 19th of July, 1952.
And then my colleague, Dave Altman, who is the media manager for Vasco, he said,
do you know what happens or what happened on 19th of July, 1952?
I said, no, I wasn't around.
So he introduced me to the Washington flap.
In Washington, ghost-like objects dart across the radar screen
at the CAA Traffic Control Center at National Airport for several hours.
This was a national event.
It was all over the press.
It was in newspapers saying, saucers on the White House lawn.
It prompted a call between Truman and Edward J. Ruppelt, who was the head of Blue Book at the time.
And you had this Washington invasion or D.C. flyover where there were saucers all over D.C. at the time.
And it was July of 1952, but it was specifically two weekends.
It was the 19th and 20th, and it was the 26th and 27th.
So I find that absolutely remarkable.
So there I started understanding, like, there is something more to these transients.
And at the same time, I've been having all this discussion for several years with people who think,
no, it's just plate defects.
You're trying to see systematics in plate defects.
Real quick, just for the audience, what is a plate?
And why are other astronomers saying that you're only seeing plate defects
when you're looking for these flashes of light?
In the old times, in the 50s, in order to make a picture of the sky with a telescope,
you used big glass plates, big.
They were big and heavy.
They had an emulsion on top of it.
And then they tried to observe the sky, and they made a survey observing the sky,
like the Palomar Observatory, for example, and Harvard.
They took images of the skies with these plates.
And these images, they have been digitized.
So even if they are somewhere in an archive, then you today can access the digital images.
And it was assumed or known, I don't anymore know if I should use known or assumed,
that many of these dots that could be there could be some kind of emulsion defects.
And people thought, okay, so in order to select a star or something like that,
people normally took two images and only selected those that appeared on two images.
But if you do that, you're missing a lot of short-lived phenomena
that might only be seen for a few minutes, because then you miss all that.
It's not going to be in your samples.
And astronomy is all about sample selection.
The way how you define your sample, you need to think through the criteria very carefully
when you start doing this research.
Yes, so when we have been talking about these multiple transients,
the people say, oh, you're probably just running into plate defects
that just happen to coincidentally look like stars.
And when you say emulsion, what does it mean?
And this chemistry you put on these plates.
So the chemistry you put on the plates, when the light shows through it,
you get almost like a stain or like a record, an inkling.
Exactly, a bubble.
Of what was in the sky.
Yeah, exactly.
And if you have bad luck, you get a plate defect, like a bubble or something like that.
But if you have something real, then you will get a star.
Yes, and so you have these plates and they come from the Palomar Observatory?
Those that I work with.
And was this a well-respected observatory at the time?
Yes, it's one of the greatest ones.
And Fritz Zwicky was there.
And there were many very famous astronomers that were there.
So yeah, so we are working with this stuff that people have been using for doing really great astronomy.
Now we're going back and looking at these digitized images.
And of course, I'm having my discussion with people thinking, ah, it's just plate defects.
And then there's a simple way of testing it, actually.
How do you test that?
That's much stronger.
Well, one of the tests we did were these alignments where we still found things.
But there's an even cooler way how we can test that.
You can actually see if you have the same number of transients when you look outside the Earth's shadow or when you look inside the Earth's shadow.
Because all the time, the Earth casts a shadow.
It's like a cone.
And the further you are from the Earth, the narrower is this shadow.
So my hypothesis was that these transients came from solar reflections at 42,164 kilometers from the Earth or somewhere there around.
And one of the ways how you can check it is to see are there more transients inside where you know the Earth's shadow is at a certain time?
Or is it like fewer transients?
And of course, for every transients, we have the coordinate, and we also have the time of the observation.
So you can calculate is it inside the Earth's shadow or not.
And if it would be plate defects, you would have no deficits.
If it's 100% solar reflections, you will have zero transients there.
And if you have that a part of them are real and a part of them are plate defects, then you will have a deficit.
And you can basically estimate how big a fraction of your objects that seem to be authentic.
Of course, what do we do?
We test this.
Yes.
Because we have this code from a guy called Guineer.
So it's a public code.
And then we have the transient sample from my colleague at the Spanish Virtual Observatory.
So it's quite easy to test.
You just insert the coordinates from the sample into the code, and you count things.
And guess what?
We get a huge deficit.
Wow.
And that's when you start saying, like, did I do something wrong?
And you start thinking, did I calculate the area of a circle on the sky correctly?
And you start doing all kinds of things just to test.
Did I screw up?
And for the audience, so you're basically showing that the Earth's shadow would not, obviously, a solar reflection wouldn't show up there.
Exactly.
So a real object, you know, that was in the way of the sun, you would get a solar reflection.
A non-real object, you wouldn't get anything, right?
And so what you're showing is that these are real solar reflections because there is a deficit in the Earth's shadow of these objects.
Exactly, because inside the Earth's shadow, if the sun doesn't reach, you're not going to get the reflection.
While if you're outside the Earth's shadow, it's going to reflect sunlight.
So that's a remarkable finding because it shows that these are real objects.
Because the idea that there are plate defects, that's not going to play favorites, you know, as far as the Earth's shadow or not Earth's shadow.
It's just going to be evenly distributed throughout.
A plate defect is a plate defect.
Exactly.
And it's possible that many of the transients we've been working with are plate defects because we only see one that there's a deficit of one third.
So, yes, maybe there are a lot of plate defects in the samples, but you still have a 30% deficit or 30% to 35%.
It still means that 30% to 35% of the objects we are working with come from solar reflections.
And not any solar reflections because these flashes that we see and these short flashes and not streaks, they're associated with things that are extremely flat and extremely reflective.
Wow.
Like mirrors.
And that makes it more fun.
Mirrors.
Glass.
Interesting, yeah.
Not something, not a stone, not a rock.
Right.
Not ice.
And this is...
Not round, flat.
This is from the Palomar Observatory before we had satellites in space.
Yes.
So, that's fascinating.
And if you think about it, plate defects, again, would be...
You're going to have some margin of error due to plate defects.
Maybe, like you said, 30%, 35%.
But it's not going to be only, you know, where the sun is.
That makes no sense.
So, even if you would have 80% of, like, plate defects, you still would have a substantial fraction of the objects that seem to be real.
And that's what counts.
I would be happy if it would be 1%.
But when you get, like, 30% to 35% and you say, am I calculating it correctly?
You almost hope for it.
At this point in the interview, you might be wondering about the fact that Beatrice is looking at the most prominent astronomical observatory in use at the time.
So, why wasn't this discovered earlier?
And why haven't these findings been replicated?
Well, a man who held just about every clearance in the book and ran the Harvard Observatory in the 1950s, who was also part of the Bureau of Public Standards, basically compiling a lot of the astronomical data known to the public in the 50s and 60s, was a guy named Donald Menzel.
Well, Dr. Donald Menzel came out swinging against UFOs.
But thanks to Beatrice and others, we know the true story.
He was even caught by his understudy, Dorit Hofleit, destroying astronomical plates at the Harvard Observatory.
And he helped the U.S. Air Force to debunk the Washington 1952 flap.
And two or three months after, he suddenly becomes the director of Harvard Observatory, and he destroys one third of the photographic plates.
And he doesn't ask, as I understand from the records, he doesn't ask the astronomers to select the plates.
No, he asked his secretary to go and throw away one third of the plates.
And there's a woman, Dorit Hofleit, that has been, like, telling about the story in her memoirs.
And kind of, he started revenging on her later, too, for, as I understood it, for that she tried to protect some of the plates.
He also threw away a number of the logbooks that are keeping the observations and what plates exist.
So you only have a handful of observatories in use at the time.
And you have a national security state, headed up by people like Don Menzel, tightly controlling the information disseminated to the public.
It's not beyond belief to me, then, that a widespread cover-up could have occurred.
So we've shown that these aren't plate defects, because plate defects don't move intelligently around based on the Earth's shadow.
They also don't move intelligently around based on nuclear detonations occurring in the 40s and 50s.
And if you're wondering just how ubiquitous the UFO-nuclear connection actually is,
check out my interview with the great journalist Robert Hastings, author of the book UFOs and Nukes,
who's chronicled 167 Q-cleared nuclear-base employees who have blown the whistle on UFOs showing up all over our nuclear installations.
Roswell was the site of the most nukes in the U.S. in 1947 at the time of the Roswell crash.
And lest you think this is an American deep state PSYOP, you can go as far as Japan, where a town named Ino,
which is right next to the Fukushima Prefecture, has a mountain, Mount Sengon Mori, where UFOs constantly show up.
Many of the townspeople are obsessed with UFOs.
They have a museum on top of this mountain dedicated to UFOs.
Ino is directly adjacent to the Fukushima Prefecture and their civilian nuclear grid.
In the 90s in Zimbabwe, over 60 schoolchildren all saw a UFO land and an alien descend out of the craft and telepathically speak to them.
And where is this school's location?
And you know an area of school that was near a uranium mining site?
That is right, as far as I understand.
When we first started selling merchandise at AmericanAlchemyMerch.com, we had no idea how complicated and annoying selling merch could be.
We talked to a dozen different platforms and companies, comparing shipping tools, payment options, website builders,
and it all felt like way more of a headache and complicated than it should be.
We decided on Shopify, and within days, our store was up.
Everything was running cleanly in an automated way, so we could just focus on the brand and the vision we had for it.
That's when it hit us.
Ideas don't scale on inspiration alone.
They need a structure, a container.
Shopify provides that structure.
It quietly powers millions of creators and brands, about 10% of all United States e-commerce.
From big names like Gymshark and Mattel, to solo creators building from their bedrooms.
Shopify made it simple to build a store that actually feels authentic to us,
which matters when your brand lives in a niche like alternative tech, UFOs, or fringe science,
and when you have a very clear brand vision.
Plus, their AI tools help write descriptions, organize products, even clean up photos,
so we can focus on what matters and what we care about.
Building the best custom merch line possible with the coolest designs,
like our UFO cowboy tee and the atomic age tee.
Plus, Shopify handles all of the unglamorous, more painful stuff.
Shipping, returns, email marketing, all in one clean dashboard.
It's like having a silent partner who never sleeps.
Our favorite part of the product is the dashboard,
which gives us complete demographic information.
We can see where our orders come from,
making it easy to know who our most loyal, consistent customers are around the world.
That's just one example, but Shopify really makes your life easier.
Bring your next idea to life, with Shopify quietly handling everything behind it.
Sign up for your $1 per month trial, and start today at shopify.com slash jesse.
Again, that's shopify.com slash jesse, j-e-s-s-e, for a $1 a month trial.
Again, that's just $1 a month to try Shopify, the state-of-the-art solution in e-commerce.
So, this is amazing, because you've basically found pre-satellites in space, objects surrounding the Earth.
How many of these transients did you find?
Well, it depends on how one counts now.
Our original sample is around 105,000 transients from just the northern hemisphere,
but we assume that it's only one-third of these that are relevant,
so we can count on 70,000 all over.
However, I don't know how many of these transients might be associated with only one object,
or if it's like one object could be several of them.
I just don't know.
At the moment, we have to investigate this.
Yes, because a transient is a flash of light.
Exactly.
And so, it could be the same object flashing, traveling, or whatever.
And you found this over what period of time?
It's over six years. It's 780 hours of exposure time.
Okay.
So, yeah, we need to do the calculations correctly.
I think it's something like 1.1 transient per square degree per hour.
Yeah, yeah.
Wow.
So, like, almost like 15,000 per year or something.
It's a fun number.
Yeah.
What I didn't know is that there's, apparently, since the early 1960s,
there were something called uncorrelated targets.
And people have been finding them in hundreds per week or something like that,
where, again, they see something only once or a few times on a radar or with optical sensors,
and then they can't track it.
So, it becomes an uncorrelated target, and they are always reduced from the background
when people calculate the number of objects in space, let's say, space trash and satellites in space.
How do you separate an uncorrelated target from a satellite?
How do you know?
Because it's not orbiting like a satellite?
Because they can't track it.
So, if I understand it correctly, NASA and ESA and those always remove it from the background.
Okay.
Sorry, they remove this background of uncorrelated targets from the total number of things that they see
in order to calculate the number of objects in space.
However, I think that they don't do it themselves.
It's done by militaries, and it's classified lists.
So, it's kind of becoming a little bit more fun.
I'm trying to look into this right now.
Yeah.
So, maybe, like, you mentioned recently, like, you know, NASA is kind of the more civilian space exploration app,
but obviously, they do intelligence work as well.
But maybe Space Force has these targets, these uncorrelated targets, and they remove them for NASA?
I think that's what I heard from someone on the inside, yes.
That they don't do it themselves.
It's the Space Force that has this list.
These lists are classified as also those early from the 1960s.
Because what I would like to have is one of these lists that coordinates and check if they vanish in the shadow.
Totally.
That's what you want to do.
Because if they didn't vanish, they wouldn't just be noise.
Because it sounds like, systematically, people looking at space are calling them uncorrelated targets.
You're basically, it's like a, oh, they're just, it's noise in the data or something.
It's something to be filtered out.
But in fact, you have other agencies that are systematically tracking the noise.
Because it's not just noise.
These are objects, maybe.
It's very interesting.
And I learned also that it's like they make up the majority of the things that we see on the sky today.
But again, I didn't know about it.
So I'm wondering a little bit, are my transients similar to these uncorrelated targets, of course?
Yeah.
That's one of the things I'm wondering about.
Because that would be interesting.
That would be amazing because 15,000 a year or 20,000, you know, whatever number that we come to is a lot.
I mean, the amount of satellites in space, like, I don't even know what we're at right now.
But I mean, obviously, Starlink is dramatically increasing the amount in the sky.
But it's not a ton.
And the uncorrelated objects, just for the audience, because we've jumped back and forth between transients,
which are these light flashes that you were detecting in these plates from the, you know, 50 to 56.
And uncorrelated objects.
Do we know that these are the same thing?
I have no idea.
I'm just speculating around this.
I'm just curious.
I'm trying to look into this right now.
This is just where my thoughts are wandering.
But if you saw that there was a drop-off in these uncorrelated objects around the Earth's shadow,
you could show that, again, they're physical objects.
And maybe if we could show that they were the same amount as what you found in the plates from, you know, the 50s,
maybe you'd get, you know, some sort of match.
But I would love to see that.
Like, especially these uncorrelated targets, if they come from optical sensors,
it would be super interesting to see if they vanish in the Earth's shadow.
It would also support not only that they're physical, but that they are artificial.
As it turns out, these uncorrelated targets are a gateway to a much deeper rabbit hole
stretching all the way back to the dawn of the space race.
Our story begins in 1953, four years before Sputnik.
Enter Major Donald Kehoe, a retired Marine Corps naval aviator
and one of the earliest public advocates for UFO disclosure.
Kehoe states something astonishing,
that the Air Force was tracking two unknown artificial satellites,
400 and 600 miles up in low Earth orbit.
The timing here was likely not a coincidence.
That same year, a very unusual project started at White Sands Missile Range,
a military-funded initiative to track small natural satellites,
think asteroids captured in orbit.
Two remarkable scientists were in charge.
First up is meteorite expert Dr. Lincoln LaPaz.
Before joining this special search for mini-moons around Earth,
Dr. LaPaz headed up Project Twinkle,
an Air Force investigation into unexplained green fireballs
showing up across American nuclear sites.
Documented at places like Los Alamos and Holloman Air Force Base,
LaPaz arrived at the conclusion that these green fireballs
were not a known natural phenomenon,
and they seemed to propel themselves intelligently.
Second on the project, we have Clyde Tombaugh.
Yes, that Clyde Tombaugh, the man who discovered Pluto.
The man whose ashes are now speeding towards interstellar space
inside the most expensive urn ever built,
NASA's New Horizons spacecraft.
Until the day he died,
Tombaugh remained steadfast in his conviction
that some UFOs could represent visiting alien spacecraft.
So one has to wonder,
given wild rumors from credible sources
and the cast of characters involved,
what exactly did they actually find?
On August 23rd, 1954,
Aviation Week and Space Technology published a statement from LaPaz,
one which begged way more questions than it answered.
LaPaz confirmed that there were indeed two unknown objects.
But simultaneously, he claimed that the two unknown objects
were fully identified natural asteroids
caught in Earth's gravitational grasp.
He might have been doing this to dispel American domestic panic
that this could have been Soviet tech.
But if you read between the lines,
there's a lot that just doesn't add up.
Firstly, these observations directly corroborate Kehoe's story.
White Sands Missile Range actually was tracking
two unidentified objects in low Earth orbit.
But it also contradicts just about everything else we know
about the historic and scientific record.
These two quote-unquote natural satellites
never show up again in any of the literature
on asteroids and near-Earth objects.
Given that the moon is regarded
as the Earth's only permanent natural satellite,
these two mini-moons should have been
a major astrophysical discovery.
I'm talking national news major.
Yet we never heard about these two objects again.
Perhaps strangest of all,
in the official Near-Earth Satellite Project's final report,
these two objects aren't even mentioned.
Not only that, but the report concludes
that there are no natural satellites orbiting the Earth.
But if that was true,
if there were really no natural satellites,
then what the hell were these two unknowns?
Perhaps most remarkably,
the most important U.S. government documents surrounding UFOs
from exactly when the Palomar Observatory
was making these observations in the early 50s,
quite literally refers to objects with metallic
and light-reflecting surfaces
that were flat on the bottom.
So the Air Force and CIA documents at the time
described objects that exactly sound
like the mirror-like features
Beatrice's data implies.
These documents include the 1947 Twining Memo,
the 1948 Project Sign Analysis,
and the CIA's analysis of the 1952 DC UFO flyover,
along with Blue Book lead Captain Edward J. Ruppelt's analysis,
and more.
UFOs are consistently described
as light-reflecting, luminous, shiny, metallic objects,
characteristics that would likely show up
as light transients on astronomical plates
like the Palomar Observatories.
Have you tried to corroborate your findings
from the Palomar Observatory?
Because people maybe forever will try to say
it's plate defects,
even though plate defects aren't going to be biased
towards, you know,
what's not near its shadow
and where the sun is hitting.
That doesn't make any sense.
Unless they are intelligent plate defects.
Unless they're intelligent.
They move around on the plate
just to avoid a shadow.
Yeah, so they're the real conspiracy theorists.
The plate defects people are, you know,
they're in this, yeah,
intelligent plate defects.
Exactly.
Have you tried to look at other observatory data,
other plates from the 50s,
to cross-reference that data
against the Palomar Observatory?
We really want to do it.
It's a big project
because every time you try to,
let's say,
look at a new plate collection,
it's a big extraction.
Like the whole process
to look through the plates,
even the digital ones,
it's a project for maybe two years or so.
So I hope I will get
maybe a postdoctoral researcher
to help to do this.
A lot of people watching this
might be asking,
oh, it's convenient that Beatrice,
who was interested in UFOs,
is finding, you know, UFOs.
How would you respond to those people?
Because the way you're describing it,
to me,
it's kind of undeniable
from a first principles viewpoint
that this is worthy of investigation
and it's very clear, but...
It's called a scientific method.
You have a hypothesis.
When you build the LHC
to look for the...
When they built the LHC
to look for the Higgs boson,
they also have a hypothesis
in the beginning.
When they look for a particular particle,
they know what they are looking for.
Is it there or not?
Yes, that's right.
It's a scientific method.
Why should UFOs or alien life
be an exclusion?
I mean...
That's a beautiful way to put it.
The scientific method involves
the interplay between hypotheses
and testing.
And if you can't even have
the hypothesis
that there could be
other life
or other objects
that we don't detect out there,
you're not going to obviously find it
because it's...
Yeah.
So if you go very generally
and you look for UFOs
and you start looking...
I mean,
I've seen some astronomers
suggesting that you should
just look without any hypothesis
and do like...
classify things
like you're classifying butterflies.
I think you're not going
to find anything.
Well, obviously.
Because you have no hypothesis,
you don't target your experiment
and you are going to invest
years into that
and you might have
a great catalog of things
but I'm not interested
in the catalog.
Yes.
I want to ask the question,
I want to design the experiment.
Of course,
you're going to have
a lot of pitfalls,
things that can go wrong.
It's all trial and error.
We're learning continuously.
But this is what I want to do.
I want to test the question,
I want to do the experiment
and I want to analyze the data
and see what is the outcome.
And it's a great example you used.
You said LHC,
which is the Large Hadron Collider,
which is CERN,
this big particle accelerator.
The Higgs field,
I believe,
was predicted in the 70s
and they actually discovered it
much later,
obviously,
with the Large Hadron Collider.
So it's a perfect example
of you need to be open
or knowledgeable
about the thing
you're looking for
before you find it.
It's not just...
Science is not like
remove your brain
and you're just like
an instrument or a sensor.
You have to target your sensor
against something.
And so that's what you're doing.
And here's where I think
things get even more exciting
for people like me
who have been into UFOs
for a very long time
and have long known
about this connection
between UFOs
and nuclear detonations.
I mean,
it's a ubiquitous phenomenon.
There's a great book
by a journalist
named Robert Hastings
called UFOs and Nukes
and it documents
the global widespread
phenomenon of UFOs
showing up around
nuclear installations,
nuclear civilian energy grids,
and nuclear weapons facilities.
You have 167 Q-cleared
missile-based security personnel,
radar operators,
guys that work
at these bases
who are basically hired
to protect
the crown jewels
of defense
and they have to report
if they're taking
Tylenol or ibuprofen.
They literally have to be
the picture of mental health
and they all say
they see UFOs,
saucers,
Tic Tacs.
And so you found
that there might actually
be a connection
between nuclear
and UFOs in space.
So my colleague,
Stephen Brewell,
he has been leading a study.
I'm co-author on this paper.
So he has used the sample
from the Spanish
Virtual Observatory,
the same sample
that we used
for the Umbra test,
exactly the same thing.
And he has tested
a hypothesis
of that there's
a correlation in time
between our transients
and nuclear bomb tests.
And he finds a correlation.
It's weak,
but it's there
and it's statistically significant.
He also finds
a correlation
between UFOs
and nukes
and between UFOs
and transients
and all of them
are statistically significant.
So you have this triad,
UFOs, nukes
and transients.
Wow.
And is it specifically
nuclear detonations?
Yes.
So it's the timing
of nuclear detonations.
Yes, within a day
you see this increase
in transients.
As you know,
on American Alchemy,
we cover a lot
of technology
that goes beyond
human limits.
This is about technology
that helps the body
catch up
and feel good.
I'm talking about
the iRestore LED
face mask,
a red light therapy system
that uses
clinical grade wavelengths
to boost skin cell
energy production.
The same exact principle
used in the top
recovery clinics
and bio-optimization labs
in the world.
I've been using it
most nights,
10 minutes while I'm reading,
prepping for a show
or decompressing.
It's completely
hands-free,
comfortable
and engineered
to deliver consistent
light intensity
across the face.
Not that uneven scatter
most cheaper masks use.
It feels like your face
is taking a warm bath.
What it's doing
is called
photobiomodulation,
stimulating mitochondria
to repair tissue,
reduce inflammation
and improve circulation.
You actually feel
the calm
and rejuvenation
after a session.
I've tested a few of these.
This one really stands out
for the build quality.
It feels like it was built
in a high-precision lab
and it's not just
a cheap beauty gadget.
So if you're into
real evidence-based
recovery tech,
this belongs
in your setup.
Head to iRestore.com
and use code
JESSE25
for an exclusive discount.
Again,
iRestore.com
code JESSE25.
Red light therapy
has really been
a game changer for me.
So I hope you love it.
Originally,
I trained as a
clinical psychologist,
but I quickly moved
into doing
biomedical research.
So as part of
getting a PhD,
I got training
in research design,
statistics
and have practiced
that,
you know,
the research skills
and statistics
for many years.
I approached
Beatrice via email
and I said,
you know,
what do you think
of trying to explore
this further?
And she was nice enough
to agree to do
a Zoom meeting
and we started
talking about it.
And she became
very excited
about the possibility
of systematically
looking at this,
which she had not
really thought
about doing before.
And we kind of
came up with the plan
for how to do it
and over the course
of the past year,
compiled this
enormous database
with 2,700 days
in it.
And for each day
we recorded,
was there a nuclear
test that day?
There were like
134 over that
period of time.
Was there a transient
that day?
And there were
transients were only
seen on about
300 days
out of those
2,700.
And then we looked,
is there a relationship
between those
and a relationship
with UAP sightings
in the old
Center for UFO Studies
UFOCAT database,
which covers
that period of time.
And, you know,
I was shocked.
We got a really
interesting finding
that was highly
significant statistically.
And I double-checked
it, triple-checked
it, and then reached
out to Beatrice.
She was very excited.
And we immediately
started writing it up
for a paper,
which was actually
just accepted this week
at a journal
called Scientific Reports.
That's amazing.
Congratulations.
So, how strong
is the correlation
that you found
between the transients
and nuclear tests?
Let me put that
two ways.
So, statistically,
there is an
8 in 1,000 chance
that this is an error,
which means
it's pretty unlikely
that it's an error.
And then the other
way to look at it
is in terms of percentages.
So, out of those
2,700,
days,
if there's no
nuclear test,
there's a transient
on 11% of those days.
But if there's been
a nuclear test
the day before,
then it's
almost 19%
of those days
have a transient.
So, that 11%
versus 19%
is about
a 68%
increase
in risk
for a transient
if you've had
a nuclear test.
And so,
when you're
documenting
all these nuclear tests,
these are tests
presumably
at the Nevada
test site,
which turned
into Area 51,
maybe the Marshall Islands,
like those sorts
of nuclear tests,
and then,
you know,
maybe whatever
Russia was doing
with the Tsar bomb
in Kazakhstan,
that sort of thing.
that is all true.
It's Kazakhstan,
there's some
British tests
in Australia,
and then the U.S.
tests in New Mexico
and in the Pacific.
That's right,
there's WUMERA
test range,
which
the head of the
nuclear division
actually in Australia,
the joint intelligence
organization,
was a guy named
Harry Turner,
and he was obsessed
with UFOs.
And so,
I think it's probably
not a coincidence
that he was overseeing
a lot of those
nuclear tests.
But, yeah,
that's fascinating.
Is there any way
to geofence
the transients
to maybe correlate
it even more tightly?
I think,
in principle,
there is the possibility
of doing,
kind of,
looking at general
directions,
because all of these
that we've looked at
so far were taken
from California
at the Palomar,
Mount Palomar Observatory.
There are plates
from that same era
that are taken
at other observatories
like the Vatican Observatory.
And if we could get
access to digitized
plates from some
of these other locations,
I would think
we'd be some ability
to kind of triangulate
on those days
when you get a transient
that coincides
with the nuclear test
and may be able
to identify
roughly what direction
that was in.
So, right now,
we haven't been able
to do that, though.
This would be
a really big deal,
I think,
if, you know,
the entire consensus
sort of accepted it,
because already
you have people
like Robert Hastings
documenting
160-plus
queue-cleared
ICBM security personnel,
radar operators,
guys at nuclear bases
with no incentive
to lie,
no histrionic
streak
in their personalities.
Often they're tested,
actually,
for being sound of mind.
They're on what's called
the PRP,
personal reliability program.
They have to be inherently,
you know,
kind of credible witnesses,
and they're all seeing UFOs.
And what your study does
is it almost
implies,
possibly,
that these are coming
from space.
They're not just showing up,
you know,
locally
at the Air Force base.
Yeah,
so here's the pieces
of information
that I like to point out
when I'm talking
to people about this.
And I have to say,
a few years ago,
I would think
I was crazy
for saying this,
but these are just
statistical facts.
So Beatrice has shown
that these transients,
the number of transients
drops dramatically
when they are in an area
where the Earth's shadow
would be.
So that indicates
that they are reflective
objects in orbit.
They're not plate defects.
Our findings indicate
that these things
were in the sky
the day after
a nuclear test,
and they weren't there
the day before.
So somehow,
based on a nuclear test
going off,
within 24 hours,
you have these objects,
whatever they are,
appearing in
geosynchronous orbit.
Now,
who is behind that?
You know,
where did these come from,
and how can they be
so close
that in 24 hours
they're able to be here?
And I don't know
the answer to that,
but it really is
thought-provoking to me
in an existential way.
Are there any
kind of
first-order
debunks
that you've thought of
when it applies
to your findings?
So, like,
the first-order debunk
with Beatrice
would be that
these are plate defects,
and I think she
answered that
pretty substantially
with, you know,
unless the plate defects
are intelligently
shifting themselves
based on,
you know,
light patterns.
It doesn't really
make sense, right?
So, do you have,
like,
a first-order debunk
that you've thought of
or addressed
or plan to address
in the future?
Yeah, so,
the things that are,
and this is all
pretty obvious,
but the transients
were identified
using an automated system.
It's not true AI,
but it was an automated
process conducted
by a computer,
and I know
for a fact
that some of those
are errors
because I've,
I've gone through
at this point
probably a hundred
of these transients
manually,
which is a lot of work,
but you can compare
and see why the computer
thought it was a transient,
and there are some things
that are errors in there.
So,
that is always a concern,
but the thing is,
I,
like,
for example,
with the nuclear tests,
I looked at the transients
that were seen
the day after
a nuclear test,
and for each
of those dates
that happened,
I have manually confirmed
that there was
an actual,
real,
obvious transient,
at least one of them,
on that day,
and that gave me
more confidence
that this isn't
some weird error,
some random pattern
that we've capitalized on.
So,
I know there's
real transients
on these days
when the nuclear tests
happened,
but the debunk of it is,
is it something local
to the observatory,
right?
And what's interesting
is the transients
correlate not only
with nuclear testing,
but also show a small
but statistically
significant correlation
with UAP reports
from the general public.
Whoa.
So,
on a day
when there is
a nuclear test,
or see,
day after a nuclear test,
and there are UAP sightings,
you get a much higher
risk of a transient.
So,
they all kind of
are like a triangle.
They're all together
as one thing.
And that's fascinating to me,
and you can't explain that
by anything
that was local
to the observatory
or the film.
Those associations
wouldn't be there
if it was
plate defects
or radiation effects.
If it was
the bomb casing,
just,
let's say,
some bit of it survived,
it's not going to sit
in one place
in the sky
for 24 hours.
to be seen
as a transient afterwards.
So,
just none of the things
I would think of
make any sense.
And,
you know,
as a psychologist,
most of the research
I do
has a lot of error
in it
because you're basing it
on what people tell you.
And there's error
in this data set,
but it doesn't undo
the fact
that there is
a real signal there
that is clearly detectable
and is actually
quite large
when it comes
to the Nuclear
Testing Association.
Well,
also,
if you're doing
kind of pointed
error correction
on the days
that these,
you know,
transients
seem to show up,
then you're actually
saying that 68%
more likely,
you know,
transients,
nuclear,
is a baseline statistic
and it's probably
higher if there are
errors in the entire
data set
and there are probably
more transients
than,
you know,
we think.
Yeah,
same thing
with the UAP sightings.
A lot of error,
a lot of those
are prosaic things
that just,
there was no ability
to,
you know,
research them.
So,
our plan hopefully
is to use AI
to try to clean
the transient data,
you know,
train the AI
to tell the difference
between a bad plate
or dust
or a streak
on the plate
and a real transient.
And what you just said
is true,
that if we do that
successfully,
we're going to get
rid of the error
and end up
with more signal
and that should
increase
the associations
we see.
Now,
I want to mention
one thing too
and this is just
kind of an odd fact
that I find interesting
is when we look
at the data set,
the last time
we saw a correspondence
between a nuclear test
and a transient
was March 17, 1956.
Okay?
Now,
our study goes on
for an entire year
after that
and there are
an additional
38 nuclear tests
over the course
of that year.
Not a single time
is a transient
associated
with a nuclear test
at that point.
So,
it was like,
well,
what happened
suddenly in 1956?
And I was reading
an article
that a guy
named Larry Hancock
with the SCU did
where they were looking
at sightings
of UAP
at nuclear facilities
like nuclear
production facilities,
nuclear plants,
things like that.
And what they found
was high levels
of activity
from 1949
until 1953
and then it just stopped.
Even though
more facilities
came online,
suddenly they weren't
seeing UAP anymore.
And it just got me thinking.
It almost looks like
whatever it is
was showing
an intelligent interest
in all things nuclear
up until
between 1953
and 1956
and then suddenly
wasn't anymore,
at least for a while.
That was kind of
odd to think about.
I don't know
what that means,
but that was
intriguing.
Yeah,
I'm trying to think
of what happened
in 1956
or 1957.
I mean,
that's when
NICAP formed,
which was the first
civilian UFO
research program.
That's when
the International
Geophysical Year
happened,
where Antarctica
became a no-fly zone
and a bunch
of scientists
internationally
met together
to discuss
things of this nature.
So maybe
there's something
around that.
I believe that was
56, 57.
Maybe.
But I don't know.
Yeah,
and if these
are,
we always have to
consider the possibility
that there's some
very odd form
of plasma
life.
You know,
I don't know
what that would be,
but some organism
that may give
the appearance
of this
that can
hover in the sky
and appear
like a transient
and might be
interested
in nuclear
testing.
But it is hard
to conceive
of any
kind of
organism
that would
be able to do
what these
things seem to do.
Yeah,
absolutely.
So how many
transients
are we talking
about total
in this
data set?
It is surprisingly
large,
keeping in mind
the error,
but there are
over 107,000
over that,
what is it,
eight-year period.
Okay,
wow,
that's remarkable.
So like a little
over 12,000 a year.
Yeah,
so if we think
that 90%
of these are error,
let's just be
conservative,
we've still got
over 10,000
things that were
in orbit
reflective prior
to the first
satellite that
seemed to be
interested in
nuclear tests
in some way.
Do you have a
sense of the
error rate?
Because if the
error rate is
10 to 20%,
I'd say far
more confident
in your study.
If it's like
90%,
I might be a
little more,
okay,
let's do the
error correction.
I think the
best way to
think about that
is something that
Beatrice has
talked about,
which is when
she looks at
the transients
and where
they are
and calculates
which transients
are in sunlight
and which are
in shadow,
when you look
at the data
that way,
in the shadow,
the number
of transients
drops by about
30%,
right?
So that kind
of presents
the lower limit
for error
would be
maybe about
30% of these
being real
transients,
70% error.
I don't think
it's actually
that high,
just having
manually inspected
these.
But it would
make sense
that you'd
get more
transients
in the light
than in the
shadow side,
right?
If they're
in orbit.
Yep.
So, okay,
so I see
what you're
saying.
So, like,
up to 30%,
but even
that, like,
you'd expect
some delta
between those
two, so it's
really maybe
up to 25%
or something.
I don't know
what the right
mental bottle is.
There's no way
for us to tell
at this point
exactly.
Yeah, it
sounds like
the best way
to corroborate
this, just
get as many
observatories,
like, their
data and
kind of
cross-check
all of them,
right?
Yes.
So if anybody
out there has
access to
digitized plates
from places
beyond Palomar,
please talk to
us because I
think there's
some very
interesting things
we could do
with that.
And one more
thing that I
like about this
result is that,
again, it
disagrees with
the plate
defects, unless
their intelligence.
Yes, exactly.
If there's any
sort of correlation
between nuclear
and UFOs, it's
like...
Even if we...
Yeah, yeah.
So the emulsion
issues are
somehow biased
towards, you
know, nuclear
detonations, like
that all of a
sudden becomes
much crazier as
a null hypothesis
than just admitting
that there are
these unidentified
objects.
Yeah, people
could of course
say, oh, it's
just cosmic rays
then, or it's
something, you
know, it's some
high energy
particle, but you're
not, you're also
having a correlation
with UFOs.
And plus, if it
would be cosmic
ray particles, they
wouldn't vanish in
the Earth's shadow.
No, they wouldn't.
Also...
At 42,000, so...
They wouldn't vanish
in the Earth's shadow.
They also wouldn't be
systematically tracked
by, you know, maybe
other military
organizations, you
know, while
civilian-facing
organizations are
sort of, you know,
systematically
removing them.
So, is this data
that you receive
from these plates
from the Palomar
Observatory, is that
used in other
serious scientific
investigations?
Do other astronomers
look at that data?
They are used by
lots of astronomers.
So, if there are
systematic plate
defects in what
you're seeing, then
this would discount
any study online
that involves
these Palomar,
this Palomar
Observatory, this
Palomar data.
And you're saying
that it's used by a
lot of serious
astronomers.
No, but what is
usually done, and
always has been
historically done, is
that people only use
the images that,
let's say, the
objects that can be
found on multiple
images, and then you
get rid of all the
transients and the
plate defects.
Okay.
Are there other
examples of plate
defects causing this
number of transients?
Not what I know.
Okay.
So, you've never
heard of an example
like that?
No.
But these
intelligent plate
defects are
correlating with
UFO events, with
nuclear bomb
tests.
They are also
hiding in the
Earth's shadow, and
they're sometimes
being aligned.
They are
remarkable.
Yeah, that's a
pretty remarkable
set of plate
defects.
In 1961, legendary
astronomer Frank Drake
started Project
OSMA, the first
ever organized search
for interstellar radio
signals.
Drake scrounged
together an antenna
and dish using
scrapped radar parts
from World War II,
and pointed the whole
apparatus skywards in
hopes of intercepting
an alien
transmission.
In doing so, he
initiated the largest
scale search for
intelligent life our
astronomical community
has ever engaged in.
SETI, or the
Search for
Extraterrestrial
Intelligence, had
begun its 70-plus
year life.
Outside of a few
unresolvable blips,
like the famous
wow signal discovered
by Jerry Amon at
Ohio State, no alien
radio signals have
ever been detected in
a repeatable,
consistent way.
Nonetheless, the
search is still in
its infancy.
One study literally
calculated that the
volume of the galaxy
that SETI has scanned
so far is like
comparing the volume
of a hot tub of water
to all of the Earth's
oceans and asking,
where are all of the
fish?
Even back in the
early 60s, at the
start of SETI, some
of its scientists
were already exploring
radical alternative
possibilities, even
ones that went far
beyond basic radio
signals.
One such outside-the-box
thinker was electrical
engineer Ronald Bracewell
and his concept of a
communicating probe.
Let's say you're
trying to have a
phone call with
alien broadcasters
in Epsilon Botees,
some 203 light
years away.
You send a message,
hey, what's up?
406 years after you
sent the original
message, comes the
response, nothing
much, how about
you?
The point is, it
would take 406
years just to
exchange those two
sentences.
Interstellar radio
beacons don't exactly
make for engaging
real-time conversation.
The speed of light is
the fastest thing we
know, but it's also
painfully slow.
Here's where Bracewell
saw an intriguing
concept.
Instead of waiting
around for radio
signals to cross
interstellar distances,
why not send a
physical robotic probe
to the star system
of interest?
Even if you couldn't
have a real-time
conversation with
someone from another
star, you could
upload an automated
messaging system, or
even eventually your
mind, into an
interstellar spacecraft,
which could then,
upon arriving in orbit
of the destination
planet, after eons in
the void, initiate a
real-time conversation
with the local
lifeforms.
But what would the
first message be?
How would one even go
about starting such an
interspecies dialogue?
Bracewell's idea was
simple.
You'd intercept whatever
radio transmissions the
locals were already
sending out, and then
send those radio
transmissions back to
them.
Bracewell took his
speculation one step
further by considering
that such a probe may
already be lurking
somewhere in the dark
recesses of our solar
system, waiting to reach
out at any moment.
One may recall a
relevant scene in Carl
Sagan's classic novel
Contact, which follows
SETI astronomer Ellie
Arroway as she intercepts a
genuine extraterrestrial
signal sent from aliens in
the Vega star system.
In a wild plot twist, the
initial contents of the
message come as some shock.
Hitler's speech at the
1936 Olympics was Earth's
first-ever television
broadcast to break through
the ionosphere and reach
space.
So in the novel, Hitler is
also the first representative
of humanity the Vega
civilization sees.
Not exactly a good first
look.
In a manner just like
Bracewell's concept, the
Vega aliens decide to
respond by bouncing
Hitler's speech back to its
initial source, encoding
instructions inside of it to
build an interstellar
wormhole device.
It's worth remembering that the
solar system is a very big
place.
It's also a very ancient
Given the vastness of space
and time in our solar system
alone, where would any such a
probe park itself?
The Earth-Moon Lagrange
points would be the ideal
choice.
Think of Lagrange points as
pockets of stability, where
gravity, rotation, and orbital
motion all balance out, and
objects within these pockets
stay still.
If our solar system truly is
awash in alien time capsules and
artifacts, they'd accumulate in
Lagrange points, like a grand
celestial treasure chest for
space-bound archaeologists.
If you wanted to send a probe to
monitor our planet for millions or
even billions of years, the Lagrange
points are a great strategy for
playing such an observational
long game.
Okay, but Jesse, isn't this
episode supposed to be all about
hard data?
Why all the sci-fi speculation?
Well, it so happens there's a
long, well-documented, unexplained
radio phenomenon that eerily
pattern matches to many of these
ideas and predictions.
I'm talking about long-delay
echoes, or LDEs.
The story begins back in 1927.
Norwegian shortwave radio
radio operators began to notice
something odd.
Shortwave radio naturally travels
around the world and makes its way
back to its source, usually creating
an echo one-seventh of a second
after the initial signal.
This is completely normal and
expected.
One-seventh of a second is how long
it takes to travel around the entire
Earth's circumference at the speed of
light.
Radio waves, of course, travel at the
speed of light.
But for some transmissions, a ghostly
echo would follow, sometimes up to 30
seconds later.
Much too late to be a normal shortwave
radio echo.
The radio operators who first noticed
this phenomenon were completely baffled.
Norwegian physicist Carl Stormer quickly
got to work trying to explain these
mysterious echoes.
To this day, a definitive answer
remains elusive.
A vast majority of LDEs are likely
caused by radio waves bouncing through
plasma in Earth's ionosphere.
A few are more mysterious, perhaps even
echoing from the Earth-Moon Lagrange
points.
Some of the longer delay times match the
travel time to these Lagrange points.
And one study even found a statistically
significant increase in LDEs when the
Earth-Moon L5 Lagrange point was above
the horizon.
Just consider for a moment how closely
long delay echoes resemble Bracewell's
concept for interstellar communication,
taking local transmissions and bouncing
them back.
This, coupled with a possible origin in
Earth-Moon Lagrange points, paints a picture
eerily similar to the long hypothesized
notions of what contact could look like.
Could some of these echoing Bracewell probes
be what Beatrice has detected on the
Palomar plates?
When you spend time with other credentialed
astronomers, after rounds of them
questioning you on possible plate defects,
them doing mathematical calculations,
does anybody still hold out as skeptical
after spending weeks plus with you and diving
into the data?
I mean, the only one I can comment about now
is my referee.
Okay.
And I think he or she is sending bad comments
that are kind of constructive, asking for
more tests.
And I think people are always going to be
skeptical.
There is like...
When you say your referee, what does that
mean?
So, we are working through the revision of the
paper, and it's undergoing like a review
process, which means you are getting back a
lot of questions, whether you are questioning
like your methods, etc.
And I think this process is very important
because it helps you to test your method.
And it also gives you confidence about the
method when results stay robust.
And in general, when I interact with
astronomers, I think the first reaction is
like, oh, it's, you know, it can't be.
Well, it's just my first reaction as well.
Like, it can't be.
But if you see it, then it's there.
And I suspect that scientists are going to be
slower with accepting certain results.
I think the ontological shock among scientists
is going to be more brutal than among the
general population.
Yeah.
Because we are very self-confident about that
we are the smartest.
For sure.
In the universe.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So...
Are you trying to get this published in a
like a prestigious academic journal?
We're trying the traditional way through
peer review.
It's difficult because there's, of course,
it's a touchy topic.
It's touchy results.
Yeah.
And there's going to be a lot of
skepticism.
But the way how I'm seeing it is that
we might not be able to convert anyone
at the moment,
but we can make our data publicly available
so that anyone can go there
and they will have the access to the code as well.
Yeah.
And then they can get their own
ontological shock.
Why should only I have it?
That's the question.
Why did you decide to go public
before getting this published
via peer review?
Let's say like this.
Because I know there's going to be
a lot of pressure on me.
I already have experienced it
from people that are trying to
like save me
by asking me not to talk about it
or like, no.
That's so weird.
It has been a really unpleasant
process in some ways.
Why would they be saving you?
Yeah, because they think they save me by
they think, okay, if you go out with this,
there's going to be this and that
and all these horrible things
are going to happen to you,
et cetera, et cetera.
And I know that
it's going to be tough with the pressure.
And I thought it's more fair
to put out the results,
even the preprint early on
so that people can see
this is where my thoughts are at right now.
Because then
they might also see how things develop.
Yeah.
What happens,
what happens to the results,
have they changed?
It might also be a safer way
when it comes to pressure
because if you
don't put it out
and it leaks out instead
that a lot of people know about it
but they are still not official,
there's a bigger risk
that someone will come
and try to really stop me.
Already now,
people have been kind of,
some of them have been
a little bit unpleasant to deal with.
Have you been approached
by aerospace or military
or people with intelligence backgrounds?
I have been approached
by some people
I suspect have it.
Okay.
And that have been
a little bit scary
to talk to.
Okay.
I mean,
after that the result was out,
I have also been approached
by very,
very nice people
with that kind of background
who have been
instead of supportive.
Yes.
And I appreciate that.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
For me,
it's important to like
meet people who are supportive.
There are good and bad people everywhere.
But you've,
it is,
to me,
it's interesting
that academia
is trying to throw
the kitchen sink
of skepticism
and they don't know
what to think about it
and, you know,
God willing,
you get this published,
you know,
in this academic
prestigious paper.
It's been really scary,
especially like with people
who are,
some of the people
who I thought were my friends
and then they come back
and they comment something
and they try to
push you down maximum
and you say,
hey,
we shared so much
and we talk so much
and I've been so vulnerable
with this person
and then they
try to
stop you from
making an interview
or talk about your work
or something like that
and that's where I just,
why is this?
Why is this happening?
It's a scary result,
I understand.
Yeah.
It's a super scary result,
but...
I think it's an exciting result.
It's not scary.
Well,
it's exciting and scary,
but it still has to be,
I mean,
it has to be out there
and if it turns out
that it was some mistake
in the calculation later,
okay,
then it happens,
shit happens,
we are all humans,
I'm also human
and I'm also learning
and all this stuff,
but the ideas will be out,
the methods we develop
will be out,
someone else
who might have
better methods than me
might use the same ideas
for the Earth's shadow,
alignments,
pre-Sputnik plates,
combine them
and maybe we'll find
really great support
for what we see.
The value of
any scientific endeavor
is how
against the updating
of the consensus
it is.
So if you have something
that's totally not correlated
from what,
you know,
most astronomers think,
that's the most valuable thing
that you could ever look into
and so
the idea that
you shouldn't look into that
is,
to me,
insane
and it's
people who want
to defend,
basically,
the establishment
and the status quo
and,
you know,
it's crazy how we replay
the same cycles over again
but,
you know,
Galileo,
you're like a modern Galileo
or something.
So literally,
in some ways,
because you're looking at,
you know,
it's historical data
but it's through a telescope.
My hope is that
the second,
if we get it published
and we will make
these data sets
publicly available
and people can simply
go in and check it
for themselves.
Yeah.
And they can reply
through by writing a paper.
Right.
Not by doing some,
I don't know,
just complaining to me
they can write a paper.
So you're open-sourcing
this for everybody
to be able to
come to the same conclusion.
I want people to go in
and do this themselves
because I also want
a confirmation
from the outside.
That's beautiful.
So that's how I'm thinking.
I do think it is
telling,
perhaps,
that academia
is more,
like,
disinterested
or skeptical
and they're saying
don't ruin your reputation
and then
you have
aerospace,
military,
those sorts of people
are coming to you
and they're saying,
you know,
they're expressing
more interest
almost as if
maybe they know
a thing or two
about what you've
already found
which has been
my experience
in many things
that I've found
when it comes to
exotic propulsion
or UFOs
is the military
and aerospace
are often like,
there's something there,
you know,
and then academia
has no idea
how to even
conceptualize
what you're talking about
because they're
in this kind of
ivory tower citadel
which is kind of
separated from reality.
I think there's
like,
a certain amount
of like mismatches
one realizes
when one is
interacting with
academics.
I had recently
someone telling me
like,
oh,
every astronomer
wants to be the first
one finding alien life
and you're doing
a mistake,
you're doing the same
mistake as
and he read some names
and I'm just
like,
yeah,
he was upset
over that I wrote
the paper
and that I'm going,
like,
that I might publish it
and I'm just
thinking like,
I'm not out here
to be the first
in something
because if
this result
is correct
then I'm far
from the first.
There are thousands
or ten thousands
of people
who know about it.
There are millions
of UFO reports.
There's nothing
about discovery here.
The only thing
that would happen
is that there is
scientific data
confirming something
that is already known
and probably there's
loads of results
that are classified
related to this.
There's nothing
related to discovery
of being first.
Well,
this is how
science moves forward.
If you read
Thomas Kuhn's
The Structure
of Scientific Revolutions,
he says science
moves forward
more due to politics
than due to truth.
And so,
if you think about
who was the first person
that hypothesized
that we live
in a heliocentric universe
that revolves around
the sun
or solar system,
it was the universe
at the time,
was actually
a guy named
Aristarchus
who was a
third century Greek.
Nobody believed him
and he was forgotten
and then in
the 16th century
you have Copernicus
saying,
you know,
we live in a
heliocentric universe
and then,
you know,
obviously Galileo
helps kind of
see that
through a telescope.
But the point is
is that
people can be
not listened to
for the longest
amount of time
and then
posthumously
be right
and get no credit
and then
it's the right time,
it's the right place
and the discovery
gets born.
but it's way more
about the social
zeitgeist,
people being receptive
and ready
than it is
purely truth.
I agree.
And also,
what about the,
you know,
somebody at the
Palomar Observatory
or a great example
is I interviewed
you last time
and you talked
about Dorit Hofflite
who is this astronomer
who ended up being
a very well-respected
astronomer herself
but at the time
she was kind of
an assistant professor
I think for
Don Menzel
at Harvard
at their observatory
and she talked
about Don Menzel
who is
basically as prominent
in UFO lore
as any astronomer
or astrophysicist
there is
who was privy
to classified Navy
and, you know,
all sorts of data,
military data
and he was a big
UFO debunker
and he was caught
destroying astronomical
plates from the
early 1950s.
It's amazing
the whole thing
and it happened
two months after
the Washington
1952 flap
when, by the way,
that's when we have
our interesting
transient cases too.
There you go.
And then
connect that now
the story
with Don Menzel
to the fact
that the
Vera Rubin telescope
is going to remove
a lot of
classified satellites
and other objects
and now also
that we know
that there's
a background
of uncorrelated
targets
that are classified
also
as far as
I understand.
I mean,
that seems like
a pattern to me
and very worthy
of...
As far as I understand
that's what I
understood from my
source
at NASA.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Well, no,
we can investigate
and look into it.
I would love
to learn more
about this
and check
exactly where
it happens,
where do they
remove them
from which
calculation
and I would
like to learn
more about it
and can you
find a list
from the early
1960s somewhere?
Yeah.
And not only
like 10 of them,
you want something
like thousands
of them.
In light of
Dr. Villareal's
latest paradigm
shifting results,
perhaps we should
at least consider
the possibility
of non-human
technology.
We can also
examine the testimony
of the legendary
French godfather
of ufology himself,
Dr. Jacques Vallée.
Young Jacques
was working
as an astronomer
at the Paris Observatory
as part of its
nascent satellite
tracking program.
One night
on July 11th,
1961,
he and his
colleagues noticed
something truly
bizarre,
an unidentified
object orbiting
the Earth.
The object
was in retrograde
orbit,
going the opposite
direction to
the Earth's
rotation.
To unpack
why this was
so weird,
we need a bit
of Rocket
Science 101.
Many of the
world's top
launch facilities
are located
along the equator.
And no,
dear alchemists,
it's not for
some freaky
symbolic occult
ritual.
It's actually
to get an extra
boost from the
Earth's natural
rotation.
If the Earth
spins on its
axis and your
rocket shoots off
in the same
direction as
that spin,
it takes some
of that momentum
with it on its
way up.
To go against
the Earth's
rotation and
enter a backwards
orbit is much
harder.
As baffling as
this mystery
object's
backwards trajectory
was, it also
may be a clue
to possible
intent.
Retrograde
trajectories often
show up in
polar orbits.
In a polar orbit,
the satellite
passes directly
over the
North and
South Pole,
making it the
only orbit
capable of
imaging the
entire Earth's
surface as the
planet turns
below.
In other words,
if these objects
were indeed from
an alien civilization,
they would have
been peering down
from a perfect
vantage point to
survey the Earth.
Some try to
explain away
Jacques' orbital
mystery sighting
by invoking
the Corona
program, a
series of
highly secretive
CIA-sponsored
satellites first
launched in
1960, kicking
off the modern
era of orbital
espionage.
The Corona
satellites did
have a nearly
polar orbit.
However, it's a
very insufficient
explanation.
As Vallée pointed
out in a later
interview,
Later, I found
out that other
observatories had
made exactly the
same observation,
and that in fact
American tracking
stations had
photographed the
same thing and
couldn't identify
it either.
It was as bright
as the star
Sirius.
You couldn't
miss it.
It didn't reappear
in successive
weeks.
Sirius is the
brightest star in
the night sky,
so if this was an
espionage satellite,
they weren't doing
a great job of
hiding it.
Corona satellites
were deliberately
built with less
reflective materials
than others at
the time,
making it extremely
incompatible with
the exceptional
brightness that
Jacques reports.
Jacques also
mentioned that the
object did not
reappear in successive
weeks, also strange
and inconsistent with
the corona satellite
explanation.
What happened next
would shock young
Jacques to his very
core.
His superior at the
observatory, Paul
Muller, got a hold
of the data.
The next morning,
Muller, who behaved
like a petty army
officer, simply
confiscated the tape
and destroyed it.
Jacques would later
recount realizing that
scientists were human
beings like the rest of
us.
When their reputations
were threatened,
when their ideas
were challenged,
they reacted by
eliminating the data.
If the data didn't
fit their preconceived
notions, they just
got rid of it.
In many ways, this was
the inciting incident
which sent Jacques on
his lifelong hero's
journey to the
furthest edges of the
unexplained.
It also parallels the
heated response
Beatrice now faces
from many of her peers,
and it shows that her
anomalous observations
are in good company.
They don't exist in a
vacuum.
Do you feel like the
world is ready to
accept this?
I think there is no
such moment.
It just happens when
it happens.
Yeah.
On the other hand,
like you say,
sometimes some knowledge
doesn't land well because
it came in the wrong
moments.
I don't know.
But now we have all
the whistleblowers
coming out, or that
they came out and they
gave really great
testimonies, all these
people who have
talked about their
experiences.
Many of them are
really, really
like, really, really
intelligent, brilliant,
healthy in all ways.
Yes.
And it's like people
who want, like,
role model people.
No, we're getting to,
I think, a tipping
point.
Even on my little
YouTube show, you
know, it's like we've
probably broken maybe
15, 16 of these
people with, again,
the intersection of
very credible
backgrounds, Green
Berets, Air Force
Combat Control
recruits, National
Geospatial Agency,
elder statesman,
advisor to the
president, in the case
of Harold Malmgren.
You have all these
people saying the
same thing.
I just interviewed a
chief of aerospace
medicine, you know,
one of the top
doctors.
He was attached to
NASA.
He was at the Air
Force.
He was a senior
doctor there.
And he saw
something.
So it's like,
we're getting to a
tipping point, I
think, where it's
like, okay, one
thing is a
campfire story, but
like, you know,
a hundred?
Like, how do you
explain that away?
I mean, it starts to
get really
interesting.
I mean, if I look
at everything that I
learned in the last
years, I will be
fair.
I don't think we are
alone.
I think we have
company.
And that's my
impression.
I'm hopelessly
curious.
And I cannot, I
cannot stop once I, I
mean, once you see
these kind of results,
it's not like you can
just give up and say,
no, no, I, you
know, I should go and
do some classical
astronomy to support
my living.
You just can't.
It's also like
something you become
dependent on.
Yeah.
Trying to satisfy
that curiosity, ask a
new question, you
have to know.
I think it's just
going to take time for
this to get out
there.
I think when people
actually see this
published and read
it, I think it's
if they think about
it, I think they're
going to be very
intrigued by this.
So it's going to be
interesting to see
what, if anything,
this changes in terms
of the way people
think about science
of UAP.
But I know there
are many other
interesting scientific
projects going on
in the UAP area.
And I think in the
next, you know,
five or ten years,
it's going to be
night and day from
what it has been in
the past.
And we're going to
start seeing a lot
more peer-reviewed
studies, assuming
journals are willing
to take them.
That's always the
concern, is because
of the topic, a lot
of journals don't
even want to touch
it.
We've spent most of
this episode examining
the data, but with
results that so
thoroughly challenge our
existing modalities and
worldviews, it's worth
stepping back and trying
to grasp at a bigger
picture.
So what does all of
this mean, and what
are the deeper
implications?
As with any cosmic
shift in perspective,
Carl Sagan's pale blue
dot comes to mind.
Our imagined self
importance, the
delusion that we have
some privileged position
in the universe, are
challenged.
But what does this all
mean if our pale blue
dot is being intently
studied by other
little pale dots?
Pale dots that fully
surround it.
What new meanings do
Sagan's words carry if
we're actually not a
lonely and obscure
speck, but instead so
enveloped in cosmic
company that tens of
thousands of alien
satellites were studying
our planet before we
could even launch one
of our own?
I can't answer that in
this video, but maybe
trying to contemplate
those questions is a
next step in our
collective evolution.
And if you ever do
find yourself staring up
and watching a starry
night sky, just ask
yourself, who or what
might be staring back?
I want to thank Dr.
Beatrice Villarreal for
her time and for sharing
her remarkable findings.
I also want to thank
Dr.
Steven Bruhl.
Until next time, I'm
Jesse Michaels, and this
is American Alchemy.
Alchemist, did you
enjoy that?
Well, here's the thing.
That episode was just
the tip of the iceberg.
If you want the full
picture, head over to
the American Alchemy
magazine we just
launched on Substack.
That's where we deep
dive into all sorts of
crazy topics that we
don't have time to fit
into every video, with
weekly articles exploring
all of the strange,
forgotten, and
conspiratorial corners of
space, history, and
high weirdness.
So join up today at our
free or paid tiers on
Substack.
I am including the full
link in the description
of this video.