Gary and Mary Ruth, we've been working on this story for a long time,
and we'll tell you right up front that it's going to be hard to swallow at first.
In 1989, a soft-spoken scientist in Nevada went on local television
and said something that would baffle the world for the next three decades.
Do you copy over?
He said that he had worked at a secret government facility called S4,
just south of Area 51 in the Nevada desert,
where his job, his actual job, was to reverse-engineer the propulsion system of a craft,
a craft that was not made by human hands.
A flying saucer, 53 feet in diameter, no seams, rivets, panels, buttons, wiring, or controls.
Ladies and gentlemen, today's guest is the white whale of American alchemy guests,
the enigmatic and ever-elusive Bob Lazar.
Robert Lazar.
Bob Lazar.
Lazar.
That Lazar dude freaked me to f*** out, man.
Oh, he's a freakout.
Bob is basically a walking paradox, a human headspinner.
He almost feels like an optical illusion of a person.
Back then, Area 51 meant nothing.
We've now heard a former director of national intelligence who oversaw all American intelligence
agencies openly discuss a UFO tracking program housed at Area 51 specifically.
We've also seen past directors of the CIA, congressmen and women, and whistleblowers across
agencies endorsing the existence of a decades-long, multi-generational UFO crash retrieval and reverse
engineering program.
But Bob is an anomaly.
He's on an island.
He's still the only person to have gone public claiming he worked directly on a craft of non-human
origin.
We've speculated about his story for years.
Today, we get to talk to him directly.
They really wanted to see if they could affect the flow of time.
Did they have a stated purpose for...
No.
In this interview, we get to ask him our most skeptical questions about his background, his
education, his past, how he knows what he knows, and why he hasn't been forced into
silence.
John Lear was super into UFOs before you got the job.
Why do you think it didn't come up in a background check?
There are a lot of people out there who say you faked your educational credentials.
Did you ever wonder why they didn't view you as a liability?
But we also ask our most awe-inspiring questions.
We learn new details about where the craft he worked on was actually retrieved.
We discuss the beings that may have occupied it, where they come from, and what they want
with humanity.
We even learn about Bob's current home laboratory experiments.
He's still investigating the gravity-altering force he encountered while working on a flying
saucer in the 80s.
You heard me right, Bob is currently working on exotic UFO science in his personal lab.
How did the reactor work?
Through x-rays, we were able to determine that there's a hollow tube.
But this interview gets even crazier than that.
I surprise Bob with a scientist at NASA who's doing his own experiments on anti-gravity.
What kind of voltage are you using?
Right now, about 400 volts.
That's unbelievable.
I also had the honor of showing Bob legendary, never-before-seen footage of a UFO at Area 51.
People have been trying to get their hands on this specific footage for years.
Ready?
Yeah.
I'm going to the beginning.
Here we go.
Holy moly.
Oh, s***.
This interview spans multiple days with both Bob and filmmaker Luigi Vendatelli, the maker
of S4, the Bob Lazar story.
Luigi has spent four years working closely with Bob to depict exactly what he saw and worked
on at S4 in vivid, hyper-realistic detail.
We really, really paid attention to what Bob said throughout the entire time.
So we didn't invent anything.
Without further ado, please welcome this week's American Alchemist, the man who helped reverse
engineer a UFO, went public, and lived to tell the tale.
The original UFO whistleblower, Bob Lazar.
The glistening frequency, sir.
How is this possible?
Nothing too unusual about that.
The existence cannot longer be denied.
We're living through the biggest transformation of the financial system in a hundred years.
And most people are still using the same platforms their parents used.
I started to investigate the financial space in 2012 because I genuinely believed that the
fiat dollar system was broken.
Not slightly broken.
Structurally, fundamentally broken.
It's what you might call a long con.
Or perhaps a Ponzi scheme.
I started to believe that a transparent, decentralized alternative wasn't just possible.
It was necessary.
I've spent 13 years researching it.
Living it.
Talking to the most serious minds.
Building it.
Kraken is the platform I kept coming back to with my own money.
So when we finally decided to bring on our first ever financial sponsor in four years
of doing this show, we went to them.
Because I've used the product and I already believed in what they're building.
Every other investing platform is essentially the old system with a better app on top.
Kraken is different at a foundational level.
They've been operating since 2011, through every market crash, shout out Mt. Gox, every
industry collapse, every moment other platforms failed their users.
And when everything went catastrophically wrong in this industry, the people responsible for
making customers whole didn't go to the biggest names in finance.
They came to Kraken.
On top of that, they publicly prove, not promise, prove that every dollar you deposit is fully
accounted for.
Anyone in the world can verify it at any time.
No fine print.
No blind faith.
Just proof.
You can buy stocks and crypto in one place, earn better rewards than any investment account
you've ever had, and send money anywhere in the world without those annoying fees your
bank charges you for the exact same thing.
Again, I've never taken on a financial platform as a sponsor in four years of this show.
Having full control over your money shouldn't be about belief.
It's the whole point.
So go to kraken.com slash AA to learn more and get $25 in Bitcoin.
Again, that's kraken.com slash AA double A.
Owning the power of your money isn't just a belief.
It's the whole point.
One of the main reasons I'm able to go multiple hours on these podcasts while staying mentally
sharp is because of this little drink.
It's a product I started using years ago, and it's called Ketone IQ.
I know the founders Jeff and Michael personally, and I was thrilled when they agreed to sponsor
the show because it's one of the few products I trust to give me clean, sustainable energy.
I've been taking a little shot of this thing during every long recording, and it lights
my brain on fire.
As you can see, Bob even took a shot during this one.
The reason I keep coming back to these products is because I don't really do coffee.
Coffee gives me a spike of energy, and then at some point, I get jittery and I crash.
Ketone IQ is fundamentally different.
It gives you clean, steady mental clarity with no crash and no jitters.
Here's the science behind why it actually works.
When you're running on glucose or sugar, as your brain is most of the time, it's essentially
burning dirty fuel.
Your brain could be like a Ferrari, but you're feeding it 87-octane fuel all the time.
Ketones are what your brain actually prefers when it's operating at its best.
Normally, you'd have to fast for days in order for your body to switch from glucose to ketones.
This little shot of Ketone IQ gives you the ketones directly, so your brain runs the way
it's supposed to, without any spikes or crashes.
It was originally developed through a multi-million dollar Department of Defense contract for elite
cognitive performance under stress.
Bob Lazar probably could have used that at S4.
So the same technology that's used by soldiers in high-demand environments is now available
to anyone in the form of this little drink.
So visit ketone.com slash alchemy for 30% off your subscription order, plus receive a
free gift with your second shipment.
That's ketone.com slash alchemy for a whole 30% off.
Or find Ketone IQ at Target stores nationwide and get your first shot free.
Bob Lazar, I don't even know what to say.
This is a make-a-wish day for me.
This is an absolute honor.
I'm so grateful for you being here.
I have so many questions for you because there are a lot of people who say they've seen things
in the sky or they've had ephemeral experiences, sometimes even with beings.
There are very few people who have consistently held to the exact same story over the last
almost four decades now.
And it involves working on a craft and essentially reverse engineering or parallel process engineering
what is a craft of non-human origin, an exotic craft.
And so you are really one of one.
And I can't wait to dive in.
And I just want to thank, before we start, Luigi Vendatelli, who is the amazing creator
of this movie that you are in.
Physical evidence now exists, which proves that there is life elsewhere.
And at least one form of that life has been here.
I want to start with your childhood.
And what was little Bob Lazar like?
I guess he was like a little scientist.
I mean, I wasn't into sports at all.
Still aren't.
Instead of playing with toys, I take apart clocks and things like that that my parents had and,
you know, put them back together.
I was just very inquisitive.
Were you a rule breaker at all?
Yeah, for the most part.
I really had a problem with authority.
So I really didn't matter if it was my parents or teachers, whatever, telling me what to do.
I said, I just don't recognize your authority to tell me that I can't do what I'm doing.
And yeah, that just seems to be part of my DNA.
Yeah, it seems to be a running theme in your life.
So authority felt sort of arbitrary to you.
It's like, why are you in a position to have any power?
Right, right, right.
You're not even, you really don't even understand what I'm up to and, you know, you're already trying to put the kibosh on it here.
So, no, go away and leave me alone.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Did you have any interest in UFOs, aliens, anything like that as a kid?
No, no, no.
I thought that was all silly.
Yeah.
No, I was always into science and science fiction when I was a little kid.
I watched, I think, like five and six.
I watched that, oh, the super marionation series like Fireball XL5 and Thunderbirds and, you know, they were all like marionette shows, but they're all space and cool and rockets and, you know, this is all great.
You know, that's what.
And then later on, you know, Star Trek, science fiction, because it always looked like that it was just a prediction of the future to me.
It didn't look like it was, you know, stuff that was never going to come true.
It just looked like eventually this stuff's going to happen.
And for the most part, science fiction turns into science given enough time.
Becomes science fact.
Yeah, yeah.
Were there any inspirations sci-fi-wise that you felt had like a real impact on you as far as your, you know, what you were interested in as a kid?
But, you know, everybody my age, a boomer that's an engineer, doctor, scientist, whatever, they'll always point back to Star Trek and always give that a nod because that was, so that was probably the biggest thing back there in the 60s and 70s.
Yep.
And so where'd you grow up?
Well, I was born in Florida, but most of my growing up, you know, I was cognizant of what was going on.
It was Long Island.
Okay.
New York, yeah.
Interesting.
You ended up at Pierce, is that right?
Or what was the kind of progression from childhood?
I just moved around.
Okay.
You know, it depended where I was at the time when I went to California and, you know, on the East Coast.
Yep.
It was just location dependent.
You know, like I mentioned the other day, I moved so much.
Yeah.
Yeah, it was almost like a military family.
Yeah, was it because your dad had jobs that he was switching around or what was going on?
You know, I really don't know what it was, but we were just always moving.
Yeah, interesting.
And, you know, always having to make new friends and whatnot.
But, I don't know.
Yeah, yeah.
It was just the way it was.
My father always did some weird things that strained things up his sleeve.
So, I don't know what was going on.
Yeah, I think there was some potentially shady stuff going on in the background.
Interesting.
Okay.
What did he do professionally, just like surface level?
He had, I know he had some connection to the mob at some point.
Okay.
I mean, he had like a food business, a wholesale food business, you know, that distributed food to grocery stores, you know, all over the place.
But there was, and he had a big connection to race horses.
I mean, I remember when I was a little kid of the, what do they call it, harness racing, you know, where they sit in the little sulky behind the horse, little two-wheeled contraption.
And, you know, I remember those guys, the jockeys, riders, whatever you want to call them.
But I remember, you know, playing in the living room and hearing those guys deciding who's going to win the race and things of that sort.
So, I mean, I knew that there were some shady things going on.
Yeah, whenever you have race horses and tracks, there's often some money laundering.
Yeah, especially back down in the, you know, early 70s and stuff.
It couldn't, it couldn't be more corrupt.
Absolutely.
You know.
Interesting.
Okay.
And so, he was involved in that, but maybe there was some other stuff kind of going on in the background.
Yeah, and nothing where people are hurt or anything like that.
You know, not, not mob stuff, but.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
But, you know, I mean, just some questionable things.
Never talked about.
Yeah.
So, I mean, we did, we did move around a lot, but.
Spent most of the time either in.
Well, it really depends what year, you know, I was somewhere.
And were you into nuclear science as a kid as well, or just kind of like science generally?
No, just science.
I mean.
Okay.
My friends were.
I had a friend whose dad was a chemistry professor.
So, you know, we'd go and hang out with him and bring home chemicals and, you know, play with him.
But it was, yeah, from as young as I could possibly be, it was always tinkering around with something science related.
Yeah.
So, at school, what was that like?
You're this rebellious kid.
You're into science.
Did you hate school?
Yeah, yeah.
Because you saw.
I hated school because it's just interfering with my time.
I want to get home and get back to tinkering with my stuff.
You know, I don't.
You know, you couldn't bore me any more than I was.
I didn't want to go to a music class.
I don't care what they're doing here.
And on, you know, everything as social studies, I don't care who won what war.
Just let me go home.
You know, I've got other things I'd rather learn.
But, you know, the classes that I was in, that matched my interest, I did well with.
But everything else was a waste of my time.
What were you tinkering with at home?
Probably at that time, probably electronics and chemistry.
Okay.
And then how'd you get the job at Los Alamos?
At the time, I was working at Fairchild Electronics in Simi Valley, California.
And I was just tired and burnt out of that.
And just sent a resume to Los Alamos.
But really laid heavily on the stuff, not my work history, things that I did.
Aside from work, I took my wife's little Honda, built a jet engine from scratch and put it in there.
Then, in fact, that was one of the things I, you know, sent in a resume to him.
Oh, by the way, I built this car.
And, yeah, when I moved there, the local paper put that on the front page because they thought that was really cool.
And that's why most people remember me at that time because I drove it to work at Los Alamos.
Yeah.
In fact, they yelled at me for, you can't run the jet coming into the lab because it scares the shit out of everybody.
How fast would the car go?
212.
Jesus.
Yeah, yeah.
On that car, it's super dangerous.
I would never do that today.
That's insane.
Yeah, but...
So you're putting, like, a Bugatti engine on a Honda Civic and you're like...
Yeah, in a way, yeah.
Unbelievable.
Yeah, it's silly.
But you're stupider when you're in your 20s, yeah.
Well, what was your top speed?
212.
Yours was 212.
Yeah.
You went 212.
El Mirage Dry Lake in California.
You're insane.
Maybe, but that's how fast the car went.
But the Honda Civic is not set up for the jet engine that you put on it.
Well, it was after I put it in there.
Oh, so you helped with the suspension and some of that stuff.
You improved.
Wow.
Yeah.
That's impressive, man.
That's cool.
Well, while working at Los Alamos National Lab in 1982,
the local newspaper did a front-page story on a jet car I had built.
Coincidentally, Dr. Edward Teller was giving a speech at Los Alamos that same day.
So Edward Teller, for the audience, was the creator of the hydrogen bomb.
Coincidentally, that same day on the paper, if you turn over the front sheet,
was the advertisement for Ed Teller coming the next day.
Wow.
Giving a lecture, you know, at the lab, so.
So you go to, like, a talk he gives or something?
Yeah, he was about to give a talk.
I got there early.
He's sitting outside reading the paper because the door was locked.
Uh-huh.
So that's, I wanted to go super early, too, because I thought maybe it's going to be crowded or whatever.
He's reading the front page of the paper because, or else I really didn't know how to go out and say anything,
but I went, oh, it's the perfect segue.
He's already reading about me.
So I was like, hi, Ed, I'm the guy you're reading about there.
What was Edward Teller like?
He's a grumpy old man.
That's just the only way I could describe him.
Did he have any sort of distinct accent or facial?
Of course he has a distinct accent.
Ed Teller, yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
A bit thick Hungarian.
Yeah, he had giant eyebrows and, yeah.
Yeah.
I mean, he looked exactly like himself.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Fascinating.
And so what was the conversation like?
Are you like, hey, that, you know, that's me.
And then what did he, what did he say?
He said, well, that's, that's fascinating.
But, you know, I can't remember it verbatim, but he said.
But it is grossly impractical.
I said, yeah, it's not made to be a practical, you know, mode of transportation.
And then we only spoke for a short time and then you can hear the door unclick, swing open.
And a guy greeted him, oh, Mr. Teller.
And so they brought him in and, you know, that was that.
But as time went on, I made reference to that meeting when I sent him a resume after I had moved on from Los Alamos.
And he remembered me.
And that's who directed me to EG&G, how this all started to go to S4.
Have you ever seen, there's a, there's a video of, um, Edward Teller being questioned on his relationship with you?
Yeah, yeah, of course.
It's really funny because he, first of all, he goes into, he's being questioned on nuclear propulsion and he, like, doesn't want to get into it.
It's very clear.
And then he's questioning on you and he has the exact same reaction.
It is, in my opinion, not interesting.
I don't intend to answer it.
If you ask me that question on camera, I will shut up.
I will sit silent.
You're not going to get an answer right on me on that.
Okay.
And if I ask you on camera if you know Bob Lazar, can you just say no?
I will sit silently.
I mean, I spoke to the guy before he went and interviewed Teller.
He was one of Teller's students.
And he said, you know, I'm going to bring up you to Teller.
And I went, that would be awesome.
Yeah.
And it would be awesome to see how fast he denies me.
You know, and he did immediately.
But he denied you in the same way.
First, he goes, yeah, technically you could get, you know, a real power source from nuclear.
And basically implying he knows a lot about it, but he's not going to talk about it.
Yeah.
I think he said, yeah, is there anything other than fish and refusion?
That's right.
No, nothing that anybody interested about.
Yeah.
But there's total annihilation, you know.
And yeah, he just completely discounted that, which is interesting for Teller.
Do you think that he is talking about, because you talk about this 115, you had a problem.
I don't know if that's what he was referring to.
Goes up to 116, and then you get this matter, antimatter annihilation thing.
I don't know if that's what he was referring to, but he's also, but he's clearly not addressing
the most powerful nuclear reaction there is.
And why would he do that?
And he's clearly also denying the nuclear knowledge in the same way that he's denying
his link to you.
Which to me is such a tell that he obviously met you.
Yeah.
It's really weird that he would do that.
And so you were at Los Alamos, and were you working with other physicists at the time?
Yeah, yeah.
Or what was your main kind of like day-to-day responsibility there?
Well, it changed.
Um, I did some, I was building, I think, uh, this was for the particle accelerator.
They wanted to be able to trim the voltage to a very fine degree.
So I was building some high voltage power supplies, stuff that's insulated by fiber optics, so you
can make adjustments, you know, from a distance without interfering with, you know, the electric
fields or anything.
Um, and day-to-day there was just maintenance on the targets and experiments we were doing.
So it's cryogenics and, you know, dealing with, uh, high power magnets.
And, I mean, what else?
Radio actors' materials.
Yeah.
Um, you know, Los Alamos stuff.
I mean, I'm just trying to remember what I did every day, but it was, uh, nothing, it
was, there was no really regular routine.
Mm-hmm.
You know, we'd either be working on getting ready to do an experiment, so we'd be working
on, you know, the detection equipment.
Yeah.
Or setting up the experiment.
And, um, it all had to do with, uh, you know, the output of the accelerator and adjusting
that.
So this was a particle accelerator?
Yeah, yeah.
Oh, interesting.
Yeah, it's a half mile long linear accelerator in Los Alamos.
Oh, cool.
And the beam splits off, it, uh, it comes down and it, it splits off into different experimental
areas.
So you can conduct a whole bunch of different experiments, you know, just from one, one beam.
And they can put different things in the targets to make different particles and go different
directions.
And depending on the speed of the particle going by and its spin and how long it's in transit,
you can calculate its mass and, you know, backtrack and then put things together.
And, you know, analogy I always gave was, uh, it's, it's like if you wanted to analyze
a Swiss watch, but you really couldn't look inside.
But so you could take it and throw it as hard as you can at a concrete wall and then it busts
apart and all the pieces go flying off.
Yeah.
Well, by looking at those pieces, you could backtrack everything.
You could see if one was spinning a certain direction and you know, the rotation and how
fast it came off, then, you know, the mass of it, if it was turning before and by the
angles, you can put it back there and eventually you can reassemble the thing and see how it
was made just from the particles flying apart.
So essentially what an accelerator does is smash something apart and then we can figure
out how it all goes together just by monitoring those particles.
It's so cool.
Yeah.
So, I mean, that's, that's, that's what I did at Los Alamos.
Did you, did you get the sense that there were two branches of science, science that
was a little more classified and then public science?
No, not at that point.
Not at that point.
I thought we were all on the same level.
Yeah.
Now I know, um, you can't say why they erased you from MIT and there are a lot of people out
there who say you faked your educational credentials.
You have very good, I think, reason that at least passes, you know, Joe Rogan and some
other people who I really trust their sniff test.
He said that he was working on something for the government at, and they sent him to MIT
to learn something.
But I will ask you, is there anything you can say high level that hints at why you can't
talk about why you're at MIT?
Well, I was sent there.
Okay.
And, um, if you're sent like there for a specific reason, um, maybe to do some classified research
or work.
Yep.
Um, it's going to be off the books.
Yeah.
I mean, but it's also, you also can't talk about it because it's still, I mean, look,
the government's never going to come and prosecute me for, at least I hope not, for releasing
information about S4.
Yep.
But assuming I was working on a weapons system, that's always, it's still covered under the
security agreement.
And at this point in my life, I just don't want to make any waves.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
So, um.
No, I think that's very reasonable.
It's also, I should note, and this is me talking and not you, MIT Long is a university, you know,
affiliated research center.
It's called the UARC.
And they do all sorts of classified stuff.
You know, they have a.
Yeah, yeah.
Super soldier program.
They're, you know, we're always at the forefront of nanotechnology.
And so, uh, the idea that, uh.
Well, anything I would have potentially been working on wouldn't be so outlandish as super
soldiers or it'd be just very conventional.
Sure.
Um.
You know, but still classified material.
Yeah.
Touching stuff.
I think, I think, I think it's just helpful because, um, this stuff is circulating out there.
And, you know, the idea that you would get sent to that school specifically and work on
something that you can't talk about is very feasible.
I'm not saying that I did get sent, but if I would have gotten sent.
Theoretically.
Hypothetically.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
You got sent there.
If I got sent there, uh, you know, I, yeah, there's a very clear possibility I wouldn't be
able to talk about it and I'd be working on some classified stuff.
If you wanted to hire a guy who could think clearly out of the box and help solve problems,
but who could be discredited if you needed to do that, Bob was probably the best person
in the country at the time.
He was perfect for it.
George Knapp was originally this very instrumental part of Breaking Your Story in 1989 as part
of KLAS.
Uh, did you, you took him to Los Alamos, is that right, at some point?
Yeah, I told him all this Los Alamos stuff and, um, I said, well, let's go there.
I'll show you.
And, uh, security was a little more lax back then.
Uh, so I, we got in a plane and, uh, you just rented a car and, you know, at that time,
everyone I knew still worked there.
So including the guards, we're getting in, hey, Bill, Bob, you're back, you know?
And so we're in and, uh, you know, just took charge everywhere.
There's my desk, here's this, and, you know, walk in here.
And I still knew combinations to places of water.
I'm sure it was not all a hundred percent legal, but yeah, George just walked around,
filmed everything, spoke to people that I worked with.
And he said, all right, we can check that box off.
And then, um, we went back.
Yeah.
And so, cause I also, you know, again, I want to, uh, uh, address some of these like detracting
comments circulating online.
And there are people who are like, oh, he just quizzed the physicists, you know, at Los
Alamos, but he really had some other job there or something.
First of all, like your, your, uh, description of a particle accelerator and, and how to actually,
you know, detect subatomic particles, I think was, you know, first class.
And then second, you have a guy in George Knapp, which you are, you have to either, um,
accuse him of some sort of collusion or something in his orientation towards you or admit that
you showed him around, people knew your name, you know, he saw it.
Yeah.
And clearly he was trying to suss you out by asking you to invite him.
Right.
Presumably.
Yeah.
I just don't pay attention to the detractors and the nonsense.
I mean, to me, we're, we're, we're past that.
Now I never met Dr.
Teller again, but in 1988, when I decided to reenter the scientific community, I sent him
him a resume and inquired about a job.
Dr.
Teller responded by telephone and told me that he was no longer active, but just functioned
in a chief consultant capacity.
He gave me the name of a contact to call in Las Vegas.
I made that call and things progressed from there until I got into the program at S4.
And so you sent him the resume and he remembers you somehow.
And which.
Yeah.
Cause I made mention of the jet car in Los Alamos.
And then, and then he sends your resume to EG&G and then you get a job there.
I don't, I don't know if he sent it.
He, uh, when he did reply to me, he, he gave me information, contact information for EG&G.
So I don't know if he said, or just have a look at this young man or something like that.
Or, or if he did send the resumes, I don't know what happened behind the scenes.
Did you know anything about EG&G at the time or.
I know they did measurements.
They did all the, uh, I mean, those are the guys that came out and figured how to, you
know, photograph, uh, you know, an exploding nuclear bomb without it getting overexposed.
Um, they did all kinds of things, make giant flash tubes so you can photograph cities from
bombers and, and stuff.
So, um, that's about all I knew.
I knew they were just, uh, you know, a contractor that did weird stuff for the government, but,
you know, leaning heavily in the nuclear testing area.
It's a company that is the namesake of Doc Edgerton, who was MIT faculty actually, and.
Edgerton, Grimmerhausen, and Greer.
There you go.
Many types of cameras will be in use.
The most important are fast packs, which operate up to 9,000 frames per second and expose their
entire footage in a fraction of a second.
Have you looked at any of the other, you know, I obviously are really into nuclear and then
you worked on UFOs.
There's this amazing book that I always cite that I'm sure you're aware of Luigi called
UFOs and Nukes by a friend of mine named Robert Hastings.
And he talks about UFOs like Tic Tacs, saucers, orbs, all these different shapes and sizes of
UFOs showing up at nuclear bases all across the U.S.
I've certainly heard that.
Isn't that interesting?
And there are 167 whistleblowers who are on what's called the PRP program, where they
have to report if they're taking ibuprofen because they're guarding the crown jewels of
American defense.
Oh, really?
167 of these guys.
Wow.
Yeah.
There's really 167 of those guys?
167 of these guys.
It's really wild.
And they have teeth.
Yeah.
That's incredible.
I mean, that should be investigated further.
And I'm sure it is, but not publicly.
But I mean, you're talking about nuclear sites.
If you're talking about nuclear sites, you are at the very core of national security.
So my point is, is if you're doing the photography of that early on, you've got to have some asymmetric
knowledge of UFO stuff.
That would be my guess.
Yeah.
They were the guys documenting and photographing everything from every angle from everywhere.
Yes.
So if, in fact, all that stuff was going on, EG&G had to catch something.
Totally.
And EG&G, it keeps coming up for me, too, in my own investigations.
Even there's this thing called the Wilson Davis memo where the scientist who actually lives
in Austin, his name is Eric Davis, meets with the head of J-2 Joint Chiefs, under whose purview
is all military technology.
A guy named Admiral Thomas Wilson.
And they're in the parking lot of EG&G.
And Thomas Wilson is like furious that he doesn't have oversight over this specific corporate
program, which seems to be reverse engineering exotic UFO material.
So you get a job at EG&G.
What's your first touch point there?
And so you have a little bit of context, but...
Yeah, I originally went in there.
I didn't know what the job was.
Yeah.
But they interviewed me for that.
And somewhere in the middle of it, they said, you know, we actually have a different job
that we're thinking of plugging you into now.
I think I went to the bathroom and when I came back, they said, we're changing channels.
We think we have.
And I think, so I don't know if they were both something at S-4 or something else was
going to be for EG&G or the Department of Naval Intelligence.
And then they thought maybe S-4 would be a, you know, a better fit.
I don't know what, again, what went on behind the scenes, but there were two jobs there and
they decided I'd be better off with the second one.
And the second one was S-4 out at the Papoose Lake area.
And what were they screening for?
Like, what do you think they were asking you and trying to get at?
And then when you go to the bathroom, why do they shift?
I don't know.
And they say, this guy is actually going to, that UFO thing we're stuck on, this guy is
going to break it wide open.
He could be a good hire there.
Do you have any sense?
I don't think that's what they said.
But I think they were stuck and I think they kept, you know, just because of the way the
place is arranged, they kept trying to attack the problem from the same direction all the
time, you know, which is only going to yield the same result.
In fact, if you expect anything else, you're nuts.
That's the definition of crazy, right?
Doing the same thing and expecting different results.
But, um, yeah, most of their questions was not about, um, my technical knowledge or work
experience.
It was what I did after work and, you know, like the projects I built, why did you do
that?
Um, and I think they were just looking at trying to find somebody that was outside of the box.
And I think that's where I fit.
Cause before that you had really straight laced scientists, physicists, technicians, you
know, that abided by the rules and all that.
And they look, we need a little push from another direction.
And I mean, it's my guess.
I think that's why they popped me in there.
At that point, do you have any idea what you're getting yourself into?
No, no.
But the, you know, they said it's at a remote area and the work hours can vary.
Some people are out there for, uh, two weeks on one week off.
Yeah.
Um, some people, and you know, it depends if they're married or not or anything and, you
know, can spend that much time out there.
Some people only go out three days a week and, you know, so, and some people are just
on call and, you know, for the time being, it would probably just probably need you sporadically
going out there on call and, you know, until we get you up to speed.
And do you have any problem with traveling?
I said, no, no, no.
You know?
So I thought, wow, if it's out in the desert, um, it's probably, I thought it was the only
thing I knew about the desert was at that time, it's a nuclear test site.
So I thought, I thought it was weapons related and, you know, specifically nuclear weapon related.
And I was going to be at, uh, you know, the nuclear test site at somewhere, you know,
stationed near Mercury.
The way it worked was they'd call me at random days and they'd say, Mr. Lazard is now such
and such time.
We need you to come out today.
So I'd go out there.
I'd drive out to EG&G Special Projects, which was right in McCarran Airport at that time.
I'd go through a little security there and then out on the tarmac and board one of the
Janet flights.
They were only used by the government for going back and forth to the test site.
Yeah, we just took off and landed.
Yeah.
And, uh, I still thought I was at the, you know, I didn't know what I was at, Area 51.
Yep.
And you land at Area 51.
Yeah.
And first of all, at that time, Area 51 meant nothing.
So it's just, this is known as Area 51.
Okay.
As all the, all the, you know, the test sites split up into areas.
It's Area 2, Area 5.
So it's 51.
Okay.
At what point, uh, do you go to ask for?
You know, these, I've told the story so much and it's been so long.
All the days kind of mix and infuse into one now.
So I can't separate what you did on that day.
What'd you do on the third day?
I don't know.
You know, it's just, um, of course, but I don't think we drove down on the first day.
I think it was just a paperwork and stuff day.
Uh, but the second day for sure, we drove down, um, got in the bus and it was a long bumpy
ride.
Um, and that the windows were blacked out on the bus and it was just a navy blue painted
bus and it, it seemed like we went South, um, by the time we got there, it got off the
bus.
I, I mean, the sun was setting to my right.
And then what happens next?
Well, I mean, when you mean when I got there?
Yeah.
I mean, that's where we, Dennis led me in, um, and he's Dennis for the audience.
I guess you can call him my supervisor, but he was kind of my shadow and everything.
He was just attached to me.
This is Dennis Mariani.
Dennis Mariani.
Yeah.
And so he leads you in.
He leads me in.
There's a, there's a guard there.
Um, we get past him and then they had to train the, uh, hand reader to give me a, a card
to open the doors.
So that's the first time I saw that hand scanner.
I get the card.
He shows me this, you swipe on the door and it records every time you come in and out
and do everything.
And is there a bodyguard or like, uh, no, no.
Once you're in the room with the scanner, there's nothing.
There's just a door you open up, but it's just a really long, really long corridor and
just kind of, it's not modern looks old.
It's just painted cinder block with light green and dark green.
Kind of looked at my old kindergarten or something.
It's this vast expanse.
And is all of it underground or in a mountain or?
It's kind of on the side of a mountain.
Okay.
You know, it's, so the hangers are right on the side or it's a hill.
I guess whatever you want to describe it.
Sure.
So the hangers are there and then the corridor is in back of the hangers.
So that gives you hangar access.
And there were nine hangers.
So, um, and they're fairly big.
So that explains why the corridors were so long.
And so you're in there, you see this vast expanse, then what happens?
We went to review the briefings first.
So that was off to the right.
We came in, there was a desk there had, somebody had already laid out all the, uh, the briefings,
which were summaries of the projects going on.
So they didn't go in depth, but in case your project connected to some of these in some way,
you had to have a brief overview of what else was going on.
Project Galileo was the first, uh, you know, the first briefing on there.
And that was your project.
Yeah.
And then, but you had other briefings as well.
And, and, and that was project looking glass.
Looking glass and, uh, sidekick.
And sidekick.
Okay.
Yeah.
And so I imagine you take most interest in Galileo and, but you also look through looking
glass and sidekick.
Is that right?
But Galileo dealt with the propulsion system of the craft and, um, and the directives that
are given, uh, there were two primary directives is one to, uh, duplicate the propulsion system
or components thereof with available materials, available earth materials.
It's, uh, um, and directive two was to be able to remotely, um, disable the operation of the
system.
Uh, and some, I don't know how it was worded somewhere.
The word at all costs was in there.
So, um, that was really a high priority, but they wanted to, uh, they certainly wanted to
duplicate it, but they really wanted to disable it.
I do think that's an important distinction in the mandate of the program.
It's to not necessarily reverse engineer, but to parallel engineer, find ways to, with
terrestrial normal prosaic engineering, build.
Yeah.
Or come up with a hybrid system, something.
I mean, the, the bottom line is we want to produce the effects this machine is having.
So just do it in any, yeah, however, however you can just, yeah, just do it.
Which makes sense given the skillset they seem to take interest in with you because you are
this outside of the box thinker.
Yeah.
You're not this prim and proper traditional academic or something who does not want to
break rules who might be extremely high IQ, but, uh, isn't necessarily rebellious in the
way they think, they think within these sort of narrow confines they're given.
Yeah.
They were, they were just looking to come at another angle and maybe we can, you know,
uncover something.
And, and just for the audience, what is sidekick and what is project looking glass?
Sidekick was the weapon potential of the craft.
The craft, if you're familiar with it, has three of the, uh, emitters on the bottom look
like large trash cans and they send out the gravity waves or whatever form of energy is,
but excuse me, sidekick dealt with using those to focus a particle beam to stop it from diverging.
So there was, it, it appeared to be there, there was some sort of weapon potential of doing
that.
Like a directed energy weapon.
Yeah, I think it was a particle weapon.
So, um, I don't know where the, what the source was, but that's, that's just what the briefing
contained in it.
And, um.
Are you given any other context before reading these documents?
No.
And when you're reading these documents, what, what's going through your.
No, I mean, some of the stuff in there was just nonsense.
I mean, and you wonder, is this like a test?
Um, you know, there is stuff like, you know, the aliens had made 65 corrections to, um, you
know, in the evolution of humans and things.
And as Barry explained to me, um, he said, look, they keep everything classified here,
but if somebody says something, you know, and they hear it on the grapevine, they said,
yeah, they've got a disc, an alien craft at, you know, down at the test site.
They don't know where it comes from, but everybody that they give briefings or information to,
they put unique nonsense information there.
So like if I had said anything, they, you know, I said, yeah, there's flying saucers
down there and aliens made 65 corrections.
They go, Lazar is the guy that, that, so that's, I think they put it in there to attach
to a person, you know, he got this and they make it something enticing to say.
So you go through these briefings, what happens next?
At some point I went to the nurse who, um, it was the only female that was there.
Uh, she, she said, you know, we have to do an allergen test and I guess they had a bunch
of samples from different materials.
They do a little grid on my arm and then just pricked them and, you know, waited for a reaction.
Um, they gave me something to drink, which is supposedly supposed to boost my immune system.
It was a, you know, a deep orange, yellow color.
And I think that was because the vitamin B was in there and I can, I can taste that
because it's really a nasty taste.
What did it taste like?
Yeah.
Like a vitamin B solution.
Okay.
But it did, but it also had a pine taste to it.
But anyway, that was that.
I wasn't allergic to anything as it turned out.
And eventually get it, go in and was introduced to Barry, who's going to be my lab partner.
And, um, you know, from what I understand, I was replacing somebody that he worked with.
Hmm.
What was Barry like?
Barry, I don't know.
How would you describe Barry?
Barry was very enthusiastic.
Yeah.
He was, he was really happy I was there and, uh, really excited to show me stuff.
Um, but clearly a lot had been done before I got there.
Yeah.
If this was new, everything would be white, right?
Everybody would be in, you know, I mean, you always want labs and everything white in case
you see a little speck of dust or a part falls somewhere you can identify them.
You wouldn't have, you know, wooden lamp or lab benches and things like that.
You'd probably have people in full respirator suits if they're just beginning, but these
guys had reached a point where it was nonchalant, where they were, they were touching, you know,
working with this stuff.
And, um, you know, it really wasn't a thing as if they were taking apart a car engine.
So, um, they had made a lot of progress and they weren't afraid of what they were working
with.
Although we were plenty afraid of the reactor.
And, and you, at no point were you like, this could be some like, you know, anti-gravity
secret program that, you know, I just wasn't cleared to.
No.
Okay.
I mean, initially when I first saw it, I went, oh, that's what this whole thing's about.
You know, it's, it's just, it's just our new fighter and it looks like a flying saucer.
So that's why people believe in flying saucers.
Cause they see these new fighters flying around and, you know, but, um, yeah, it became quickly
obvious that that wasn't the case.
Like we have no idea how the thing works.
It does stuff that's physically impossible and there's no country in the world could make
something like that or have the power density that it has.
It's an inconceivable.
So to, you know, to, to affect space and time, look, if another country was able to build
something like that, the United States wouldn't exist, you know, to anybody who, who's a detractor,
who doesn't, who could think maybe this was a U S object, something man-made or something
that they put there as a prop.
Some people would say, do you think they were trying to deceive Lazar or other people and
all that there's, because I built it, there's one physical aspect of it that is impossible
to build period.
A hundred percent not possible is it's as far as if we have to consider it being a 50 to
almost 53 foot diameter craft, the main level, which is the level that Bob was able to access
and, and, and at one point stand up in the middle of that main level is in the center
of the disc.
And there is nothing that was visually witnessed on the bottom level when he peaked, that is
a supporting column holding that 53 foot diameter floor.
We have nothing on earth.
Yeah.
There is no material.
You know, that's, that's the first I've ever heard of that angle.
That's, that's really interesting.
That's right.
Well, it's because I built it.
Yeah.
I think you know more about the craft at this point.
Because of the thickness of the floor that we could see because of the lip of the access
way, we could see the thickness of the floor.
Also where the honeycomb hatchway is, you could see the thickness of the floor.
That thickness.
Yeah.
52 feet diameter.
There is nothing on earth.
With no central support.
That would not be doing boring like this and maybe, and potentially collapse.
There's nothing.
We have nothing.
That's, that's a completely unique.
Yeah.
Structural anomaly.
Good job, Luigi.
Yeah.
No, I never, never even entertained that.
That's fascinating.
Yeah.
That's, that's great.
But that's, that's a hundred percent true.
Yeah.
There's nothing that can do that.
That's so interesting.
What is the color of the craft itself?
It's kind of a pewter, stainless looking, but it's, Luigi and I were talking about this
the other day.
It, it looks different close up than it does far away.
Describe.
How so?
Jeez, I wish I could.
I've tried to describe this a lot.
And, uh, what's interesting is that I, my friend, Gene Huff, who was my kind of confidant
at the time.
And, um, you know, I tell him about this stuff and I said, you know, one of the weirdest
things is if you're, if you're close to it, you know, it, it, it looks like the craft
and it, and when you get far away, it doesn't look right.
It looks more like a cartoon.
Um, and, um, so Luigi spending two and a half or three years modeling this and getting it
in and sure as hell, whatever they did, uh, Luigi will probably best tell you about that.
Um, when they take the camera and they put it in the hanger and look at it close up, it
looks like it should.
And if they back it off, it doesn't look the same.
It looks, so they were able to, whether intentionally or accidentally kind of duplicate it.
I mean, they've got the model so close that it has, it's taken on some of the characteristics
of the actual craft.
And there's a part of the craft that you describe as blacker than black.
Is that right?
Yeah.
What is that?
You know what they call the portholes around the top?
Sure.
I do not believe are portholes.
You know what?
I think there's a black ring that goes around the top part of the craft and that's, we call
that the insulator ring.
Um, above that, I have no idea what's in that top section, but that's where these small
square slash rectangular holes are around.
They are assumed to be like some sort of planar array where there is some, something similar
to a computer in the top section.
And those arrays determine whether it's looking at starlight or whatever, uh, it determines
its place in space.
Um, but they, they don't look black.
They look so black.
It's, and it's not just Vantablack.
You know, they almost look like a bottomless pits in there, but I know they're solid.
I mean, Barry told me they're solid.
Um, I guess I don't know.
Barry claimed they're solid.
So to be technical, I don't know for a fact.
I mean, but, um, I still think there's some kind of sensors, but it, it's, that is some
unusual material.
And when you go in there and look at the craft, it's a real ominous, creepy feeling.
And a lot of it is because of the black.
Just, it doesn't, it doesn't look right.
Did anybody else say that going into the craft gave them an ominous feeling?
Yeah, he did say it was, it was definitely unnerving.
I think was his word looking at those.
And, and just being in the craft generally, was that like a kind of ubiquitously known
thing at S4?
Like you walk into that thing?
I didn't hear that from anybody, but it certainly was for me.
Interesting.
Yeah.
Because the first thing you think, boy, that must've been so exciting.
And yeah, from a outsider, it might be, but no, when you're really there, it wasn't exciting.
It was, it was really frightening.
And you walked around the, what looked like the cockpit of this thing?
First of all, you can't just walk in.
It's much smaller and narrower than you think.
You have to crawl in and you really can't stand up until you're almost right in the center.
Um, so it doesn't have really, it's really all unusable space.
Um, even if you're a small creature, there's a lot of unusable space in there.
Um, and you know, because I, everything seemed to have a critical function to it.
Um, I'm sure there was nothing for decoration.
There's a reason to have all that space and the reason the craft is shaped like that.
Um, but there were three things that look like seats.
We call them seats, other humps, large rectangular smooth objects in there.
There were three of those.
Uh, we know those to be the amplifiers.
They work with the, with the reactor that amplifies the gravity wave and it's, you know, channeled to the emitter, which is right under the amplifiers.
Um, again, we just called the seats cause they look like seats.
It would be, I think it would be funny if it turned out that they were not seats at all.
Um, yet another component we just knew nothing about.
Well, Bob always found it to be really weird, uh, that when the wave guide is applied right on top of the reactor, these two guys, they're, they're looking out.
There's a, there's a, one of the archways that become transparent.
So they, he believes that maybe that is where they're looking, but this guy here is staring at a pipe.
Oh, the, the archway becoming transparent is so they can see.
Yeah.
Oh, it's so interesting.
I never like made that connection.
Yeah.
They're looking at it.
Oh.
And there's a screen that appears, the blue screen with a symbol.
With the like Korean like language.
Yeah.
And then I, I've always thought, and I thought maybe they all become transparent.
Maybe the whole arch, like the whole, all the archways can become transparent.
What, why, why would it only be one?
Cause it's so dark in there.
Fascinating.
And you saw a translucent, like almost Korean looking symbols.
Is that right?
Yeah.
I saw the wall become translucent.
And at some point saw some kind of, what I would call symbols, but not on a, in a three-dimensional
way, not on a flat screen or anything like that.
Explain how you saw it.
Cause you were explaining it to me yesterday.
Yeah.
It wasn't like it was a screen.
Um, it was just like, it was a three-dimensional character sitting in there.
Almost like a projection you said.
Yeah.
I, he, he was explaining it to me yesterday because he explained it actually better yesterday
than before I produced it.
Yeah.
And you were saying it felt, it looked almost like a projection on that area.
No, it wasn't a projection or it was on something.
It was just a three-dimensional thing in the air.
Describe the day that you saw this thing fly.
Um, it was already out, um, uh, Barry and I were in the lab and then Dennis came in and
he said, Hey, why don't you guys come?
We're doing a test flight, you know?
So, oh, this is great.
So we go out through the lab door, right into the hangar.
It was already outside, uh, sitting on the ground.
And, uh, shortly after we got out there, uh, oh, I did notice there was a radio.
And I mentioned this in Luigi's movie, a VHF radio and they're in communication.
So it, it, it made me almost positive that there was somebody in the craft.
Yep.
Uh, yeah.
I don't know how, where they'd be sitting or how they would, why they're even in the
craft, because it's, like I said, it's so uncomfortable, unusable space.
They'd have to be hunched up or trying to sit on the edge of one of those seats.
So, um, that put aside, uh.
So you think they put a person in there?
I think so, because they were communicating back and forth.
Did you hear a voice?
Yeah.
Whoa.
Yeah, yeah.
So you heard a voice coming from the craft.
No, from the radio.
From the radio, from the VHF radio.
Yeah, yeah.
But presumably coming from the craft.
Yeah.
Wow.
So he was monitoring, I mean, they must've had some other instrumentation set up on the
crafts, because he was monitoring something.
Do you remember what the voice?
That was just.
Not a thing.
But it was something.
Because I, I mean, I was more stuck on the fact that, how is a radio wave getting into
the craft?
This doesn't even make any sense.
VHF being very high frequency?
Yeah.
I mean, it should be distorted by the gravity wave going around it.
Anyway, shortly after the craft began to lift off the ground silently, had a little corona
discharge glow on the bottom and lift it off and drifted up into the sky and kind of moved
around.
During that test flight, Dennis motioned for me to come out and, you know, look up at it.
And then he told me to walk forward and the craft was just sitting there stationary.
And I walked out underneath it and he motioned for me to look up.
I looked up and I couldn't see the craft.
So I thought it flew away.
And then he said, you know, come back.
And, you know, I, I walked back and I just walked back.
It caught my attention.
I see the edge of the, the craft.
So if you move, you can see it.
And if you walk underneath it, you can't.
So you can clearly see it's, it's bending the light.
You can see the sky above the craft.
So you can see that it's in its little envelope.
And, um, then it kind of slid over to the left and right and then sat back down.
Is what you saw, did, did it look like what we talk about when we talk about UFO videos
and what we, you know, it's just like, look at the, you know, Nimitz, you know, 2004
FLIR video or, or even some of the, maybe a better example, some of the optical videos,
which are often grainy and fuzzy.
And maybe that's due to gravitational lensing or some sort of space time perturbation due
to these effects that you're talking about.
But when you're seeing this craft fly, are you thinking this is the UFO stuff that's like
in the lore?
Yeah.
You are.
Wow.
Yeah, for sure.
I'm just because of the, the way that it can move.
It can just negate, I mean, it's, I really don't know how to describe it.
Um, I mean, things like inertia really don't matter to it.
Hmm.
Um, it just, it gets away with murder when it, when it comes to flying.
Did you ever think, um, we are being tasked to figure out this reactor, even like, you
know, the shape of the craft is sort of really confusing to us.
How the hell do they know how to fly this thing?
Yeah.
That goes through your head.
Like you're like, yeah, well, I mean, yeah, like I said, you know, clearly they've, they've
had a lot of time with this craft already.
It could have been decades for all I know.
So they're familiar with it.
So, I mean, they, they knew the emitters have to be rotated, you know, to couple to the
reactor.
I mean, they knew how to fly it.
Um, so that these guys were somewhat proficient with it, but it, so it would be your kind
of base case assumption that now we have functional, what you might call alien reproduction
vehicles or UFOs that humans can fly.
If in 1987, 88, you had stuff that was, you know, we could at least test and you could go
under them and stuff, then you would think that now we're probably, we've probably made
much more progress, I assume, or what, what, what do you think?
I do not think so.
No.
You don't think so.
So you think we're, we can test these things and use them in a rudimentary ways, but we
don't understand how they work.
No, it's like the, you know, analogy I, I gave, you know, you can go back to the 1800s
and drop off a motorcycle.
Yep.
With the keys in it.
And, you know, you can look at it and go, wow, that's never seen anything like that before
and look at the plastic fenders on it and wow, that's unusual material.
And, you know, there's the key.
And eventually if you tinker with it long enough, someone's going to turn the key and
it's going to start.
Yep.
And they're going to go, okay, we turn it off and go, all right, that's on and off.
And, you know, eventually just given time and human, human ingenuity, they're going to
get it throttles here and they'll become proficient at driving it.
Yeah.
But when it runs out of fuel, we're done.
And when it comes right down to it, they can't even make that plastic fender.
Right.
So, yeah.
So, you can become proficient at using it.
And I think that's where we are.
We had some knowledge of that.
But I think if we had developed that technology, we would have absolutely already seen it.
We wouldn't be wasting one minute building a conventional fighter or other.
Why?
Why would you?
And they say, oh, well, it's secret.
Yep.
So, jet engines were secret when we first came out with them and we built a whole fleet.
You know, we'd absolutely divert every resource we had to duplicating these things.
Do you guys think there's any chance that the craft is flown with somebody's mind, some
sort of mental?
It could very well be.
Yeah.
Because there was obviously no physical controls to it.
Right.
When the craft was being tested, the only test I saw from close range, it was already out
of the hangar.
And when I went into the hangar, the bay doors between all the hangars were open.
They had big, you know, there's the door that leads to the outside that's at an angle.
But there's also big bay doors between all the hangars.
Those were open for some reason.
And when I came in to go witness that, I was able to look down and see that, boy, there's
other, because nine of them all the way down there.
What's going through your head and emotionally, how do you feel?
Well, first of all, where did they all come from?
How could you, I mean, I could see you found one somewhere.
There's a crash or whatever.
You found one.
You don't find nine.
Nine.
I mean, where, where did they come from?
None of them are, are damaged to any degree.
Although the, when I call the top hat had holes in it, but it looks like it was shot, you know,
projectile, but there, it wasn't, you know, damage from, you know, crash or attempted landing.
Um, so where did all this stuff come from?
There's so much missing to the story.
Did they all look like the exact same sort of replica?
No, each one was different.
Okay.
But the material all looked exactly the same.
The color, um, the sheen.
So it looked like they were all made of the same material.
So the reactors and the propulsion were all the same.
The material was all the same, but the shapes were somehow different.
Do you remember?
I mean, maybe they're specialized craft, you know, you can take a step back from humanity
and you go look at all the cars driving around.
Well, you got a truck.
That's a real long thing.
You look at a Volkswagen.
That's like a little, you know, and you see a motorcycle gone, you know, they're all,
but they all have the same somewhat type of engine, you know, internal combustion engine
is a powering them all.
So they must have all different functions.
And maybe that's just what we're looking at is just, you know, and who says they're
all men?
Maybe some of those things are drones of some kind.
People associate you with the kind of Billy Meyer sports model.
Like, you know, the craft that looks like that.
It looks exactly like that.
Exactly like that.
Like I thought Billy Meyer was absolutely ridiculous because I I've seen some of the pictures
and this is what I mentioned to you the other day.
UFO researcher syndrome.
I think the initial pictures Billy Meyer took of the sport model looking craft are a hundred
percent genuine.
There's no way that that there could be another one of those that just coincidentally looks
exactly like what I call the sport model.
So I think he absolutely photographed that and it was real.
And I think at the time he got a lot of attention and, you know, he printed books and everything.
And I think as time went on, he kind of missed that.
And then he started making some models and taking some new pictures and the other pictures
look ridiculous.
Right, right.
They do.
It looks like, you know.
And there's something about like dinosaurs in his book.
And yeah, I know it looks like there's styrofoam balls all into it is.
Yeah.
I found some more pictures, you know, come back.
And, you know, so, uh, I think that's, you know, that, that's just a personal belief.
Yeah.
You, there's no way you can tell me that those original pictures aren't genuine.
And, and so that's the craft you worked on, the eight other crafts.
What did those look like?
I could only see two.
Okay.
Clearly, because from the angle, all you can see is just a little piece.
And then, then all you can just see is the hanger out there.
Um, but one looked like what I call a jello mold, which is more like a bundt cake without
the hole in the middle.
And then the other one, as I previously mentioned, a top hat, like a carnival top straw hat with
the, and the brim had, uh, a hole in it.
So.
Is your immediate instinct, uh, humans didn't make these?
Yeah.
At what point do you, do you not see, uh, like an American flag on one of them or?
On the sport model.
They, I saw that like the first day that I went in.
Okay.
Uh, was there any talk of how these crafts were retrieved?
Uh, I know, I mean, I know the Navy.
Got the sport model.
And I think that, that was, from what Barry said, that was an archeological dig, which by
the way, isn't in the desert.
It's in the water.
And I, if there's another term for an archeological dig that's in the water, I don't know what
it is.
I thought it's still a dig, but, um, yeah, that I don't know what body of water, if it
was the ocean or lake or what, but yeah, that came from the water.
I, I, again, according to Barry, I didn't see this in documentation, but, um, yeah, that
was happened upon by the Navy and that's, that's all I know.
And that's, I just theorize that's how the Navy got in control of everything.
It's what you constantly hear is, um, you know, you have things like, you know, Hughes
aircraft building the Glomar Explorer, which, you know, subsea, you know, uh, uh, discovery.
And, um, you have some, some actually more, more recent Lockheed subsea, you know, super
subsea, uh, uh, submarines and drone sort of things that seem to be able to, you know,
uh, uh, scan the seafloor.
And, uh, there's a great book called, uh, the silent war by John Pina Craven.
And he was, uh, um, high up in the Navy and he talks about retrieval of exotic technology
on the seafloor.
And I, I wonder, you know, you have Tim Burchette as a Congressman from Tennessee who says there are
five hotspots in oceans all around the world.
You know, we think they're coming in from way out.
Maybe they did millennial ago, but they're here and they're in these deep water areas.
And that's why, I mean, like we say, we know more about the face of the moon than we do.
What's, what's going on there.
And we have a higher propensity of sightings around these five or six, I believe, deep area,
deep water areas.
And you, I don't know, there's another, I have one friend in the Navy who's, you know,
anonymous source.
Maybe one day we'll do an interview, but he talks about the movie, The Abyss by James Cameron.
Yeah.
And he says maybe that scene where, you know, this sort of glowing object shows up isn't,
isn't too far off from the truth.
So look, one of our science fiction movies is going to be correct.
That's right.
Yeah.
That's a safe bet.
And we were talking last night with Luigi about Pascagoula, Missouri was the site of the production
of nuclear subs for the Navy.
And you have a famous case there of some fishermen who, you know, experience an alien abduction
and have a UFO experience.
So yeah, there's something going on with the ocean.
There is.
It's been from the very beginning.
George Knapp has interesting footage around Baja, Mexico.
On the other side, you have Tampir, which seems to be a hotspot.
You have the Caribbean, Bahamas.
Yeah.
I think that's where all these guys are hiding out.
That's exactly.
Do you think there's a possibility it's, you know, the ultra terrestrial hypothesis?
So this is this idea that they're ancient remnants of a, like an antediluvian civilization that
existed pre-Ice Age or pre-Younger Dress.
An antediluvian?
Yeah.
And that they're more advanced than a, they're like the place of what we call Atlantis are
these, these beings who have coexisted, co-inhabited the earth with us.
It could, it really could very well be.
Right.
And if you just look at the size of the ocean, you can hide an entire civilization down there
and we'll, especially if they're immune to the effects of the ocean, just got to be
deep.
Yeah.
We'll never find them.
Would any of the scientific principles that you looked at as far as the bubble being created
around the craft and all of that somehow be immune to salt water?
Like, would it be able to travel transmedium?
Because that's one of the.
Yeah, absolutely.
It's so interesting because that's the observable.
That's light bent around the craft.
Yeah.
I'm sure a raindrop would do.
It's so fascinating.
I've been involved in this whole thing since 1987 and since the eighties or even before,
let's go even all the way down to the sixties, everybody always talked about the U S air force
and project blue book and project blue book.
I mean, Bob Lazar comes out in 1989 and says they weren't crash saucers.
They were intact craft and it's the Navy that's in charge.
And funny enough, 40 years later, that's what people are talking about.
Yep.
So, you know, when I see the new whistleblowers come out like Eric Davis or people that we're
seeing, I'm not skeptical at the fact that they were involved in something.
What I find very, like, basically very interesting is that they're all saying exactly what Bob
said in 1989, but they never say Bob Lazar is possibly factual.
Right.
Yeah.
That's hilarious.
Well, there's Bob has nothing to do with that, but everything he said is right though.
Yeah.
They said they're like high level.
There's definitely a decades long multi-generational crash retrieval operation, but the one guy
who says he's worked on the craft is somehow full of shit.
No, no.
Yeah.
That makes sense.
Everything is right though.
I believe there aren't that many crashes.
There just aren't that many crashes.
If you had to guess, how many crafts are in U.S. possession now in hangers?
Now?
I don't know.
I mean, nine.
Nine for sure.
Yeah.
That's it.
I mean, I can only talk about what I've seen.
Do you think they have a sense of ontological treat?
Like when you see all this stuff around, you know, the ability to manipulate timelines with
looking glass or even just manipulate time on a local scale, and then they're saying that
they found these things at archaeological digs under the ocean.
Do you have a sense that they have like a metaphysical model that's like greater than
the average citizen?
So it's like their origin story of humanity.
Maybe.
You think maybe?
Yeah.
I think there's a good chance of that.
Is your kind of Occam's razor explanation that these are extraterrestrials?
Do you think they're time travelers?
What do you think?
I think that that's all equal.
I mean, there's just as much chance that they're, you know, time travelers, visitors
from another dimension, us from the future, or aliens.
I don't see anything pointing in any specific direction.
I go with the aliens just because we've seen it so much in our movie.
I think we're just trained to think that.
And it's palatable.
Well, you can see other worlds.
This can go travel in another fashion and get there.
There's probably life there.
They probably build things.
And, you know, it all makes sense.
Yeah.
You know, but when you go to other dimensions in time, well, can you even time travel at
all?
I mean, will that ever be possible?
You know, maybe, maybe not.
How do you get here from another dimension?
Why would you care?
I would go to another dimension and start hassling people over there.
You know, so, I mean, the other things don't make sense.
So, yeah, I lean, I guess the Occam's razor is aliens.
But it could be any one of the other possibilities.
Or one that we haven't thought of that's just completely ridiculous.
What do you think was the top speed?
Of just conventionally moving?
Yep.
I don't think it really had a very high top speed.
Really?
Yeah.
Hmm.
Like, if you had to...
It depends.
I mean, it depends on how it was being...
Because you can maneuver it in a couple different ways.
So, of course, how would I know?
I mean, the speed it could attain.
But I'm just thinking about an Omicron mode where it's just sitting there and moving.
But you think about...
Delta.
Yeah.
At delta, the speed's going to be near infinite.
It's going to appear somewhere else.
You think almost close to the speed of light or it would look like it's hopping across space-time
or something?
No, it would far exceed the speed of light.
It'd be faster.
Yeah, because you're not going in a linear fashion.
You're just jumping over.
Wow.
Because it's bending...
It's warping space-time itself.
Yeah, yeah.
So, it's, you know, for a given distance, you'll get, you know, to the destination far faster
than you would if you were traveling at the speed of light.
And it's like crunching space-time behind it and then in front of it...
I don't know what's going on behind it.
It's like riding a wave or something?
It's just bending space around it.
Did you hear anything around pulses involved in the propulsion?
Yeah, yeah.
It's not a continuous...
It's like a...
It pulses.
I don't know what the maximum range of each jump is, but I know it's like a 10 millisecond
recycle time in between it.
So, the craft is always doing this.
When all three of the amplifiers are being used for travel, they're in the delta configuration.
And when only one is being used for travel, it's in the Omicron configuration.
You guys do an amazing job of depicting the configurations.
And so, what is delta exactly?
Delta is using the three...
There's three amplifiers, delta.
Yes.
And that's where they all focus together on a destination.
Okay.
The craft puts its belly in that direction, and that's how it moves.
The Omicron is where it only uses one of the emitters to propel itself.
Or it's not really propelling itself, it's doing the opposite.
Essentially, you create an indentation in space-time so the craft moves forward, which always gives
it...
If it's operating in Omicron configuration, it's never really stable.
It's kind of a, you know, somewhat undulating movement, you know?
It's so interesting.
And, yeah, it's fascinating.
That seems to be a common thing, the craft sort of wobbling.
Yeah, this wobble.
Yeah.
But when it switches to delta, as soon as the two other amplifiers come on online, that thing
locks in space and time, and then it's, you know, able to focus in any direction and move
there instantaneously.
Oh, all right.
What's up?
That's good.
You're in our mid-century living room set.
You have Luigi, Vendatelli, Bob Lazar, and Logan is a longtime UFO nut.
Okay.
And do you watch WWE at all?
No.
He is the guy in WWE right now.
He has an amazing podcast as well.
I've known his brother, actually, for like a decade plus.
Dude, I got to say, Bob, it is an honor to meet you, man.
Absolute legend.
What a privilege to talk to you.
Oh, thanks.
Good.
Good to meet you.
I don't know if Jesse gave you any context to why I wanted to talk to you.
They have a bit.
Yeah.
But maybe let me rehash it.
Okay.
So, Bob, check this out.
I have in my possession UFO footage that has a story behind it that...
Is compelling, but not convincing.
And I've been waiting to just do something with this footage or receive confirmation of sorts.
And I see this particular orange disc sometimes in UFO videos and documentaries.
It pops up every now and then.
But when I was watching the trailer for S4 that you guys released, about 80% of the way through the trailer, you guys show a disc that is at night, but then kind of coats itself in this orange...
Right.
Yeah.
That's right.
Dude, I paused it there and I said, oh my God.
That looks exactly like the footage that I have.
So, this footage, supposedly authentic, was taken by two college kids who wanted to go to Area 51 in the 90s, I believe it was 1995, and film their experience of trying to see if they could stumble upon a UFO or just alien activity of sorts.
Let's break this down.
A couple of college-age guys drove out to the Black Mailbox, an infamous landmark entrance point to Area 51.
It's along the road that leads to Groom Lake, extremely close to where Bob said he worked.
It's nighttime.
They're parked right in front of the fence surrounding the secret facility.
The lights are off on their car, and they have a camera resting on the armrest, pointed through the front windshield.
And then it cuts to under the dashboard, and you see something very clearly illuminating, like, the top of the dashboard, and they're, like, hunkered underneath the car, and they're whispering to each other, like, I think it's out there, like, I don't know what it is, maybe we should go out there.
And they're, like, kind of scared.
Get down, get down, get down.
Then something appears just beyond the glass.
The craft is hovering extremely close to the car.
It's orange and slightly wobbling or undulating in place, as if it's on a wave.
You can hear the two guys whispering.
Look at how there, how there.
Over there.
Yeah, that, to me, is exactly how it was described by Bob.
It's exactly, like, like your hand did, your hand did.
Yeah, it's moving the right way, it's the right color, and it's the right shape.
So it makes it very compelling.
The intensity of the light, there's something very, very bright that is affecting that.
The dash is being lit.
It's the dash of the vehicle, and the craft is above it.
Right, right.
And look at the intent, here's the dash, and look at the intensity of the light that's going to happen here.
Right.
Whoa.
There.
Those, those are really.
Yeah, and it's fading in and out.
Yeah, you can't fake that.
You can see that it wobbles exactly like your film.
But it wobbles.
It wobbles.
That's the important thing, yeah.
So it does comport with your video.
It wobbles, it glows like that, in that color, in that shape.
That's wild, dude.
Yeah, I mean, it's wild.
It's impressive.
It is.
The craft emits an orange-reddish color, which is not a coincidence.
A craft with strong field interactions, like the ones that Bob alludes to, creates an ionized
plasma sheath around itself.
The dominant atmospheric gas on Earth is nitrogen.
Ionized nitrogen that interacts with plasma glows red-orange.
This classic observation of a glowing reddish or orange ball of light, moving silently and
erratically, is one of the most commonly reported UFO descriptions across decades of sightings
worldwide.
You know what?
Did you see that movie?
No, I didn't.
Now, I know this footage is grainy.
And while certainly fascinating, it's far from conclusive.
But it is another fascinating data point.
What Luigi's movie almost definitively vindicates is the existence of S4.
Remember, when Bob went public in 1989, Area 51 itself hadn't even been officially acknowledged
by the government.
And to this day, S4's existence is still denied.
It's not supposed to exist.
But Luigi used Google Earth's historical imagery to go back in time and found a 2022 version
of the area surrounding S4 that was not yet blurred to obscure the site.
And yet, vehicle tracks are visible in these older satellite images.
You can clearly see the tracks.
Look at them going in every direction.
And you can look at all the traffic.
Yeah.
Right?
Yeah, that's not one guy driving around.
No, that's not one guy driving.
Exactly.
So again, there's no public out there.
So what are you doing?
Luigi also shows Bob a high-quality aerial photograph taken by a pilot roughly 17 miles from Papoose
Lake.
The image had previously circulated online, but Luigi enhanced the contrast a bit to reveal
additional details.
And if you look carefully in this version here where the contrast has been changed, as we
zoom, look what you see.
Yeah, you can start seeing the...
You see them clearly right there.
Yeah, the slanted rectangular doors, yeah.
Finally, and perhaps most damningly, the map of Papoose Lake was literally altered eight
days after Bob Lazar went public in his first anonymous video.
You heard me right.
They changed the map eight days after Bob started to speak out.
And the map was clearly modified in a way that would specifically hide the existence of
Bob's S4.
Bob went public on May 15th, 1989.
And he didn't come public.
His name wasn't public.
It was him as Dennis in silhouette.
And eight days after that, the United States Department of the Interior, who works on the geological
maps of the landscape at the test site where it's Groom Lake, Papoose Lake, and the whole
Nevada test site, actually modified all the maps there, specifically Groom Lake and Papoose Lake
and Papoose Mountain Range there.
And there's a stamp on all the modifications, because the modification was dated 1989.
So on the actual small print, it says maps modified 1989, but the stamp of the exact day is May
23rd, 1989, exactly eight days after Bob went public.
And specifically, they are getting...
Just Papoose Lake.
So they're removing S4.
No, what they removed, the specificity there is the specific thing they removed is there's
a road that leads from Groom Lake down to Papoose Lake.
And as it leads down to Papoose Lake, the north end of the lake, the road forks off, it splits
off in two areas, to the west of Papoose Lake and to the right of Papoose Lake, where S4
is.
They specifically removed the road to the east of Papoose Lake, and they kept the same
one to the west, which, why would they do that?
Why would you suddenly remove the road that goes to S4?
And leave everything else there.
That was an amazing discovery.
Yeah, and it's there.
I mean, it's not like, we're not making anything up here.
I was very specific of like, I don't want to put anything that makes us look like we're
inventing stuff.
This is verifiable.
You could order these maps.
The other thing I think that's interesting is for people doubting the story, Jeremy Corbell
and Ross Colthart found a bunch of people who have verified Bob's presence at S4, right?
Uh, I don't know if you have as well.
I think arriving at 51 or getting on the bus or something.
That's right.
Yeah.
I think they found a bunch of people.
George Knapp also had some people and they got threatened back then.
And they were told six people that were threatened and, and basically they never made it forward.
George talks about it in, in the interviews we did with him.
And he's talked about it in the past.
And he says, they all received the phone call.
They were all threatened and they never went public.
And, and, you know, for anybody who is a Bob Lazar detractor or doesn't believe the story,
you then have to not believe George Knapp because why would George lie about that?
What's his, what's the benefit here?
You know, and somebody is going to say, well, it's because he put his name attached to the
Bob story.
No, not when that was happening.
He was still investigating the Bob story.
So he said that back then.
It's not like it's new information.
He was getting a lot of shit.
Yeah.
Being involved with the story back then.
It was not, certainly not a feather to stick in his cap.
You know, it, it's, it's something I, I really want to put a lot of emphasis on because
of all the haters out there is this happened when he came out.
It was in 1989.
It was a different era.
It was a different time in the world.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
So, you know, the people now that think that Bob Lazar is a grifter or what, where I'm a
grifter because I'm making a movie about this and whatever, you know, this happened 40 years
ago.
I was interested in UFOs 40 years ago and believe me, I was not popular.
This was the most unpopular topic when it came out.
It was considered to be so don't touch that because it's going to ruin your life.
So why would, first of all, why would Bob Lazar do that?
And then why would George Knapp, a respected investigative journalist in Las Vegas who already
was well-known and had a good job, why would he hang his, his reputation and ruin his entire
career just to support another law, another liar?
Yeah.
Like it doesn't make any sense to me.
No.
It really doesn't.
So, you know, let's not forget those.
Yeah.
And he has multiple P bodies.
He's well-respected.
Exactly.
As you said, outside of UFOs.
Yeah.
Did you learn any other details about the guy that had died that you were replacing?
They had an operating reactor.
So apparently, which is also brings up all kinds of other questions to me, um, apparently
the reactors and all the craft are exactly the same.
So that makes me think of a manufacturing facility.
Yeah.
That's like a Ford making an engine and it goes in, you know, a bunch of different models.
How can all these crafts have the same, you know, the same power system or propulsion system
in them?
Um, anyway, I don't want to go off on a tangent, but he had a reactor.
So it was probably from some, one of the other crafts and why they did this is beyond
me.
They took it out to the nuclear test site and they physically cut into it while it was
running under load and it exploded.
And all, I think there were three guys there, maybe more.
They were all killed.
So, number one, why would you do that?
Number, number two, it makes me think either they were extremely desperate and want to just,
well, find out what's in there and, you know, and, uh, why would you even do it while it was
operating?
They were extremely confident or extremely confident that they knew what was going on
in the reactor, where they could safely cut it.
And they had a reason to get in there.
Um, but apparently that information never made it back, whatever they gleaned from it,
or even their suspicions at the beginning, because Barry and I were kind of starting from the
beginning on the reactor.
Uh, so everything they had done previously was lost.
Anyway.
You ever learn the guy's name or any details about, do you, does Barry have a last name or?
Yeah.
Barry, uh, Castillo, it's spelled Castillo, but Castile, I don't know how it's pronounced.
Have you ever tracked him down after?
I think briefly decades ago, we made a real, cause there was another guy that would come
in and out once in a while named Renee.
Okay.
Don't remember his last name, but I mean, at, at some point I really put a lot of effort
into trying to find Dennis Mariani and Barry.
And, uh, I think some people did track down Dennis.
I think he died not too long ago.
Okay.
Um, I don't know about Barry, but, uh, I, I never was never able to find it.
Cause I mean, back in the time I was looking for him, there was no internet, you know, so
you had to go through public records and stuff and, uh, it was much more difficult than it
is now.
Yeah.
And I, I know of one instance in which the name Dennis Mariani was corroborated by somebody
at, you know, uh, Nevada test site.
And so, um, uh, you know, I won't, I won't go further than that, but, uh,
because it's not right.
It's not my thing to tell, but you're, you're giving names and, you know, I think some of
these people could still be alive, which is pretty remarkable to you.
Like maybe we could track some of them down and they could back you up.
I wonder, I mean, they have to know.
I'm kind of wondering why nobody else came out, you know?
Yeah.
Um, I mean, although Barry wouldn't talk about it much, you know, um, there are times I kind
of mentioned, you know, holy cow, can you believe this is being kept secret?
And he goes, I, it sucks.
I know.
Yeah.
So he didn't think it was, you know, he wasn't with the program as far as keeping this from,
you know, the entire world.
What was his background?
No idea.
Okay.
Um, but there was kind of a collegial goodwill between you and him.
Yeah.
And he'd goof around sometimes, which was nice because everything else was just so rigid
and military.
So, you know, I'm sure the story where he threw the golf ball at the reactor and, you know,
sometimes we'd start just start talking about stupid stuff.
So it was, it's good to see a normal person, you know, that just acted like, you know, a human
instead of a robot.
What happened when he threw the golf ball at the reactor?
He was showing me the field on it and he said, check this out and took a golf ball and,
you know, intending to hit the reactor.
And instead it bounced off the field and then hit a ceiling tile, which dislodged it and made
all the little particles, you know, come down.
And we knew Dennis was going to be coming back in two minutes.
So it was, you know, red alert.
We had to, you know, grab the stools and go up and re-ascend and clean it up and everything.
And, you know, shortly after that, Dennis walks in and says, you know, what's going on?
Nothing, nothing.
You know, we're working like we should be.
I mean, this is a remarkable detail around the reactor.
You have this sort of force field like thing, this like repelling force.
Yeah.
Once the, uh, a hemisphere on top of a plate, you know, about the size of a basketball,
maybe a little bigger on top of a 15 inch square plate, um, the hemisphere is removable.
Once the hemisphere is put back on, um, if the emitter is in the right position,
the reactor will turn on immediately and it'll produce a gravitational field around it and
you can push on it and you, you can't, you can't touch the reactor from that point.
I mean, it, and it, it's somewhat elastic, you know, like if you have two light poles
of a magnet pushing them together, you get that it's the exact same field, but without
metal, it's just your hands.
But as I said before, what, what's really interesting is, you know, you can move the
reactor on the table and once you turn it on and you're pushing on the field, the reactor
doesn't slide.
So it's not transferring the force to the reactor.
It's pushing your hand away.
But so that's, it's, it's really interesting to me.
How did the reactor work?
This is all guess.
This is just all guesswork.
Yes.
Um, it has a super heavy element in it, which appeared to be 115 on the periodic chart.
Uh, there's a little tower in it and from x-rays, we could see that there's a loop around
the base plate.
So it was theorized, apparently Barry with his other lab partner.
They thought that was a, uh, cyclotron, an accelerator, and that the tube that came up the side was an
off-ramp, essentially.
And that particle or whatever was being accelerated interacts with the 115 and somehow that produces
the gravitational field.
How did it feel on your hand?
It, it, it felt exactly like pushing magnets together.
Okay.
It was just elastic.
I mean, it was compressible to some degree.
And then when it got close to it, you're nothing is getting past that.
With magnets, you have to have like pulls for them to repel.
Yeah.
And in this case, you're not, you know, it's just a matter repelling matter without polarity.
Does it feel like a, what does it feel like?
Does it, is there a texture to it or?
No, it's just, it's just elastic, but it, it, it becomes, it's not linear.
But does it feel like it's logarithmic, you know, it's, it's easy to push and then it becomes
impossible.
There's no way you're getting past the next three inches.
You could probably sit a car on top of it and nothing would change.
Does it feel like saran wrap or does it feel like, like, what, what does it feel like when
you're in it?
Does it feel like.
No, it just feels.
It's literally like air, like.
Yeah.
I see what you're saying.
You know what I mean?
I describe that.
Yeah.
Like, is there a.
No, it just.
Coolness, a heat.
No.
It's just like space time itself.
Yeah.
It's just.
I don't know how to describe it.
Sure.
Yeah.
But it's, it's just there.
I mean, at this point, I don't, I don't even think it's gravity.
What do you think?
I think this is an, another completely unique force.
It doesn't behave enough like gravity.
And explain why it's so different.
Like, I mean, because at least my thoughts at this point are, I think gravity is just
a property of matter and it's only an attractive force.
I'm not sure you can have anti-gravity.
Um, like if it was gravity, you know, at one point, Barry showed me, he had one of the
emitters, it working.
He put a lit little kitchen candle right at the focal point and he powered up the, the
reactor and the flame stopped flickering.
It stood there frozen in space and time.
And, but I could see the light from the candle, the flame was still visible.
Also, he removed the candle and then rotated the emitter.
I don't know if it was another direction or more of the same way, but it made a little
black ball in the air where no light was escaping, looking like a little black hole.
But no, you could just tell there was no light at the focal point right in the air.
It was just a dark area.
So there it's affecting light, but it wasn't in the candle test before that.
So it, it, it's a really unusual, unusual thing.
When Bob mentioned this anomalous force coming from the craft's emitter, I immediately racked
my brain for anyone in conventional aerospace circles who talks about something similar.
And then I realized I just interviewed the lead electrostatic scientist at NASA, Dr.
Charles Buehler, who talks about something very similar.
Okay.
Where the heck is this energy coming from?
Because if I was to stick this in space, it would accelerate with the power off.
That's a problem.
You see, there's a long lineage of people studying gravity control or anti-gravity in the United
States.
Perhaps my favorite example is mid-century inventor Thomas Townsend Brown, who discovered that
when you apply a high voltage to certain asymmetric capacitors, they produce thrust.
That's right.
Propulsion with no fuel, no exhaust, no propellant, just electricity as the input, converted directly
into motion.
A new model for space propulsion that could eliminate crude chemical combustion rockets
forever.
Now you might think that's insane and defies Newton's laws.
And I'll spare you all of the corroborating research that I've dug up showing that Brown
made real breakthroughs in the world of anti-gravity.
Dr. Charles Buehler at NASA has taken Brown's experiments to the next level, with modern
instruments, more rigorous controls, and decades of electrostatics expertise from his work at
Kennedy Space Center behind him.
He's done over 2,000 of these experiments and controlled for just about every variable
you can think of.
And he's also getting millinewtons of thrust, basically real propulsion with electricity as
the sole input.
And you can't really argue with his authority to make these claims.
The man literally runs electrostatics at NASA.
He's the incoming president of the American Electrostatic Society.
And he's contributed two fundamental principles to the field of electrostatics that are now
widely accepted.
So this is kind of an interesting moment in history, because we have a man who reverse
engineered UFOs, and then we have a NASA lead electrostatic scientist.
So I thought I'd just leave it to you guys to kind of nerd out.
Yeah, well, first of all, hi, Charles.
Hi, Bob.
This is a very exciting moment for me.
I'm a big fan.
Now, the thing about Bob Lazar is he kind of exists on an island.
We've never seen him interact with other highly credentialed engineers in aerospace.
And what I've learned after spending time with him is he's actually pretty skeptical when
it comes to other scientific anomalies.
Man, I'm real interested to hear, you know, your physical experiment setup.
Is it a hybrid of your idea and T.T.
Brown's, or are you just duplicating one of his experiments?
I mean, what, can you explain to me what it looks like?
What's your test setup look like?
Gosh, there's 2,000 variations.
I'll try to do my best.
I mean, how is this, I'm sure you've seen the lifter ion motors and stuff along those
lines.
How is it different from those?
A few ways.
The ion thrusters obviously use ions in the air to give them momentum oscillation.
What's interesting about this force, even though it's sort of the same geometry can be
used, but in high vacuum, you'll get the thrust.
But it's always in the opposite direction of the ion thrusters, which is really cool.
Because what happens is you have a sharp electrode in the ground plane.
However you do that, you can come up with a million ways to do that.
So in air, when you do that, you'll break down the gases, either in the corona or some
fold like that.
In vacuum, we can actually see these forces arise, but they're always in the opposite direction
of the ion wind, which is really interesting.
That is very interesting.
It's the same direction as the rocket exhaust.
You never think of that.
So it really messes with you.
So that's what's interesting about it.
That's one main difference.
Wow.
Yeah.
Well, that's really interesting.
I mean, the fact that it's in the opposite direction of where an ion thruster would be.
And you've done it in a hard or reasonably hard vacuum, and you're getting measurable thrust?
Oh, we have.
We've been doing that since 2020.
So the last six years, we test almost every day, probably every other day, different configurations
or zero in on a configuration, test another concept.
And that is an ongoing iterative process.
So yes, we have tested a high vacuum, 10 to the minus six or better.
The champion can get up to 10 to the minus seven, but enough to prove to us that there's
no ion wind.
What kind of thrust in newtons or grams are you getting?
Well, we're still playing around in the hundreds of microneutons or millineuton ranges.
So I think the highest we've gotten is probably up to the 50 millineuton mark.
But that's when we stack these together.
We don't learn a lot from them when we do that, other than we can make more thrust,
which is important.
But we like to understand the thrust density, if you will, of each thruster.
So we're trying to optimize each type, optimize each parameter space that we have access to
before we can get to larger chambers or outer space to test the megastructures.
Physically, how big are these thrusters?
Oh, they're not very big.
They're about six inches, maybe six by six, roughly.
Okay.
In that range.
It's a nice size.
You know, we can make them bigger, but we don't gain anything by that.
We just try to keep them manageable so that we can do different things with them, stack
them, try different boltages, and then we try to measure the currents.
We make sure that in many cases there is no current, which is very odd.
I would say.
Isn't that interesting?
Yeah, I'd say.
Turn the power source off and it keeps going.
Wait, what?
Yeah.
It is very annoying that in some cases when we trap the charge in there, that's all that's
required.
So that really eliminates a lot of things.
So a physically larger one doesn't get you any more thrust, but you can stack them and
get increased thrust.
Well, the physically large one will, but we won't learn anything from it.
You know, we can do eight inches or 10 inches, which we have, but we're not learning anything
from it.
We want to learn, you know, what is the best geometry, shape.
We want to optimize.
We know area is one of the ways.
That will be optimized later once we're in space.
But on ground test particles, we're kind of fixed by the geometry of our chamber.
Once we get some funding here, we do, Drew does have almost a walk-in size chamber in
his garage.
You can walk in it.
When that comes online in a few months, then we can test much larger versions of it.
So the thrust does depend on the area.
It does depend on the volume.
It does depend on the voltages, the typical things you would expect.
But we try to optimize it as much as we can with the chamber that we have actively running
right now.
How much are you charging them up to?
What kind of voltage are you using?
Well, when we started in 2016, it was at the Townsend Brown level, 150,000 volts.
Okay.
Thank goodness we're not anywhere near that now.
I think we're operating right now about 400 volts.
You're at 400 volts?
Yeah.
So his belief is that it's really Brown thought that the voltage range was the thing causing
the thrust.
But Charles' belief is that that's sort of a proxy for electric field strength.
And there are obviously other ways to amplify electric field strength that lower voltages.
And so he's using 400 volts.
Yeah, but I can't.
It's shocking.
1.5 millineutons.
That's unbelievable.
Man, I want to come over and hang out with you.
I can introduce you guys.
Put your hands on it.
Do whatever you like.
You're more than welcome.
Isn't that exciting?
Yeah.
I can't believe you're getting these results.
And I can't get past the 400 volts either.
If you increase the voltage, you don't see any change in thrust.
Oh, you'll get more thrust for sure.
We'd like to stay, you know, 200 volts, 500 volts.
We'd like to stay low if we can.
Okay.
Yeah.
It's a preference.
I mean, we'll average, we'll test up to 2,500 volts.
We can start worrying about breakdown when you get more about, you know, about that.
Because these systems are getting much, much smaller.
So we don't have access to the higher fields anymore.
It's material properties that we have to deal with.
But we like the 2,300 volts.
So it gets rid of other nuances like Corona wind or anything like that.
Right, right.
Yeah.
All that stuff gets tossed out.
You're not even ionizing the air in air at 400 volts.
I mean, it's nothing.
That's why I was so shocked because all those other effects drop out right as soon as you drop the voltage down that low.
And you can get some cleaner data then that's, damn, this is really cool.
We're converting Bob on Townsend Brown.
Well, yeah, thank you for this.
Really appreciate it, man.
Good to meet you.
Good to meet you, too.
Take care, guys.
Take care.
That's really fascinating.
Isn't that wild?
Yeah, it's a little more than just wild.
I know, right?
Yeah, it is.
I mean, that's significant.
I think so.
It could really be significant.
You know, the thing is, the first thing I would point out, there's something wrong with your tests.
But not in 1,500 tests.
No.
You know, when you've gone through it that many times and have done it for this long, boy, and you've adjusted all the potential parameters and fallouts.
No, I can't.
I know.
Yeah.
I, you got to assume there's, that the thing's working.
But you also, you mentioned DC voltage in the craft.
And that was.
Yeah.
That's also a Townsend Brown that is high DC voltage.
Yeah, it's not just high DC voltage.
I even mentioned it on, you know, Joe Rogan that I, I think the material the craft is made from is an electric.
And so it only, just like a, a magnet always has a magnetic field to it.
An electric always has an electrostatic field to it.
Interesting.
And I think, I think that's certainly something important.
Were there high climb rates to the voltage likely?
You know what I mean?
Like really high climb, like, like, like fast, you know, swinging up in voltage.
Oh yeah.
I'm without a doubt.
It's so fascinating.
Cause it's, it's literally all the Townsend Brown stuff.
It's like fast, high DC voltage, like fast climb rates.
Yeah.
You know, well, I wonder if that really applies to the craft more than I was giving it credit for.
I think it does.
Especially after your conversation with B-Lay.
Yeah.
I mean, now that's making me wonder.
It could very well be.
But again, because of the high voltage on the craft and.
And it's DC.
Yeah.
So there's no magnetic field interference.
Right.
Man, that's.
We're making progress live here.
And he might've been so far past this already, but.
Well, the funny thing about Brown is he was looking for a power source that was nuclear for like the rest of his career.
Oh, yeah.
He figured out the electric avidics and then he called it the flame jet.
Boy, that would have been the guy to have there other than me.
Well, I mean, you and him, I'd just.
No, no.
You don't need me.
You'd walk off set.
No, you and him would be.
I'd just get in the way.
But yeah, he'd be the guy to have there.
And you were given some theories like there being two gravities, gravity A and gravity B.
Was that in the briefing documents or was this told to you?
Actually, that's I think that was part of what Barry.
Barry had other lab notes.
And I don't know if those were previous documents or documents that he had, but there were lab notes.
And this was the direction they were going in at one time.
There are two specific different types of gravity, gravity A and gravity B.
Gravity A works on a smaller micro scale, while gravity B works on a larger macro scale.
Gravity A is what is currently being labeled as the strong nuclear force in mainstream physics.
And gravity A is the wave that you need to access and amplify to enable you to cause space-time distortion for interstellar travel.
Gravity B is like cosmological scale.
And gravity A is like subatomic scale.
Apparently.
Which it is really interesting.
Because I remember your kind of OG science tutorial.
We were texting about it last night.
Yeah, the excerpts from the government Bible.
Yeah.
The original tape that you did.
And it's amazing.
So it sounds like the kind of gravity A is like basically the perimeter of the atom or what you're dealing with.
But, again, I'm just repeating stuff that I was told.
It's not like I conducted an experiment to verify that.
But it is almost the solution to what has been keeping physics stuck for so long.
Yeah, possibly.
Which is the ability to quantize gravity.
Right, right.
Possibly.
That's so interesting.
If, in fact, that's gravity.
Have you ever, you know, we were talking about this, but gravity-like fields.
And I want to give this to you because you can make sense of it more than me.
And we were talking about this last time.
Oh, yeah.
This is this guy, Burkhard Heim.
Have you ever heard that name?
I've heard the name, but I don't know anything about him.
So he, at the age of 19, became deaf and blind due to an explosion.
And he was a German.
And he ended up moving over to the U.S. and working for Lockheed Martin in the 50s.
And was renowned as just a total genius.
And he had a really interesting theory of gravity, which involved, I guess, two gravitational
fields and, like, some of these, like, subcomponents of gravity.
I wrote this down because it's honestly beyond my pay grade.
Gravity breaks down big and small scale.
So it could be gravity A and gravity B.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Specifically, standard gravity, G, is the tensor summation of three gravitational components.
It's GG, which, big G, little g, which is scalar gravity propagated by the graviton.
By the graviton.
So he's going with gravitons.
For that.
Okay.
GGP, dark energy slash matter propagated by the gravitophoton.
And GQ, vacuum field, a repulsive force propagated by the quintessence particle.
So in addition to the standard four forces, gravity, electromagnetism, strong nuclear, and weak
nuclear, EHT, which is Extended Heim Theory, which is named after him, adds two previously
unrecognized gravitational forces, which brings us to six fundamental forces.
Wow.
And what I find interesting about that is there's Amy Eskridge is this anti-gravity researcher
who actually died under very mysterious circumstances.
And she apparently was, at the end of her life, kept talking about a sixth force.
That was like-
A sixth force, really?
Sixth force, yeah.
The sixth force is anti-gravity.
That's what my group has a mathematical equation to physically describe.
We have six force on lockdown.
And so I wonder about, you know, this book.
And there's these two guys in Germany who are very high conviction in this extended Heim Theory.
I'd like to read it.
Well, it's yours.
Well, thanks.
Oh, that's really interesting.
Isn't it interesting?
I'm also on that.
I think it was not gravity.
I don't think it is.
I don't think it's gravity.
Yeah.
It's something else.
Something else going on.
Yeah.
Because if it were, right, if it were gravity well that you'd normally see, it's a little
black hole, a little gravitational source.
You'd just see everything getting sucked into it, no matter what.
Other things would have acted differently, too.
Yeah.
Light lensing and, yeah.
So it's.
It almost feels like.
It almost has to be.
It's almost like it had rude access to reality itself.
Like it froze time.
Yeah.
But if it froze time, how come the photons were still coming out of it?
You see a glowing candle.
It should be dark.
Can it freeze time in some local space?
But still.
Confine it.
Still the photons are flying out.
Yeah.
Or maybe.
And if you say, well, it doesn't affect photons.
How come it made the black little ball?
Mm.
So.
What do you.
So have you.
Where do you think?
Do you have a best candidate for what it is?
No.
Hmm.
There.
There is.
No.
That's why I think.
I mean, I lean towards this is, this is another force and just stop calling it gravity.
Hmm.
But.
Do you think it's what.
As Barry said.
The only thing we know that does this is gravity.
So we're calling it a gravity generator.
Hmm.
Okay.
And then.
And it's.
Being created.
Ostensibly due to this proton bombardment of element 115 and then.
Possibly.
You get 116 and then you get a decay and then.
If in fact all that's occurring.
Yes.
Yeah.
It's so interesting.
I mean, don't forget that in the film we did not include the mechanical watch experiment
that was also conducted in the lab.
So there was the candle, the black ball and the mechanical watch.
We didn't put it in there just because we wanted to shorten the film.
Hmm.
But there's, there was another experiment, Bob, remember?
And there was like a mechanical watch that just stopped.
Yeah.
Hmm.
I mean.
Whoa.
That's another indicator where Bob said.
Just like the, I mean, it's kind of similar to the candle.
It just stopped.
Hmm.
But I could still see it.
Yeah.
Hmm.
It's like it's freezing.
It's time.
It's freezing movement.
Freezing movement.
But not affecting anything else.
There's nothing that just freezes a move.
No, it doesn't.
But that is really, time is so weird because we, we only.
Something that inhibits kinetic energy.
Right.
Which would be, that would be really weird.
Well, it's so weird, especially given all of the forms of possible kinetic energy.
You're talking about a, a watch, a mechanical watch and a flame are very different things.
Yeah.
So, it's so strange.
While you were there, did you tell anybody what you were working on?
You know, your, your wife at the time?
No, Gene Huff.
You told Gene Huff?
Yeah.
Okay.
Well, I told John Lear too.
Yeah.
And you even brought them to see.
Oh, yeah.
To see the test.
Yeah.
Because I had the test flight schedule.
Yep.
So, I know it's a Wednesday night.
Yeah, we're going out there and you guys are going to see it.
This is John Lear and today is March 22nd, 1989.
We're standing just about eight miles due east of Groom Lake, Nevada, the super government secret test site.
And just a few minutes ago, we saw one of the government extraterrestrial UFOs fly over there.
We've all watched it for about seven or eight minutes.
Right here, I have my Celestron scope.
It's eight inches.
And I had it focused in for about 15 seconds and saw for myself that, in fact, it was a disc.
There isn't much to see with the camera back in that day.
And that was while you were working at S4?
You showed them, or was it afterwards?
That was, boy, that's a tough question.
That was while I was working there.
Okay.
Yeah.
When you saw the UFO with Gene Huff and John Lear and you kind of, you know, took them, what was it, to the little mesa?
Was it a mesa?
No.
It was right outside.
It was before, you know, before you get to the black mailbox.
You know, the reason anybody knew about the black mailbox, everybody wanted to know where the road was that we turned down.
When you come up the highway, it's this first dirt road you go down, but there's no landmarks around there.
And if you keep going, like, another mile or two, there's a black mailbox.
So I just said, it's around the black mailbox.
Yeah.
And that just got repeated, and everybody thought the black mailbox road is where it is.
It's not anywhere near where it is.
When all you guys went up there and you saw the UFO fly, and I'm sure they were just totally shocked, were you allowed back at S4 after that?
Yeah.
Well, yeah, the first time they didn't know we were out there.
Oh, they didn't know.
Yeah, yeah.
We only got caught the last time.
Okay.
No, they would never have let me back.
So after the last time, you weren't let back there.
Right.
That was it.
That was absolutely it, yeah.
You were finished after that.
No, they're not going to, oh, come on back.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
They were pretty pissed.
Yeah.
Why did you decide to come out and approach?
I don't know, because, like, I was still getting followed.
There was always somebody parked outside my house, and I was starting to get scared.
And, you know, I think that's when I first started telling Gene.
I said, you know, hey, if all of a sudden I disappear, you know, I'm working out at the site there.
And eventually I told him, he said, why?
Are you working on secret weapons?
Or something?
And I said, no, I'm working on this.
And, you know, kind of told him.
But, I don't know, I'm just getting concerned about what's going on.
Why do you think they were following you?
I don't know.
It might just be normal security.
Did you take anything from the lab?
Well, not at that time.
Okay.
Later.
But that's interesting that they were, we'll file that away.
But it's interesting that they were following you as if you had done something wrong when you were just showing up to work.
No, but, I mean, you know, they were still doing, they allowed me in there and they were still progressing on my clearance.
They were still going through background checks and, but they really wanted me on site operating quickly.
And they kind of let that slide because I've had clearance before.
So, you know, but, yeah, they were looking at some other things, too.
Got it.
That concerned them.
About you personally?
About my relationship.
Okay.
Got it.
And so, and then they were digging into that?
That's kind of.
Yeah, you know, you have to have a stable family background if you're going to be, you know, playing around with state secrets and stuff like that.
Sure, yeah.
They don't want you being crazy.
They don't want you drinking.
They're going to be checking out, you know, how you play with friends.
If you were going to rages, they want to make sure, you know, your wife wasn't running around.
And they don't want any stress or any, anything to.
But then at that point, if you see these, like, you know, black cars parked outside your house, why isn't your reaction?
Okay, I'm just going to kind of eat it.
Like, they're going to, like, you know, give me, like, a colonoscopy as far as, like, you know, literally, like, knowing 360, everything about my life.
But I'll be able to retain my job at S4.
Or do you just, you get scared and you're like, I got to, I got to come out.
I guess it's, I don't really remember how I felt back then, but I, I was just getting a little concerned.
Yeah.
And did you.
I think it couldn't hurt to at least tell one person, you know, so.
Did you want, because John Lear gave the files on you to George Knapp, right?
A KLAS, is that how it went down?
Gave the files on me.
Or gave the, like, um, said, like, you know, hey.
Yeah, I mean, I, yeah.
John Lear is the one that contacted George Knapp and said, you should speak to this guy.
Okay.
So, he played kind of intermediate.
Was he going rogue on his own?
Or did you say, hey, can you contact, you know, George or somebody in the local news to help me get this stuff out?
No, I think, I mean, at that, well, things were starting to get weird and, um, uh, I, I don't really remember how that went down, but I think, you know, George said, look, you gotta, you gotta get the information out publicly because that's the only way, that's the only thing that'll protect yourself.
I said, that's really stupid.
I'm not going to do that.
And, you know, it was just a couple days later going, well, maybe it's not that stupid, so, um, and was it, do you think it was, um, self-protection or idealism?
Were you, was a part of you like, this needs to be out, this is crazy, the government's hiding.
Yeah, yeah.
But it was, it was an equal part of self-protection, too.
Yeah.
No, fair enough.
Um, Lear is somebody, I think a lot of people have questions about because he was.
He had crazy beliefs.
Crazy beliefs.
You know, I mean, some of the stuff was so ridiculous, you know, I would sit there and just talk to him and go, you are absolutely out of your mind if you believe.
Yeah.
I mean, he didn't believe the sun was hot.
And he said there were people living in the sun.
There's no one living in the sun, John.
And, um, said, yeah, they, they built the moon on Jupiter and, uh, that's where they manufactured it and they towed it into Earth's orbit.
But what is giving you these ridiculous, why are you believing this nonsense?
Yeah.
And, um.
How'd you meet him?
Um.
Gene Huff was a real estate appraiser.
And, uh, at the time, John was looking to get a loan on his house and, um, he had been on, George Knapp had a show on the record, like after the news.
And John Lear had been on there back when he wasn't so have, well, I wasn't, I wasn't going to say he wasn't so crazy, but didn't have such crazy ideas.
You know, I mean, he was, uh, look, he was an accomplished pilot, a brilliant guy.
And he had, you know, tons of files and had lots of great contacts.
The only problem with John was he had no bullshit filter.
Yeah.
I mean, he could have a four-star general tell him something and he'll write it and put her in a file and he'll have some derelict that's walking by his house and go, I know Jell-O thinks.
And he'll go, all right.
And he'll put them in the same file and they have the same level of credibility going, what are you talking about?
You know?
Um, so, uh, he drove me crazy because of that.
But, um, he did, you know, earlier on he was, you know, less exotic with his theories and, you know, it's spoken to George Knapp.
I had seen it on TV, so had Gene Huff.
And, um, anyway, he wound up doing the appraisal on his house and I went with Gene.
Yeah.
To, you know, help him measure it.
And, uh, you know, kind of got talking to John and that's how we met.
But he's such an odd character because his father created the first business airliner in the U.S., the Learjet.
Yeah.
Bill Lear, aviation legend.
Yeah, Bill Lear invented the autopilot, invented the eight-track tape.
That's right.
I mean, he's, uh.
Radio direction finder.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah.
He was, he was quite a guy.
He was.
And so, um.
But he, I mean, he had a problem with John too.
I mean, John was eliminated from, you know, his will.
And John showed me his will.
You know, every paragraph said, except, you know, everybody gets this, except John Olson Lear.
Except John Olson Lear.
Except, I mean, he was so angry at his kid.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It just completely removed him from the will.
Maybe, um, Apple fell far from the tree, like, you know, as far as, uh, uh, you know, aviation engineering prowess or something.
But, uh, John Lear won all sorts of records as a pilot.
He was a very impressive pilot.
But, um.
Oh, yeah.
Credit is due where credit is due.
I mean, he had all kinds of world records.
And it's just, uh.
It's just his filter.
John Lear, uh, was super into UFOs before you got the job at Area 51 S4.
Like, I think he had a UFO blog.
And so, do you think, like, why do you think it didn't come up in a background check that you were friends with this guy?
Oh, it did.
They absolutely asked me about John Lear like the first day.
Okay, okay.
Yeah, what's your relationship with John Lear?
In fact, that might have been the first question.
Really?
Uh, yeah, at EG&G when I sat down.
That's, that, yeah.
It's the first thing they mentioned.
And what did you say?
I said, he's a crazy friend.
Yeah, yeah.
And, uh, I don't remember what else, but I just, you know, told him some stuff.
Yeah, he's met him.
Yeah.
He's, uh, it's fascinating.
And, I mean, John would just do the craziest stuff.
You know, back then he'd, uh, he flew L-1011s, which is a big, big jet, you know.
I don't know, it's 400 people on it or something like that.
And, you know, occasionally he'd call and just, you know, be like a Tuesday night, eight o'clock.
Hey, you want to go to Minneapolis?
Oh, okay.
All right, meet me down at the airport.
Wear a suit.
And come on.
So he'd be a pilot and, you know, the pilot of the craft.
And I'd come on, he said, just come on the tarmac and tell this guy and, you know, walk
up in the plane.
And he'd tell the co-pilot and engineer, hey, this guy's from the FAA.
So he's just going to be observing us and taking it.
So I take the jump seat behind the, you know, pilot and just fly with John.
Did he talk to you about UFOs before you got the job at S4 Area 51?
No, it didn't talk to me about him, but I mean, he spoke about them.
Did he ever?
Yeah, I mean, he used to tell me there are aliens living in the mountains alongside, you know, I think it's I-95 or something.
Right.
The highway.
He said, yeah, there's a billion of them in there.
It's so crazy.
Did he ever show you anything Billy Myers related?
I don't, I don't recall.
Okay.
I think, I think when I described, I think when I described the craft to him and drew it, I think he brought out the Billy Myers book and he said, I think that's where I, in fact, it is.
That's where I first saw it.
So we saw, uh, we showed him the Billy Myers tape.
I said, yeah, that's, that's not like the craft.
That's the craft.
That's so interesting.
So yeah, he kind of helped you piece it together.
Is, did he, um, was he still affiliated with, cause he was a CIA cargo pilot till 1983, I think.
Yeah, that's true.
Did he, uh, continue flying for them after that or did he disappear?
Okay.
I don't think so.
Yeah.
Cause he was, he's this interesting character to me because it seems like he has crazy access to area 51.
Like he's like snooping around and taking photos of like F-117s.
And he even leaks the details of the F-117 to George Knapp, but then he still like knows all the security guards there.
So I'm like, what's his, what's his deal?
You know?
I mean, I had been out at, you know, but before the S-4 thing, um, you know, out in the desert in the middle of the night with binoculars and stuff trying outside, uh, Tonopah.
Yeah.
You know, trying to get pictures of any new aircraft that's flying around.
Cause I mean, he was obviously a big aviation buff.
Yeah.
You know, and I was into that too.
Sometimes I'd just go out and watch, you know, fighters taken off from Nellis Air Force Base.
Cause you could get right up to the fence there.
And, and, uh, you know, so it was, uh, yeah, he was definitely into snooping around and saying whatever he could find out.
I, uh, I mentioned Jacques Vallée, uh, earlier.
He, you met him, right?
Yeah.
I met him and, you know, we spoke briefly.
And then, uh, um, from what I remember, uh, somebody was talking about making a movie with him.
And then after hearing about me and talking, they started talking about, well, maybe we won't, we'll do it on Bob instead.
And he was super pissed off.
Really?
Yeah.
And then from that point on, all of a sudden, you know, everything Bob said is crazy.
Really?
Yeah.
But, uh, yeah, initially he was, uh.
Cause, cause yeah, he writes, he wrote a book called Messengers of Deception and he writes about you and he says, um, you know, Bob Lazar seems to be very legit.
But, uh, he also talks about this pine salt drink he drinks, you know, this, this drink he drinks and the memory lapses it caused.
Now what?
There's no memory.
No memory lapses.
That's a bunch of nonsense.
Okay.
That's a bunch of, it's, you know.
So it was like this vitamin B shot that was like immunity related.
Yeah.
That's all it was.
Okay.
Again, you know, we're working with completely unknown materials.
Yeah.
We don't know what, and apparently people had severe reactions.
To some of this stuff, just touching the craft.
So yeah.
So they had dealt with that before.
I feel like I can defend you on 99.9% of things.
And then the one thing I have trouble with is the MIT thing.
Cause that's the other thing circulating is it was, did you get your master's there or you were sent there?
I was sent there.
On a specific kind of program, isolated program.
Yeah.
And then.
And I did, I did a lot of auditing in both places.
And then on, on Caltech for Caltech, what was that?
So you were sent to MIT and then Caltech was different.
Caltech was way before that.
Okay.
That was, you know, but, um.
And now.
I don't know.
I guess if I really look through old paperwork and stuff, I can come up with things, but that's
never been.
Yeah.
And I think George Knapp found, I think some people who knew you at Caltech.
I mean.
Yeah.
One other question that people have is why were you allowed to give him a tour of Los Alamos
after, uh, you know, you blew the whistle on area 51?
Like, why wasn't there this like nationwide directive at all of the national labs?
Like, don't let this guy back.
Like, and look, it was really nothing.
I mean, we got on a Southwest flight, came out there, rented a car, drove up.
And, uh, I still knew all the guards and stuff like that.
So we came up and he's, you know, it's like, Lazar, you're back.
Yeah.
Just going in there to, you know.
So you think it was just like, it was just like a different time.
And.
Oh, it's, you can't.
Los Alamos is so much higher security now.
I mean, it was so nonchalant back then and we just wrote right into the experimental
areas, came over, hey, I was at Georgia, this is my desk.
Were you surprised?
Was it part of you nervous that there would be some red alert?
No, not at all.
You were like.
Zero concern.
You didn't worry that there was any sort of coordination between area 51 and Los Alamos.
Nobody knew what was going on there.
It was just, like I said, it was very lax atmosphere.
In fact, a year or two after that, they were so concerned about that.
I think they called it the Tiger Team came in to test security there and they failed so
horribly that they just redid everything.
And, you know, after that point, you're, forget it, you're not going in.
But, yeah, I like still had keys and things.
Yeah, it was.
It was not even a problem.
When did you start United Nuclear?
99, 2000.
Did you ever work with the government with United Nuclear?
Yeah, yeah.
Oh, yeah.
Okay.
Yeah.
I mean, we still, we supply them, you know, they train Department of Homeland Security,
FBI.
I mean, we sell them stuff all the time, especially when they're training people to use radiation
detection equipment.
I mean, we'll give them or sell them, you know, radioactive sources so they can go hide
something in a warehouse and give the trainees a Geiger counter, go find it, you know.
Did you ever wonder why they didn't view you as a liability given your, you know, late
80s experience at S4 Area 51 and they were just down to do contract work with you?
I don't know.
You know, but one hand doesn't know what the other is doing in the government.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's kind of a mess.
No, and it's a...
I mean, in fact, part of, you know, United Nuclear, when it was just beginning, some
of the stuff we're selling was kind of questionable.
You know, this could potentially, you know, be used for explosives or stuff like that.
Great.
So, went down to the FBI and reviewed everything with them and they went, no, you can, that's
cool.
Went down to the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, and Firearms.
No, we're good, you know, and the Postal Service, no, everything's good.
All right, great.
We're going to go sell on it.
And then, you know, raided by the Consumer Product Safety Commission, they come in with
a SWAT team with a machine.
Woke my wife up out of bed with, you know, an M16 bindered in her face.
Jesus Christ.
You know, it's like, we checked with everybody.
I didn't check with us.
So, don't you guys talk?
So, yeah, one hand has no idea what the other's doing when it comes to the government.
Yeah, no, I believe that.
Is there any part of you that thinks that they wanted you to come out and that they wanted
some frameworks?
Because, to your point, it's maladaptive to have this completely shut out from, like,
to have a STEM student who's talented and, you know, some random state.
Why go through the complicated...
I mean, why make it complicated and make me do it?
Right.
Why not just do it yourself?
Put out the high-level framework and say, yeah.
This whole complicated scenario with this guy coming in and hope that he does something
you want, that doesn't make any sense.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
No, I think that's fair.
There's this John Lear interview where, again, it's impossible to parse what the hell is
going on with that guy.
Look, I have heard John Lear tell my story.
Yeah.
And it is so wrong.
It's unbelievable.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I mean, he puts...
I mean, he inserts himself in there in a prominent position, you know, well, I got Bob, you know,
to get the job to here and this.
And what are you talking...
It's completely inaccurate.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
And in this interview, he says, like, yeah, Admiral McClellan, who was a Navy admiral, came
to me and he was MJ level, you know, MJ obviously in the UFO lore would be like the elite, you
know, kind of committee that governs this whole topic, came to me and he said, we got to get
Bob on the job because we know that we can hide his...
In some ways, it's corroborating your story because it's saying, like, no, he was there.
He was at S4, he was working on this stuff.
But we need to get Bob specifically because we know we can have plausible deniability because
they'll never be able to find his MIT records.
It turns out that MJ-1, the head of MJ-12, is a guy named Admiral Mike McClellan.
He wanted to get some of the information out because he didn't want to...
He thought that some of this information should be out in the public.
We don't need to keep all this secrecy.
So he decided, trying to figure out a way to get it to the public.
So he knew that I was a blabbermouth and I would tell anything I knew.
They investigated Bob Lazar and they knew that he was a genius, but that he had a background
such that they could instantly discredit him.
And then I...
So I thought about that for a while and I was like, what the...
What is this?
And I couldn't even find an Admiral McClellan and then...
I've heard that name before, but the thing is I...
That's interesting that you've heard it.
Yeah, I have definitely heard the name.
It could have come from John Lear, but I don't know.
I mean, the thing is, some of the stuff he's saying absolutely can be true or absolutely cannot.
Totally.
I don't know, but I mean, you know, I love the guy.
He was a great friend.
He just thinks differently.
And I mean, it's sad he died.
I wish I had spent more time with him.
Yeah.
But after I moved, it was just impractical.
But yeah, I mean, if you're talking about statements John Lear made, boy, it's tough.
It's really tough to find out what's accurate and what's not.
It's decoding the Voynich manuscript or something.
Yeah, yeah.
But yeah, no, he's a complicated guy.
He...
So I think, and we talked about this a little last night, and maybe this is an interesting
follow-up for this show, is I think he might have been talking about a guy named Mike McConnell,
who became NSA director later.
But he was involved in some S4 Area 51 stuff related to Dan Barish, whose story, I think,
honestly holds up a lot less than your story.
But it's, you know, it has to be noted because it's one other guy who's mentioning S4.
And so Mike McConnell's kind of involved there, and he was a Navy Admiral at the time.
So I think about that, and I'm like, I wonder if Mike McConnell was somewhat involved.
When you came out as Dennis, was that a shot across the bow against Dennis Mariani?
Yeah, sure was.
So you were trying to kind of get at him a little bit?
Yeah.
What were your feelings towards him kind of personally?
Were you resentful, or were you, yeah, how'd you feel towards him?
I guess somewhat resentful.
I don't know.
It's hard to tap into how I felt back then.
Yeah.
Why do you think, and I know, Luigi, you might have some theories here too, why do you think
Dennis wanted to meet up with you at the end of this whole saga?
At the casino.
And then you meet up with him at the casino, and then you're speaking to him, and Gene Huff
is looking, and he's just not even, like, looking at you.
Like, what is that about?
I don't know.
I think Dennis really had something to say, and I don't know.
I don't know if people from S4 got there and changed his mind.
I don't know if he intentionally wanted me to go out there just to get me away from the
house.
I really don't know.
Because you got back to the house and something had been taken?
Yeah, things were missing, yeah.
Anything of consequence?
Yeah, yeah.
Anything you can talk about?
No.
Okay.
So, you know, I mean, there's...
I don't know.
It's all guesswork.
Yeah.
I mean, when we sat down, even Gene Huff, I spoke to Gene Huff about that.
And Gene's perspective to that was he saw Bob walk up to Dennis.
And it's an important part because I always think about the fact that Gene Huff was there.
Joe was also there.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, we were all...
We all had eyes on him, yeah.
And what Gene said was, you know, Bob Lazar walks up to this guy Dennis, this blonde, you
know, military-looking guy, and Bob's talking to him, and the guy's not even looking at him.
And that caught Gene's attention.
It's like, you know, if Bob was making that up, what did he do?
Just pick out a guy out of nowhere and starts talking.
If the guy was a nobody, he would have turned around and go, like, what do you want?
Yeah.
He would have been like, stop talking.
Yeah, no.
I mean, I kept saying, Dennis, Dennis, I'm here.
You know, what do you want?
What's going on?
I don't remember my exact words, but he never even looked up at me.
And, yeah, I just walked over to Gene and said, he's...
I don't know what the deal is with Dennis.
We both turned around and he was gone.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah.
That's so interesting.
So, I wonder, a part of me wonders if he himself wanted to come out after you or something.
Or there was something he needed to come out.
Unfortunately, it's all speculation.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
He could have wanted to come out.
He might have been part of, well, let's get Bob out of a house.
Yeah.
There's a thousand, but there's no direction to go in.
I mean, that was so striking from the documentaries.
They put a, your gun was set up in your own car and the doors were open in the parking lot, right?
And then you walked in.
Yeah, that happened more than once.
That's scary, man.
Yeah.
Did you?
And I mean, we would lock it and test the door and because it had happened before and go, all right, let's lock, lock, check, check every single thing.
Okay.
Mario, it's locked.
It's locked.
Okay, we go into the gym, we come back out, everything's open.
Did you, was there ever a moment where you were like, over 50% I might get assassinated?
Yeah, because it's why I said we have to look under the car, see if there's something wired in there or a bomb.
I mean, we were even afraid.
The only thing that wasn't open, I think, was the hood where the engine was.
So we were afraid to open that, you know, and finally did, but looked over the car.
But yeah, I was afraid there was a bomb on there or somebody wired it up.
But as George said, I think they were just screwing with me.
Yeah, Mario, you know, Mario talked a lot with him and we really, really spent a lot of time.
And it's hard to, he also kept saying, it's really hard to like explain and express what that worry was.
Because I was with, he said, I was with Bob all the time and we were scared that something was going to blow up.
And he says, I was so going through my hard times that I didn't care.
I just told Bob, stay out and I'll try it.
And he would start the car because he was like, fuck it, I'm going to do it.
But you could sense that even from Mario's perspective, there was a real worry.
And so, you know, this is something that clearly was causing a lot of worry, not just for you, but for Mario as well.
Because it's like, what the hell is going on?
The doors are unlocked again.
And, you know, why are they doing this?
So clearly you think something could go wrong.
So whether they were trying to just intimidate or do something, whatever that was, it was happening according to those guys, to these guys.
Did you get the sense that there were maybe mob ties?
Like there was some, you know, they talk about the UFO legacy program sometimes like it's a cartel or like a mafia that exists outside of the state.
Did you get the sense, and obviously you're, you know, going back and forth from Vegas and Vegas is a hotspot for that sort of thing.
Did you ever get that, that sense?
Not that it was the mob per se.
Yeah.
But it was like, these guys were disconnected from the government.
They were like their own.
Yeah.
They were their own cabal.
You kind of get that.
But like, even I feel like John Lear was like, like he had, you know, there's a picture with him and G Gordon Liddy.
Do you know who that is?
It's this like, yeah, I know the name.
I don't remember who he is.
He's this FBI agent who was this kind of agent provocateur who was very involved in Watergate and stuff.
And you get the sense that that whole world, like the people, the Mormons who were around Howard Hughes, and there was a lot of mob, you know, there's a lot of mob activity there.
And it was like, they were kind of like, you could, you could see a civilian government official calling them and then being like, fuck off is the vibe.
Yeah.
That's exactly.
We're doing our thing.
Yeah.
Is undeniable.
You think so?
Yeah.
I'm a hundred percent on that.
I know you've also, cause you know, you live in Montreal and there's stuff there and I'm sure you've, you've bumped into things and people.
I, I, I, I always talk about it when, when I talk, when I hear about all these government organizations and government secrets and the intelligence community.
And I think a lot of researchers and I think a lot of people researching this should also pay attention to what organized crime did back then, back in the sixties, the seventies, the eighties, the nineties, and how those organizations operated and what they did.
Cause it's a very similar way of keeping secrets.
And, you know, I think that there is some tie somewhere.
I'm not saying that they're involved and they're in charge of anything and that's not what I'm saying, but I'm saying there is clear motivation for somebody who's trying to keep a secret to have ties with, with let's say the mob.
So that if ever something or somebody does start going to rogue, well, you could basically scare that person and say, well, you know, these guys will come after you and that'll scare somebody more than a lawyer will come after you.
That's right.
Well, it seems like they, they were going after, they were going after your marriage and like they, it's called blackmail techniques.
Like that's what it, it feels like it's compromise systems and you look at.
Yeah.
They weren't, they weren't taking the legal angle at all.
No.
Which is really, if you want to enforce something like that's, that's the way you do it.
Uh, which is pretty wild.
I mean, you see this stuff with the Epstein thing too, where it's just, they're just clearly is this distributed kind of compromise system and it deals with spooky science.
I don't know if you're tracking any of this stuff, but like.
Yeah.
I started looking into it.
Isn't it wild?
Yeah.
It's, it's really wild.
And then he says.
And it's so widespread.
It's widespread.
And here's, what's crazy.
He's interviewed by Steve Bannon and Epstein is, this is at the end of his life.
Yeah.
And he goes, why did you put a Zorro ranch where you put it?
And he goes, well, um, you know, a bunch of, uh, Los Alamos physicists were retiring.
And so, you know, they were kind of aging out and I wanted to speak with them.
Los Alamos, which was the high energy lab up in New Mexico was losing all its scientists.
And you bought your property out in New Mexico to be near that?
Yes.
Because the scientists were going to be, they cut the funding for high energy physics.
And you're like, oh my God, how lax is our DOE, you know, department of energy security.
And then he realized, you know, Bill Richardson was kind of in with the Clintons and he was
the secretary of energy and he's there and he's just systematically siphoning American
nuclear secrets, which, and then he goes, there's another email where he said, I killed
ponds back in the day or whatever.
And he's talking about ponds and Fleischman who are claiming to get cold fusion results.
And so it's like, what is Epstein dealing with cold fusion?
And then he's, he's hanging out at Harvard with the math department.
None of that makes any sense.
It's weird.
Really strange.
I used to drive by that ranch all the time.
I lived really close to it when I lived in New Mexico.
Yeah.
And, uh, they always called it the Victoria's Secret Ranch because there were models there.
Everyone knew that is the Victoria's Secret Ranch.
So you would drive by Epstein's Ranch and they would call it the Victoria's Secret Ranch.
Yeah, you could see, I mean, not right by it, but as you drive it on the road, you can
see it up on that.
Yeah.
Well, you know why they called it that?
It's because he was close with Les Wexner, who was the CEO and founder of Victoria's Secret.
Yeah.
Oh, okay.
So you would drive by there and they would call it that.
Everybody called it that, yeah.
No way.
We'd drive up to Los Alamos to pick up alpha radiation probes, something my company did.
And, uh, you know, we'd come back, but yeah, every, every time we drove out, we passed by
it a couple of times.
That's so nuts.
Damn.
So what do you, do you, cause like, it's also for the people that are like, disbelieve your
stuff.
It's like, look at all this bizarre, it's like this cabal is controlling science or something,
you know, it's so weird.
That is really weird.
Yeah.
And it's, I get, you know, I'll say it, it's, it's, it's just, we're just talking about Epstein.
That's one guy.
It's not just one guy.
Clearly not.
No, it's not.
It's not just one guy.
Not at all.
He's a front.
Yeah.
It's just not, it's not.
I mean, he might've been the ringleader, but it's, uh.
There's a lot of people.
Or he might've been an extension of something much.
Yeah, he could be.
But he was obsessed with the Casimir effect and he would hold these.
Oh, he was?
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
He would, he would hold these gravity conferences.
And then the very fact that he's saying.
I mean, do you know that for a fact?
Yeah.
This is all in the emails.
This is all a fact.
Oh, it is?
Yeah.
There's an old colleague of mine, Eric Weinstein.
It mentions the Casimir effect?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Wow.
Yeah.
So this old colleague of mine, Eric Weinstein, has this theory of everything in physics where,
you know, it involves gauging gravity instead of quantizing gravity beyond my pay grade.
But I find it interesting.
And Epstein, like, somehow knew about his theory before, like, just about anybody else did.
And so, so Weinstein's like, how is Epstein so tied in with the Harvard math department?
Do you think it was just his hobby or something like science was his hobby and he just had
money so he, uh.
No.
The ability to connect to these.
I think there, you read his emails and it's like there's somebody behind him who knew
exactly what to look for and, but he didn't know.
He was like a low level version of it.
And so he'll say things like, you need to boost your physics.
Time is much weirder than you think.
It's actually just a function of the vibration of cesium atoms.
And you're like, how, who's giving you this stuff, you know?
And then he's sort of like mining people for the info and weird.
I mean, did he, he said that?
He said that.
Yeah.
Which is true.
It is kind of.
It's an atomic clock.
It's just a vibrating cesium.
Yeah.
So, yeah, I mean, it, it's true.
I don't know if that's what time is, but it's our perception of time.
Time is very weird, isn't it?
Wouldn't you say on a, in a, just from a pure physics perspective, it's, it's a weird,
it's an anomaly.
It's strange.
Yeah.
Like, like it's, we can't, it's the most used noun in the English language, but we can
only define it with respect to the movement of macroscopic bodies or to oscillations on
an electromagnetic wave.
But it's not like a, it's a thing that we're like, it's almost like fish in a fish bowl
where like the fish are trying to even describe what water is, but they don't, they can't because
they're in it.
Yeah.
And then we're in time.
You have to be outside of it to describe it.
I mean, that's, that's it.
And you can't be outside it.
I, it's just, it's just a concept that makes us happy is what time is.
Do you think that there's something about time being weird that might help explain some
of the UFO stuff?
Yeah.
I think there's, there's definitely something there.
Cause if gravity's off.
There's organic chunks that are missing from physics and, uh, I think some people have
access to that.
Yeah.
I think so too.
But I mean the, um, cosmic red, the other thing that this guy, Burke Hardheim says is that
the cosmic red shift is the repulsive form of gravity.
And if you look at dark energy, you could literally just look it up.
It's like this, it's not one of the four fundamental forces, but it's just, you know, the universe
is inflating.
Dark energy really exists.
Yeah.
That's.
And dark matter too.
I'm not, I'm, yeah, I'm not really buying either one of them.
Dark matter's never been detected, but it's just, it's just there to.
It's a placeholder.
To justify gravity's weakness.
Yes.
Yeah.
And then.
I mean, to me, that's, I always viewed, that's what gravitons were.
That's why this caught my attention because he's.
Yeah.
Back on the graviton bandwagon.
Well, gravitons are interesting because as early as the fifties, you know, there's all this like
crazy hardcore anti-gravity research and then it kind of disappears.
Yeah.
But you had a bunch of people saying we're going to be gravity.
It's right around the bend.
There's a guy named George Trimble, who was a VP at Martin corporations, RIAS research for
institute for advanced study.
And he was this really wacky thinker.
And, um, he worked with Lewis Whitten and probably Townsend Brown.
And, um, you know, they would say like, it was, it's going to take us the time that it
took to build the atom bomb to basically beat gravity.
And they were Stanley Desser and Richard Arnowit, who were famous physicists at the time from
Princeton, were talking about gravitons.
And they were like, we have a very clear theory of gravitons and we know how to do this.
And the two things that come up for gravity, where there's a lot of smoke, but no fire is
the thing we just talked about with Buehler, extremely high electric field differentials
creating thrust.
And then the second thing is very fast rotating spinning superconductors.
Those two things seem to have some.
But is that actually gravity?
So there's another force.
30 years has gone by and I've kind of been doing my own research.
And, uh, I'm just more convinced that, that I'm right about that.
And can you say anything about that?
What do you think you're right about?
That there's another force and it's not gravity.
And what is the, if you were to characterize that force as distinct from gravity, so gravity
clearly you'd have all these other by-product effects, the photons.
And what, what's, what does this force do that's different?
What is it, what does it look like?
Well, it's a, it's a repelling force, but I think it's something that works closer to
the way you would think in a science fiction movie.
You can have gravity and anti-gravity, but you really can.
I think gravity is just an attractive force.
I think this other force, you can, you can, to make, simplify it, push or pull.
And I think it, it also affects the flow of time exactly like gravity does.
I think it affects light.
It does some of the, some of the observations you would have with gravity would also overlap
in this other force.
But I think it's, I think it's a unique force.
Have you ever measured this force?
Next question.
All right.
Yeah.
You have?
How have you measured it?
No, no.
There's no follow-up question.
Okay.
Fine.
Is there anything kind of high level that you can say as far as your, the goal of your
research, you know, post the experience, like what you would love to do?
Oh, just to duplicate anything.
Just to duplicate anything.
Yeah.
Okay.
I'm sure I can.
You think you can?
Yeah.
I'm sure I can.
You feel confident?
I'm a hundred percent confident.
Yeah.
I, I'm going to.
Have you already gotten some interesting results?
Yeah.
Okay.
That's why I'm a hundred percent confident.
Yeah.
The thing is just to scale stuff up.
Okay.
What do you hope your legacy is?
So like 200 years from now, a kid.
No one's going to know who I am.
I don't think that's right, man.
Think about it.
Like if there are these, you know, this lineage of technology that is completely separate.
Come on.
I'm going to be overwritten by people.
Look, there's other Bob Lazar's and things that are going to come along.
Look what's happening.
All the people that came out since then, you know, there's going to be other people like
me.
Eventually some more of this is going to come out and yeah.
They're amazing.
They're amazing people who've come out since you first and foremost.
Yeah.
And there's going to be bigger, more important ones that you just aren't going to look back
to the eighties and think you're just going to focus on those guys.
Well, I would put it the invert.
I would say if you have like a, an army of people coming out after you, the fact that
you're the first makes it even more interesting.
I think it's, it's more likely you'd be forgotten if no one comes out after you.
Do you, do you hope to vindicate your own experience through your own scientific experimentation?
Yeah, I do.
That's exciting.
That's cool.
But I have no idea what other people are doing.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
But I know exactly what not to do.
Yeah.
That's what we did it us for.
So it's, it's actually a big leap forward.
And you saw one hanging up against the wall?
Yeah, it was sitting on the wall and it had, there's actually an error in the movie.
It has one hole in, in the room of it.
Not two.
Um, but yeah, there was just a hole with it bent out, clearly bent out as if it was
shot from the bottom.
Why do you think, oh, it looked like it was shot.
Yeah.
Interesting.
So do you think it was shot with like a kinetic weapon, mechanical weapon?
No, no question.
Whoa.
And do you think it was a human weapon that shot it?
I don't know.
It looks like something we would have done to stand it up, shoot through it, see how,
how we can penetrate this material.
Whoa.
Do you, have you ever heard anything about like electromagnetic pulses and UFOs and them
taking out UFOs, taking them down or anything or?
Well, that was, that was the other directive of the project.
It was.
Directed energy.
Well, yeah, it depends what you're talking about.
There's, I mean, our directive was duplicate the propulsion system at any cost is directive
one and directive two was be able to disable the system at a distance at any cost.
Do you think?
And then, so that's somewhat directed energy, but then there is also project sidekick, which
is a weapon.
So that's also directed energy.
So, yeah, it kind of depends where you're going with that.
I guess, had you heard of any UFOs prior to that getting shot down with directed energy
with electromagnetic pulse?
I think the only thing I ever heard prior to that was stories about the Roswell craft
getting hit by lightning and crashing or something.
I think it's the only.
Are there any of these stories, like, do you think that Roswell happened?
Are there any of these stories you lend credence to?
I don't know much about the, the Roswell crash other than, you know, what I've, what I've
heard, but it sure seems like they were working real hard to cover something up.
That's true.
The Roswell crash was not one crash.
It was, it was not in one place only though.
It might've been a round of two.
Yeah.
I really think it was, there was something that happened in the air and there's like
debris that was scattered all over Mack Brazel's ranch.
And then there was the actual pod with the beings that was crashed.
I think it was like a two miles away where the hikers found it with the kids that were
hiking.
And so clearly it was two different places and the bamboo, the, the pieces that looked
like bamboo with the, the writing, writing on it.
That was that Mack Brazel with the, the memory metal and then the pod, the only information
we have of that is the bodies.
And one of them was already being eaten by some, uh, animals.
No way.
Yeah.
The body's being eaten by some animals?
One of the, from what I remember reading and at the time there's one of them was obviously
dead and it was decaying.
Like there was an, it was clearly some animals that got to it.
Wow.
So, but that was.
I hadn't heard that, but the only, the only thing I remember about that was Jesse Marcel
was the.
Yes.
The military.
Yeah.
Right.
And, um, he said when, you know, they came to take pictures or the pictures they took,
he said, that wasn't the stuff that we found.
Whoa.
What general Ram, Rammy.
Yeah.
He said, yeah, they replaced it with, he said, that's not what we found.
Well, he's.
That's the guy.
And there's that iconic photo and it's him with this like tinfoil-y weather balloon
thing.
Yeah.
And he said that, yeah.
He claims that the material was right off to the side of the frame.
It's so interesting.
He said, yeah, that's, that's not the stuff.
And his son, who's a Air Force flight surgeon, said that he took the material home and he played
with the material.
Yeah.
Which is crazy.
On the kitchen table with his wife.
Yeah.
And here's what's where stuff gets even crazier.
In 1949, there is a contract between Battelle Memorial Institute and Wright Airfield, which
turns into Wright Patterson, which is where the wreckage, the Roswell wreckage was rumored
to be taken.
And it's like around, um, alloys, like titanium, different titanium alloys and this titanium
nickel alloy.
And nitinol.
Nitinol.
Yeah.
Nitinol, as you know.
Memory metal.
Is basically memory metal.
And nitinol was classified, essentially showed up in a Navy lab in the sixties.
Yeah.
And that's what Jesse Marcel describes the material as.
Because that's, that's really indestructible stuff.
Yes.
And I remember him saying, it's vernacular.
We gave, we whacked that as hard as we could, you know, right.
And it, it didn't bend.
And I, I remember that.
They tried to burn it.
They tried to cut into it.
Yeah.
And it just goes back into its original shape.
And I just actually interviewed.
Yeah.
It's one of the, I mean, you can take that metal and flex it a million times and it doesn't
crack.
It's what they, I mean, they use that in artificial hearts because you can, it can keep flexing
and it just doesn't wear.
It's wild.
Then, then, and, and then you have Philip Corso saying that he helped dole out a lot
of this material and it made it into the civil sector because of his position.
He was, you know, Pentagon's like, you know, foreign technology desk or whatever chief.
And so you have this contract from 49.
Nobody knew what Nittanol was, Nittanol was.
And then in the sixties, it appears in public randomly at a Navy lab.
It's interesting.
That's really interesting.
I never heard any of that.
And I just interviewed a guy who was a witness actually of the Varginia crash in the 1990s,
1996 in Brazil.
And he says the same thing.
He says he held the material in his hands and it went, he would kind of mess with it and
then it would go back into its original form.
So did you ever experience anything like that with the material, with material that would
go back into its original form?
Did you hear anything about that?
No, other than working with Nittanol.
Yeah.
But you did work with Nittanol.
I sell it.
But did you work, you didn't work with it?
No, no, no, no.
Okay.
So you didn't hear anything around, around that there?
No, not, not a peep.
Did you hear anything about any other materials?
No, that's material science.
We're not allowed to know that stuff.
Oh, okay.
So that was a whole other.
Yeah.
Interesting.
Which is really stupid.
And you saw a photo or photos of an alien autopsy, right?
Yeah.
If in fact that was true.
Do you think?
Yeah, it was part of the briefing.
What did the photos look like?
I guess if you want to call it a gray, something small.
It had a T cut in the chest and there was one single organ removed from the chest.
Was that kind of a visceral experience for you?
Was that kind of, you know, gnarly or were you like, eh, whatever?
No, you know, at this point I'm going, what am I looking through?
Yeah.
You know, it, it, it was just kind of all glancing through like, give me a break.
There were rumors that the program was going to maybe move to Indonesia or Southeast Asia
when you were leaving?
No, no.
They, there were, they were anxious to move the project out of there completely.
And, you know, ideally they said they would have loved to go out to the South Pacific,
maybe Kwajalein Island or something, but they said the expenses would have been so great.
It's just impossible.
But they just wanted to get away from eyes.
It's just too close to things.
If you had to guess, do you think that the program is completely out of area 51 and in
some foreign place now?
Yeah.
I don't, I don't believe it's there anymore.
That would make sense.
Yeah.
I don't believe it's there.
I think that moved way long ago.
Yeah.
And you discovered Element 115, right?
It wasn't discovered.
It's something Barry and I were working on.
Okay.
So, I mean, you can't really say I discovered it.
You know.
Oh, I thought your contribution was that you discovered.
Our contribution.
Okay.
It was what I was doing.
So, yeah.
But what I can't say, it was just me.
What technique?
But it was the, um, God, what the hell was it that we were using?
Oh, atomic absorption spectroscopy.
Atomic absorption spectroscopy.
Spectroscopy.
Yeah.
And you did that.
I mean, we had the equipment there.
We also had something to do X-ray diffraction to.
Wow.
And, yeah, it wasn't, Barry was much more familiar with the equipment.
But, um.
And you, but you don't know the exact isotope?
No.
Did you know it at one point?
Like when you discovered it?
Yeah, yeah.
You did?
But you forgot the isotope?
Yeah, I have, I have no idea.
Oh, man.
Because that would be, that would.
Yeah, I know it would really help.
It would really help.
And it would, it would also be a Nobel Prize for you.
It would be like, oh my God, they figured out like a new isotope at that level.
No, but I'd have to be able to produce it or.
Sure.
You know.
Right, right, right.
So it doesn't matter.
Yeah.
I mean, but, you know, the lab in Darmstadt, Germany produced, you know, a few atoms of 115.
So, I mean, they discovered 115.
Yes.
So, I mean, they, they made it, you know, we.
Yeah.
We recognized it.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So.
But if you.
I don't think it would help you because it's not like, you know, the way we try to synthesize,
you know, new elements is, you know, taking ions and smashing them together.
And it's kind of, whatever comes out, comes out.
It's not like you can go, we're going to make a specific isotope and make it all stick together.
It's just like, you know, it's the old smashing the Swiss watch against a concrete wall.
Ooh, look what came out.
You know, that's it.
If you possibly took a little bit home, though, could you do some of those techniques again and do it?
No, I couldn't.
You couldn't because you don't have the.
I can't, yeah.
You need the equipment.
I mean, you need the equipment, like, you know, accelerators and things.
That's.
So you don't have.
Something like that.
So you wouldn't have the stable isotope at home.
Or you do.
Or maybe.
Well, I don't have it at my house.
Okay.
If that's what you're asking.
But didn't you, at one point, maybe take it home?
Yeah.
So that, but then.
Are we recording?
Yeah, but.
So no.
Okay.
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
Yeah.
But then can't, but then couldn't you figure out the isotope if theoretically you did?
Or no?
Yeah.
Okay.
Yeah, you could.
All I'd have to do is have it again.
Okay.
Oh, I see.
That's a bummer.
I hosted a debate between Eric Weinstein and Eric Davis.
Eric Weinstein's this former colleague of mine who's a physicist.
And then Eric Davis is this other guy in UFO world who focuses on exotic propulsion.
Weinstein said that he did.
He was kind of exasperated.
He was like, why are there no theoretical physicists on the program?
But you talk about theoretical physicists on site at S4.
Oh, for sure.
Okay.
I think they were exhausted by him.
And I think they kept going over that road and never got anywhere.
Interesting.
And they were looking for just, let's just do something out of left field and see what
we come up with.
So, no, I don't know.
Again, that's what made me think this isn't gravity at all.
This is a new forest entirely.
Yeah.
And you know what I found interesting to you is you said bismuth seemed to have come up.
Like that was something.
There is something about bismuth.
You might be starting to notice a through line starting to emerge in this conversation.
And it keeps leading back to the same place.
To put it bluntly, Bob's work at S4 looks a whole lot like all of the documented knowledge
we have on anti-gravity experiments done in the last 100 years.
Now, again, these claims don't lie in the realm of conventional proven science.
But while there's no proverbial fire, there is a whole lot of smoke around them.
I'm talking not only of the experiments of Townsend Brown, but of Eugene Pokletinov,
Ning Li, and others.
And one single element might tie all of these stories together.
Bismuth.
There's a reason why Bob Lazar kept hearing about it at S4.
Here's why bismuth matters.
We'll break down the science as clearly as we can.
It starts with something called a K-factor.
A K-factor, or dielectric constant, is simply a material's ability to store and discharge
electric fields.
Now, this has important implications for historical anti-gravity experiments.
You see, the higher the K-factor, the more thrust or propulsion you see in Townsend Brown's
capacitor experiments.
Brown spent his career searching for high K-materials that could amplify the effect he'd
discovered.
Bismuth is one of them, and it's often mentioned in the context of his anti-gravity work.
There's even an interview from this guy, Lewis Witten, who's at RIAS, which is Martin
Corporation, pre-Lockheed Merger, their anti-gravity outfit, where they were studying sort of the
most exotic propulsion modalities.
And he says in this interview with the American Institute of Physics, there's a guy named
Townsend, who claimed to have an isotope of bismuth that repelled instead of attracted.
Material that works well for historical anti-gravity experiments comes up in the UFO reverse engineering
program.
Go figure.
But it gets weirder.
Bismuth and element 115, muscovium, share the same number of valence electrons.
Valence electrons are the electrons in the outermost shell of an atom, the ones that determine
how an element bonds, reacts, and behaves chemically.
Bismuth has five.
Muscovium, or element 115, has five.
They sit in the same column of the periodic table, group 15, which means they have essentially
the same chemical personality, the same bonding geometry, the same family of crystal structures,
the same tendency to form the layered compounds that produce the most exotic quantum behavior
known to material science.
Lazar described element 115 as the fuel source for the craft's propulsion system.
Mind you, this was in 1989, before element 115 had ever been synthesized or named.
When it finally was synthesized in 2003, it turned out to be anictogen, a group 15 element,
the same chemical family as bismuth.
And bismuth is basically the most electromagnetically bizarre stable element on Earth.
That's either the most chemically literate lucky guess in history, or it isn't a guess
at all.
Now here's where the science gets genuinely strange.
Bismuth is one of the most unusual elements on the periodic table.
Most high-K materials are passive.
They sit there, holding charge, and do nothing else.
Bismuth is different.
It fights back.
Expose bismuth to a magnetic field, and instead of being attracted the way iron pushes towards
a magnet, it pushes away.
This property is called diamagnetism, and bismuth has more of it than any other stable element
on Earth, not slightly more, dramatically, anomalously, inexplicably more.
The reason lives inside the atom itself.
Every electron does two things simultaneously.
It orbits the nucleus like a planet around a star, and it spins on its own axis like a
tiny top.
In lighter elements, these two motions barely register each other.
But bismuth sits near the bottom of the periodic table at element 83, one of the heaviest stable
elements that exists.
And in super-heavy elements, something extraordinary happens.
The electrons in the outer shell move so fast that they enter what physicists call the relativistic
regime.
They're traveling at a meaningful fraction of the speed of light.
And when something moves that fast, the universe starts playing by different rules.
At those speeds, Einstein's physics takes over from Newton's.
One consequence is that these screaming, curling outer electrons generate a powerful magnetic
field just from their own motion.
And that magnetic field slams into their own spin.
This is a process called spin-orbit coupling.
And in bismuth, it's ferociously strong.
So strong that bismuth's electrons become, in a sense, magnetically self-aware.
Generating an opposing field in response to anything applied to them from the outside.
So that's why bismuth has anomalous diamagnetism.
The electrons aren't just passive.
They're pushing back.
The most amazing thing is, leaning into it, putting all your force on that, nothing moves
at all.
And when the reactor's off, you can easily slide it.
This also makes bismuth a natural topological doping.
Meaning when you introduce it into certain crystalline materials, it induces what physicists call
topologically protected quantum states.
These are electron states so geometrically locked into the structure of the material that
they can't be destroyed by disorder or impurities.
They are, in a very real sense, protected by the shape of reality itself.
Element 115, with the same five outer electrons as bismuth, would have dramatically stronger
relativistic effects.
And it would theoretically be an even more powerful topological doping.
Best hosted, physicists predict, in chalcogenide crystal structures, which happen to be the exact
crystal family that bismuth-based topological insulators already prefer.
Same column, same electrons.
The dial just turned up to a level we've never engineered.
Okay, I know what you're thinking.
How do you get from this exotic chemistry jargon to UFO propulsion, or a force that bends
spacetime?
Well, here's where the chemistry ends, and something bigger begins.
In Einstein's general relativity, energy and momentum in all forms, including the energy
stored in fast-spinning relativistic electrons, technically curves spacetime.
Every electron is, in the most literal physical sense, warping the fabric of the universe around
it.
Now, for ordinary matter, this effect is so incomprehensibly tiny, it effectively doesn't
exist.
But a small group of serious physicists began asking dangerous questions in the 1990s.
What if, instead of spinning randomly in all directions, their gravitational effects canceling
each other into noise, you could align them into a single coherent state, all pointing in
the same direction, all pushing together?
This was the life's work of Dr. Ning Li, a physicist who dared to dabble in antigravity.
More specifically, she worked in gravitomagnetic theory.
Li was a woman who eventually left her position at the University of Alabama Huntsville to work
full-time at Redstone Arsenal, on research so sensitive it effectively vanished from public
view.
And the chair of her department at University of Alabama Huntsville, Larry Smalley, was
so high conviction in her work that he left with her.
Before she died, Li proposed that in superconductors, materials where electrons surrender their individual
identities and merge into a collective quantum state, the gravitomagnetic effect of those electrons,
normally washed away by thermal chaos, would suddenly snap into alignment.
They'd become coherent, directional.
She was trying to build a gravity engine in a laboratory.
Let's compare that with Bob Lazar's work on UFOs in the 80s.
Years before Ning Li's work ever became public, Lazar described three cylindrical emitters at
the base of a craft.
The emitters at the base of Lazar's craft didn't produce thrust in the traditional sense.
They didn't push against air or expel mass.
They generated a directed alteration of the gravitational field itself that the craft would
then just fall into, not propulsion, geometry.
The craft didn't move through space.
It literally bent space, and space carried it.
That description, organized field-generating devices producing a directional gravitational effect
by aligning and focusing a force that normally cancels itself to zero, is structurally, almost
precisely, what Ning Li was theorizing in a laboratory thousands of miles away, using completely
different source material, arriving at exactly the same place years later.
When the craft is in operation, there is a high voltage detectable on the skin of the craft.
And then there's the hull of the craft.
Lazar said that he believed the craft's hull material was an electorate, basically a material
that permanently stores an electric field, the electrical equivalent of a permanent magnet.
I think the material the craft is made from is an electric.
And so it always, just like a magnet always has a magnetic field to it, an electric always
has an electrostatic field to it.
Interesting.
And I think that's certainly something important.
Again, bismuth titanate is one of the finest electric materials known, used in high-temperature
sensor applications precisely because of its stability.
Now, if you were designing a hull material for a craft that needed to interact with gravity
wave emitters, maintain a permanent electric field, and respond to both electric and magnetic
stimuli simultaneously, the material that checks every single box is bismuth ferrite.
That's right, again with the bismuth.
It's a material that is simultaneously ferroelectric and magnetic, where the two properties talk
to each other, where you can control one with the other.
No other readily available material sits at the intersection of diamagnetism, topological
insulator behavior, high-K dielectrics, electric properties, and multi-ferroic coupling simultaneously.
But bismuth does.
And a theoretical stable version of element 115 might do all of those things on steroids.
Bismuth sits right at the edge of where relativistic electron behavior begins to dominate everything.
By the time you get to Muscovium, you might have full-fledged space-time engineering.
And then what's really interesting is Gary Nolan has this magnesium bismuth piece in his
lab at Stanford.
You'd need some sort of motive to, you know, with, in certain cases, heavier elements, create
isotope ratios that you just don't find.
It doesn't make any sense from, like, and then it also, the thing was found alongside
of, like, an observed anomaly in the sky in a crash.
And it was, like, in the 50s or 60s, like, one of which was literally a beach in Brazil,
Ubatuba.
And the similarity between Brown and Bueller's antigravity and Lazar's sports model don't
stop there.
Brown would use DC pulsing and, like, you know, kind of high climb rates of the voltage.
So that the voltage would, there'd be a steep climb rate where it would, you know, increase
very, very sharply.
The microsizing waveguides for terahertz, you could have very high frequency, you know,
energy going into the craft.
There's something about bismuth, I think, that's.
Yes.
That, yeah, that's undiscovered.
And so much that we're unable to do because it's at the limit, you know, of our technology.
Bismuth at S4.
Bismuth in Townsend Brown's experiments.
Bismuth's properties in Ning Li's gravitomagnetic theory.
Bismuth as an ideal hull material for a UFO exactly like the one Lazar described.
Bismuth in the UFO samples that Stanford professor Gary Nolan is analyzing right now.
The preponderance of evidence now and the Department of Defense admitting that these things are
real, that the data is real, not what the, there's no conclusions.
Yeah.
The data is real.
There's so much more than there was 40 years ago.
Yeah.
I mean, all these guys are at the cunning edge.
All my information is so old and probably outdated.
So who knows how the craft operate now or what kind of craft they're using or if they're
even manned.
So.
That's true.
I think everything I know is outdated.
It's just interesting to look back at.
Hmm.
I don't take any money from this stuff.
And as far as attention, I hate fucking attention.
I don't like being on shows.
I just want to kind of hide in the corner and do my own thing.
So that's, I got enough hugs when I was a kid.
And do you, do you feel like you've, you know, on the first Rogan episode, you had migraines.
Do you feel like you've suffered, like your anxiety levels are higher than they would be?
Yeah, I've had five heart attacks since I was on the Hulk Rogan's, and my arteries are clear.
It's all stress.
I'm sorry, man.
I just had shingles all through my face.
It almost made me go blind again was from stress.
It's, yeah, it just wears you down over time.
I hope you know you're, you're loved and appreciated and, uh, you should be able to just zone out the world with where you're at in life right now and just enjoy the, the fruits of this, you know, amazing.
That would be cool.
I am so hoping to be able to retire at some point where I don't have to deal with insane customers or, yeah.
I could just sit at home and read books like this.
I think that time is very, very soon, and I think it's the best use of your brain power, too, because I want to see.
I'd actually like to get back into this stuff.
That'd be amazing.
Well, I'll send you interesting people.
Okay.
Yeah, well, I'll, yeah, I'll consume everything you can send.
I love it.
Oh, yeah.
To be careful what you wish for.
Well, Bob Luigi, this was a total honor, and you should be so proud because I know you were into this stuff.
I feel very lucky when people say, like, oh, like, you should feel vindicated.
They'll say that to me, and I'm like, what the fuck are you talking about?
I was like, I got very lucky with the timing of, like, when I got into this stuff.
But truly, I speak to you, and I'm like, oh, my God.
Like, there are people like yourself who have been into this stuff for decades in a totally thankless way.
Like, not only thankless, but.
Less than thankless.
Ostracized, exiled, laughed at constantly.
And so, to anybody out there saying, Luigi's cashing in on a, you know, movie or something like that, fuck off.
Like, you don't know what you're talking about.
It's poetic justice and karma that you made this movie, truly.
So, I want you to know that.
I appreciate that.
Yeah, man.
Did you ever think that we'd be here now?
That, like, we'd be, you know, on our podcast watching you on Joe Rogan with Bob yesterday?
Hi.
When you guys were talking, I was reading a message from my sister, Veronica, who's been...
It's hard for me to see it that way because you can't imagine everything that happened.
And for me to get it from her is, like, the biggest success because I put her in danger because of this.
And I didn't know if it was going to work.
I still don't know where it's going, but we just went for it.
And knowing that, you know, all the past, there's a lot of negative associated to it.
And I'm so proud of the team.
I'm proud of Chris Matteau.
That's, like, my right hand and all.
It wouldn't exist if it wasn't for Chris.
It wouldn't exist if it wasn't for Veronica.
It wouldn't exist if it wasn't for Emily that was at the office taking care of everything.
We all know who that is.
It wouldn't exist for Vanessa to be doing all this minutiae work online and finding all...
We wouldn't have found the Ed Teller tape if it wasn't for Vanessa.
And this was scary.
This was frightening.
This project depleted your company to zero.
To zero.
And we were attacked.
Nobody knows this, but we were attacked ferociously for over a year and a half.
Yeah.
And we're...
I know the full story, and we probably can't get too into the weeds, but I'll just say high level.
There was some really crazy, scary fuckery that occurred with you on an institutional, like, debanking level kind of thing.
Big time.
Where it's like, what sort of power do these people have as far as the antibodies, you know, going against you?
Yeah.
Unbelievable stuff.
Stuff that all the...
If you say it, it sounds so crazy that you don't want to say it because people won't...
Yeah, they're like, give me a break.
Come on.
It happened.
Have you experienced that your whole life?
Have you experienced, like, little things like that?
Yeah.
But I didn't expect this to happen to Luigi.
Not coming from those people.
Yeah.
Getting, you know, or demanding, Luigi, we want all your communications with Bob Lazar.
On a court document.
Yeah, we want, what the hell are you talking about?
Yeah.
Have you ever gotten something like, sir, we can't accept your payment here?
You're like, what?
Anything like that?
It's a little weird.
What do you mean, we can't accept your payment?
Like, something like that, you know, something like there's something going on in the background
of some routine thing you're trying to do.
Go to a bank, you go to, you know, a store or something.
Oh, and we're just, we don't want to deal with that.
We don't want to deal with you.
And you're like, why?
Yeah.
I mean, that has, that was...
A long time ago, a couple things like that happened.
Decades ago.
Do you remember?
Nothing now.
I don't remember specifically.
But people kind of messing with you.
But yeah, on an official level, they said, you know, you're radioactive.
We don't want to deal with you.
It's tough, man.
Well, you found the one, the one gig you could get, which is selling this, you know, sort
of a lot of this crazy stuff to you.
It's cool.
Well, this has been such an honor.
I really appreciate you both.
And, um...
It's always fun coming.
It's always fun, Jesse.
It's always great, man.
Okay, so there are orange-reddish UFOs that have been flying around Area 51 since the 80s
and 90s that wobble like they're on a wave at low altitudes.
The sports model UFO Bob worked on might use principles similar to documented antigravity
research, and crafts of non-human origin are being recovered at the bottom of our oceans
all over the world by the Navy.
Bob Lazar will either be forgotten entirely by history, as he predicts, or as I predict,
he'll be heralded as a canary in the coal mine, the forerunner in a stampede of revolutionary
new science.
Whether you believe or disbelieve his story, it should be treated as a puzzle, with very
real truths underlying it meant to be discovered by those who take the initiative.
So if you think there's something to any of this, don't let up.
As the first man on the moon Neil Armstrong once cryptically said,
There are great ideas undiscovered.
Breakthroughs available to those who can remove one of truth's protective layers.
Layers.
If you're still watching and you made it through all of the exotic UFO science, you're one of
the first to hear about this.
We just dropped a new limited merch collection.
Two tees, one off-white, one vintage black, plus hat.
The design has a timeless retro-future feel.
You can wear it every day.
If you've been watching the show lately, you've probably already seen me wearing it.
This is a limited run, so when it's gone, it's gone.
Head to AmericanAlchemyMerch.com to grab the Believe drop today.
And while you're there, the Cowboy UFO T is a fan favorite we always keep in stock,
along with the Atomic Age design.
Thank you all so much for following and supporting the show.
Woo!