There are places on Earth where the line between the known and the unknown wears thin.
Brazil is one of them.
It's a country of rainforest, rare minerals, and some of the strangest UFO encounters ever recorded.
Lights over the Amazon, beams from the sky.
A creature with red eyes and skin that's lethal to the touch.
There's no one better to walk us into that mystery than today's guest, Aldo Ribello.
Brazil's former minister of defense, current presidential candidate,
and a man who's spent decades at the center of Brazilian power.
A man who's probably seen firsthand into the UFO vault.
And who said, on the record, that if the United States opens its own files, he'll open Brazil's.
Claro que sí.
Today, he's also the man who'll look you dead in the eye and tell you that the phenomena is real.
The records about such unidentified celestial phenomena date back to antiquity.
They're not new.
In this unprecedented candid conversation, we cover it all.
We get into the Chupa Chupa attacks in Kolares in the 70s, where UFOs in the Amazonian night sky allegedly fired mysterious beams
that left villagers with burns, blood loss, and puncture wounds.
A multi-month event affecting 200 people.
So serious that the Air Force ran a real investigation on it called Operation Prata.
We touch on Brazil's mass UFO radar incursions of 1986, an unforgettable night for the Brazilian military.
And then there's Varginha, Brazil's very own modern-day Roswa.
What the fuck are you playing now, brother?
Rebello basically acknowledges that in 1996, in the small city of Varginha, something crashed.
It was recovered.
And a non-human creature, or multiple creatures, with slick, oily brown skin and big red eyes,
was seen by multiple witnesses.
And even treated by a neurosurgeon in a hospital.
I know that sounds like a Spielberg movie you'd want to watch.
It's actually a case that Spielberg is familiar with.
Except this isn't Hollywood.
This is the former Brazilian Minister of Defense sitting across from me, telling me it was real.
In America, our equivalent would be a former Secretary of Defense, like a Jim Mattis or a Robert Gates,
saying that Roswell was real.
Saying candidly that, yeah, a saucer probably did crash in New Mexico.
And beings probably did emerge from it.
And in doing so, he gives validation and voice to all the witnesses, researchers, doctors, military personnel,
and ordinary people who have been attacked, dismissed, and ridiculed over this subject for decades.
And he provides shelter and safe haven to those who haven't come out yet.
Believing that a phenomenon like this exists, of course.
To Ribello, the real question isn't whether the phenomenon has occurred.
It's where it came from, why it was here, and what it means for the future of science, society, defense,
and where humanity stands in the universe.
So with that, enjoy this historic conversation with Aldo Ribello,
Brazil's former Minister of Defense, current presidential candidate,
and the man who'll tell you that some of the strangest stories you've ever heard might also be the truest.
Ignition sequence 5.
How is this possible?
Nothing too unusual about that.
The existence cannot longer be denied.
When we first started selling merchandise at AmericanAlchemyMerch.com,
we had no idea how complicated and annoying selling merch could be.
Shopify made it simple to build a story that actually feels authentic to us,
which matters when you're operating in a niche like alternative tech, UFOs, fringe science, and all the other stuff we cover.
Shopify's AI tools help write descriptions, organize products, even clean up photos.
In our case, it allowed us to focus on what matters and what we care about, like design and brand vision,
and building the best custom merch line possible with the coolest clothing there is,
like our traditional Japanese Fukushima t-shirt and our cowboy UFO tee.
Sign up now for your $1 per month trial and start today at Shopify.com slash Jesse.
Again, that's Shopify.com slash Jesse, J-E-S-S-E.
$1 to try Shopify, which is the state-of-the-art solution in e-commerce today.
Thank you so much to Shopify for sponsoring today's episode.
Today's sponsor is one of my favorite products.
It's a product I genuinely love.
Cowboy colostrum, which offers the highest quality bovine colostrum available in the United States.
It's 100% made in America from 100% American grass-fed cows.
I consume it literally every day and I've been a fan since it first came out.
Unlike other colostrum brands, which cut corners, Cowboy is what they call true first day whole colostrum.
In other words, they collect it from the source.
So if you want to feel amazing, both gut and brain, heading into summer, this is one simple daily habit that can actually deliver results you can see.
For a limited time, our listeners get up to 25% off their entire order.
Just head to cowboycolostrum.com slash Jesse and use code Jesse at checkout.
That's 25% off when you use code Jesse, J-E-S-S-E at cowboycolostrum.com slash Jesse.
I'm here with Aldo Ribello, who is a former minister of the Chamber of Deputies, former minister of defense, former minister of sport, current presidential candidate for the Christian Democracy Party.
Although there's some controversies I want to talk about there, but you've had an illustrious history.
You are a cornerstone of Brazilian politics.
You are currently running against Lula and Bolsonaro, but in many ways you kind of exist at the intersection between both.
You are kind of the almost Plato's philosopher king of Brazilian politics over the last 20 or 30 years.
So I'm very excited to speak to you about your philosophy of Brazilian sovereignty.
You're a long career.
But the reason that I am here, as you know, I focus on kind of anomalous phenomena, the nature of reality, is that you tweeted something very interesting.
You said as former defense minister, I am provoked to speak on the subject.
You're talking about UFOs.
I know what the armed forces have in their archives.
What I can say is that if the US government reveals its documents, I will do the same if I am elected president of Brazil.
So I'm very excited to be here.
Thank you for having me.
It's an honor.
Thank you so much, Jesse.
And welcome.
Welcome to Brazil.
I know it's your first time here in my country.
So welcome.
I hope that your stay does justice to you, not only as a journalist, but also as a guest.
What was the first time, if you can recall, that you started to take UFOs more seriously?
Was there a moment, do you remember, when you first heard about UFOs?
Yes, in my youth, there was this huge curiosity about these phenomena, and it was a type of healthy curiosity, because the news was divided between phenomena that were observed, and there was also sci-fi literature that used this subject matter as the object of writers, journalists, and also aficionados.
So it got all of our attention, and we saw that in the movies, in literature, and yeah, it got my attention.
I've never monitored it really closely, but I've always been curious about seeing it in the news, especially with regards to phenomena that is related to national defense concerns.
In Brazil alone, there are hundreds of episodes, but three at least were closely overseen by the armed forces and the Brazilian intelligence and defense systems.
One occurred in the state of Pará, in the 70s, another one was in the 80s, in a town called São José dos Campos, and the other one was in the 90s, in the south of Minas Gerais, in the town of Varginha.
These episodes were documented, were overseen, the armed forces were interested in the subject, because there was a concern that these events could pose a risk to national defense and security.
And naturally, this, for me, someone who's always been concerned with issues pertaining to national security and national defense, as also part of Brazil's foreign policy.
This is what led me to keep up with at least these three events.
Hmm, I'm very excited to talk about all three events.
I want to start with Prado, Operation Prado in 1977, Calares.
It's a fascinating case, and it's a very dark case, because you have the people in this village, this little fishing village, were being terrorized, essentially.
They called it the Chupa Chupa, because their blood was being extracted.
The mayor was in deep fear.
You had men and women sleeping in 50 to 60, you know, in one place, just so, you know, the men could defend the women.
Because often it was younger females that were the targets of these sorts of attacks, and it felt like lasers and directed energy were being beamed at them.
So, what do you know about this, and what do you know about this specifically that the rest of the public might not know?
Well, Jesse, what all of us who keep up with this phenomena know is what has been documented, and there's a lot of it.
Because there is testimony of the military who were in charge of the operation, because they had to send a whole task force to monitor these phenomena.
And there are accounts of not only military, but also a physician, a doctor, who attended to the victims of these incursions, of these strange, unidentified beings.
At night, they would see those objects in flight, and the method never varied.
As it was flying, the object would cast down a beam of light, that light illuminated the person and paralyzed them.
From in that white light came a second beam, which was yellowish in color and roughly 30 cm in diameter, that would be pointed at the person's chest.
After that, there was another beam that was red.
This beam would make a puncture.
It extracted blood and also put something in the body of the victim, something like an implant.
There were several deaths.
So there's a suspicion that they were laser beams.
But no one really knows what kind of beam struck and affected those people.
And after being hit, these people had perforations, blood loss, they were anemic.
They also suffered other…
They felt numbness in their bodies.
A number of injuries that were identified by the physician who assisted these people.
And the officers who witnessed it and set up the whole operation in this village, in the state of Pará, documented these objects as they were approaching.
And they couldn't identify where they were.
So, that has been fully documented.
Now, part of the reports and accounts of this event and the operation,
I mean, it was a long operation, still remains classified,
kept by the armed forces.
But that which has been documented is substantial evidence of the existence of the phenomena,
of the people that were victims of the contact with these unidentified objects,
and accounts by highly credible people.
These are officers from the armed forces and the physician who tended to these patients,
who had complications and injuries that stemmed from the event that took place in the state of Pará.
And you had an official investigation that it sort of prompted.
It was, you know, Operation Prado.
And you had Captain Holanda Lima go in and investigate.
He brought a whole team.
They documented 300 plus encounters.
They took 500 photographs and they recorded 15 hours of Super 8 film footage.
And they had a whole documentation that was over 2,000 pages.
He himself actually saw an alien being that was in a space suit.
And the being sort of gave him a hug.
And he went on record about this later, about two decades later in 1997.
And then he sadly committed suicide a few months after that.
The Super 8 footage.
This is still, I believe, exists in the defense ministry.
Did you ever see it?
And do you have access to it?
Jesse, there is no question that there was an official operation executed by the Brazilian Armed Forces to monitor this phenomenon.
With the title, Operation Prado.
So, this isn't up for debate.
The operation took place.
It was an official operation led by the Armed Forces to monitor these phenomena in the state of Pará.
The second fact is the existence of the diagnosis and the testimony of the physician regarding the victims that were affected by the same phenomena.
There is no question about that either.
The only question that still remains is about a report that was not documented or disclosed.
On part of the then-captain, who later became a colonel, when he passed, he was a retired colonel.
That part of the report, which is still classified, which remains confidential,
is what we didn't have a chance to analyze or witness what it's comprised of.
So, we only have access to that which has already been disclosed.
And it's a full detailed description of the contact, the testimonials, and the testimony of the members of the armed forces that were responsible for leading the operation.
So, there's no doubt about that.
Now, you seem like a very thoughtful person who doesn't just take in evidence that's anomalous and not think about it a lot.
Do you have any leading theories about what Kolaris was?
Because it's such a bizarre fact pattern.
You had puncture wounds, blood taken.
It almost looked like ultraviolet burns on a lot of people.
You had a physician who was present, actually, Dr. Carvalho, who famously went on record seeing two women who basically had strokes, who died due to these UFO contact events.
Do you have any theories as to what caused all of this?
There's a list of injuries, and all of this is part of the diagnosis of the medical report.
It wasn't just a matter of the strokes or anemia or blood loss.
Other consequences, like numbness, and a variety of others, that resulted from the contact of these people with these unidentified objects and beings.
You see, I don't have the scientific knowledge.
I was not present during the event.
In order to develop a theory regarding the origin of whatever it was that was reported.
Not only in this event that happened in Kolaris, but the others as well, like in Varginha.
And if science itself, with all of its resources, all of its means, can't clarify, I think it would be reckless on my part in trying to develop my own theory on the origin of these phenomena.
It really wouldn't be prudent of me to even attempt to provide a diagnostic after decades of efforts from experts and scientists and people who dedicated their whole lives,
like Nick Pope himself, who went to his grave saying, well, I can't account for the 8% of the facts.
Who am I to say anything?
Fair enough.
You know, Jacques Bellet is one of the godfathers of UFO research.
He's French.
He's an astronomer.
He was actually involved in the invention of the internet.
And he came down to Kolaris to investigate.
His diaries are called Forbidden Science.
And he came to the conclusion because he spoke to Dr. Carvalho, who saw 35 patients who all had the same sunburns and puncture wounds and the two women that died of a stroke.
And he was just astonished that science can't even look at it.
It's almost too much for humans to cope with, for our kind of epistemology to kind of understand.
And so I think that's very fair to not come to a conclusion.
But I hope that we can study this in a more official capacity.
You obviously are running for president.
There are rumors about conversations between you and Bolsonaro.
I know you've had some issues with the Christian Democracy Party.
If you were in office, would you start to have that conversation in a more official capacity?
Would you try to get the best and brightest Brazilian scientists on these sorts of topics?
Yes, provided that the common denominator is the national interest.
The reserves have to protect national security.
I believe that here we have a classic liberal common notion that the state should not have secrets.
People can have their secrets. Companies can have their secrets.
But there are some people who believe that the state should never hold secrets.
I think there are secrets that are personal, secrets that relate to trade, corporative secrets, scientific secrets, technological secrets,
and secrets that are national, of the public interest, that pertain to the state.
The state, many times, is forced to adopt procedures that it can't announce publicly,
especially in the areas of defense, foreign policy, and intelligence.
This information will be revealed taking into account that there is a common agreement with other countries.
That's why I conditioned the disclosure of this information from Brazil to the disclosure of the same information from the United States.
Because a significant part of this information, and I guarantee you, is shared.
If a man who is an expert migrated from the UK to the United States to do the same job,
it's because there was some level of reciprocity, or you could even call it complicity,
between the intelligence services of both countries, with regards to sharing this information.
So, to the extent that this information may be shared and disclosed under a reciprocal agreement,
this should be done for the benefit of science, for the dissemination of knowledge,
even if it does eventually, in many cases, raise a sense of uncertainty and suspicion.
Because, of course, if you admit that there is life outside of our planet, it's not a small matter.
It isn't merely scientific, it involves morals, it involves philosophy, and religion.
Some very sensitive nerves are going to be touched upon,
that have to do with human history, human culture, and human traditions.
So, it's very important to be cautious when you touch on these very delicate, sensitive issues,
that have to do with the values of humanity, which is a must.
Brazil is very interesting to touch on what you just said,
because it sits at the intersection between traditional Catholicism,
but you have people practicing traditional Catholicism,
and also Candomblé, Umbanda, Alan Kardich is a, you know, spiritist from the 1850s,
who obviously had his whole taxonomy of, you know, non-corporeal beings,
you know, huge following in Brazil.
And so, it's an interesting place in that you have the traditional religious element,
but you also have the openness to some of these phenomena.
And so, do you think, UFOs, in your mind, do you think it's consistent with Catholicism?
How do you think people in Brazil would react?
Because, in my experience, I almost think that it feels more natural,
and it feels like they're more open to the phenomena than in places even like the U.S.
Jesse, the concern regarding this subject appears in a very indirect way.
When I was really young, there was a book that was released here.
It was super successful. Everyone read it.
Chariots of the Gods, the Portuguese title would translate to
Were the Gods Astronauts?
So, did they build the pyramids?
And that ignited a wave of curiosity.
Science fiction movies, movies about extraterrestrials,
the possibility, or not, of the existence of extraterrestrial life.
All of this raises a huge commotion, a lot of curiosity,
especially when fiction addresses these ideas.
So, it shows that people have a lot of interest and curiosity about the subject.
And maybe even beyond interest and curiosity,
it also reflects and reveals an existential concern.
In other words, what are we in the world?
Are we alone?
What if we're not alone?
How do you explain these other forms of life, these other beings?
If we, here, were created in the image and likeness of God,
if this was how man was created,
are we ready for a different circumstance, another hypothesis?
I believe that this has to be discussed with a lot of respect and a lot of caution.
It's not something that can be subject of mere speculation.
Unless we're talking about fiction, then it's absolutely fine.
Movies, literature, talking about if Gods were astronauts,
about an alien aboard a spaceship, that's fiction.
Science, however, has another level of responsibility.
It can't treat the subject that way.
There's a book by Carl Sagan,
who was probably one of the greatest scientific exponents in the United States,
called Demon Haunted World,
in which he touches upon the amount of scientific ignorance of American society,
of rulers, of statesmen.
Ronald Reagan, for example, would rely on a card reader to make his decisions.
Back then he would say that there was only one that had a background in science,
which was the Prime Minister of the UK, who had a degree in chemistry.
So he would say that the average American was so ignorant, scientifically speaking,
that they had the equivalent mentality of someone from the end of the 19th century.
So these people would look at science from a great, great distance.
Their worldview is explained by the presence of demons,
and not by the presence of science.
So that has to be taken into account.
That situation.
According to him, a survey was done with Americans,
asking them how they believed the dinosaurs had vanished.
And 90% of Americans would say,
well, it's because they couldn't fit into Noah's Ark.
And that's why they disappeared,
because they were left out of Noah's Ark.
So this issue has to be taken into account.
And it's not exclusive to the US, it's all over the world.
It's true.
And that's a great book by Carl Sagan, The Demon Haunted World.
Sagan's very interesting, though, because he also wrote the movie Contact,
and the book, Pale Blue Dot.
And in his early diaries as a child, he speculates a lot about UFOs.
He has clearly a wonder for, you know, the universe.
And he talks about, you know, platonic objects, you know,
things like higher dimensional space objects that, you know,
like a tesseract that you would only see the shadow of
if you were kind of on a lower plane.
And so, you know, I go back and forth.
I wonder what he actually believed about UFOs.
And I know Nancy Reagan and probably Ronald Reagan
had their astrologer.
But maybe sometimes, you know, mystical ways of knowing
are also, you know, valid, too.
You know, Baba Vanga would, you know, regularly advise world leaders.
I believe Bolsonaro, who you've, you know,
now have sort of a friendly relationship with,
he, I think, has an astrologer as well.
Yes, and there is a type of astrology,
which would turn to knowledge as well,
which is Egyptian astrology.
It's not the astrology that comes from horoscopes that you read in the newspaper.
That's another thing.
The astrology that was referred to in Egypt
was based on the rigorous examination of the stars.
It wasn't this mere poppycock made to sell these packages with astrology and horoscope issues
that were sold with daily papers.
There's another important book by Carl Sagan, which it's called, I'm not sure in English,
but in Brazil it's called Billions and Billions.
And he touches upon this issue with a lot of care and a lot of sensibility.
And I believe that in this way,
I believe that the care taken into how science should approach this subject
has to do with taking into account the scientific knowledge of people.
Because you shouldn't really breed desperation or create panic.
It's very easy to create panic.
You know the Orson Welles story, the radio show.
In other words, he created panic by simply telling a story that wasn't real.
It was fake news.
But since he was such a competent and efficient communicator,
as Orson Welles was known for, he whipped up a panic on a news radio show.
So I understand the caution and the prudence of science,
because it's different from a mere opinion,
from a piece of literature, a short story, a novel, a movie.
When science makes a statement about a specific subject,
there's a weight to it,
which is not the same as what fiction authors write about.
Very well said.
I want to go kind of in chronological order.
So we talked about Operation Prado, Kolaris in 1977.
In 1986, in May, you had 21 unidentified objects spotted in four different Brazilian states.
You had six fighter jets that were dispatched from bases near Brasilia and Rio.
And all of them were scrambled by these objects.
And you have the Air Force making a very fascinating official statement on the whole thing,
saying these were basically aircraft flying in ways that we technically don't understand.
They were flying, you know, at extreme speeds and maneuverability.
What do you know about that night in 1986?
Yes, and in fact, the fighters that we had at the time were state of the art.
The F-5 jets, which were American, but also the Mirage fighters that came from a base close to Brasilia,
the Annapolis Air Base, which was built very close to the capital of the country.
And those jets flew from the base in Santa Cruz, in the state of Rio de Janeiro,
and from the Annapolis Air Base in Goiás in the attempt to intercept the UFOs.
But after that, other pilots in the Air Force reported very similar phenomena.
And long after that, and in the 80s, there were many reports by pilots from the Air Force that were documented.
One of them, for example, was a pilot that was flying from Chile to Brazil, flying a fighter jet.
And he says that an object made its approach at a very high speed,
and that when he tried to approach it, the object took off, and this is documented,
at a speed of 25,000 kilometers an hour, according to what the radar picked up.
So the existence of the phenomena is undisputed.
I sat down with José Manuel Fernández, who worked for the Brazilian Air Force for 34 years,
and was an air traffic controller at Sao Paulo's Congonhas Airport on May 19, 1986.
This was the same night as the mass sighting known as Brazil's Night of UFOs.
Fernández watched in real time as fighter jets scrambled to intercept these UFOs,
only to be completely outmaneuvered and outmatched.
So I relayed the information.
I could see the fighter jet, the F-5 fighter jet.
You know, reach supersonic speed to try and reach the object.
But curiously enough, and I can assure you, that I speak the truth.
Even though the F-5 was moving at supersonic speed,
as the fighter jet was in pursuit of the object,
I could even see the tracks that were left by the fighter jet.
You know, the object was just playing hide and seek.
It would just show up and appear at a very distant point.
So when the F-5 would try to come closer,
the object would just simply disappear,
and then just reappear further down.
What's up for debate is what these phenomena are.
That's what still has to be investigated, discussed, identified.
And this could also be an effort that is more in the interest of science
than the interest of defense.
Because really, when it comes to the national defense of countries,
this was never reported as a risk or threat, right?
Or registered as such.
The information that these objects would be trying to collect or capture
really cannot be verified.
However, in terms of threats or risks or even damage for the defense of Brazil,
the United States, England, Russia,
there's no record that any of these phenomena resulted in damage for these countries.
So therefore, from the point of view of national defense,
it's a permanent reason of concern, but it's not really a risk.
So much so that the concerns in Brazil in the area of defense have subsided.
But what still remains is the question, the shadowy area,
what hasn't been brought to light in terms of science.
To this day, from a scientific point of view,
there's more dark than light when it comes to these phenomena.
You've mentioned some of these UFO cases in the context of advanced technology.
Do you think that some of what we've experienced maybe on this night, for example, in 1986,
or some of these other Brazilian encounters are not in fact, you know, other beings,
but they're our own advanced technology.
Obviously, the United States has conducted military, you know,
secret operations in Brazil since World War II.
Jesse, it's very hard to believe that the United States commands the technology to produce objects
that can move at 25,000 kilometers an hour.
The U.S. sacrificed a generation of their best pilots in trying to overtake the Russians during the space race.
When Gagarin, Yuri Gagarin, took his first orbit trip and the world was astonished,
the U.S. entered a situation of despair and panic
because they were surpassed in an event that gave the Soviet Union international projection.
Gagarin was received in New York and São Paulo as a celebrity, respected, cherished and admired around the world.
To overcome this, an American author wrote a novel about this.
They actually made a movie about it as well.
They brought together the best pilots in America to an air base.
And the majority of them died trying to do it because they didn't have the equipment.
They didn't have the material.
It couldn't resist a space flight.
And the widows learned of the deaths of their husbands, of these very young pilots because they didn't have the right material.
If the U.S. in fact had the material that would resist what was seen involving these objects,
they wouldn't have sacrificed their own pilots.
I'm not sure if it was Paul Kennedy, a writer, who described this in a very nice novel about…
No, it was the same one who wrote A Bonfire of the Vanities.
This one that wrote a book.
Tom Wolfe wrote the right stuff.
Tom Wolfe wrote the novel about the sacrifice of these young pilots for America in the space race.
So I don't think that it had anything to do with espionage on part of the U.S. or even the Russians.
They didn't have that material available with that degree of resistance that would endure that kind of speed.
It would have melted by much slower speed than that.
So that kind of explanation just isn't reasonable.
Yeah.
I mean, even in the 80s, the U.S. was just starting to build stealth craft.
But the rumor, even the rumors of the most advanced stealth craft was Mach 4, Mach 5, which is, you know, 3,000 to 4,000 miles per hour.
So 25,000 is just orders of magnitude more advanced than, you know, anything that we had.
Maybe you had some unmanned drone there, but I don't know.
I think it's very hard to believe.
So you would agree with the Air Force Minister Brigadier Octavio Julio Morea Lima's statement that these things, we detected them, they were what they were, and that the facts are what they are.
And we don't know what they are.
You would agree with that, that these are sort of genuine?
I agree.
Absolutely.
Totally.
We…
We don't know what they are, what these phenomena are.
We don't know what these objects are.
And it's so hard to identify them that science itself is unable to develop a theory on it.
They can develop a theory about what they are not.
They are not man-made.
They cannot be man-made.
Because in science, the ability to build that kind of material at that level of resistance, there's no alloy that can resist that kind of procedure of these objects and these phenomena.
No man-made object would be able to move at that speed.
I mean, look, in the 40s, in the UK, and then in the 70s, in the 80s, what kind of material would resist 25,000 km an hour? Impossible.
Not here, not in the US, not in Russia.
Okay, but who else could have done it?
Who was leading the special alloy production for rockets and spaceships were the US and Russia.
That's it.
But not at that level of sophistication, no.
Some of the patterns are just remarkable.
You see 90 degree turns, so it's breaking Newton's laws, conservation of momentum.
And Captain Viriato recorded this thing on radar, and he recorded it Mach 15, doing a zigzag pattern.
If you were elected president or vice president, would you ever sort of look into this radar data and consider exposing some of this radar data and maybe the Super 8 footage from Kolaris to the public for broader research and study?
I would rather look into all those reports, to look at all the footage and talk and consult with those who are interested in the subject matter at hand.
There is multilateral interest, we're not the only ones interested in it.
There's probably this interest in identifying that phenomenon in the States, same in Russia, maybe in China as well, Germany or the UK.
So I believe that this should be the object of a multilateral agreement among countries, with the inclusion of the two most important key elements, which are the fields of defense and of science, the world of science.
Perhaps an international conference to be responsible for that.
A consultation with experts and scientists, physicists and experts in defense, so that the world can start looking into this with more transparency, more responsibility and more scientific curiosity.
So that these phenomena are not just constrained to the world of fiction, because fiction can explore very successfully the curiosity and humankind's existential concern as well.
That's a beautiful vision and I hope that happens, because there are all these patterns that start to develop if you deeply research this stuff.
But I think a lot of the scientific community just looks away, they don't look at the patterns.
And so, I don't know, one example is that, you know, the Amazon River Basin is 7,000 or I think it's 7 million square kilometers.
And you have obviously outlets, rivers all over Brazil, and water is a very important part of the UFO phenomena.
They often seem to go submerge into water, come out of water.
They're indigenous myths going back, you know, centuries about, you know, water people and that sort of thing.
So, it would be very interesting to develop an international coalition and have our best and brightest scientists from all different countries really in an unbiased way investigating this.
Well, that's probably because when it comes to unknown phenomena in space, there really is no visible financial interest.
Einstein got to the theory of relativity because there was a search by mankind to turn matter into energy.
So, you had capitalism and expansion, the system needed energy, which was scarce, but it was the main input for the development of capitalism.
And scientists from all over the world were looking for a way to turn matter into energy.
And the theory of relativity, Einstein's equation, which is comprised of energy equals mass times the speed of light squared,
is basically to turn a small particle of matter into a large amount of energy.
That is what led to the theory of relativity.
It has nothing to do with the need of understanding and identifying these phenomena.
There is no clear financial interest in that.
If there were, perhaps the world would have mobilized academia, scientists.
The United States spends over half of their budgets on military research.
But this was never the focus of this investigation.
So, I think that once that comes up as a possibility, maybe then science will actually be interested.
Because now it's more of an existential issue, a curiosity.
And unfortunately, science is funded, but it's not funded by curiosity.
It's got much more practical objectives and much more material drivers than scientific curiosity.
However, governments can mobilize part of their science towards multilateral initiatives to first gather information.
And once information has been compiled, to work out what's common and how to move forward.
Perhaps nothing can be solved in a first conference on that topic.
But you could establish a process to shine a light on a matter that, to this day, there's only been shadows.
Yeah, well said.
And I think as much as studying UFOs or exotic propulsion or some of these, you know, free energy, it seems sort of useless.
I think in many ways, you know, even if you look at semiconductors, it came from a bunch of people who were considered crazy in Copenhagen thinking about the nature of reality.
And before that, they said electromagnetism was the last act.
There'd be nothing, you know, after that.
And then you get the quantum revolution.
And even with electromagnetism, Marconi, you know, was told that he was, you know, not a very good student and that he was crazy, that, you know, you'd never be able to send electromagnetic waves as far as he did.
And so I think there's a lot of value actually in government spending on science that seems useless because that ends up being the most useful.
It's the science that is the most existential, deals with the contemplation of reality itself.
Exactly, because science comes from experimentation.
The steam engine has been around for 2,000 years.
Someone from Egypt, from Alexandria, realized that when he heated up water, steam created mechanical energy.
But that remained as it was for 2,000 years until someone in the UK said,
actually that mechanical force discovered by Heron from Alexandria could actually move a steam loom.
And then Heron from Alexandria's steam engine became what drove the industrial revolution in England.
And then the military revolution.
Because then the UK created the steam engine and the British Navy ruled over China and then over the world.
So this transition from experimental research and knowledge to technological knowledge and economic activity is a natural step.
And humankind is familiar with it.
Most probably Einstein wasn't thinking about the atom bomb when he thought about turning matter into energy.
But what happened was, just like the steam engine was turned into the steam gunboat,
you see, matter, uranium, was transformed into the atom bomb, which was dropped on Hiroshima and Nagasaki.
But that's how science works, for better or worse.
Hmm.
There's a small town in southern Brazil called Varginia.
It has 130,000 people.
And in January of 1996, something absolutely remarkable happens there.
My friend is a documentarian.
His name is James Fox.
And he made a movie called Moment of Contact.
and he's spoken to maybe 15 to 20 people
between people who have seen beings
and people who have seen the craft.
He's triangulated the flight path
and basically this cigar-shaped Tic Tac craft
seemed to have some sort of puncture in it.
Gas was coming out of the back.
It crashed on something called the Maolini Farm.
An ultralight pilot named Carlos DeSouza,
who was also a geography teacher,
held pieces of the craft in his hands
It seemed to have bounced
the rear end of the craft,
which was completely destroyed.
There were pieces everywhere
and the front of it,
which was practically half of it,
slid further and ran into a tree.
That's literally what it did.
It ran into a tree,
hit the tree and stopped.
Thinking he's looking at a blimp
or some kind of experimental aircraft,
Carlos' first thought is that there were people inside.
So he rushed to the crash site to help.
And that's where he realized this wasn't a normal crash.
The very first thing that I observed
and that really caught my attention
was the smell.
Because at that moment,
what I was expecting was the smell of diesel fuel
or kerosene or aircraft fuel.
It's normally a very strong smell.
And on the contrary,
the smell that I felt at the crash site
felt like ammonia.
It was very strong.
I don't know what was the fuel
or the substance that was there,
but it was a very strong smell,
something different.
And it began to burn my eyes.
A military convoy then pulled up
and soldiers started to secure the area.
Before they reached him,
something on the ground caught his eye,
shiny pieces of metal from the wreckage.
He picked it up.
When he tried to crumple it,
the material went back to its original shape.
And a soldier,
huge,
really strong,
probably two meters tall,
came running, shouting,
get out of here,
get out of here.
And just at that time,
I could see quite a few pieces of debris
on the ground,
and I picked them up.
And it was kind of curved.
And then I was surprised
to see how light it was.
You know,
aluminum foil
that you use
to wrap up chicken
to roast
that you use normally in the kitchen?
It was that kind of weight.
It didn't weigh anything at all.
And I thought,
well,
this is strange.
All right.
So I said,
I'll keep it.
And so I crunched it up.
And so I made this kind of movement,
you know,
to put it in my pocket.
And what happened
was this foil or this sheet
regained its shape.
Sounds a lot like the Roswell crash material.
Foil-like,
weightless,
and impossible to deform.
Carlos wanted to keep it,
but things took a turn
when he was ordered to leave
at gunpoint.
And then
that soldier
arrived,
took his rifle
and started hitting me
on the chest
and saying,
get out of here.
And I started to question him,
saying, no.
There are people there
who are going to need help.
I'm going to help them.
I'm a pilot, man.
I know what they're going through.
He took a step back,
raised his gun,
cocked it,
and pointed it
at my head.
Pointing at my head
right here
and said to me,
I'm not asking.
I'm giving you an order.
If you don't leave,
I'm going to blow your brains out.
And
he was later
apprehended
by some men
in dark suits.
The beings then ran off.
Three women
who seemed
very honest
to me
saw the beings.
It was a red,
you know,
red eyes,
brown
with skin color.
And
it seems like
one of the beings
was also apprehended
by the military.
by
a guy named
Marcos
Cheresi
who was a soldier
and
that he died
due to a puncture wound
from the being.
And
even
Armando
Fortunato
who did the autopsy
basically
saw it was a
bacterial
that he had never
seen before.
and
then all of these
people at the hospital
mentioned treating
an ET being.
There's a neurosurgeon
Italo Venturelli
who manages
the whole chain
of three hospitals
but
regionalis
where they held
this being.
He was there
and he was checking
the work of a guy
who stitched up
and actually worked on
did some
basic,
you know,
operating procedure
on this being.
So you get
thing after thing
after thing
this whole chain
of custody
of this being
different witnesses.
To me,
it's the most
interesting UFO case
globally
as far as
documentation
because it's from
the 90s
and a lot of
these people
are still alive.
What do you think
about this case?
You know that
that event
created a celebrity
in Brazil.
Its name is
the Varginha ET.
Nobody saw
the Varginha ET
but everyone
knows about
the ET.
By the way,
this phenomenon
the Varginha ET
became a
national phenomenon.
In fact,
sometimes
people will
kind of
poke fun at it
they'll joke
around about
when someone
becomes a celebrity
or famous
they say
that they're
more famous
than the Varginha ET.
Now,
even if the ET
itself
remains,
shall we say,
unseen,
the phenomenon
was documented
and also
documented
both
by the military
and in the
field of health,
the medical field,
the testimonials,
if not all of them,
but most of them,
are publicly
well-known,
disclosed.
We're talking
about testimony
from doctors
like Dr.
Italo Venturelli,
a chief neurosurgeon
from Hospital
Regional.
By his own account,
he showed up to work
like it was
any other day.
His colleague,
another neurosurgeon
named Dr.
Marcos Venesis,
pulled him aside.
At first,
he showed Venturelli
a tape,
grainy footage
of what looked like
a small child
with a deformity
getting patched up
after a procedure.
But then,
Marcos Venesis
insisted that Italo
see his patient
in person.
He brings Italo
into the room,
where he came
face-to-face
with the being
for four entire minutes.
He was just lying there
with a surgical drape.
One hand in
and the other out
like this.
Nothing here
and it's peaceful.
The bed positioned upright
like we do
for neurological patients.
Eventually,
the reality sunk in
that this patient
wasn't human.
He had arms.
He had a chest.
Hal's wife
asked if he had nipples.
I didn't see nipples.
I didn't see a nipple
lying there like that.
Neck.
Very small mouth.
The eyes.
Like this,
as if they were drops.
Like that.
Lilac.
And very peaceful.
There was no suffering there.
No suffering at all.
There was no bad smell.
No odor.
No nervousness.
Nothing diabolical.
A very angelic
kind of being.
Totally at peace.
It's hard to overstate
how bizarre
this must have been.
A neurosurgeon
walking into
what should be
an average day at work
only to find
what looks like
an alien creature
lying in a hospital bed.
It's not bleeding.
It's not in pain.
It's breathing normally.
No problem.
Everything's fine.
The being looked at me.
As I always say,
it looked at me
with a very beautiful look.
Not a judgmental look.
Not a look of fear.
It had the look of someone
who understands very well
what is going on.
But it was a different person.
A different being.
It wasn't human at all.
It wasn't
a case of human anomalies.
It was a different being.
I've been dealing with humans
for 46 years.
But back then,
about 30 years ago,
we knew how to tell
when it was
or wasn't a human.
What's intriguing
is that
they didn't lead
to the initiative,
for example,
of submitting
those who witnessed
the events,
both in the medical
and military fields,
to be questioned,
to help
shine a light
on that event
and
maybe lead
to potential hypotheses
about
what was seen,
about what was
witnessed,
what it meant
and
the possible origins.
No,
they hid it under a rock,
so to speak.
The problem was treated
with a lot of
secrecy
and they didn't
move forward with it.
The possibility
to clarify what happened
never took place,
except for
the city of Varginha itself,
which turned into
a sort of reference,
touristically speaking.
The town hall
created a museum
to acknowledge
and value
the phenomenon,
to document it
and to give it
a sense of permanence,
to take it away
from the world
of fantasy
and turn it
into something,
a phenomenon
that was part
of the town's history,
the region's history,
here in the south
of Minas Gerais.
By the way,
the town
is next door
to international
soccer superstar
Pelé's hometown.
It's close to
Tres Corazones
where Pelé
has a property.
I've had the opportunity
to go to Varginha
and Tres Corazones
and in Varginha
the phenomenon
is undisputed.
There's no doubt
about whether
it happened or not.
Now,
officially,
for example,
health authorities,
the Medical Federal Council,
because there were
physicians involved,
they'd never get involved
in the records
or in the
investigation
of the event.
And the armed forces
were even more
prudent,
especially when it came
to reasons
that involve
issues that have
to do with
national security.
Not just defense,
but national security,
which is broader.
Yeah,
I mean,
you had
a base there,
ISA,
and it seemed like
they were all
kind of mobilized
immediately when
this crash occurred.
There was actually
an air traffic controller
that also claimed
that he said
YUSAF,
and he says
the U.S. Air Force
was involved.
And then there's
even a pilot
in the United States
that just testified
before Congress.
I'm sure you're aware
that a lot of the
witnesses came to the U.S.
They actually came
on my show,
and they also went
to Washington, D.C.,
and they spoke
with a bunch
of Congress people.
And you have
a U.S. pilot
now saying
on record
that basically
there were missions
that were now
scrubbed
from the record
going on
between, you know,
CIA, Air Force,
and Virginia
around that time
in 1996.
My name is
Fred Klaassen.
I'm a retired
U.S. Air Force
bird colonel
and fighter pilot.
In order
to secure
a cargo plane,
a specific
protocol
must be
adhered to.
The tasking
would be sent
back to
Air Mobility
Command
at Scott
Air Force Base,
Illinois,
who has
command authority
over all
U.S. Air Force
cargo aircraft
and refueling
tankers.
The paper trail
has begun.
So do you think
that the U.S.
is involved
in a lot
of these
sort of UFO events
and crashes
in Brazil?
The United States
are involved
in everything
all over the world.
The question
should be
what isn't
the U.S.
involved in?
It's obvious
that events
of that nature
would immediately
pique the interest
of the United States.
Because
let's just work
on the basis
of the hypothesis
that an unidentified
object
was
in the reach
of
a government.
That unidentified
object
would raise interest
across
many different ways.
Because first,
the object,
what was it built
from,
what kind of material?
You see,
what was the technology
that allowed
that object
to move
at such a speed?
What were the alloys
that were used
to build that material?
What were the
communication instruments?
Or,
what was the fuel
that was used
in order
to make
that object
move?
All of that
involves the interests
of defense,
of science,
and obviously,
the U.S.
would definitely
be concerned
that such an object
didn't fall
in the wrong hands.
So either
we managed
to
find the object
or the Russians
will,
the Soviets
will.
So,
it's a matter
of national security,
of national defense,
and also
of science.
Because
you could reveal
a whole world
of perspectives,
of possibilities,
in
high resistance
alloys
just based
on one
of such objects.
I'm not saying
that this is
what happened.
I'm just saying
that there would
be a natural interest.
That interest
wouldn't stop
at metal.
If you're truly
trying to understand
the craft's technology,
you're also going
to be interested
in the craft's occupants.
And in Brazil,
there's a whole
parallel story
about that,
with rumors
that the
Varginha creature
was eventually
transferred
to U.S.
custody.
The story
was he was
taken,
carried to Campinas,
to a very famous
pathologist,
a friend of
Dr. Armandus,
Palhares,
and that they
then took it
to Area 51.
I don't know.
That's what
they say, right?
There's a unit,
an army battalion,
in the town
of Três Corações,
because the army
there holds
the oldest school
in Brazil
for the formation
of sergeants.
There's another
sergeant school
for the Air Force,
but that one's
in Guaratinguetá
in the state
of São Paulo.
So,
in this
base,
this army base,
there is
a battalion,
which has
its hierarchy,
they can mobilize,
and it's very
close to Varginha,
maybe 30 kilometers
away.
So,
obviously,
the unit,
or at least
part of that unit,
went to provide
support to
an operation
that involved
the presence
and the existence
of these phenomena.
So,
I've no doubt
that there's
an interest
from the U.S.
But,
whether that
did take place
and how,
that is still
shrouded
in some mystery.
And there is
indeed
close contact
between the two
defense departments,
especially
when that
phenomenon took
place.
I mean,
both Brazil's
defense department
and that
of the U.S.,
I have no doubt
about that,
because we have
a history
of cooperation
when it comes
to defense
that dates back
to the Second
World War.
There is
a previous history
with Germany,
with France,
but as of
the Second
World War,
our biggest
cooperation
in the military
and defense
came to be
with the United
States,
because
in Italy,
there was
a Brazilian
army division
that
fought
alongside
the American
soldiers
in Italy
against
the German
forces.
You were
a defense
minister
under Dilma
Rousseff
in 2015-2016.
Did you
look into
UFOs in
that official
capacity at
all?
No.
We had
other concerns.
Inside
of the
Ministry of
Defense,
we have a
classified area
that is only
shared by the
minister or
some experts,
but it's
more geared
toward the
area of
intelligence,
because we
have military
intelligence,
which pertains
to the
high command
of the
army,
which has
an extensive
history.
We have
naval
intelligence
as well.
I believe
it works
similarly in
the U.S.
And we
have air
force
intelligence
also.
And we
concentrate
information in
the intelligence
department of
the Ministry
of Defense.
And as
with any
other
institution,
we have
classified
data and
information
that
cannot
be made
available.
There is
the concern
regarding
cybernetic
threats
because
there is
the possibility
of attacks
on the
institutions
by hackers,
by people
who want
to eavesdrop
and collect
information
or simply
eavesdrop,
snoop,
and release
sensitive
information.
So, this
is probably
the area
where the
classified
information
is concentrated.
And in
air force
command,
which is the
institution
that kept
a closer
eye and
received reports
with more
frequency
because they
were conveyed
both from
military pilots
and also
civil aviation
pilots that
many times
made the
reports to
control towers
that are also
supervised and
controlled by
the air force
command.
So, the
information,
therefore,
is concentrated
in this area.
same goes
for the
army,
because they
also participated
in some
of these
operations.
So, the
reports come
from army
officers.
However,
the discussion
in society
with regard
to this
agenda
has decreased
in importance
in recent years.
I'm not sure
if it's only
in Brazil,
but at least
in Brazil.
We see
that the
discussion
and the
information
regarding
these
phenomena
has migrated
to the
civil sphere
much more
rather than
remaining only
in the
military sphere.
You said
that fundamentally
you do think
something happened
in Virginia
in 1996.
When you
hear the
testimony of
Italo Ventarelli,
he's this
neurosurgeon,
he manages
a few
hospitals,
seems like
a very
competent guy
who's never
made a penny
off of his
testimony,
and he says
he sat
face-to-face
with what
he describes
as an
extraterrestrial
being for
four minutes.
Do you
believe him?
Of course
I believe him.
Why wouldn't
I?
Believing
that a
phenomenon
like this
exists?
Of course.
Because
these were
phenomena
that
had
the testimony
of totally
credible
witnesses.
three
girls
had no
reason
to
make up
a vision
or invent
a creature
just to
testify about
it.
They couldn't
and they had
no reason
to make it up
between themselves
that they
saw a
different
phenomenon
or creature
that hadn't
made any
appearances
previously
or had been
witnessed.
Same goes
for the
doctor
and the
military
officers.
They had
no reason
to make
it up.
One of
them is
Dr. Armando
Fortunato.
He's the
forensic
pathologist
who performed
an autopsy
on the
soldier
Marco
Charisi.
Marco,
who is
patrolling
Virginia
for the
being
while driving
his vehicle,
sees the
being out
of the
corner of
his eye.
He tells
his fellow
soldier to
stop the
car.
He jumps
out and
he grabs
the being
in order
to apprehend
it and
take it
to the
hospital.
The
infection
he had
is
extremely
rare,
not
impossible,
but its
virulence
and severity
caught
Dr.
Janini's
attention.
A
scratch
or
some
sort
of
contact
with
an
extraterrestrial
shouldn't
be ruled
out.
That
infection
quickly
turned
lethal.
After his
death,
his case
landed on
the desk
of Dr.
Fortunato,
and the
samples went
to one of
Brazil's
most respected
pathologists,
Dr.
João
Jemini,
owner of
IPD
Laboratory
in
Virginia.
What they
found lying
in Marco's
body in
that autopsy
was so
disturbing
that both
men are
still talking
about it
decades later.
said recently,
last year,
that the
bacteria found
in the
material
examined in
the
laboratory
is not
common
in our
country
and that
the bacteria
was extremely
virulent
and which
are very
progressive,
deviating
from the
norm of
everyday
practice
in Brazilian
medicine
and that
he did
not rule
out,
given the
circumstances
that had
come to
him,
that the
bacterium
could be
an alien
bacterium.
According to
Dr. Armando,
Marco's
sister said
that Marco
had come
into contact
with the
Varginia
creature.
And later,
Dr.
Jemini told
filmmaker and
friend of
mine,
James Fox,
that he
thought the
bacteria had
strange
evolutionary
characteristics.
I think it
was like the
term we used
was the
never seen
an advanced
bacteria of
this strain
behave the
way it did
ever before
or since.
And even
Cesario,
who was
working on
him,
it's like I
threw the
kitchen sink
that should
have,
all the
antibiotics
I gave
him should
have saved
his life,
but it
didn't do
anything.
Because I've
never seen
anything like
it before
since either.
So it
was an
adaptation or
an evolution
of a
particular
bacteria on
earth,
but that
they haven't
seen on
earth,
that type
of
evolutions.
It's the
best way he
described it to
me,
as a
neophyte.
So we're
not talking
about an
unknown life
form,
but a
native
strain,
acting in
a completely
unfamiliar,
unprecedented,
almost
upgraded way.
We have
pretty good
testimony from
a number of
witnesses on
the Brazilian
side that the
entities, the
ET, went
back to
America, but
we don't
know what
happened to
the craft
itself, as
here, any
rulers of
where the
craft went.
The
information
that's held
by the
Ministry of
Defense
is strictly
classified.
Therefore,
it cannot be
disclosed or
released under
any
circumstances,
unless there
is an
international
agreement.
I said
that if
the United
States
discloses
its
information,
then we
also have
the right
to do
so, but
that, of
course, remains
purely
hypothetical.
So if
the
Bar-Hein
incident
didn't
happen, then
it wouldn't
be classified.
So that
tells me...
Oh, James,
he already
said on
record, I
know it
happened, we
just need to
interpret what
happened.
The problem
is not the
existence or
not of the
phenomena.
The issue
is explaining,
identifying precisely
what happened.
That's the
object that poses
itself naturally
as a challenge.
The phenomenon
existed, it
was there.
The objects
were there, the
creature was
seen.
But what
was it?
And where
did it come
from?
And why
were they
there?
What did
they want
from us?
I believe
that this
is what
really is
of scientific
interest, so
that we can
begin to
theorize about
it.
I know
you're speaking
very casually
about the
phenomena being
real, and
then the fact
that we don't
know exactly
what it is.
I just want
you to realize
how historically
unprecedented and
amazing, in my
opinion, it is
that somebody of
your caliber is
saying that.
because really
until this
year, politicians
all over the
world at
civilian agencies
like NASA or
intelligence agencies
like the CIA or
even elected
officials were
professionally
gaslighting and
telling basically
the public that
this stuff is all
fake.
And so I think
it's amazing to
have a former
defense minister,
current presidential
candidate, who is
kind of the
ideological
backbone of a
lot of modern
Brazilian politics
say in such a
kind of passe way
that, of course,
UFOs are real.
Look, I believe
that it would be
the first time in
history that
nation states
would start
becoming interested
in a non-existent
event, you know,
in something that
is impossible.
Why did the
British Prime
Minister organize
a committee
inside the
Royal Air
Force, inside
the RAF, to
study these
phenomena?
Why was there
in the United
States such
dedication to
the investigation
of these
phenomena?
Why is it
that in
Brazil the
Army and
the Air
Force created
a unit to
monitor these
phenomena?
why have
pilots of
jet fighters
formally educated
and trained
to deal
with all
types of
airspace
phenomena
reported
on more
than one
occasion,
these phenomena
in detail?
Would they
simply make up
that they had
an encounter
with an object
that moved
at 25,000
kilometers an
hour?
Why would
they?
Frankly,
if they
didn't make
it up,
if the
physicians
in the
state of
Pará
or the
doctors
in the
town of
Varginha
documented
with their
professional
credentials,
with their
professional
responsibilities,
these phenomena,
the people
that were
impacted by
them,
why wouldn't
you lend
these people
credibility?
Now,
this is but
just a part
of the issue.
See?
The testimonial,
the witness,
and the existence
of the phenomena.
The other part,
the other issue,
is identifying
the meaning
behind them.
This means
that the
inexistence
of the phenomena
can't be the
answer
to ignoring
the science.
Because
this takes us
back
to a period,
to the times
of old,
when humans
didn't believe
that in fact
it was the
Earth
that revolved
around the
Sun.
People didn't believe
because they
didn't know
it yet.
Many times
the consequence
of ignorance
is the denial
of that which
you don't know.
So,
I merely attribute
the denial
of these phenomena
to the
inability
to
explain
what they mean
and what they
represent.
But all
the testimonials
cannot be
challenged.
And people
with authority
in life
to
provide
testimony
as we have
around the
world.
Well,
I think
millions of
Brazilians,
you know,
after,
hopefully this
makes national
headlines,
will feel heard
and will feel
seen by their
leaders around
this topic.
Because I think
a lot of people
have seen things
in the sky.
And in
1954,
actually,
in the
Escola Superior
de Guerra,
you know,
basically the
National War
College here,
there was an
Air Force
captain,
Olivera,
and he said
this phenomena
is real.
And,
you know,
he was very
passionate about
that.
In the U.S.,
we have very
many equivalents
too.
So I think
a lot of
people who've,
you know,
we have a
great researcher
here,
Pacacini,
who was very
deep on the
Varginia case,
he's filming.
And,
you know,
a lot of these
guys have felt
very,
probably
unrepresented
by their
leaders.
And so I
think they'll
be very,
just feel very
emotional and
excited that
somebody of
your stature is
sort of giving
them that
validation.
I wasn't
approached.
They tried to
kill me.
Really?
Yes,
I was coming.
One of those.
What did they
try to do?
What they did,
they shot me.
Shot my car.
This is
researcher
Vittorio Pacacini.
For others,
it might be easy
to casually
dismiss UFOs
as a modern
PSYOP.
But he remembers
when investigating
a crash like
Varginia
could get you
killed.
One of those
days,
because I used
to go back
and forth,
Tres Corações
City,
Varginia City.
Mama was
living there.
Used to stay
with my mama.
So you were
well known as
being the
primary investigator
of this,
going back and
forth.
Yes,
everybody.
I was there.
I went to the,
I called the
media to give
the names who
were involved,
the militaries.
I gave all the
names, the
operations.
I was the one.
There are videos
all over the
country, all over
the world right
now about it.
So everybody
knew me and
the secret
service, the
intelligence
service probably
was paying
attention in all
of us.
One of those
nights, I was
coming back
from Varginia
to Tres
Corações to
have dinner,
my mama,
relax, have a
good night of
sleep.
In the middle
of the way,
a car behind
me, I
don't speed
up, okay?
I'm nice and
easy, listening
to some
Bocelli,
okay?
Laura Pausini,
nice music.
And then,
the car didn't
pass me.
I felt that
a little
strange.
Kept going.
All of a
sudden,
hit my bumper,
okay?
My back
bumper.
Twice.
Okay, for
the noise, I
knew it was a
shot.
I stepped on
the accelerator
to give me
distance,
okay?
I got some
distance from
this car.
I took
distance so I
could stop
the car and
abandon the
car.
Otherwise, I
would be a
rabbit running
from the
fox until a
point that the
fox would
grab me.
And I had a
friend at that
time with me
all the time.
It was my
357 Magnum,
okay?
Nobody knew,
but I was at
that time.
the director
of the
Minas Gerais
Shooting
Federation.
I had a
lot of
training with
my 357
Magnum.
So they
were fucking
with the
wrong guy?
Well,
probably.
So I
stopped the
car, got
some distance,
I abandoned
the car and
went behind
the trees,
hoping that
they would
quit that
operation.
It didn't
work very
well.
I escaped.
but the
car came,
a black
car.
But since
the headlights
were on,
I could see
somebody with
an arm and
a gun
outside the
window and
he shot
twice again.
He missed
my car.
I wasn't in the
car, but he
missed because
the first two
shots hit my
bumper, my
back bumper.
But the
other two
shots they
missed, I
didn't.
Because when
they passed, I
was behind a
tree right next
to my car.
When they
passed, and
they missed the
car, they
passed.
I fully
discharged six
times.
And I also
heard, I
broke the
windows and I
hit the
metal.
Okay, I
had a speed
loader.
I emptied the
gun, get a
speed loader once
again and six
more.
If you ask me if
I killed somebody,
I don't know.
Because I didn't
go there to
check it out.
because I was
afraid they
were waiting
for me.
So, immediately
I got back to
my car and
went back to
Virginia to
find a public
phone and
say, Mama,
they tried
again.
Don't worry, I'm
still here.
I'll wait for
the sunrise and
I'll be back in
Três Corações.
Don't worry.
The thing is,
when it comes to
politics,
especially when
the person
holds office
in the
executive branch,
they're driven
by immediate
events.
You have to
deal with
practical problems,
you have to
solve practical
demands,
and that which
demands no
solution,
because the
solution doesn't
involve a
material economic
interest,
it's always
sidelined or
postponed.
This means you
have to
entrust
the investigation,
the debate
of these issues
to the people
who understand
that there is
an importance
that goes beyond
the material,
the importance of
science,
the importance
of shedding light
on that which
for humanity
can expand
horizons that
are still unknown
to them,
or that they
still don't master.
And especially
the world of
politics,
and even the
military,
are driven
by very
immediate
interests.
Someone
holds office
and they
remain there
for two
years,
right?
And two
years is
just enough
time to
pay some
bills,
to manage
units,
solve problems
that pertain to
human resources
that they'll
eventually have
under their
command.
there's just
not enough
time to
deal with
goals
and interests
that aren't
under their
direct
responsibility
and other
the attainment
of the
solution
that is
possible to
be provided
by him.
So this
issue of
investigating
UFOs,
objects,
unidentified
objects that
appear here
and there
is far
removed
from the
demands
of the
authorities
that tend
to
administrative
issues
and
defense
in
governments.
Well,
you're right,
most political
leaders aren't
particularly
academic
or erudite.
In the
U.S.,
you had
Woodrow
Wilson,
you know,
in the early
20th century
who was
president of
Princeton,
but since
then it's
been very
few and
far between
as far
as,
you know,
people who
are really
well-read
and polymathic
and kind
of renaissance
type people,
it seems
like you
are.
I know
from your
son Pedro
that you
have a
library of
over 6,000
books,
many of which
you've read
personally,
you've taken
notes on.
He said
that he was
writing his
thesis and
he was using
your books to
research the
thesis and
that you had
sort of notes
all throughout
the books.
And so I
think that
allows you to
think more
broadly about
some of
these nature
of reality
questions than
people who
are just
trying to
execute on
functional tasks
ahead of
them.
And it's
in the
vein of
Plato who
said that
the king,
or not
calling you a
king, but
people who
are leaders
should be
also philosophers
and they
should be
sort of the
most learned.
And I feel
like in
modern politics
that's kind
of been
divorced.
thought received
its best
contributions
from those
who dedicated
themselves to
abstract thought.
Greek
philosophers
have lasted
so long
because they
thought well
beyond their
everyday needs,
well beyond
their immediate
concerns.
Plato,
Aristotle,
even Arab
philosophers,
Jewish
the Romans,
they were
philosophers
of abstraction,
in other
words,
of general
ideas.
From
general ideas
they attempted
to explain
everyday
phenomena.
But
modern politics
has lost
that ability.
It's all
about the
immediate
power struggle.
the abstract
plane
has
all but
been
dismissed.
It's all
about conquering
immediate
power,
remaining
in power,
working
to maintain
power.
And anything
that's not
part of that
is either
dismissed
or neglected,
belittled.
And it's
not exclusive
to Brazil.
The same
thing happens
in the US
with a few
exceptions.
But the
democratic world
lives off
of managing
its deficiencies,
its crises,
the contestation
and protests
of politics,
the loss
of quality
among public
people.
It's lost
its ability
to select
in the U.S.
which is
the role
model of
democracy
that the
world looks
up to
with more
interest.
There used
to be
elections,
but there
used to
also be
selection
parties
used to
select
their
candidates.
There was
a time
the man
who conquered
the North
Pole,
Lindenburg,
he used
to be a
celebrity,
a well-known
person.
Had he
been a
candidate,
he would
have had
80-90%
of votes.
But he
made a
very
interesting
remark
to Nazi
Germany.
And the
leaders
of the
Republican
Party
said,
no,
this could
lead to
conflict
with
Germany
tomorrow.
Our
President
cannot
state
such
views.
So
he
was
sidelined
in
the
convention
of
the
Republican
Party.
Specifically
because
there
was,
in addition
to the
elections,
something
previous,
which was
the
selection.
Politicians
weren't just
elected,
they were
selected also.
There was
a sort
of
committee,
a senior
group of
people,
more seasoned,
who functioned
as a sort
of filter.
And
contemporary
politics
has lost
the ability
to filter.
Democracy
has become
something
very contradictory
because
an increasingly
more open
democracy
is a
possibility.
But
the quality
of public
people,
unfortunately,
has collapsed,
especially
from that
point of view
of knowledge,
the ability
to perceive
the world,
to consult
science,
to support
public
planning
and public
policies.
That's what's
happening all
over the
world.
Yes.
There's a
great book
called The
Fall of
Public
Man,
and it
talks about
how public
life has
become a
panopticon
prison.
And there
used to be
a phrase
called,
you know,
private vice
public virtue,
where a lot
of people
who we
consider
great
leaders,
you know,
didn't have
the most
perfect
backgrounds,
but they
were the
man for
their time,
you know?
And I
think now
today,
you almost
have this
two-pronged
thing where
you have to
have a
perfect
personal
record,
and so
nobody would
ever want
to go
into politics
because you
have to be
this sort
of,
you know,
jump through
every hoop,
start the
perfect
foundation here
and virtue
signal
constantly.
Or on the
other side,
you have
reality TV
stars and
social media
people because
they've sort
of grown up
in that and
they don't
even care.
And so
you end up
with a
completely
intellectually
vapid
landscape.
And it
sounds like
you sort
of resonate
with that,
but it's
definitely
the case
in the
U.S.
And so
it seems
like you
are,
you know,
an anachronism
in many ways.
You're a
rarity in
today's
political
world.
Yes,
that's true.
the same
thing
happens
here because
you have
in politics,
there are
celebrities
in politics,
communicators,
the TikTok
phenomenon.
These are
people with
a lot
of
engagement
from an
electorate
that isn't
very well
read,
lacks
education
and guide
their decisions
based on
social media.
It's based
immediately on
emotions,
it's not
based on
information.
The ability
to move
people
is what
drives
the vote
and therefore
politics.
And what
starts to
happen
in the
political
world
is this
deficiency
on part
of the
candidates
and what
also begins
to occur
is a
phenomenon
that was
called
by an
American
theologian
the
corruption
of
virtue.
What's the
corruption
of
virtue?
The
corruption
of
virtue
is the
use
of
virtuous
causes
for
very
non-virtuous
objectives.
So when
you want
to
take
oil
from a
different
country,
you don't
say you
want
oil,
you say
you
want
democracy.
So you
bring down
a
government
and you
say that
it was
for
democracy.
Democracy
is a
virtuous
cause,
so people
support
it.
But what
you actually
want
is
oil.
And
when
you
come
to
the
Amazon
and you
say that
you're
going
to
defend
the
environment
people
support
that
because
the
environment
is a
virtuous
cause,
an
important
one,
a
humanitarian
cause.
But it's
not
really
about
the
environment.
What's
at stake
is a
different
interest,
maybe
mineral
resources,
water,
biodiversity,
sources
of
energy,
whatever
is in
the
Amazon
that
is
of
interest
to
those
people.
So
they
resort
to
the
environmental
cause
because
it's
a
virtuous
agenda.
So the
corruption
of
virtue
is
very
present
today
in
politics,
geopolitics,
in
diplomacy,
and all
international
relations
and
politics
across
countries.
Yeah,
absolutely.
It's
very hard
to
criticize
an
NGO,
a
nonprofit,
some
sort of
international
organization
that seems
like it's
here to
help,
when in
fact,
those can
be used
in
predatory
ways to
gain
leverage
and to
deplete
resources
and to
do all
sorts
of
things.
I
mean,
one
kind of
interesting
phenomena
that
actually
occurred
today
was just
announced
that
the
Vatican
is
working
with
Anthropic,
which is
this
AI company
in the
Bay Area.
And so
you have
this
interesting
idea
of
perhaps
a
religious
organization
weighing
in on
a
technology
and
sort
of
attempting
to
possibly
regulate
it.
Have
you
thought
about
this
at
all?
Is
this
at
all
interesting
to
you?
I
have
thought
about
it
and
I'm
very
worried
about
it
because
three
or four
weeks
ago
the
Economist
magazine
on the
cover
of
The
Economist
and
their
main
news
article
talked
about
the
five
main
AI
organization
leaders
and
called
them
the
new
barons
of
global
economy
the
men
who
will
replace
oil
tycoons
steel
these
are
the
new
tycoons
they
hold
a
lot
of
power
so
this
article
said
that
they
have
offered
a
study
on
the
risk
of
finance
being
attacked
by
hackers
study
shows
a
huge
vulnerability
in
the
financial
system
the
US
government
is
very
concerned
about
that
and
asked
them
not
to
publicize
the
study
because
if
it
were
to
be
made
public
it
would
confirm
to
those
interested
in
hacking
the
system
what
they
were
looking
for
because
the
study
would
show
exactly
where
the
vulnerabilities
are
in
the
financial
system
but
the
economist
was
talking
about
the
exponential
increase
in
crime
the
financial
system
that
originates
from
AI
artificial
intelligence
isn't
exclusive
to
banks
it's
also
available
to
those
who
want
to
breach
bank
secrets
so
what
is
the
problem
is
the
US
government
only
wants
a
small
group
of
companies
to
have
access
to
these
AI
studies
these
companies
argue
that
if
this
happens
China
would
be
at
an
advantage
because
it
would
make
available
to
all
of
their
companies
this
information
and
knowledge
therefore
Chinese
companies
would
have
an
advantage
over
American
SMEs
if
only
the
major
companies
had
access
to
it
the
Israeli
author
Yuval
Harari
anticipated
these
concerns
in his
two
books
Sapiens
and
Homo
Deus
so
mankind
is creating
the ability
to create
life
and to
exterminate
life
and
artificial
intelligence
is
creating
his book
claims
that
mankind
will create
an AI
that will
be so
powerful
that it
will want
to replace
the Homo
Sapiens
Machina
will want
to replace
the Homo
Sapiens
that
theory
which
10 years
ago
might have
been
considered
science
fiction
is a
real
thing
today
so
the
concern
on
part
of
the
Vatican
is
valid
their
concern
is
valid
because
it
will
involve
international
efforts
and there
will be
a dilemma
between
freedom
and
control
how do
you strike
a balance
between
these
two needs
because
they're
contradictory
and antagonistic
because
if freedom
if you have
full freedom
then there
is no
control
and if
doesn't
have
any
limitations
then there
is no
freedom
so
this
is a
challenge
that
has
to be
shared
by the
whole
world
and
not
only
governments
but
religious
leaders
as well
that
must
be
the
concern
of
the
Vatican
no
one
is
exempt
from
this
situation
speaking
of
extremely
advanced
technology
a
documentary
just
came
out
of
the
United
States
where
you
had
a
former
CIA
director
Brennan
and
former
director
of
national
intelligence
James
Clapper
and
you
had
a
whole
host
of
intelligence
officials
quoted
people
like
David
Grush
who
was
you
know
former
national
geospatial
agency
a bunch
of
people
down
the
line
saying
that
the
U.S.
is
not
only
involved
in
UFO
research
but
they
have
materials
and
they
have
saucers
and
crafts
hangers
where
they
are
working
on
reverse
engineering
these
UFOs
and
they
have
alien
bodies
as
well
that
they've
recovered
alongside
these
crafts
really
remarkable
statements
do you
believe
those
statements
are
true
I
would
need
more
information
about
this
situation
but
if
unknown
machinery
or
equipment
that might
provide
access
to
material
that
human
engineering
hasn't
been able
to develop
is
in the
grasp
of
United
States
authorities
that would
require a
level of
knowledge
that perhaps
isn't
available
to us
even
even if
global
science
has made
such
progress
Carl Sagan
himself
used to
say that
when it
comes to
the
universe
human
knowledge
is still
a grain
of sand
in the
desert
it's
a drop
in the
ocean
what we
know
compared
to
what's
out
there
in
the
universe
so
first of
all
I think
science
needs
to
be
humble
it
needs
to
acknowledge
its
limitations
or
for lack
of a
better
word
ignorance
scientific
and
those
who
have
dedicated
themselves
to
learning
more
need
to
admit
that
there
is
still
so
much
we
don't
know
and
also
need
to
admit
that
politics
once
Einstein
was asked
why man
was able
to take
control
of the
atom
but
not
stop
the
atom
bomb
and
this
was
his
answer
because
politics
is a
much
more
complex
science
than
physics
politics
is
much
more
complex
so
we
need
to
rebuild
bridges
between
politics
and
science
because
politics
built
on
ignorance
and
lack
of
knowledge
can
lead
us
to
the
worst
catastrophes
so
science
really
needs
first
and
foremost
to
acknowledge
its
own
limitations
its
own
ignorance
and
it
needs
to
keep
an
eye
on
and
charge
the
field
of
politics
more
scientific
responsibility
because
otherwise
we could
get to
the point
of no
return
in that
relationship
and this
field of
artificial
intelligence
is
precisely
the
most
sensitive
point
of the
situation
why do
you think
UFO
disclosure
seems to
be
happening
globally
now
do you
have a
take
on
why
this
whole
topic
has so
much
momentum
over the
last
five or
ten
years
in a way
that it
hasn't
had for
a century
and
you know
the US
the Department
of War
is now
dropping
all these
documents
that it
has you
know
the Department
of War
has a
specific
website
that has
500 million
hits
more than
the entire
US
population
you have
congressmen
in the
US
that take
up the
UFO
issue
that are
seeing
all sorts
of amazing
popularity
because
you know
really
people
grab
on to
the
issue
but do
you have
a sense
of why
now
what caught
my attention
was that
the controversy
came up
recently
because
of
a dialogue
let's call
it a dialogue
between
former
President
Obama
and current
President
Donald
Trump
so
they had
this dialogue
and
I wonder
why would
a former
US
President
from a
very
recent
period
and the
current
President
who has
so many
responsibilities
tough issues
to deal
with
in fact
he missed
out on
his own
son's
wedding
ceremony
to
monitor
negotiations
with
Iran
very
closely
and
to open
the
Strait
of
Hormuz
to put
an
end
to
the
conflict
but
he had
time
to
have
this
controversy
with
President
Obama
a
former
President
of
the
United
States
also
has
a
very
busy
schedule
conferences
talks
all over
the
world
not only
would
they
waste
time
or
spend
time
with
a
current
president
at
a
time
when
the
world
tends
to
underestimate
treat
in a
belittling
manner
this
issue
and
saying
oh
it's
not
important
it's
not
relevant
at
all
never
happened
it
doesn't
exist
why
would
two
such
important
men
start
dealing
with
something
that
didn't
exist
that
supposedly
has
no
relevance
importance
either
something
happened
or
something
is
about
to
happen
right
I
don't
know
exactly
what
happened
or
what
could
happen
what
I
can
say
confidently
and
with
certainty
is
that
if
the
current
president
of
the
United
States
who
doesn't
have
the
time
to
go
his
son's
wedding
has
the
time
to
deal
with
this
issue
I
mean
to
deal
with
the
war
with
Iran
or
relations
with
China
the
president
of
the
United
States
doesn't
deal
with
more
than
two
or
three
problems
a
day
it's
impossible
for
them
to
deal
with
more
than
two
or
three
problems
a
day
that
are
key
to
the
country
I
know
that
I
worked
very
closely
with
presidents
I
was
a
minister
I
worked
in
political
coordination
I
was
a
political
leader
I
saw
the
president's
diary
they
delegate
to
ministers
and
they
use
their
secretaries
from
different
departments
science
and
technology
defense
state
secretaries
they
all
have
their
own
schedules
and
the
president
chooses
two
or
three
issues
to
deal
with
every
day
so
suddenly
in
the
middle
of
all
that
this
subject
emerges
and
re-emerges
the
subject
of
unidentified
objects
flying
within
controversy
between
both
the
former
and
current
head
of
state
obviously
this
requires
anyone
capable
of
rational
thought
to
realize
that
something
important
might
be
said
or
revealed
what
exactly
only
he
knows
yeah
and
Obama
sort
of
walked
his
statement
back
he
talked
about
Area
and
alien
beings
underground
there
but
then
you
realize
the
documentary
that
got
made
that
I
was
talking
about
it's
called
Age
of
Disclosure
John
Brennan
was
his CIA
director
and
James
Clapper
was
director
of
national
intelligence
and
then
Obama
has
a
production
company
where
he's
making
a
movie
about
the
first
abduction
in
the
United
States
Betty
and
Barney
Hill
in
so
he's
definitely
interested
in the
topic
have
you
looked
into
those
sorts
of
phenomena
like
close
encounters
of
the
third
kind
where
people
meet
beings
face
to
there's
one
that's
famous
here
Antonio
Villas
Boas
I don't
know
if
you
ever
heard
of
this
in
the
60s
but
there
are
many
cases
where
people
seem
to
like
you
know
interact
with
the
beings
ships
have
you
ever
seen
anything
like
that
or
no
I've
only
heard
what I
saw
in
the
news
it's
an
expression
that
we
use
in
Brazil
too
there
was
a
phenomenon
an
event
close
to
Uberaba
in
the
state
of
Minas
Gerais
this
very
well-known
event
involving
a
group
of
students
who
were
on
an
excursion
in
the
mountainous
region
of
Minas
Gerais
and
one
of
the
girls
moved
away
from
the
group
for
a
while
and
just
vanished
and
the
investigations
never
came
to
a
conclusion
about
what
happened
to
her
this
young
girl
she
was
with
this
party
and
the
local
press
said
that
it
was
like
a
phenomenon
of
abduction
in other
words
she
disappeared
due
to
a
immaterial
phenomena
and
this
is
of course
in the
literature
but
it's
not
part
of
my
knowledge
or
domain
nor
is
it
my
role
to
make
further
considerations
about
it
this
phenomena
you
know
the
final
case
I'll
bring
up
is
there's
a
Stanford
professor
named
Gary
Nolan
who's
a
famous
professor
in the
U.S.
and
I guess
there was
a columnist
here
at
O Globo
his name
is
Ibrahim
Sued
and
he was
mailed
a little
piece
of a
UFO
because
this
crash
was seen
by this
fisherman
on the
beach
in
Ubatuba
have you
heard of
this
case
in
No
but they
only got a
part of it
of the
object
they didn't
get the
whole thing
and that
ended up
with Ibrahim
Suedj
and he
sent this
part of
the object
to this
scientist
at Stanford
in the United
States
Yes
exactly
so
this
fisherman
sees
this
thing
zigzagging
flying
in a
sort
of
a
pattern
it
blows
up
on
the
beach
and
fragments
fall
out
he
then
mails
this
to
Ibrahim
Sued
he
then
mails
it
to
Jacques
Vallée
the
French
UFO
researcher
I
met
mentioned
earlier
Jacques
Vallée
is
close
with
Gary
Nolan
the
Stanford
professor
and
he
says
I
want
you
to
do
mass
spectrometry
on
it
test
and
so
he
tests
today
I've
seen
it
actually
myself
and
it
has
99.9%
magnesium
a level
of purity
in the
magnesium
that you
would never
find
naturally
on earth
you only
find
magnesium
with
sort
of
alloys
so
extremely
interesting
fact
pattern
that's
very
strange
and
even
stranger
is that
science
did
not
go
any
further
they
didn't
make
any
statements
about
what
this
could
mean
or
about
what
it
represents
scientifically
speaking
who
could
ever
here
among
us
build
similar
material
or
process
a
similar
alloy
and
why
was
this
type
of
alloy
built
what
was
the
goal
of
this
these
are
the
questions
that
science
should
be
asking
as an
alternative
I
agree
speaking of
controversies
between
present and
former
presidents
in the
United
States
I think
you are
very
interesting
because
you
exist at
the
intersection
between
Lula and
Bolsonaro
in many
ways
you are
kind of
the
intellectual
fabric
between
them
obviously
you
worked
with
Lula
now
it
seems
like
Bolsonaro
is
taking
up
some
of
your
ideology
but
very
few
people
can
be
described
as
sort
of
a
former
socialist
communist
now
nationalist
so
you are
sort
of
like
this
walking
paradox
but
I
think
you have
remained
consistent
in
some
underlying
ideology
how
do
you view
your
role
now
in
Brazilian
politics
and
how
do
you
think
this
next
election
is
going
to
shake
out
I've
always
been
a
nationalist
my
origin
is
nationalism
earthbound
the
countryman's
nationalism
I was
born
in the
countryside
I was
born
with the
help
of a
midwife
I'm
not
sure
how
to
translate
it
to
English
I
was
educated
in
a
rural
school
then
I
attended
an
agricultural
school
technical
agricultural
school
and
everything
pointed
to
the
importance
of
national
history
domestic
the
national
memory
history
as an
explanation
of who
national
community
because
we
have
a
common
history
and
then
I
joined
the
communist
party
because
we
were
under
the
military
regime
I
fought
for
freedom
of
speech
for
amnesty
the
freedom
of
association
political
and I
spent a
long
time
there
but
I
had
always
been
a
nationalist
and
as
I
stood
by
these
convictions
I
saw
that
the
world
in
the
past
years
has
been
guided
by
two
types
of
nationalism
the
that
resulted
in the
independence
of the
United
States
which
was a
struggle
against
colonial
powers
American
independence
was a
nationalist
struggle
the
independence
of the
countries
in
Portuguese
dominated
America
and Brazil
were
nationalist
struggles
the
independence
of the
Spanish
colonies
in
America
was
a
nationalist
struggle
so
it
was
the
nationalism
of
the
emerging
countries
against
the
nationalism
of
the
colonial
empires
because
Britain
wanted
colonies
to
maintain
its
own
nationalism
and
the
same
goes
for
Portugal
and
Spain
so
recently
we
saw
a
wave
of
national
struggles
in
Africa
we're
talking
about
the
nationalist
leaderships
that
fought
for
the
independence
of
African
nations
against
France
England
Belgium
Portugal
and
who
had
African
colonies
the
struggle
in
Vietnam
was a
nationalist
struggle
the
defense
of
the
country's
unity
etc
and
this
is a
contemporary
struggle
you
have a
dominating
nationalism
against
a
defensive
nationalism
democratic
therefore
I always
attempt
to
see
the
positive
sides
of both
Lula
and
Bolsonaro
because
no one
votes
on a
party
or a
candidate
because
of their
negative
aspect
every
political
leader
if you
look closely
at their
biographies
solely
focusing
on the
flaws
of their
private
life
no one
can
escape
if you
look
at the
private
life
of
Alexander
the
Great
Julius
Caesar
you'll
hardly
look
and
say
no
they're
perfect
what
should
be
examined
is
their
contribution
to
the
development
of
the
world
Hellenization
promoted by
Alexander
the Great
recognizing
the importance
of Greek
culture
so that's
the lens
we should
look
through
here
in Brazil
why does
Lula
have so
much
prestige
because
he has
a
social
concern
with the
poor
with
minimum
wage
and
this
concern
should
be
valued
people
recognize
this
it's
not
because
he
was
charged
with
corruption
because
of
the
mensalão
operation
car wash
people
don't
vote
for
this
and
why
do
they
vote
for
Bolsonaro
was
it
because
he
didn't
deal
with the
pandemic
the way
the
population
wanted
because
he
belittled
the
struggle
and
other
important
issues
of the
country
people
don't
vote
because
of
that
people
voted
on
Bolsonaro
because
they
see
in
him
the
concern
with
the
yellow
and
green
with
the
national
symbols
concern
with
family
values
which
the
left
wing
many
times
see
as
something
conservative
he
values
family
religious
values
which
are
very
important
especially
for
the
poor
Bolsonaro
values
this
so
I
think
that
it's
important
to
bring
together
that
which
from
the
population's
viewpoint
being
concerned
with
the
poor
is
important
being
concerned
with
Brazilian
sovereignty
is
important
it's
to be
concerned
about
national
values
about
family
values
about
religious
values
so
my
nationalism
is a
democratic
nationalism
so
it's
about
reducing
inequalities
and
appreciating
democracy
and
this
is
what
I
mean
I'm
not
talking
about
the
form
of
parliamentary
democracy
I'm
talking
about
the
ability
of
a
country
to
establish
dialogue
analyzing
its
conflicts
and
finding
common
solutions
because
we
are
united
in
our
problems
public
safety
is
not
a
problem
exclusively
of
the
left
or
the
right
price
of
fuel
doesn't
have
a
left
wing
or
right
wing
agenda
when
station
you
don't
find
a
different
price
depending
on
which
candidate
you
voted
for
I
think
it's
the
same
around
the
world
in
the
states
gas
price
is
the
same
for
democrats
and
republicans
alike
if
a
criminal
is
going
to
mug
you
he's
not
going
vote
for
oh
you
voted
for
him
no
he's
going
to
rob
you
period
so
if
the
problem
unifies
the
country
so
should
the
solution
I
was
a
minister
under
Lula
I
was
speaker
of
the
house
when
he
was
president
I
was
government
leader
in
congress
and
I
worked
alongside
Bolsonaro
for
more
than
years
on
the
same
committee
of
foreign
affairs
and
national
defense
we
would
travel
together
we'd
talk
of
course
we
had
disagreements
because
I
was
from
a
left
wing
party
and
he
was
more
conservative
so
it's
important
to be
able
to
disagree
but
to
also
find
common
ground
solutions
I
was
speaker
of
the
house
from
a
left
wing
party
and
I
was
invited
by
the
speaker
of
the
house
in
the
United
States
who
was
a
Republican
to
visit
I
was
very
well
received
we had
an
important
agenda
we
talked
about
Brazil
Venezuela
Bolivia
and I
was
welcomed
by the
assistant
secretary
of
state
for
South
American
affairs
and we
became
very
close
after that
he became
ambassador
to
Brazil
at the
time
I
held
office
as
minister
so
I
think
this
is
what
it's
about
Jesse
you
have
to
hold
on
to
your
beliefs
but
you
should
place
the
common
interest
the
national
interest
dialogue
above
everything
else
you
mentioned
the
economist
before
I
used
to
read
the
economist
all
the
time
and
in
the
kind
of
mid
2000s
you
had
a
term
that
the
economist
would
always
write
about
BRIC
Brazil
Russia
India
China
the
developing
economy
and there
was this
narrative
that all
four of
those
countries
were
going to
sort
of
overtake
the
developed
world
in a
lot
of
ways
Lula
obviously
pulled
a lot
of
Brazilians
out of
poverty
but
you've
had
setbacks
since
the
protests
in
and
you know
things
haven't
gone
I think
the way
that
in the
mid
2000s
one
would
have
hoped
aspirationally
as a
Brazilian
how do
you get
back
to that
momentum
when it
comes to
GDP
growth
and
future
progress
well
Brazil
is a
very
rich
country
but
it's
also
a
closed
off
country
blocked
institutionally
speaking
in
Brazil
we have
the
largest
mineral
reserves
in
the
world
China
has
so
much
rare
earth
because
it's
examined
all
of
its
territory
Brazil
has
much
more
rare
earth
than
China
across
all
of
its
territory
if
you
go
to
Roraima
in
the
north
of
Brazil
it's
very
difficult
not
to
find
rare
earth
even
close
to
Varginha
in
the
south
of
Minas
Gerais
you
find
an
extreme
density
of
rare
earth
if
you
go
to
Goiás
in
the
center
west
of
the
country
you
will
find
high
density
rare
earth
the
United
States
bought
a
single
mine
we
had
of
rare
earth
for
billion
2.5
dollars
we could
have
of
these
mines
authorized
but
everything
is
blocked
oil
extraction
potassium
gold
extraction
so
it's
important
to
lift
these
restrictions
in
mining
agriculture
in
cattle
raising
Brazil
is
the
largest
basin
of
protein
and
grains
in
the
world
Brazil
is
the
largest
frontier
of
energy
in
the
world
we
could
increase
our
hydroelectric
power
generation
twofold
if we
set up
five or
six
plants
in
the
Amazon
there's
no
railway
system
in
Brazil
no
waterway
system
China
has
been
building
50,000
kilometers
of
railways
and
has
been
doing
this
for
years
and
Brazil
doesn't
have
a
single
train
connecting
its
two
largest
cities
Rio
de Janeiro
and
São
Paulo
there
isn't
a
single
train
connecting
the
federal
capital
the
of
Brazil
to
any
other
city
in
the
country
so
the
country
needs
to
change
the
United
States
connected
the
Atlantic
and
the
Pacific
in
the
mid
19th
century
railways
across
the
country
to
this
day
we
have
not
been
able
to
reach
the
Pacific
ocean
by
rail
so
Brazil
is a
country
that's
blocked
that
needs
to
be
unblocked
unrestricted
so
that
we
can
create
a
sovereign
rare
earth
fund
issue
bonds
for
rare
earth
and
even
receive
royalties
for
rare
earth
and
in
very
little
time
Brazil
can
become
a
prosperous
country
with
very
good
growth
rates
as
long
these
restrictions
are
lifted
but
for
that
you
need
public
policies
not
only
economic
policies
hmm
there
are
rumors
now
and
I
guess
want
to
ask
you
the
Christian
democracy
party
seems
to
have
come
up
with
something
around
expelling
you
and
so
what
do
you
have
to
say
about
that
controversy
I
know
you
reject
the
idea
and
then
on
the
backs
of
that
people
are
now
saying
that
you
might
be
throwing
your
hat
in
with
Bolsonaro
and
so
I
want
to
ask
you
are
going
to
be
running
alongside
Bolsonaro
no
I'm
going
to
remain
a
precandidate
the
leader
of
the
party
invited
another
precandidate
who
hasn't
said
anything
thus
far
but
they
looked
into
his
performance
and
his
polls
were
very
low
so
I'm
keeping
my
precandidacy
on
my
agenda
because
my
precandidacy
isn't
just
about
the
elections
I
need
to
communicate
my
agenda
to
Brazil
bring
back
the
development
of
this
country
the
agenda
of
national
value
defense
national
science
technology
national
diplomacy
infrastructure
employment
increasing
income
especially
for
lower
income
people
living
on
minimum
wage
who
can't
live
with
dignity
that
is
my
agenda
national
unity
I
don't
want
a
fragmented
country
you
can win
an election
with a
polarized
country
but
you'll
never
govern
a
polarized
country
you'll
be
wasting
energy
and
you
need
to
gather
energy
creativity
and
enthusiasm
of
people
around
hope
what do
I mean
by hope
economic
development
leads
to
hope
development
leads
to
discipline
when
people
see the
possibility
of doing
better
in life
they study
they look
to become
more
qualified
to go
and look
for a
better job
for their
lives
and
when
there
is
no
development
when
there
is
no
hope
that
as I
said
leads
to
discipline
what
you
get
instead
is
despair
and
is
the
road
to
perdition
especially
among
the
young
that's
what
drug
trafficking
in the
Amazon
is
all
about
it's
an
alternative
for
young
people
who
don't
have
an
economic
alternative
they
live
off
government
aid
a
very
large
part
of
the
population
in
the
Amazon
depends
on
because
there
is
no
economic
activity
there
so
we
need
to
pick
that
up
again
across
the
country
we
need
to
bring
the
country
together
around
shared
objectives
in the
19th
century
Brazil
became
independent
as a
monarchy
and
that
monarchy
protected
the
unity
of
the
country
because
republics
would
have
segmented
Brazil
so
we
had
a
monarchy
that
brought
the
country
together
but
there
were
still
civil
wars
local
leaders
who
wanted
their
own
republics
the
emperor
at a
certain
point
invited
the
most
important
of
those
leaders
and
said
I
want
to
have
an
administration
that
will
reconcile
people
I
want
to
have
a
ministry
that
will
reconcile
both
parties
I
want
you
to
have
an
administration
with
both
parties
so
there's
a
huge
division
in
Brazil
now
it's
almost
like
a
cyber
civil
war
it's
a
war
in
social
media
it's
online
but
it's
civil
war
there's
a
lot
of
hatred
a
lot
of
intolerance
we
need
that
so
this
country's
energy
can
go
towards
building
something
of
course
there
will
be
lots
of
disagreement
on
many
points
but
will
we
only
have
disagreements
is
there
nothing
that
brings
Brazilians
together
what
unites
Brazil
what
brings
us
together
business
owners
workers
the
middle
class
academics
the
military
religion
for
the
country
to
get
back
to
growing
we
need
to
decrease
inequality
we
need
to
place
value
on
education
I
think
we
can
bring
this
country
together
a
country
that
places
value
on
democracy
is
the
ability
to
talk
okay
you
think
you're
left
wing
you
think
you're
right
wing
but
the
country
is
above
that
citizens
are
not
left
or
right
wing
they
want
a
solution
to
their
problems
they
want
to
be
able
to
pay
their
bills
month
to
pay
for
groceries
to
make
rent
to
pay
for
their
car
children's
school
the
pharmacy
their
problems
can
we
offer
them
this
administration
so
let's
see
you're
in
favor
of
two
people
of
the
same
sex
being
able
to
get
married
and
you're
against
it
okay
let's
talk
about
it
okay
you
think
that
there
is
racism
in
this
country
fine
let's
talk
about
it
but
that
cannot
be
above
the
common
shared
interest
I
believe
that
this
is
the
political
solution
the
economic
solution
is
to
unblock
the
country
political
solution
is
to
unite
the
country
around
everything
that
can
bring
people
together
unite
people
have
you
studied
other
success
stories
when it
comes
to
governance
over
the
last
years
places
like
Singapore
with
Lee
Kuan
Yu
or
Taiwan
you know
Chiang Kai
Shek
where you
have
massive
growth
and
do
you
think
like
a
certain
industry
can
be
what
reboots
growth
here
in
Brazil
you
mentioned
rare
earths
obviously
that's
a
key
area
of
contest
between
the
US
and
China
specifically
when it
comes
to
refinement
is
that
it
or
do
you
have
other
ideas
for
how
Brazil
really
gets
back
to
high
growth
territory
I
do
have
an
interesting
example
in
the
United
States
which
was
Lincoln's
choice
as the
Republican
Party
candidate
at a
convention
when he
wasn't
the strongest
candidate
there were
two governors
who opposed
each other
I believe
that were
much stronger
candidates
than Lincoln
was
but the
conflict
between
these two
suitors
made
Lincoln become
the consensus
solution
he was a
lawyer
who'd lost
an election
to the Senate
that was
described in
the book
and there
is a
film about
his story
Lincoln's
story
and what
he did
after he
was elected
was
he asked
his competitors
to rule
with him
and he gave
the State
Department
to one
the Treasury
to the other
the key
positions
were given
to those
who were
competing
against him
in that
convention
so the
United States
does have
that example
of unity
and of dispute
for example
what happened
with
the independence
movement
there were
key differences
between
the leaders
who paved
the way
for the
independence
of the United
States
I just read
Alexander Hamilton's
biography
and he
talks about
those differences
but they were
addressed
because of
a shared
interest
a common
and the whole
world is like
that
if you look
at any
transformation
process
in the world
there are
always conflicts
disputes
but there's
also unity
and unity
should protect
what is in the
interest
of the country
Brazil
has
plenty of
opportunities
to have
relations
with both
the US
and with
China
but here
they want
to pick a
side
either
we're
paired
with the
US
and we're
going to
stick
with the
Republican
Party
agenda
and the
other
side
with the
Democratic
Party
either
with the
US
or with
China
why does
Brazil
have to
make that
choice
between
the US
or China
Brazil
should choose
why is that
because we
have
a very
powerful bond
with the
US
they were
the first
country
in the
world
to
recognize
our
independence
emperor
was the
first
foreign
head
of state
to visit
the United
States
the first
trip of a
US secretary
of state
abroad
was to
Brazil
so we have
a long
standing
relationship
culturally
we're
very close
every
Brazilian
with a
certain
degree
of
education
is very
fond
of
American
literature
Walt
Whitman
dedicated
a poem
to
Brazil's
proclamation
of
independence
a poem
dedicated
to both
constellations
we have
a constellation
on the
Brazilian
flag
and there
is a
constellation
on the
US
flag
and that
was
celebrated
by the
greatest
poet
in the
United
States
we
always
had
the
habit
of
keeping
up
with
the
literature
of
the
United
States
reading
for example
Mark Twain
Jack London
American
poets
and more
recent
literature
we all
admire
literature
from
this
American
movies
but
of course
we also
have
our
differences
why
because
the
US
is a
powerhouse
with
geopolitical
interests
around
the
world
and
here
too
so
we
were
recognized
by the
US
as an
independent
country
and the
following
year
there
was
a
rebellion
successionist
in the
northeast
and the
US
supported
that
when
the
leader
of
the
succession
was
killed
an
American
citizen
was
also
killed
who
was
encouraging
the
separation
in
Brazil
and
the
emperor
reacted
violently
with
a lot
of
repression
and
that
created
a
huge
diplomatic
standoff
because
the
US
government
the
embassy
and
the
consulate
tried
to
put
a
stop
coup
in
this
country
with
support
of
the
US
but
right
after
that
the
military
cut
relations
with
US
because
of
the
nuclear
program
and
the
space
program
in
the
Second
World
War
our
main
agreement
was
made
with
the
United
States
we
gave
the
busiest
airspace
to
the
US
which
is
in
the
northeast
we
provided
rubber
to
the
allies
there
couldn't
have
been
a
war
without
rubber
they
needed
steel
oil
and
rubber
you
can't
build
a
warship
plane
or
a
tank
without
rubber
Japan
took
the
rubber
from
the
English
and
Asia
Roosevelt
President
came
to
Brazil
twice
once
to
Rio
meet
with
Vargas
and
to
Rio
Grande
do
Norte
Vargas
never
left
Brazil
to
travel
the
US
but
Roosevelt
came
here
twice
and
he
came
specifically
to
ask
for
rubber
and
an
air
base
also
because
Germany
had
a
plan
to
invade
the
northeast
of
Brazil
to
stop
support
from
leaving
Brazil
to
go
the
allies
in
Asia
Africa
so
we've
always
stood
together
fought
differences
disputes
and
unity
we
should
remain
united
in the
interests
that we
share
we
shouldn't
do
anything
to
go
against
the
United
States
and
we
shouldn't
accept
anything
from
the
United
States
that
goes
against
our
interests
it's
like
having
a
draw
okay
what
are
our
shared
interests
here
we
are
committed
this
is
what
I
said
when
I
was
the
Speaker
of
the
House
when
I
visited
the
US
we
are
committed
to
putting
our
best
effort
into
fighting
drug
trafficking
that
is
what
we'll
do
and
secondly
putting
our
best
effort
into
making
sure
that
there
are
no
terrorist
bases
on
our
border
or
in
our
country
and
we
will
not
accept
US
military
bases
in
South
America
because
that's
going
to
create
a
difficult
situation
one
country
is
going
to
want
an
American
base
another
one
is
going
to
want
a
Russian
base
another
one
is
going
to
want
a
Chinese
base
and
it's
going
to
be
a
mess
so
we
should
have
good
relations
with
the
US
and
with
China
doesn't
fund
any
NGOs
here
they
have
their
interests
here
food
security
rare
earth
infrastructure
energy
those
are
Chinese
interests
Brazil
sends
more
than
a
third
of
its
exports
to
China
so
Brazil
must
also
have
a
relationship
with
China
that
respects
Brazilian
sovereignty
and
the
same
with
the
US
whatever
is
beneficial
to
Brazil
and
to
China
and
as
a
shared
interest
we
should
do
there's
a
lot
that
Brazil
can
do
both
with
the
US
and
with
China
Brazil
has
everything
the
world
needs
food
security
we
have
it
energy
security
we
also
have
it
mineral
strategic
resources
like
rare
earth
we
have
it
biodiversity
for the
economy
of the
future
we
have
it
what
are we
missing
we
just
need
to
choose
in
accordance
with
what
fate
has
given
us
that's
what
we
need
yeah
that's
a
beautiful
vision
I
want
to
switch
back
to
UFOs
briefly
and
say
that
actually
Brazil
is
very
forward
on
this
subject
as
of
there
was
an
ordinance
called
GC3
and
basically
any
military
branch
that
sees
a
UFO
they
are
mandated
to
give
that
information
to
the
Central
Aerospace
Defense
Command
and
so
I
want
to
ask
did
you
ever
look
into
that
in
and
if
you
were
elected
president
now
would
you
look
into
this
ordinance
has
the
objective
naturally
of
concentrating
information
and
the
ability
to
make
decisions
regarding
the
behavior
and
actions
surrounding
these
events
in the
Air
Force
which
is
the
right
institution
to
adopt
mechanisms
to
act
because
they
have
what
is
required
it
shouldn't
be
the
Navy
or
the
Army
or
the
intelligence
service
the
first
action
should
be
taken
by
the
Air
Force
naturally
and
today
in the
world
there
is
a
change
going
on
there
is
no
longer
just
one
Air
Force
they've
been
turned
into
aerospace
forces
speaking
of which
military
attachés
when I
was
Minister
of
Defense
wouldn't
introduce
themselves
as
Air Force
attachés
you have
the
Navy
attaché
you have
the
Army
attaché
and there
was
the
aerospace
forces
attaché
Brazil
still
hasn't
adopted
that
nomenclature
but it
will have
to
because
with
the
militarization
of
aerospace
or the
possibility
of the
militarization
of
aerospace
we're not
just talking
about
air
defense
we're
talking about
aerospace
defense
and as
such
it's
going to
have to
deal
with
predictable
phenomena
known
but also
unpredictable
unknown
phenomena
it's not
a choice
it's a
given
either
you
prepare
for that
or
you
cannot
fulfill
your
duties
mission
in the
defense
of
space
and
in the
defense
of
aerospace
this
is
the
correct
and
up-to-date
nomenclature
you mentioned
rare earths
being present
near
virginia
which
rare earth
specifically
which
rare earth
minerals
it's
rare earth
and
strategic
minerals
that are
found
in the
south
of
minas
gerais
it's a
quadrangle
that goes
from
pasos de
caudas
to the
municipality
of
andradas
there you
can find
the
important
presence
of
exploration
of these
minerals
also in
minas
which is
known as
the
minas
triangle
you can
find
niobium
which is
very important
in the
fabrication of
high resistance
alloys
for aerospace
applications
and the
information
from the
geological reports
about the
presence of
these minerals
in the
region of
varginha
points to
rare earth
of very high
density
and very high
quality that
supersedes
anything that
has been
explored in
the world
today
very close
to minas
gerais
we have
pasos de
caudas
city
okay
around that
area
it's plenty
of
iranian
and they
process
iranian
to make
the yellow
cake
is the
last stage
of iranian
before
you turn
it into
plutonium
or enriched
iranian
yes
right
next to
virginia
for example
but it's
not only
iranian
there's a
lot of
rare
elements
okay
in the
whole
minas gerais
states
and if
when people
ask us
why
minas gerais
well
the answer
for us
is quite
obvious
because there's
a lot
of
rare
elements
you can
find all
of them
most all
of the
periodic
table of
the chemical
elements
you will
find in
minas gerais
and you
find many
caves
we have
more than
4,000
different
caves
around
minas gerais
states
with all
these
minerals
for us
there's a
close
relationship
between
the ufo
phenomenon
and the
those
rare
elements
minerals
in the
whole
state
because it's
incredible
it's the
center of
the ufo
event in
brazil
although
all over
the country
we have
many
accounts
but in
minas gerais
it's the
center
it seems
like ufo's
often show
up around
areas with
rare earths
sometimes
they're
uranium mines
and you
know rare
yeah rare
minerals and
elements that
you wouldn't
find elsewhere
and kind of
geomagnetic
anomalies
present and
this is
throughout you
know there's
a famous
case of
61 school
children in
rua zimbabwe
seeing a
ufo land
and a
being coming
out and
it's right
next to
uranium mine
and that's
very very
common
well according
to legend
the territory
which today
is the
state of
juaraima
on the
border of
guiana
and venezuela
is very
rich in
rare earth
and strategic
minerals
so it
is believed
that when
these american
satellites
that can
perform these
scannings
searching for
minerals
all over
the planet
when they
cross over
the state
of
juaraima
the signal
is so
strong
from the
presence
of rare
earth
that the
satellite
shakes
violently
almost to
the point
of dropping
because of
the vast
presence
of rare
earth
in
juaraima
so
brazil
here's the
thing
it's all
under
indigenous
reservations
wherever
there's
minerals
and rare
earth
there has
been
demarcation
campaigns
on the
part of
ngos
on
indigenous
land
and if
it's
indigenous
land
you can't
explore in
it
touch it
it's frozen
so to speak
and it can't
be used
for economic
purposes
but there's a lot
of that in
brazil
you have that
presence
in the north
for example
you have
very important
mineral
reserves
and this
is because
when the
mineral deposits
were formed
on the
planet
this happened
during the
period that
geologists
denominate
the
pre-cambrian
era
and these
deposits
are not
made up
of only
one type
of mineral
they're what
you call
associated
minerals
so much
so that
in brazil
these reserves
are called
national reserves
so you take
the mineral
that has
the highest
presence
for example
copper
but it's
and associated
minerals
because with
copper
you have
gold
tungsten
a variety
of other
minerals
that can
be found
with a
very high
density
and brazil
one time
in the
institut de
france
in france
talking to
a physicist
he had
a map
of minerals
in the
brazilian
amazon
so i asked
how did
you make
this map
and he said
we didn't
make this
map in
brazil
we made
it in
africa
because
you know
at that
time
the two
continents
were joined
together
you didn't
have the
atlantic
ocean
separating
the two
so
african
reserves
were developed
at the
same
time
as
the
brazilian
reserves
so if
we take
into
consideration
that
they had
a
greater
presence
the
french
in
africa
which
is
on
the
same
parallel
of
the
amazon
we'll
have
the
same
in
the
amazon
as
well
so i said
very
interesting
so whenever
brazil decides
to explore
these minerals
these french
companies will
already have
this information
available
i want to
end on a
more fun
note
which is
you're
a big
football
fan
and we're
here in
sao paulo
where you
have the
team palmeras
which you
are as
deep on
the history
of as
honestly
anyone
you've
written
actually
like a
book
about this
trophy
that you
found
that was
covered
in dust
some
legends
like
roberto
carlos
and
capu
have
come
through
this
organization
i want
to ask
you
it's
you know
on
everybody's
minds
right now
in this
most recent
world cup
neymar is
being called
back the
once kind
of wonderkind
legendary
football player
he's obviously
very controversial
and he's being
called up to be
on the brazilian
national team
do you have
an opinion
on that
look
one has to
understand what
soccer means
to brazil
soccer is much
more than a
sport
soccer is a
phenomenon
that
challenges
sociologists
historians
why is
soccer so
dear to
brazilians
why is it
so
beloved
even for
people who
can't go to
stadiums to
watch games
because they're
poor
they can't
pay for
tickets
but they
love soccer
the teams
in my view
it's because
soccer was the
first way
of rising up
the social ladder
for poor people
at a time
when the country
gave no opportunity
for a young
black man
miscigenated
mulatto
from the
impoverished
outskirts
because he
couldn't make it
to university
there was no
economy
that would give
him the opportunity
to become middle
class for example
he was condemned
to poverty
condemned
to scarcity
and then along
came soccer
which promoted
and gave
the young
black man
mulatto
poor
for the first
time in history
validation
admiration
respect
so when the
first young
black man
had a position
in society
it was through
soccer
and poor people
came to see
in soccer
this virtue
of being
a democratic
sport
a sport
that really
opened up
opportunities
for those
who didn't
have any
so people
embraced
the sport
it became
a national
phenomenon
unique
the teams
in Brazil
are not
restricted
to states
or cities
like they are
in Spain
the team
is from
Barcelona
or Madrid
or Catalonia
or the team
is from
Castilla
or Basque
Country
or Galicia
not here
here the teams
are national
institutions
and people
identify
with the sport
of soccer
because of
these virtues
it was the
first institution
that promoted
the young
black man
that recognized
his talent
his capacity
only a young
man from the
middle class
could receive
this kind
of recognition
soccer
created this
opportunity
and it became
the sport
of the workers
of the downtrodden
of the immigrants
of the Italians
for example
who created
Palmiiras
the Italians
suffered a lot
of discrimination
here
by the old
elites
of the country
so they created
these teams
the rail workers
went and created
their own teams
so I myself
as a very young man
still living in the
countryside of Alagoas
started supporting
Palmiiras
because next to Santos
which had Pelé
and Botafogo
which had Garrincha
it was one of the
country's best teams
and in 1951
or rather in 1945
there was a classic match
between Corinthians
and Palmiiras
in São Paulo
to raise funds
for the Communist Party
campaign
so I wrote a book
called
The Red Game
and why were they
raising funds
for the Communist Party
it was
a recognition
of the role
of the Soviet Union
in the Second World War
the effort
of the Allies
the Communist Party
mobilized people
to go and fight
the Nazis
and Nazi Germany
so there was
this recognition
the team managers
were not a part
of the party
they merely wanted
to pay this tribute
and raise funds
for the party
in 1951
there was a championship
that was organized
by FIFA
with all the big teams
from Europe
and Palmeiras
participated in this tournament
and won
so they asked FIFA
to recognize
this as the first
club World Cup
and some time passed
with FIFA
hesitating to make a decision
and when the World Cup
was finally held
in Brazil
it was Palmeiras
centennial year
so FIFA brought together
a committee meeting
and finally they
recognized
this title
but above all
I have
a deep admiration
a deep appreciation
for the role
soccer played
in Brazil
as an institution
of social change
of validation
of poor people
validation
of the dispossessed
and of promoting
the unification
of the country
it is truly
a national passion
and Neymar
is Brazil's
most recent idol
he can still
play in this
World Cup
and we have high hopes
that he's going to be
in good physical condition
and that he can
fulfill such an important
role in the team
and that Brazil can
keep its status
as the country
that participated
in the most
World Cups
and that
won the most
well there you go
I'm sure
you know
the whole country
is waiting to see
what happens
and you answered
that in a way
that is kind of
worthy of
how religious
the following
is of
you know
Brazilian football
so thank you so much
for your time
Mr. Ribello
Minister Ribello
this has been
an honor for me
and I really appreciate
just how forward
thinking you are
on a topic that
most politicians
aren't really able
to speak eloquently about
so it means a lot
and hopefully
this is just the start
and maybe you get elected
and you know
this is the beginning
of a much longer conversation
thank you so much
for the visit
for interviewing me
and I hope that you
can take from Brazil
in addition to information
a good impression
of our country
our history
our culture
our cuisine
and that when you go back
to the United States
you'll feel the urge
to come back
as soon as possible
to Brazil
thank you very much
thank you
We'll see you next time.
Your support helps us so much and it allows us to keep making the show and go deeper into the kinds of stories we care most about.
And a little early access and not getting bogged down by ads is kind of a cool perk.
So join today.
If you've made it this far in the show, then I know you care enough to hear about this.
Our show, American Alchemy, is growing super fast.
It's bursting at the seams.
We are looking for an amazing editor to join the team.
If you're an experienced YouTube editor, podcast editor, trailer editor, or documentary-style editor, maybe you're even a traditional Hollywood editor and you're just really into our content.
And you want to work on some of the most mind-bending stories in the world.
We really want to hear from you.
We're especially looking for people who are deep into the content and who have a real editorial eye.
Someone who can dig through long and sometimes dense conversations, find the most powerful moments, build tension, create great hooks.
Basically, people who can turn these raw conversations into very high-quality, almost cinematic episodes.
Strong technical skills are a prerequisite, but especially for the documentaries we make, we really need somebody with taste, who has strong instincts around pacing, music, sound design, story structure, you know, all the things.
And big bonus points if you're genuinely into UFOs, consciousness, frontier science, and big questions about the nature of reality.
So if you're a strong, experienced editor and you know how to keep audiences engaged, and you want to work with us on some of the coolest stories in the world,
please email all your relevant work and your application to apply at jessymichaelsmedia.com.
And if you have a friend who would be great for this role, please let them know.
Thank you so much, and we look forward to hearing from you and maybe working with you.