Our next guest worked for the CIA for over two decades.
He goes, if you are Storm, die in your separate foxholes.
His name is Rolf Mowat-Larsen.
He served in various roles all over the world,
some of which he can't even speak about today.
What's the most on the brink the world has been that you can talk about?
Well, he's been shoulder to shoulder with Putin.
He describes working directly with NSA Director Michael Hayden,
CIA Director George Tenet,
and even briefing former President George W. Bush,
Vice President Dick Cheney,
and UK Prime Minister Tony Blair.
But while he's worked at the highest,
most illustrious levels of international diplomacy,
that is the least interesting thing about our next guest.
In 1991, I went on a pilgrimage to Mon Athos, Greece,
and I'm sitting at this, and I fell asleep,
sort of napping on this stone chair facing the church.
And with every step I'm taking, time is going back in time.
It was as if time was evaporating.
But I wasn't aware if I could wake up or get back to my old world
because I was going back in time.
He claims to be a time traveler.
He says that he left his 20th century identity behind in 1991
to go live as a monk in Mount Athos, Greece in the 14th century.
I became a recluse up there.
I burned my hut up there, like all the things a recluse does.
You know, I learned to fly.
And when you're flying, you're spiritually open.
He time traveled back to the medieval era for months,
eating, walking around, socializing,
and sleeping in his physical body in medieval Mount Athos, Greece.
Now I'm sure you're wondering if I mean time travel in the metaphorical sense.
Our guest stated multiple times to me
that the reality he experienced in medieval times
was indistinguishable from his current waking reality.
According to him, not remote viewing or astrally projecting himself there.
Does all of this feel as real as this interview feels?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
If senior CIA time travel whistleblower was not on your bingo card this year,
it wasn't on mine either.
But here we are.
But if it can't get any more interesting than that, it does.
Our next guest ran intelligence and counterintelligence
for the Department of Energy.
I learned some of this nation's most important secrets at DOE, not CIA.
DOE does stuff that, whew, man.
And if you know anything about this show,
we are obsessed with UFOs
and think and kind of know that the Department of Energy
has a lot to do with managing UFO secrecy and crash retrievals.
So you better believe I threw literally every single UFO program-related question
at our guest today.
I even coordinated on the questions with my friend and UFO whistleblower David Grush,
fellow YouTuber UAP Gerb,
and author of UFOs and Nukes, Robert Hastings.
Do you think that we have propulsion modalities that transcend chemical combustion?
Do you think nothing happened at Roswell?
Have you ever seen a one-of-one material?
I'll let you assess our guest's answers for yourself.
And whether you come out of this interview
thinking he's just a savvy former CIA case officer running circles around us,
or whether you think he's being genuine, is up to you.
I will say that for me,
this was hands down one of the most thoughtful and mind-blowing conversations
on metaphysics, fringe science,
and the nature of reality that I've had on this show.
So without further ado, here is all four hours of it.
Former CIA and Department of Energy Intelligence officer,
Moscow station chief, time traveler,
and religious mystic, Rolf Moa Larsson.
How is this possible?
Nothing too unusual about that.
The existence cannot longer be denied.
Before we continue, I want to take a second to thank one of my favorite products in the world,
Ketone IQ, for sponsoring today's episode.
I've mentioned this before, but I don't really drink a lot of caffeine,
I don't use nicotine, and I don't really do super well with stimulants.
Most of these things give me jitters, spikes, or a crash later on.
It feels like you're taking credit out on your future energy.
As you know, there's no such thing as a free lunch.
Ketone IQ is one of the very few things I use
that gives me clean, sustainable energy without the crash.
It's just this little shot, and I take a drink, and I feel like I'm on fire.
No ups, no downs, no nervous system weirdness.
Just clean, clear mental energy.
The reason it works is pretty simple.
It gives your brain's ketones,
which are, almost by definition, its most efficient fuel source.
Instead of pushing your system, it actually feeds it.
In fact, your body endogenously produces ketones.
So when you drink this, it supports deep focus,
long conversations, and sustained mental performance.
It was originally developed through a multi-million dollar military program
designed for high-stress environments
where cognitive performance really matters.
And today, it's used by founders, researchers, podcasters like myself,
and people who need their mind to work when it counts.
I always take a sip of one of these things before long podcasts.
This product is also really personal for me
because I've known the founders, Jeff and Michael, for over a decade.
These guys are awesome, and for as long as I've known them,
they've tried every supplement, biohack, and nootropic under the sun.
So it was a pretty good signal to me
that they decided to start a company around ketones.
I use Ketone IQ regularly.
It's like a mental cheat code,
and it's genuinely one of the cleanest energy sources I've ever found.
So before we get back into the episode,
please visit ketone.com slash alchemy
for 30% off your subscription order.
Plus receive a free gift with your second shipment.
Again, that's ketone.com slash alchemy
for 30% off your order.
Or you can find Ketone IQ at Target stores nationwide
and get your first shot free.
Seriously, this stuff works.
Thanks so much to Ketone IQ for sponsoring today's episode.
I'm here with Rolf Moat-Larsen.
I am so grateful for this interview.
I've read your book, A State of Mind, Faith in the CIA.
One of the most remarkable books I've ever read.
It's really fascinating because interspersed with stories of real-life espionage,
of kind of moments where, you know, the world pivoted,
and you literally see, like, timelines shift.
You're in the, you know, Oval Office talking to Bush and Cheney
and that sort of thing.
Interspersed with that are some very profound mystical experiences.
So why don't we start off with just why did you write the book to begin with?
All right.
Thank you, Jesse.
It's a pleasure to be here.
I'm an admirer of your work, and I look forward to telling my story
in the context of all the stories you present of people who have things to offer
that really expand our understanding of reality and of faith.
And I wrote the book because I wanted people to benefit from my story,
which is really my relationship with God.
And I like people to think of it more as a relationship than as a religious book,
and it's not, in fact, about that.
I don't proselytize or try to convert people to a specific religion.
My story started as a little boy where I was aware of the presence of God,
and the presence of God that I was aware of was something I felt a need to develop.
And I saw God as even a child as a creator God and a personal God,
which meant I could communicate.
So we opened with a little prayer, and I like to try to keep a continuous prayer idea with God
where I'm always interacting.
And there's an arena.
The reason I entitled my book A State of Mind and Faith in the CIA
was a state of mind refers to a desire to be close to God.
John Paul II, it's a paraphrase of him saying,
hell is not a place, which is an interesting concept.
You figure Dante's Inferno, it's a state of mind.
It's a state of mind of being separated from God.
And throughout my life, I had a sort of a fear of being distant from God
or not being close enough to God.
But it wasn't a traditional thing of go to church and give money.
It was more of like in my personal relationship with God,
since God knows all things, God would be aware.
And when I would pray in the way we started, I got responses
and ultimately evolved into a destiny I felt.
My destiny became tied to my relationship with God.
My destiny was to fulfill God's wishes through my life and my experiences.
And that set up certain conflicts with what I call my secular world of CIA,
which I devoted my whole career to.
Started in the military, went to West Point,
and spent six years in the army at an auspicious time in the 70s
on the Czech border, and then transferred over to CIA.
So that whole story, all those experiences had their own role
in national security, et cetera, but also in my relationship with God.
And the faith part was understanding my faith as that relationship with God,
not as what I called myself or what people thought of me in religious terms,
but in my relationship with God, how was it developing?
And was I fulfilling God's will through my actions and thoughts?
And what did you end up doing at the CIA and throughout your intelligence career?
I think a lot of people, what we try to do on the show is kind of marry
some of the most out there experiences or claims people have
with, you know, kind of rigorous credentials.
Yeah, I think that's really important.
So in my CIA career, I started as a, in Europe,
just what we call a European officer.
We had different areas of the world we were in.
That was where I started.
But I got quickly into arms control.
And then over the years, I seemed to gravitate.
I didn't think of this as things went on as being coincidental.
It began to converge with my spiritual developments.
More and more towards war and nuclear war, collapse of the Soviet Union.
I did two tours in Moscow in the old days, in the Soviet days.
I came back.
I was what we call our chief of station in Moscow
after the collapse of the Soviet Union.
Of course, I hope that gives me some credibility on my religious,
or my spiritual experiences.
But they were, they were my credibility as an intelligence officer
that I was always seem to be at the threshold of history.
Like many, I'm not unique in that, by the way.
There are so many of us that have been observers of history,
helping to make history in some small way.
And I was extremely fortunate in my career.
Moscow ended my, or we did nine tours overseas,
each two, three years under cover, sometimes deep cover,
through the whole experience, and ended the whole thing,
which I don't think was a coincidence,
in the Middle East between 2011 and 16,
when we served in the Middle East for the last five years.
So between Europe, Soviet Union, Middle East,
we sort of saw the whole world, served as CIA officers.
My wife also worked most of that time in CIA.
She's written her own book called Story of a CIA Wife.
I'll close with one thing.
I mean, people have different reactions.
The first day I walked in CIA headquarters,
you see the stars on the wall.
It makes a huge, and if the stars on the wall
are CIA officers who fall on the line of duty.
They can't put their names to the star.
There's a book that has that code book
that tells you this star here is this person.
There are people who lost their lives
serving their country overseas.
And, of course, I never wanted to be on that wall,
like any of us.
But right next to that, the stars on the wall,
was this large, bold imprint
into the marble walls of the CIA atrium
when you walk inside the big building,
the old headquarters in Virginia.
And it says, John 832,
you shall know the truth,
and the truth shall set you free.
And I thought, wow, this is really quite extraordinary
that CIA, you know, secular organization,
has this New Testament verse on the wall.
And I wondered at the time
when I walked in the building
whether I would be satisfied
that that's what CIA was all about.
Were we truth seekers or not truth seekers?
And that's the ultimate litmus test.
When we don't seek truth
and we have another agenda,
we do bad things as CIA or intelligence officers
or army officers or anything in life.
Do you find that at times the CIA
has not sought truth in the past?
Oh, of course, of course.
I mean, people are people,
organizations are organizations.
The problem with giving organizations
such powers as CIA has
is on the positive side,
you can accomplish great things.
On the negative side,
you can do very bad things.
And especially when you're doing them in secret.
You have some interesting stories
that you talk about in the book
of being in the Oval Office,
giving Bush advice,
giving Cheney advice.
Do you want to give a couple of examples there
of just stories where you kind of helped out
or advised in kind of very high up
American national security contexts?
Right.
My career breaks down into three phases, really.
The first phase was between
when I started 1983 to 1991
with the collapse of the Soviet Union.
That's what we sometimes refer to
as the good old days,
which was espionage in the shadows,
like the books you always read,
the classic espionage books
of running spies and great stuff.
And I became really good at that.
Then suddenly, boom,
almost 10 years into my career,
we get with almost exactly,
we get hit with 9-11.
And after 9-11,
I was actually in language training
to go to Asia to become
the chief of station
of a large Asian country
when I saw on TV
that the Twin Towers
got hit by terrorists.
I had been on the director,
director of CIA staff
the year before preceding 9-11
as associate director
of central intelligence
for military support.
So I was a staffer
supporting the director,
who was a good friend of mine,
wonderful director,
in my mind,
George Tenet.
And we knew that we were
going to be hit 9-11.
We didn't know where.
And I'm not in the school of belief,
and I know that it's a valid way
to think of it,
that we failed.
Well, we failed because
we allowed the attack to happen,
but could we have prevented it?
I think that's in ways
a problematic way to think of it
because I don't think
we could have prevented 9-11.
We just have to give the credit
to the terrorists,
to Osama bin Laden terrorists.
But it changed everyone's lives
and future of the world,
and that was the intent
of the terrorists,
including my little life.
So they pulled me
from my language training,
and George Tenet made me
head of what they call
the Weapons of Mass Destruction
Department
and the Counterterrorism Center,
which was to stop terrorists
from acquiring biological
or nuclear weapons.
I mean, that's a, yeah,
if the future of the world
hinges on any job,
that's the job.
I did say to George Tenet,
who I already knew well
because I'd been
on his senior staff,
I said, George,
isn't there anybody
better than me for this?
How did he respond
when he said, you know,
hey, can't you find
anybody better than me?
Oh, classic George Tenet
response.
Like I said, great leader,
a great leader of men and women.
He said, hey,
I got worse news for you.
You don't have any people yet.
I went from three people
at that meeting
that had been assigned to me
to 150 over the next weeks.
And then he said,
but you were behind the eight ball,
and he explained why,
which is still classified,
which meant there was
a plausible reason
to be worried
that Al-Qaeda might obtain
a nuclear weapon,
which was,
I can say the basics,
which was they were negotiating
with Pakistani nuclear scientists
to try to acquire
a nuclear weapon
they could use
in the United States.
This was something,
as George said to me,
we can't fail on this.
We're going to fail.
We're like athletes
playing in sports,
team sports.
Sometimes we fumble,
sometimes the other team scores.
We can't let them score on this.
We can't let them do this one time
and take out the White House
or Congress or something.
And so you're just going to have
to make sure the president
knows everything we know
when we know it.
We met as a group,
and a lot of this is in my book,
of course.
We met every day at five o'clock,
and we just pulled
everything together raw.
Nothing was going through
the normal formats.
All our information,
we briefed the director,
and when we had the meeting
at five,
it usually lasts
till eight or nine at night.
And just going around the table,
everybody sharing everything
they know with everybody,
and everybody included,
usually the FBI director,
Robert Mueller,
who, of course,
I also got to know very well.
The NSA director,
Mike Hayden,
was part of the group.
And just a number of people
around the Washington area
who needed to know.
Somebody would pop in
from the National Security Council.
Stephen Hadley,
part of it.
Stephen Hadley was often,
you know,
involved.
And everything was briefed raw.
The president was told
everything that night.
First thing in the morning,
he was briefed by Bob Mueller
and George Tenet together,
the FBI and CIA directors.
And then we would come in ad hoc.
And I would go in,
and I outlined some of the
most important,
you know,
moments of briefing
the president,
when there was something
extraordinary
from my area.
And I felt an immense
responsibility.
So the answer,
the short answer
to your question is,
I would brief the president
when there was a possibility
we were going to get hit
with a biological
or nuclear attack
because something
was developing.
And he needed to know
because usually
it was something
that we couldn't,
we didn't know
exactly the timing
and we weren't
entirely sure
of the accuracy
or the providence
of the threat.
But we knew
he needed to know
because we don't want
him to read about it
with us
when it happens.
And for example,
probably the most,
the most,
most important
of the whole,
of my whole experience
with the president
was when I briefed him
that right three weeks
before we invaded Iraq.
So now we're talking
2003.
We obtained information
that a notorious terrorist
that my people
were tracking,
his name was
Abu Musab al-Zarqawi.
He's a famous
jihadist.
He was head of Al-Qaeda
in Iraq
once we,
later.
But this is before
the invasion.
So this information
is very privileged
at the time.
And I had briefed
the president
several times
on him and his network
and how they were
trying to obtain
these weapons.
And I came in,
I said,
Mr. President,
I have bad news.
The only people
in the Oval Office
were me,
George Tenet,
and George Bush,
George H.W. Bush.
He was in a wheelchair
at the time.
So it was an amazing
sight for me
as a citizen.
And I have to say
to your listeners,
you know,
W and his father
and George
and me,
that was it
in the Oval Office
for an hour.
Wow.
And I have to tell you
as an American,
I had goosebumps.
Yeah.
And everything
I had briefed
the president,
you know,
all I had
from dealing
with everybody
I dealt with
at that level
was they were
incredibly dedicated
to serving this country.
They were incredibly
dedicated to doing
the right thing.
all the things
you hear.
And the president
is very smart.
He remembered
everything from the previous,
I don't even know
how he did it,
frankly.
He would recall
the facts
of the previous time
I talked to him
if it was a month earlier
or two months
or whatever,
he'd remember.
So this time
I told him,
we know where he is.
He's in this camp
in northeast Iraq.
Now remember,
this is three weeks
before we invaded Iraq.
So I said
to the president,
he's here
and I had
the overhead imagery
of the camp
and I had
a nominated board
with all the
jihadist terrorists
that were working
with him
and him on the top.
His picture,
his mug.
And the president
who already knew him
well,
he said,
Rolf,
what would you do
if you were me?
Now,
when I briefed
the president,
I hope this is
reassuring to
your listeners
as I tried to make it,
I did it as a,
I did it as a citizen,
like I'm not putting
any of my spin
or influence
on anything
I'm telling the president.
There's no Rolf agenda.
That was my key test.
I had facts,
I had things to say,
I never went beyond the,
and that day
we had had
an internal discussion
on exactly what I should say
to the president
about what I'm describing,
including that
we shouldn't do anything.
We should let this play out
and I was too close
to the invasion.
But when he looked at me
and he said that
I started to say
what I was told to say
and he knew me too well
so he said,
look,
I don't want to know
what they are telling you
to tell me.
What do you think
I should do?
What were you told to say?
I was told to say
we shouldn't bomb it,
we shouldn't attack it
because it could,
you know,
the invasion
and I was already,
because I was obsessed
with this terrorist.
I was obsessed
and I knew that
it was an unhealthy obsession.
I had been known
to be slightly obsessive
in work,
you know,
hopefully not other things.
But it turned out
that,
you know,
my look betrayed
because I was so zealously
telling him,
here he is,
here they are.
He says,
no,
I mean,
what would you do
if you were me?
You're telling me
not to do anything
but you're saying
something else.
I think you're
thinking something else.
So I looked at the director
and he just gave me the,
like,
he asked you the question.
He didn't ask me the question,
he asked you the question,
you answer the question.
And I looked at the director,
looked back at the president
and I said,
Mr. President,
I'd bomb it.
So nobody said anything.
He just went on a meeting.
He didn't seem nonplussed
by the whole thing or anything.
We're driving back
in the director's car
to this agency headquarters
and he says,
well,
oh,
I said to him,
well,
should I have said that?
He goes,
he asked you,
you told him,
I have no problem with it.
He goes,
typical.
Now when you get back
to our building,
you make sure you tell
everybody what you said.
And of course,
there's no,
one thing I liked,
I think I emphasized
in my book,
the right and the wrong
and who's to blame
is so much less
on our minds
when we're doing things
than people think it is.
Like,
we're just trying to make,
do the right thing.
And sometimes we do
and sometimes we don't.
Speaking of this
pivotal moment
and at least
from the
kind of public
perception,
you know,
intelligence failure
or wrongdoing,
people think of the
overall invasion
of Iraq,
which is not,
you know,
for the audience
at all what you're
talking about
with this targeted
bombing of Zarqawi.
They think of that
as an intelligence failure
because they think of
us as having tagged
Saddam Hussein
with weapons
of mass destruction
when he never had any.
And,
you know,
maybe at most
he used,
you know,
biological weapons
in Kuwait,
which is horrible
and he was,
you know,
a very bad guy.
But,
you know,
maybe this was
this kind of,
you know,
huge waste of money,
lives and,
you know,
created this kind of
void or vacuum
for which ISIS,
you know,
ironically,
to actually like
take root
and,
you know,
which kind of ended up
radicalizing the region
even more.
So,
yeah,
I'm sure you were
thinking deeply
about this
at the time.
What do you think
happened there?
I struggled with
whether I should
include this,
but I consider resigning
when we invaded Iraq.
Really?
I noted that
briefly.
I didn't get into it
in any detail.
So you were against it?
I was against the war
philosophically,
but some of my colleagues
were also feeling
it was going to be
a disaster.
The idea that
we didn't know
that it would
turn out badly,
I think most people
who had the most
experience knew
this was going
to turn out badly.
Now the decision
to do it,
at least I believe,
and I can't say,
there's a lot of,
there's a split decision
of views on this.
I don't see any
intent for the administration
to deceive anybody
that by saying
Saddam had WMD
and he didn't.
It was a failure,
a massive failure
to conclude that
it was based
on bad sources,
which is usually
the origin
of all bad decisions
in intelligence
when you have
dubious sources
or bad sources.
These were both
sources that didn't
know much
and were over-representing
and fabricating
information,
we call it,
when you're making
up information.
And on that basis,
we made a terrible
decision,
is my view.
But it was exacerbated
by the idea
that even if it had
been the right decision,
the result probably
would have been
the same because
we couldn't control Iraq
like we couldn't
control Afghanistan.
and it didn't take,
and I have a chapter
in my book
where I'm talking
to the vice president,
Dick Cheney,
who I got done
exceptionally well
also,
where he just called
me in a weekend
from the White House
and I came in
on a Sunday
to talk to him
about why are we
losing the war
by the summer
of 2003.
This is six months
after our invasion.
But I didn't say
what I was really
thinking was,
you know,
sorry Dick,
but if you don't
know what's going
on here,
I can't help you.
And then I was
really like worried
that we didn't
seem to know
what we were up
against.
And that was
the real shocker
to me of Iraq
wasn't that we
made a mistake
in the invasion
side,
as bad as that was,
is that we didn't
know what we were
getting into.
What's the most
on the brink
the world has been
that you can
talk about?
Well,
you know,
the Soviet Union
had collapsed
and the biggest
worry in Congress
and in Washington's
mind,
which we had
almost no inkling
of in Moscow
where we were
actually doing
the work,
was that one
of these nukes
would end up
in rogue states
or terrorists.
And the U.S.
government at that
time launched
a heroic,
really heroic
effort with the
Russians to try
to account for
every nuclear weapon.
the so-called
suitcase nukes.
Nukes aren't
just missiles
that come in
and destroy the
world.
That's really
the answer
to your question.
My biggest worry
was the world
would blow up,
literally.
There's nothing
fun about trying
to stop
terrorists with nukes.
There's certainly
nothing fun about
trying to recover
nukes in a country
that's just lost
control of its
entire empire,
like Russia had
in 1991,
2, and 3.
So I'd say
that answers
two things.
It answers
kind of what
the big,
there are a lot
of things to worry
about in the world.
You know,
there's biotechnology,
there's AI,
there's nuclear,
but nuclear weapons
are still,
for me,
the king of the hill
because it can
happen that fast
and we won't even
be aware of it
if we're not
really serious
about stopping
it from happening.
Yeah.
Yeah, I mean,
we're in a scary
world right now
where you have
all these kind of,
you know,
this asymmetric
warfare and all
these capabilities
and then all
this ability
for if you're
China or Russia
or some sort
of larger adversary
to gain plausible
deniability and
act through
sort of rogue
actors.
But I want
to back up
and just talk
about you've
had these kind
of mystical
downloads and I
want to talk
about the first
one.
You were kind
of a nihilistic
youth at West
Point.
Yeah.
What happened?
Well, you know,
there was a
point in my life
when I was,
I combined my
interest in
knowing truth
and to an
extreme where I
was receptive
to whatever
input I would
get to the
point I pushed
myself to an
extreme.
I had had
experiences where
I had dreams that
came true and
I realized that I
started thinking
about consciousness
and subconsciousness
and these were
things that were
affecting me in
terms of being
receptive to the
idea that there's
way more out there
than we see in
logic and reason
or even if you
add intuition to
that, right?
And so at West
Point, I did these
dream experiences.
I talk a little
bit out of the
book.
They were kind
of childish in
a way and not
very scientific.
But then when I
graduated, I went
to Fort Knox as
an armor officer.
I was going to go
to the Czech
border as an
arms guy and
they started to
become much more
vivid and the
first briefing I
got actually in
the army, a
secret briefing,
was on the
Russian nuclear
threat in Europe
at that time
because I was
going to go out
and be what they
call the covering
force.
We were literally
the closest American
forces on the
border to confront
the Soviet hordes.
Now this was in
1976, so we're
talking eight years
after the invasion
of Czechoslovakia.
So everything was
very real and
palpable.
And the Germans
were depending on
us to defend them
and the whole world
in a sense.
And part of that
briefing was the
idea that we had
tactical nuclear
weapons we would
fire on them if
they invaded.
And I was a shock
to me.
That was my first
introduction to
nuclear weapons in a
context of war,
which nowadays when we
listen to, where this
would have gone full
circle, we listen to
Vladimir Putin talking
about using nukes in
Ukraine, we have to
think about this idea
of nuclear weapons.
The tables have been
reversed.
Back then we needed
them because we were
afraid of being
invaded and he's using
them now what he
regards to be if
Russia's existence is
threatened by NATO
in the West, he would
use them too, which is
really what he said.
So the point being at
the time I'm in this
kind of mode and my
friends and I are all
going through this
together, the ones
that, four of us,
kind of the four
horsemen of the
apocalypse.
And so I had this
incredibly vivid dream
in the midst of all
this at Fort Knox
where I dreamt that I
was in a battle, like a
battle of Armageddon.
It's the first time the
mystical things turned,
I would call, turned
religious or, you know,
religious history when I
became a big advocate or
hobbyist in eschatology,
which means the theology
of the end of days,
which I kind of, now I
hobby in it because it's
such a, it started then
the roots of it, but I
didn't understand that at
the time.
And it was just such a
vivid dream.
And in the dream, these
numbers appeared, so there
were no voices.
I couldn't hear anything
and the whole, everything
was black.
So I'm in, I'm in, in a
dream state or scape in
which I can't see.
I could sort of smell like,
you know, the acrid smoke
and things like that, that
was around me.
And I was aware of these
forces gathering for a great
confrontation.
And in that sort of context
of, I would say an
apocalypse, it didn't
necessarily have to be at
the time, but I saw these
numbers roll out in cubes.
And it all was around
seven, four, seven.
So the number seven, four,
seven becomes a lifelong
number for me, like, like
an, a mystical, a mystical
number.
What does it mean to you?
To me?
Well, I, I don't know
actually, which is one of the
reasons I wrote the book.
I don't know, but my, I
think it has to be a divine
number.
It has to be something
related to what I later
became, which was a
watchman for terrorism and,
you know, these kinds of
things in my professional
life.
In my religious life, I was
getting more and more
interested in understanding
what these numbers would
mean.
So I've done everything
from read Nikola Tesla's
obsessed because the
numbers were three, six,
nine, 12, 18, 27, and
40.
So they're cubes.
So first you get seven,
four, seven.
First I get seven, four,
seven.
Then these cubes kind of
are circling in the smoke.
They were cubes.
And the cubes were these
numbers, three, six.
Well, the three and the six
were one cube, but they
kept spinning.
So it could be three or six
or nine or both, right?
Because they turn, right?
I would never realize that
if I hadn't seen it.
You know, it sounds silly
because of course they
could, but it was not a,
and then the rest of the,
well, all of course, except
for 40, a variation or a
multiple of three.
Uh, three cube, 27, you
know, three, nine, 12,
12 tribes, 40 days and
49.
I started to ascribe what
had to be religious
meanings, uh, to the
numbers.
I, I, but I didn't
understand why I was
receiving them.
Like what was the point?
You know, I began to
think as, as I lay it out,
I tried to do it in a
very systematic way in the
course of my book when I
would see the numbers and
why in subsequent, but
you asked me the first
time and I have to say a
word of my wife before
I'll say how the numbers
get completed.
Um, cause that wouldn't
be till I was in Germany
after the course.
When I met my wife, she
was a German, uh, just
girlfriend were carousing.
She was as nihilistic as I
was for lots of reasons.
And we were just party
animals.
Like we had no interest
in like long-term hookup
or what became three kids
and nine grandkids and in
our life, 54 years up to
now.
And she's in many ways
the opposite of me, just
practical, get stuff done
to this day.
I mean, we're like real
opposites.
I'm philosophy, philosophical
kind of all over the
place.
She's like on the feet on
the ground, get you
through the, you know,
with our kids, everything
was always that way.
And it served me great
cause she, I had a
tether and she'd always
reel me back in.
But that night she was
really disjointed and she
woke up and she, cause
she's always joked.
She's an average.
And I never told her this
dream.
I didn't want my
girlfriend to think I was
completely nuts.
Right.
A logical thought when
you're 19, 20 years old.
Of course.
And, uh, but she wakes
up, she goes, I just had a
really strange dream.
I said, what?
She said, well, we were at
the Schwandorf, which is the
town next to the town I was
garrisoned, which is
Umberg, Germany.
And Schwandorf was less than
a half hour away.
And there was a, like almost
a large church on a hill
there, Catholic church.
And she said, I was in by
the church.
Now we had gone, that was
our favorite discotheque was
in that town.
And we met all our friends
there three, four nights a
week.
It was like, you know,
robo-carousing party time,
as I'm saying.
And she said, it was night.
I was alone.
You weren't with me.
I'm never there without you.
She was never in that town
without me.
And she said, but I was
going down an alleyway along
the church.
I knew what we knew that the
geography of it, you know,
it was coming down a big
hill.
And I went to the end of
this alleyway.
And as I came, approached
the end, dim light, just
some lights on the church
on the side, I saw your
desk.
And I approached the desk
and there was a chair
behind it.
And the desk was facing me
and there were numbers,
cubes on your desk with
numbers on them.
Whoa.
And I said, I started
almost hyperventilate, but
I didn't want to say
anything.
I said, do you remember
what the numbers were by
any chance?
She said, well, how could I
forget?
Of course.
It was like I woke up with
all the numbers.
That's why I just woke up
because I remember it was
three, six, nine, 12.
No way.
Yeah, yeah.
It was the same numbers.
Same numbers.
One additional number, 49.
Wow.
So now, just to say one
last thing on my wife as a
witness, like for me, for
no one else, for me, I
needed this.
It's almost like a sanity
check.
I said, well, I told her
then, of course, about my
dreams.
I'd never told her that
before that.
To this day, 54 years
later, oh, 55, 56,
whatever it is, 1978 is
when that started.
She said, well, I don't
want to read your book.
I don't want to talk about
this anymore.
She had that kind of a
reaction to it, but it
doesn't in any way
diminish.
She knows the truth of it.
She knows the truth of all
of it because she was a
witness to all of it.
Everything in my book,
the earliest mystical
experiences were around
numbers and war and the
final sort of bearing
testimony to the truth
because you have to, again,
I stress to everybody, don't
start thinking you're having
these things.
You need very deep
authentication, very deep
testing of your own mind.
Are things like this true or
not true?
I just want to assure
anybody listening to any of
this that I put myself
through all that in great
detail, at great depth,
test, test, test, test.
In the end, you start to
know, is this of God?
Is this of God?
That's the essence of it.
If it's of you, if it's of
your imagination, if it's of
someone else putting in your
mind, it could be anybody.
Did she have any prior
knowledge of the numbers that
you received in your
download before she had her
dream?
No, no, none.
Wow.
And the other part, which,
you know, you know what, I
had to actually test my
mind, because remember, all
this is happening in the
non-interrediator.
I couldn't look anything up.
But right after my, you
know, in the same time I'm
having these dreams, two
other things that now inform
me, that's all they were
there for me, a perfect
stranger walked up to me in
a fish restaurant.
It was a Long John Silver's.
I don't think they're around
anymore.
There's a fish restaurant,
like a fast food restaurant
called Long John Silver's.
But you go there for fish,
which I rarely did.
I go to McDonald's.
But one of our friends
says, so the four of us
were gathered, the four
musketeers, or my friends
that, the West Point
graduates who all went to
Germany together and all
experienced all these
things, I'm saying, and
partied together.
We're sitting in the
restaurant, and this guy
walks right up to me, who
I describe in the book, and
says, read Ezekiel Daniel
Revelations, and walked
away.
We all looked at each other
like, okay, I mean, you
don't, there's nothing you
do with that.
It's just like, that's very
strange.
But it's coming at the
same time all this other
stuff, which you knew
nothing about, obviously.
When we first started selling
merchandise at
AmericanAlchemyMerch.com, we
had no idea how
complicated and annoying
selling merch could be.
We talked to a dozen
different platforms and
companies, comparing
shipping tools, payment
options, website builders,
and it all felt like way more
of a headache and complicated
than it should be.
We decided on Shopify, and
within days, our store was
up.
Everything was running
cleanly in an automated way,
so we could just focus on the
brand and the vision we had
for it.
That's when it hit us.
Ideas don't scale on
inspiration alone.
They need a structure, a
container.
Shopify provides that
structure.
It quietly powers millions of
creators and brands, about 10% of
all United States e-commerce.
From big names like Gymshark and
Mattel to solo creators building
from their bedrooms.
Shopify made it simple to build a
store that actually feels
authentic to us, which matters
when your brand lives in a niche
like alternative tech, UFOs, or
fringe science, and when you have
a very clear brand vision.
Plus, their AI tools help write
descriptions, organize products,
even clean up photos, so we can
focus on what matters and what we
care about, building the best
custom merch line possible with the
coolest designs, like our UFO
cowboy tee and the atomic age tee.
Plus, Shopify handles all of the
unglamorous, more painful stuff.
Shipping, returns, email marketing,
all in one clean dashboard.
It's like having a silent partner
who never sleeps.
Our favorite part of the product is
the dashboard, which gives us
complete demographic information.
We can see where our orders come
from, making it easy to know who our
most loyal, consistent customers are
around the world.
That's just one example, but Shopify
really makes your life easier.
Bring your next idea to life with
Shopify quietly handling everything
behind it.
Sign up for your $1 per month trial
and start today at
Shopify.com slash Jesse.
Again, that's Shopify.com slash Jesse,
J-E-S-S-E, for a $1 a month trial.
It's just $1 a month to try Shopify,
the state-of-the-art solution in
e-commerce.
And the final experience, which is
just the basis, this is just the
foundation for things in the future,
was when I was at the course getting
a lecture on the assembly and
disassembly of the M60 tank engine.
Now, you have to understand at the
time, I'm very nihilistic or whatever,
but I'm also very, I've always been
very creative and always wanted to be
a writer, even at that time.
So I'm imagining, and I was so bored
in the class, I was like, that's what
I realized, I'm not very good at tank
stuff, you know?
I mean, I ended up being, you know, I
learned forced learning.
I was good at my profession as a tank
commander of troops in the army while
I was in it, but I didn't really like it.
And this was the worst of all, which
was learning about maintenance-related
things on tanks.
So I'm writing, I'm doodling, and so I
decided to, oh, I'd come up with a name
for myself as an author.
I'll be Frederick Wolfe.
So I wrote Frederick Wolfe.
Now, that was in honor of two things I
admired at the time.
You know, you're, again, young, this is
like typical of the way I was thinking
at the time.
Nietzsche, who was my favorite, Frederick
Nietzsche, Friedrich Nietzsche, but, you
know, Frederick, kind of adaptation of
Nietzsche, who I'm obsessed, I was
obsessed with, even at West Point, I go
through some stories of Nietzsche, maybe
because he fit this idea of, you know,
to know yourself, you have to free
yourself.
You have to free, and even of God, you
have to free yourself of all constraints
on who you are and confront yourself as
to who you are, which was also a theme
at that time of a lot of the novels,
fiction I like to read, particularly
Hermann Hesse at the time in
Steppenwolf.
So the wolf came from that.
Frederick Wolfe, ah, the man searching for
his true nature, his true character.
I'm willing to lay it all out there as
a, you know, again, brask, brash guy.
And so then I said, what would be my
first short story?
I'll write it here in this class.
Well, I decided, I called it On
Suicides, Suicide Note.
Why did you choose that?
Well, I thought it'd be, I chose it
because it seemed like a really dark,
deep theme to write about it.
So I imagine the note was the note I
would leave if I actually committed
suicide.
So it was like, if I left a note now
because I don't, you know, I don't want
to encourage this thinking, anybody out
there, and it came to my senses, so to
speak, but I was getting into the
novelistic.
In fact, the irony was I've never in my
life felt in the slightest bit suicidal
ever, ever.
And I attribute a lot of that to my faith
and belief because I'm also an
inveterate optimist, even in the future
of the world.
Even with all the dark things I've
talked about, war and apocalypse and
Armageddon, and I'm actually very
optimistic about it because it's all
tied to this God I know is a loving
God.
This God is the creator God, means
everything around you in nature, you
can see God and how wonderful it is.
It's this personal God you can talk and
interact with who loves you, who wants
you to love him.
So how can you not be an optimist if
that's your perspective?
So I had that perspective, even that,
because I hadn't forgotten the
childhood things in my life that made
me feel that way.
But I'm going to go down this dark
road because it's interesting.
And one of my inspirations was Camus,
the philosopher, who was obsessed by
the question and mused that maybe the
only really relevant question to think
about was, is life worth living?
Because you have complete control of
your life from that very basic way of
looking at it.
And I, and I, so I wrote this thing
and, and that's when I had these
dreams, uh, you know, and, and at that
same time, this is all happening
concurrent with what I've talked about.
So I realized I was getting in way too
dark, way too deep.
It was, and then the dreams were
exacerbating my, my thinking again,
never got negative or self-destructive.
That's the funny part.
And I'm convinced I could have kept
plowing down that deeper, deep, that
tunnel deeper and deeper without ever
hurting myself or any, anybody or
anything, but that's not necessarily
for other people, something I would
advise.
Right.
Uh, but it all culminated in, in the
next day I saw, I gotta clear my head.
Let's go play golf.
So we were all terrible golfers, but
we like to go hacking at golf at, at
Fort Knox, they have military golf course
right on the base.
So we went golfing and you can look
this up if you need to, because I
couldn't for years had to actually look
up on the internet.
But what I experienced as we're, as
we're golfing, it was going to be a
stormy day.
You know, of course that fits, it has
to be a stormy day with thunder and
stuff, but we went anyway, you know,
being irreverent.
And at one point we reached a, I'm
trying to get, shoot to the hole
straight over this cemetery.
And of course the ball hooks, there's
an iron hooks into the cemetery.
And, uh, I, you know, I'm feeling very
non-respectful, just been in a bad mood.
Let's just put that way.
So I, I remember climbing over the
wall, I go over and wondering where
the grave is, the ball.
And I saw it sitting right centered on
this very, very small gray oval grave
in the ground, you know, and I walk up
to the ball, it's right centered on the
ball.
I said, I wonder who's trapped my ball
kind of, that literally was what I was
thinking.
Like, again, really tempting fate, you
know, I was really tempting fate.
And it says Frederick Wolf, German
soldier died November 5, 1944.
I had no idea who this guy was or
what, but I know that my birthday is on
November 5, 1954.
Whoa.
And I just dropped my club and
completely, um, freaked out by the
experience at the time.
Cause I realized there's no way that
could be, you know, coincidence.
That's the night where I had the 747
dreams.
That's fascinating.
Did you try to find anything out about
the historical Frederick Wolf?
Yes, and I did.
And it was, he was a German soldier who
after World War II was sent to Fort
Knox as a prisoner of war.
And he was involved in like a little
mini German uprising over conditions
there.
And he was shot by the guards, you know,
and killed.
And, uh, then he was of course buried
there.
I don't know why he wasn't, his body
wasn't sent back to Germany.
I never found that level of detail, but
it became also kind of this like very
interesting connectivity because I was
going to Germany.
Well, I mean, what do you, do you think
there's something apocalyptic going on?
Because you, yeah, you, this guy goes
up to you, he says, read Daniel, Ezekiel,
Revelations.
All of those books are kind of notably
apocalyptic.
Right.
You're dreaming of this sort of Armageddon
like thing happening.
Well, yes.
And, and, and, and the ways I would tie
that together would be, so the first
apocalyptic, well, future dream.
Now we're talking Ezekiel, Daniel,
Revelations.
I mentioned the person who walked up to
me at that time.
I, that's another thing I did.
I filed that away and I didn't think
about it much more, but it was always
there, you know, I kept it there.
It's going to serve a purpose later.
I didn't think that at the time
actually, but it did.
And one of the purposes was after 9-11,
I realized, oh, I get it.
I'm Ezekiel's watchman.
It's my duty to warn the people,
which is really the quintessential CIA
officer's role.
I mean, it is in a very modest way.
I don't want to make this sound too
huge, humongous.
It's just, that's what we should do.
If we don't do that, there's not much
purpose for what we do.
And I realized it was much more specific
in my case because my first dream,
which I chronicle in the book, was
Sadat's assassination on September 6th,
1981, where I was in, I was there.
I was on the scene when he was gunned
down in a parade field.
The interesting thing about it, I
wasn't thinking about Assad.
I didn't even know the event was taking
place the day he was assassinated.
And of course, given the time change
between where I was at Fort Bliss, Texas,
at the time as an army officer, it was
right before I joined the agency,
and where he was killed in Cairo, it was
the exact timing.
I woke up in the middle of the night,
having had the dream, and I remembered
it in every detail, watching in slow
motion while gunmen pulled machine
guns out of their cloaks and, you know,
shot him dead, and a number of others.
And I pictured this thing.
So I couldn't verify any of that until
the next day.
Again, no internet, no.
And it was reading it in the papers.
Did all the details line up of what
happened?
Every detail, including the timing.
It was just impeccable.
And I did do one additional thing.
I woke up.
Was there an example of like a small
detail that you dreamt of that was
corroborated the next day?
I think, well, the main, the most
important detail, which I was tying into
9-11, was among the, it's never been
entirely established, but it certainly was
in my mind that Eamon Zawahiri, who
was, of course, the deputy head of Al-Qaeda,
later the chief of Al-Qaeda, was bin Laden's
lieutenant, right?
He was one of the conspirators that pulled
it out.
And I, I mean, weirdly remember him and
another guy named Saif al-Adil, who was the
number three guy in Al-Qaeda.
Now, he's the head of Al-Qaeda.
So two of the people I pictured in my dream
became the heads of Al-Qaeda after bin Laden
was killed.
And you know they were implicated in Sadat's
assassination.
Well, it's not 100%, but I did in my dream.
But you can, if you Google it, you'll see
they probably were.
So it's like you remote viewed the event or
something, or time traveled.
Well, it felt like that.
And it felt like it because it happened at
the same time.
And the more important thing is...
Or bi-located or something.
Yeah.
Well, I had no, I had no reason to be
thinking of this.
This is the other, I think, compelling
thing.
Many experiences, particularly as you get
into the Virgin Mary and things that later
happened to me later, there was no logical
explanation why I went in that direction
except for the warning theme.
You know, the warning, the idea that was
building up to a series of serve as a
watchman, serve as a messenger.
Let's try, I want to go through the
numbers themselves because I think they're
fascinating.
And, you know, I think of 747, you know, we
were talking earlier, actually, before we
started rolling, you have the seven-story
mountain is by Thomas Burton.
Right.
And he is one of many mystics where the number
seven is this extremely important number.
I just had this guy on, Peter Lavenda, and he wrote a book called Stairway to Heaven, which
is a book about celestial ascent traditions across history.
The Merkabah, the, you know, the Ziggurat, the Hekalot, the Arit, you know, all of these things contain seven levels.
Even esoteric orders like Rosicrucianism, you have to go through seven levels and leave a garment at each level or whatever.
It's always discarding or passing a test at each level.
And so, you know, I think of seven as sort of, you know, something celestial.
Right.
And then four is the ascent or conversion into matter or something.
And then seven is like the, you know, the re-ascent into the celestial.
And so maybe there's something around fallen angels or fallen celestial beings, you know, the fall of man or something.
Right, right.
That seems really important with that, that first number.
Yeah, yeah.
Well, I, I, I think that's entirely, you know, not only plausible, but I, I think the, the track you're on is, is probably true.
I mean, it's hard to, you just have to continue to explore it and see what insights it, it renders.
That's, that's the bigger challenge is never to think of it as reached a conclusion, a continual journey and almost a non-ending journey to infinity on, on these subjects.
But to understand, to see the associations may be more important than being able to analyze the association completely, thoroughly.
Because if you, the moment you thoroughly analyze it and you're, you're sort of done with it, it means you've closed your mind to other possible interpretations.
And since we're in such a broad vista of reality, it's really what it is.
Exploring a reality that's very broad, which is not a lot of evidence we have through our normal application of language, logic and reason, which is why, again, numbers help because they take communication on a far more objective level.
If you're, but most people, including me, we're not, not that facile at using numbers in the ways that the real geniuses can with numbers and the people have defined for us what the numbers mean just for physics.
I marvel at what some of the great mathematicians have produced and the insight they've gotten from just looking into things that seem to have no purpose, much less something with a purpose.
So I think, I think you're onto something there.
Well, let's keep going.
So then you, then you have three, six or nine is three, maybe, have you, I mean, have you thought of the Holy Trinity?
Of course.
Father, Son, the Holy Ghost.
Um, six or nine, six, you know, the amount of days, you know, before the earth was, was created, maybe in Genesis or something.
Does nine mean anything to you?
Well, it's three threes, you know, it just continues a pattern of where there's a, a, a, a, a, a emphasis of three, um, you know, 12 being lots of things like 12 tribes and 12 tribes.
Yeah.
You know, uh, how about, uh, 40 days and 40 nights, of course, the temptation of Christ among 40 years for the, for the, for the Exodus from the Jewish people under Moses.
I mean, there's just lots of religious significance, but I, I hesitate to, like you've done well.
I mean, you know far more than I do about the way it ties into other fields, uh, and other potential explanations that broaden really from religion.
One thing I've done, uh, with, with ongoing satisfaction, I have no conclusion, is reach out to physicists that have, I've had a number of physicists contact me, read my book.
And, and those are very interesting, or I've given my book to some other physicists and through my time at Department of Energy, I spent three years as the head of intelligence and counterintelligence at Department of Energy between 2005 and eight.
And then beyond that, especially when I continued the nuclear stuff, but expanded it a great deal.
The EOE is an incredible organization.
Uh, we have the, what they call the, the America's national laboratories, all based in Department of Energy.
So I, it's been an amazing ride for me to get connected to all these incredibly smart people who could probably be doing anything.
Don't have to work at lower pay in most cases for, for the U S government doing things, but do it because they want to serve the country too.
So there's all those kinds of people out there that I get to know, but the physicists that I, I've given them a challenge, which is kind of what you're doing with the numbers.
I said, look, I, you know, read my book or you read my book.
I now want to know more than ever, what's the physics behind mysticism.
There have to be physics behind it.
It's not something that belongs to a different reality.
It's part of our reality.
It happens in this world.
Therefore there has to be an E equals MC.
It has to be a quantum or relativity, space, time, all have to be taken into account as to what happened and what it, how do we explain it?
Have you ever gotten a satisfactory answer?
Uh, nothing that I would describe as answering the question, but I have gotten the kind of encouragement I need that it's not a silly question.
That's kind of what I'm looking for.
Uh, it's not, I mean, the most interesting scientists, whether it be Einstein or, you know, Heisenberg has an apocryphal quote that's often attributed to him where it's like the first sip of the science, you know, the bottle or whatever, um, leaves you an atheist.
But when you get to the bottom, you know, there lies God.
Yeah.
And, uh, you know, so, so, okay.
So that's good.
So they don't think it's all, you know, that's like a bad, that's a bad framing at least for, for inquiry.
And you know what Einstein said, I want to know God's thoughts.
The rest are details.
Wow.
That's a great quote from Einstein.
That's a really great, great quote for somebody who's, uh, you know, theory has basically become the modern scientific paradigm.
Right.
And, uh.
Well, I think all, almost all the great physicists, or I would say were great ones that I certainly have become hobbyists of.
I'll never quite grasp the full math and science aspects of it, of course, but like Paul Dirac, you know, people like that.
People, I, I encourage people to, to, which I used to do when I, you can imagine a, a lay person like me, not a scientist or taking on weapons of mass destruction and trying to stop terrorists from getting bombs and biological weapons.
And one of the biggest, uh, skeptics, you know, skepticism I encountered was the Russians were really good.
I went to Moscow to lecture them and brought a bunch of people so they could stop this stuff in Russia and other places.
And it's one of the old Russians I knew from way back when we were catching and recruiting and catching spies.
Hey, you know, Ralph, we know, you know, you, you don't know anything about this stuff.
So why, why, why, you know, I said, that's why I brought all these other people.
Listen to them.
Don't listen to me.
I'm not, I'm not, if you notice, I'm not telling you the science they are.
I'm pulling it together because you have to, you have to establish science is irrelevant without the concept, understanding the consequence of science.
And I used to say that the DOE scientists quite often, if you can't explain this in layman's term and make it relevant to real people, like everybody listening to this, if we make it irrelevant to them in their lives, then we've lost our sense of mission.
So the idea with, with, with, with the, the idea of the physicists, I asked them, I tasked them, I would call it jokingly, come back to me with some plausible explanation.
The biggest roadblock I've encountered from talking to real men of science on this or women of science is they say, well, the problem we have is you almost have to create alternative, um, not universes per se, but a space in dimensions in the universe in which things occur that we can't experimentally measure.
Right.
And that becomes our problem because good physicists will say anything I can't experimentally confirm or measure is, is not.
And, and I would say, this is me talking, so I may, anybody listening could easily contradict me on this if they know more, but I've reconciled quantum and relativity, you know, as a problem of scale, nothing else.
It's just, to me, it's the idea that you're measuring things at two different extremes, but the underlying reality, there's no conflict.
It's the same reality.
Yeah.
Measured in different scales.
So we have to start thinking of when we have these mystical experiences, thinking of them as things that happen at scale, but maybe there is no time and maybe there's not even motion.
Maybe the idea of an angel of going between two different, that's why we put wings on angels, right?
It's a tradition.
Is this, is a medium of, of coming from a world at rest into a world in motion and needing to somehow cross over that divide and that barrier.
That's just the way I think of it.
So I haven't, I haven't solved any of these things, but you asked the question of how do you think of them?
And all I can say is you, you open your mind to all kinds of potential explanations.
And the truth is probably, you know, everybody, you know, I come from UFO world.
You talked about your history at the DOE and we will get into some questions there, but, you know, I think a lot of people in, you know, in that world think of the truth as something to be disclosed.
Like you can say it prosaically.
And I don't think that's the case at all.
Right.
Like, you know, I always find it interesting, you know, St. Thomas Aquinas was like working on his Sumo Theologica, this like rational explanation of, of God.
And I think he had this conversion, you know, kind of moment while he was in mass.
And it was like this mystical experience.
And then he like stopped speaking after that.
There's a, there's a scientist.
I think his name is Mishka Gregory Perlman.
And he's like in Siberia right now.
And he, he's like known in like theoretical physics world is like one of the top, like best guys.
And I've even talked to some people who are like, you know, if anybody's like sitting on like a, you know, a theory of everything that like marries, you know, general relativity and quantum mechanics, it's probably this guy.
And like, he, I think he claims that he has like a unified theory and he just won't talk.
And so there's, there's, there is this some, something very interesting about, you know, it's so on, you know, maybe the truth is just so hard to like grapple with.
And there's, there's a translation function between like what a, what a person knows and then what they can even describe to, you know, the world.
Like that's a, that's a really hard thing, um, to, to, to, to do, you know, to, there isn't some Archimedean point where like everybody instantaneously gets it all at once.
And it's just the semant, it's a semantic truth, but, um, yeah, anyways.
Well, the only thing I'd add to that, cause I think that's so important too, is, is as you approach unification of like understanding the nature of all reality in some equation form or something that could be expressed through physics or mathematics, you are in fact getting closer to what I would describe as what I think of God as.
Which isn't the head of the Catholic church or the Protestant church or whatever, it's, it's the entity of the creator God and the personal God.
And on the creator God level, I mean, if you know, on the religious side of that, the idea of God, Yahweh, you couldn't even say it.
So you, you develop a term that you couldn't even pronounce.
Now, so it gets a little bit backward, like a Pearlman who's, if he is at some level where he can no longer talk about it, that I tend that, I think that tends to happen when you reach a point of insight that just, you're, you're overwhelmed by the profundity.
If that makes sense of what you're looking into.
I want to switch gears because we've talked forever on all this stuff, but, um, you have had direct experiences with the Virgin Mary.
And that is a really rare thing for somebody with your background and in your position to say, can you go into those experiences and describe them as sort of viscerally as you can?
Yes.
For me, it's the most important part of the book.
This episode is sponsored by Superpower.
On this show, we spend all of our time trying to understand reality.
But most of us are simply guessing when it comes to our own health.
With conventional healthcare, you're firing totally blindly.
You go to the doctor, you get a few basic labs, and you're told everything looks normal.
But that thing that doesn't feel great, the chronic headaches, the stomach pain, the back pain, you don't ever really get insight on any of it.
You don't get the proper data you need.
You get no actionable insights and no real plan.
That's why Superpower caught my attention.
Superpower gives you a deep look at what's actually happening inside your body.
It's a single blood draw, either at home or a nearby lab.
And they measure over 100 biomarkers, way more than a standard physical.
You get real data on things like hormones, metabolism, heart health, vitamin and mineral levels, even environmental toxins.
Toxins that can accumulate and cause very bad things to happen in your body.
What I like is that Superpower doesn't stop at the numbers.
They turn those results into a clear, personalized action plan.
What to focus on with nutrition.
What supplements actually make sense for you.
Lifestyle adjustments.
You can even get your true biological age and can track how that changes over time.
Instead of guessing when it comes to your health, you finally have a map.
Your full health blueprint activated with Superpower.
Not only did Superpower reduce their price to just $199, but for a limited time, our listeners get an additional $20 off with code ALCHEMY.
Again, that's $20 off with code ALCHEMY.
Head to superpower.com and use code ALCHEMY at checkout for $20 off your membership.
After you sign up, they'll ask you how you heard about them.
Please make sure to mention this podcast to support the show.
So what the story was, in 1991, when I was in Greece, I went on a pilgrimage to Monathos, Greece, which is an Orthodox mountain that's something akin to the Vatican in Greek Orthodoxy, Orthodox world.
It's 20 monasteries on this amazing peninsula that juts out by Thessaloniki up in northern Greece, right?
And I got a three-day diplomatic visa to go with the Diplomats Club.
But I did it with a calculation in mind, a work-related pretext, which was I had been given a tip by a Greek very close to the president, Prime Minister of Greece,
about a monk at Monathos, who was actually a Russian intelligence officer, who was getting cover and changing his identity to go on a mission to the U.S.
on behalf of Russian intelligence and would be undercover at a Russian Orthodox church in the U.S.
to do God knows what.
But he would have, you know, just wonderful cover to be in the U.S.
So it was an amazing tip.
I didn't solicit it or it came to me.
They came to me with the tip and handed me the file so I could read it.
And then I resolved to go up there and investigate through direct, you know, direct contact.
So you're looking for this spy who's going undercover as a monk in Mount Athos.
And then you go to Mount Athos.
And then what happens?
I'm going through an all-night, experiencing an all-night service at the small Catholicon of Monastery Dionysio,
which is one of the monasteries on a huge cliff.
And I was just, they were very relaxed on, you know, how, I wasn't Orthodox to begin with, which the monks all knew.
I was just a visitor.
I just described myself as a Christian.
And so I go out and I'm sitting at this, and I fell asleep, sort of napping on this stone chair facing the church, little church on the hill.
It's a stone courtyard, all stone courtyard, very severe, very severe looking, thousand-year stones, thousand-year walls, a thousand-year throne that I'm,
it was the only chair, I'd call it, carved in the stone wall.
And I'm sitting at it.
It reminded me of the scene out of, like, Conan the Barbarian or something, you know.
It really was that kind of a feeling.
And with the waves rushing, crashing against the sea, crashing against the walls, way below, hundreds of feet below me.
You know, and beautiful, just absolutely gorgeous.
You know, amazing, mesmerizing, balmy day.
So I'm just relaxed, sitting there, fall asleep.
That's when I immediately went into this dream state.
I realized this is one of those, like, that's what had started to happen to me.
I knew when one of those meant it was not a usual dream.
So your description of, was it time travel?
I mean, I would say that's a possibility.
I mean, I don't know.
I can't.
But I felt like it was something happening.
And first, you go to 1800s Paris.
Yes.
I go to 1800 Paris, and I'm just walking down these 18th century Paris streets, and I'm walking to a brothel.
Yeah.
And I just want to see what's going on.
That's kind of a typical me thing.
And that's when I encounter what turned out to be the Virgin Mary.
Didn't call herself that, but I just felt that without an introduction.
And this one open door was, door was open, and it was like all the others.
It had, like, a waist packet with soiled condoms and things, you know, and it looked awful.
It was blood on the sheets.
And I was thinking, oh, this is awful.
And I looked at the woman, and she just looked at me with these imploring eyes, just like the suffering of the world was on her, weight on her shoulder.
What better place to be to feel that with the exploitation and things of this place?
And it just, the gravity of that hit me, because I'd also seen a scene where, like, a rotund priest is, you know, of course, this is coming unbeknownst to me, you know, kind of at the height of the sex scandals in the Catholic Church and things, too.
So I don't, I'm not tying these things together, but it just, it was very depraved, and I felt, I felt the depravity, I felt nauseous in my own dream.
And then, yeah, I walk outside the brothel, and this guy, meet this guy outside, and he says, basically, you're odious maximus, and go atone for your sins kind of conversation I have with this guy, Harry Hiller, which was one of the characters from Herman Hesse's Steppenwolf.
And Harry Hiller basically encourages me to go to Mount Athos to sponge myself or find clarity or salvation or whatever the, whatever I could find.
So, okay, so you're in 1800s Paris, you meet Harry Hiller, you see this scene, and you're confident that this is the Virgin Mary in this brothel because of...
It was a conclusion I reached, not at the time, but only after it became a pattern, if that makes sense.
So at the time, I wasn't entirely sure who this old woman was, other than she didn't fit.
And I could feel the suffering, which became a common, every encounter with the Virgin Mary, there was an element of the weight of her suffering for the world, for the fate of the world, in particular for the fate of people who are suffering, for the pain and the agony of others.
This is the common feeling I had, each of the experiences.
But I didn't know that at the moment, I just knew that, wow, this is certainly disruptive.
You know, so when I continued the dream...
Did you feel love coming from her or she...
I didn't particularly feel love.
I felt more pathos.
Like her ultimate empathy for everything.
Right.
And all suffering and all beings or something.
Nothing so much directed towards me.
What I think I put in my mind more than something she, a vibe she gave, was the idea that, man, I shouldn't be here.
Did she say anything to you?
No.
Do you, have you thought of the symbolism of her being in a brothel where all this kind of, you know, corrupt, you know, horrible deeds are being done or whatever?
Like, do you think of that as somehow significant?
Well, yes, I mean, certainly not at that time again, but certainly looking back, I realize how it fits so well into the subsequent encounters and the pattern being, okay, you want an image?
You want images of what I mean by suffering?
This is the image, right?
What can be worse?
There's very few things that are worse than that.
But certainly the Holocaust, there are things that are worse than what I, what she, she showed me the reaction everyone should have to this or her reaction to this reality of the world that I was seeing with her at that moment and sort of stumbled upon.
So then when I went back in time, it became kind of a, then it became kind of a disappearance of time to put me in the right state of mind to do the, the exploration I needed to do at Mount Altos.
So the rest of the dream sequence that I outlined in, it's called the bizarre world of Odius Maximus in my book, because it's how bizarre I felt when I knew it was still me, but I'm going now into this, I have to adopt this cover of a character, so to speak, which is a CIA thing anyway.
So I should, but it was so, it was so unique, unusual and unique to me that it was really scary.
I wasn't sure I could not be that character.
I wasn't sure that it'd ever be Rolf again.
So then I'm going back in time as I'm traveling, as you would in those days to Athens and then from Athens to, and with every step I'm taking, the time is going back in time.
And, and by the time I get to Mount Altos at the capital city, which I had sort of landed in when I came off the boat in real life now and to where I'd had the dream a couple of days ago getting there, I saw that town again, but back in, back in the 1500s, you know, and I go there and I
present my credentials, so to speak at the capital to say, if you will, the governance people there, including this guy, Monk Gabriel, who was the head.
So Harry Hiller is this character that's in 19th century Paris-ish.
Paris, I leave him.
You leave him, he said, but he says, you are odious Maximus, you must go to Mount Athos.
You go to Mount Athos, and then all of a sudden you're like a few hundred years earlier in history.
So like 1400s, 1500s.
Correct.
Trapped up there, essentially.
Trapped up there.
Was there a gradient of time moving backwards from the 1800s to the 1400s or 1500s?
Or like all of a sudden you're in Mount Athos?
No, it was a gradient.
It was a, it was as if time was evaporating.
It was a way, like with each step, you could, like it got, that was what was so, I would say, very unnerving,
was going back in time, but feeling it happening as it's happening.
And it's getting, and I was trying to adjust, but it was getting too difficult to do.
So I tried to limit any contact with anybody, like on a ship or on a coach or as I'm going back,
because I didn't want anybody to say anything that would think I was some insane person and throw me in some.
You also don't want to alter the future forever with changing a variable or something.
I did not think that, but that's a good thought.
I did not think, I remember not thinking anything profound.
It was like pure survival.
I remember being in pure survival mode, including, I would say, my mind.
I was, I hoped I wasn't losing my mind to the point where, you know,
whatever the, say, inspiration was to adopt this way of thinking of myself
as being a very onerous, bad person, that I would overdo that again.
I mean, that wasn't really the point.
I kept reassuring myself, but I would have to play this out.
So I get up there and I describe this and long and short of it, the monks take me in,
even though they argued against it.
But this Gabriel, he saw something in me and he said, we're here to, like Peter said,
open our house to those who need it.
This, this man needs it.
So I get assigned to the monastery at Dona Dionisio,
which is where I happened to be when I was having the dream.
Do all, does all of this feel as real as this interview?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
So it feels like any sort of real experience that you've had, it's indistinguishable.
Pretty much.
It's, there are things that occasionally in all the dreams, like the, the Sadat dream,
and I'd had other, you know, dreams also, which I lay out pretty much all of them
that I can remember in the book.
I had a dream of a basketball game dream, even like when I was a teenager.
And when I did, I knew immediately a qualitative reality in those dreams was close to reality,
but I could usually still understand it was a dream, if that makes sense.
So in this dream, I still knew I was in a dream.
And I could still distinguish the Rolf I was from the character going back in time.
So, but otherwise, outside of that, it seemed totally real to the point where I don't think
there were historical, like you've seen movies where there are things in, in movies that shouldn't
be there at a historical time.
You know, I didn't see telephones in the 16th century or things you shouldn't see, you know.
Were you wearing your clothing from?
And it changed.
It was changing.
It was going back time.
So your clothing was becoming more and more appropriate for the time.
Well, I also found myself, and I don't remember specifics on this, trying to find more appropriate
stuff.
So I wouldn't look like a space traveler back in the 17th century.
You know, I was trying to, like a person would do to try to fit in.
I was trying to alter my look and things like that.
I was getting a beard because I didn't shave.
You know, I remember those kinds of details.
So when I'm at the monastery, then it got deeper and deeper into what monks do, which
I learned a lot about through the dream, but also through what turned out to be two
trips there, spending a grand total of a month in Monathos.
That's the end, at the end of the story, that's what it consisted of because I got, of course,
very into this understanding, not just a dream, but then the encounter that followed, which
was the idea that you live a life in a monastery.
A lot of people just sort of quickly jump to the conclusion that's world evasion.
You just want to avoid the world.
You want to go off on yourself.
It's very selfish.
So I understand people when they say that about monastic lifestyles.
I don't feel that, in large measure, because I had this dream where I experienced it on
such an intense level, because for some people, it's the only way they can pursue God.
It's the only way they can be close to God.
It's the only way they can get themselves closer to God.
They don't give up on the world in most cases.
They're not doing it to avoid the world.
They're doing it to get close to God.
Sometimes there's a consequence of those other things when you do that.
So I felt that.
And so when I experienced the life up there, it was not experiences I had felt spiritually
before, which made, again, this was a new reality I was learning from.
It wasn't just adapting what I already knew and living it vicariously as a monk.
It was something very different.
Through the character I became in the monastery, I was growing.
I was developing.
I became a recluse up there.
You know, I learned to fly.
You know, and I remember, and I've talked to other people who have had the flying experience.
That's a different conversation we can have one day.
Because I've had reactions from people who read that part of my book and said, oh, I've done that.
I've been able to fly, you know.
For me, flying was a manifestation.
The more I think about it, I see it as a reward almost in a way.
A reward you're not asking for, but it's a tribute to opening your mind.
And when you're flying, you're spiritually open.
You're just in a different state of consciousness than you are when you're just praying, if that makes sense.
And what we talked about even right before the interview is what I didn't expect to find was,
as I went through the whole experience here, is the flying monk and I burned my hut up there,
like all the things a recluse does.
Were you doing, you were burning your hut there?
Yes.
And so this is happening across months or weeks?
In the dream, it's months.
In reality, it's the course of the dream, which that's easy for me to do years in a dream.
But in my dream state, it was weeks, days went to weeks, went to months.
And so you are aware that your reality has drastically shifted from 20th century Rolf, CIA, case officer,
to, it was trying to catch the spy on Mount Athos, to, it's like you entered a portal and you are here for days upon days.
And you are going to sleep and waking up within this.
Yes, within the dream.
That is fascinating.
Well, the biggest thing about it was I knew at the time I had to dream, as I was dreaming, that I was dreaming and I might not be able to get back.
That was the scariest thing was I felt trapped.
And I wasn't sure I was going to wake up.
And at one point, I told one of the emissaries, so this Father Gabriel, who I got to kind of know, sent this other young monk called Evagrius, and he would come and meet me.
And I remember my encounters with him, and he was encouraging me, and we were talking all the time.
And I remember some of those, I just put snippets of them in the dream, and I frankly forgot some of them.
But I just knew that it was really alive.
It was my only contact with a human being when I was at a recluse stage, which was when I was doing the flying about.
And he told me, yeah, the other monks had seen me and wondered if it was real.
So I remember that stuff.
It was just so palpable.
But then I, of course, had three dreams within a dream.
And now we're reaching the culmination of the, as I would call, the fruition of the dream.
The point of the dream was what follows.
The farther I'm getting away from myself, the farther I'm detaching my faith in God from a selfish interest in me, that's when I start flying.
That's when I start, my spiritual growth is happening when I'm being less selfish, when I'm joining, sort of I call, the general universal salvation idea of mankind, if I'd call it that.
And the more intense my spiritual experiences were getting within my dream, to the point that I had three dreams within a dream, and very quickly, because one, and they're very intense.
One night I go to sleep in my dream, and I have a dream where I'm in the middle of a big room, and we all have to go pick numbers from what looks like a barbershop number thing.
You pull the number, and I got my number, two-digit number.
Oh, I don't remember the number.
It's too bad.
It would have been great to add to the number collection.
I was so frustrated I forgot the number, but it was a two-digit number, and everybody got a two-digit number.
I thought, well, this is very strange.
There are way more than 20 or 99 of us here.
What's the number?
Nobody explained anything.
Nobody talked.
It was just murmuring, walking around.
Then I woke up.
The barber shop clanged with the number.
I pulled the number up.
I woke up from the dream, and was in a dream.
It startled me.
So then in my dream, the next day, I go to sleep in my hut, and I have another dream.
It's the second dream.
Now in that dream, now I'm standing in the room again.
It's a big, round room with seven doors.
And I'm looking at my number, and I just had this wild thought, which I had never thought religiously, like until the dream.
And I thought, man, what a bummer.
I mean, we're all going to go through these doors, I guess, and these numbers must be, and we were wearing clothes.
They issued clothes.
And I had fine clothes, I remember, with brown suede shoes.
Yeah.
And some people were with rags.
And I saw an old woman in the corner, who, again, I thought, is this the Virgin Mary, the same woman I met in Paris?
I didn't know.
So I don't want to overstate it.
But I thought, is that her?
And I said, well, I don't know.
We'll see what happened.
I kept my eye on her, but I didn't want to go up to anybody or say anything.
It was like, everything in this, I was just like trying to survive.
It was really, I was trying to survive, even in my dream within a dream.
And then the doors opened.
Seven doors opened, and we had to walk through the doors.
And I remember thinking the heretical thought, like in a way of doubting God again.
What if my number's like right under the ones that are going to heaven, I'm going to hell?
I mean, imagine missing by one number.
But it's kind of a stupid thought.
Like, if the situation were real, that's a real thing.
If there's such a thing as heaven and hell, right?
Which I've never believed after this and other things, that there's such a literal thing as that.
I think heaven and hell is in your mind.
But partially because of this.
So then, boom, wake up again, startled by this.
The doors groaning and having to walk through them.
And then the third dream is walking through the door.
And I remember it very carefully, particularly when I reread it, you know,
last night, actually, where I'm standing at the beach.
And it brought it all back to me really clearly.
It was a dark, dark night.
Not a star in the sky.
I remember that.
But the sun, it was bright light.
I thought, well, the sun's not up.
But it was a bright light on the other side of the...
And I remember thinking of the contradiction that the sun's not out.
What's that light?
It wasn't the moon.
There's something very bright on the other side of the shore.
And it was like a river kind of thing.
A river, like a wide river.
And it was turning dark.
And I could tell, well, we were all being encouraged.
We knew.
No one was saying anything.
And now I'm saying, you had to walk across the river to the other side.
Which I took, at that time, I thought, this must be salvation.
The test of salvation for all of us.
And I'm walking on the top of the water, like Christ, you know, in Galilee, you know.
And I'm thinking, oh, this can't hold me with my brown suede shoes.
And I, but it started to work.
And I said, well, if I put all my effort into my faith, maybe I'll make it to the other side.
And then people are, I heard plunk.
It was a terrible sound, like somebody going into the water and being swept away in the depths.
And you couldn't see below, except like an inch below your shoes.
And I was wondering if I stupidly think of my shoes are getting wet.
I remember thinking that.
I was like, oh, these shoes are going to get ruined.
They're going to be stained.
I really did.
And then, you know, sure enough, I get halfway across and think, I can do this.
I can make this.
And then the old woman's right next to me.
And she stumbles and loses her step.
And I instinctively just tried to grab her arm to hold her up.
And we both went swept away and I woke up.
The Virgin Mary.
Well, I don't.
What you interpret to be the Virgin.
What I interpret, probably.
Because it tied into the, but then the final scene is that I wake up.
Like this is the, I'm done with the dream.
That was, getting swept away was the final part of the dream.
So I wake up at the throne sitting there and I realized I saw a light in the church.
This was like this from distance, maybe we're going to say six, seven yards or whatever it is, 15 feet to your windows over there, right?
That's where the wall of the church was with the windows, stained glass kind of windows I had.
And I saw this red light moving along the thing.
And I got up out of the chair and moved toward the window and it had gone all the way up to the front, you know, of the church, the altar.
And was sitting there burning, you know, red.
And now I think, but the lights were related, the light and the red light, of course, of the model and the red light of Mary.
So I attached all the Marys together in the dream.
This must be this.
But to be clear, I had never seen the Virgin Mary.
So I saw the dream image of her and then I saw the light, which I took to be.
I took that light immediately when I saw it.
I talked to a monk the next day.
I said, I saw this mysterious light in the church after it was closed and it moved from here to here.
I thought he would just say, oh, are you dreaming something?
I said, well, I was awake, I said.
But he said, no, he said this.
It was like his name was Monk Timotheus.
And I ended up going back to him.
I'll seek him out.
And he ended up taking me back to his cell that they call it where they live, their little like bunk in a stone place, really, really austere, you know, rugged kind of living conditions.
And he had like 10 books on his shelf.
He gave me three of them about Athos because he said, I just want you to read more about this because this seemed like you saw that for a reason.
He goes, there are monks who have said they've seen this is the light of the Virgin Mary going down the thing.
And it seems like you might have seen that.
I don't understand it.
He was very confused by it because he said, you're not even, he even tested me and said, you're not even Orthodox, are you?
He said, no, no.
He went through that.
He said, well, I don't know, but I'm not going to doubt it.
And that's when he gave me, and I kept those books for, I still have those books.
When you wake up and you're at the church and you see the red light and maybe that's somewhat symbolic of the Virgin Mary.
Yeah, yeah.
Is that in 19, is that 1990s or is that?
Yes, that's 1991.
Okay.
So you basically, you go back to 1800s Paris, then you go to Mount Athos.
Mount Athos is days turned into months.
You are odious Maximus, this monk who goes through all these kind of ascetic protocols and you're fasting.
And you say you're burning your huts and stuff?
Well, then I finally requested permission to go away from the monastery and just be a recluse in the wild, in the wilderness.
You know, like there's a tradition there.
Some monks go out and they just separate themselves from everybody, even their fellow monks.
And the only time they see anybody is they come in to get provisions or medical emergency or something.
I mean, they don't completely abandon all ties to civilization.
If you call that civilization, they just limit it as much as possible to get even closer and closer.
And, uh, in fact, I ended up meeting a recluse who I feel was like kind of a full circle experience that I actually met a real recluse the second time I went to Mount Athos and, uh, who gave me a book and tremendous conversation we had about the apocalypse.
I mean, here, normally people get together, I'm sitting on a curb, you know, with this guy and talking about things.
And he's asking me who I was and where I worked and I have a family back in this day.
And he said, I haven't seen anybody in a few weeks.
This is kind of nice.
He was carrying bags of, um, he's carrying some, some lettuce and one bag, plastic bag.
And the other bag, he's carrying a baguette, you know, he's going back to the wild, into the woods.
But anyway, he stopped and chatted me up.
And the next thing you know, we're talking for a couple hours on, turned out into the apocalypse and everything else.
And it was amazing.
Like we both had studied the same books about this, but that's, that's the side.
That's just the idea of what it meant when I went into this room.
It was almost like I needed this full circle, which is so much of the story for me, where things are explained later.
So when I, at the time I saw the light of the Virgin Mary, I mean, I honestly didn't think that much of it.
It was a light.
Maybe it was a light.
Even the image of the old woman, maybe it was her, maybe it was not her.
So I had all those things, you know, the dream itself is the way you describe.
And that has its own, it's its own story in a way.
But it wasn't until two more things that happened with the Virgin Mary that it all came together.
It's fascinating.
And you also then come to realize that there had been Virgin Mary apparitions all over Mount Athos?
Not at this point.
Okay.
That was, but later you were.
I had talked to people there later, everything was later, including the story of the Virgin Mary being on the mountain that I'd learned and wasn't until 2006 or seven, 2007, that I heard some of the backstory of the history and lore that included the site.
So I'll save that because at this point, I don't know any of this, including, I wasn't ready at that point, prepared in the sense of thinking it would happen to me.
So there was no predisposition, for example, to actually meet the Virgin Mary or understand what, you know, like what has happened historically with the Virgin Mary.
Some people ask me that, well, when you started to have your Virgin Mary experiences, were they in any way because you read about, you know, Lords or Fatima and all this?
I said, well, I honestly knew nothing about any of that at this point.
And this was 1991.
What did you find out later in 2006 and seven about the Virgin Mary showing up at Mount Athos?
Because I think it's very fascinating that there's some historical corroboration on other people are experiencing what you're experiencing spiritually in this specific location.
Well, I find out that there's at least a legend lore that they have at Mount Athos that the Virgin Mary, after Christ was crucified and rose from the dead, was traveling along with other Christians at the time, or apostles, around in ships.
And, of course, they were all based in Corinth and places like that.
So she was on a ship on its way to sea of all things, John at Patmos, and also to go to Cyprus because Lazarus supposedly fled Israel when the Romans started looking for him because they wanted to execute him as being this person who rose from the dead.
It was a very disruptive idea that Jesus was going around raising people from the dead, right?
It was the reason why both the Jews and the Romans saw the early Christians, they called the way at that point, they weren't called Christians, as being saboteurs, disruptive to order and society.
So they were hunting him down, actually.
So he fled, apparently.
And I didn't believe that story either until, I believe, I didn't like, maybe it's true, maybe it's not.
And there's actually, if anybody listeners goes to Nicosia, Cyprus, I urge you to take a look at the Lazarus's tomb, which is supposedly in Cyprus, where he went and became the first bishop, starting the church in there.
So Mary was supposedly traveling on a ship, and there was a big storm, which that part of the Aegean is famous for that, going all the way back to the Spartans and the Athens, having a huge summer storm that ruined fleets and everything, shipwrecked fleets.
And she got blown on the island of Monathos, and there's a monastery placed on the site where she supposedly landed, went ashore, called Evaron, on the, it's on the west coast of this peninsula, at that monastery, in the south part of the monastery.
And I've been to that monastery, but it wasn't until this 2005, 2006 period, when a monk told me the whole story about this little icon in a hut right on the shore, that this hut, this is supposedly the spot where she landed at that time.
Wow.
Wow, this has got way more.
And of course, I've sent my book and gotten letters back from the Vatican and also from the Orthodox Church hierarchy in Istanbul, Turkey.
And the letter I got from the Orthodox Church was really priceless.
It said, basically, you know, we wish you had become one of us and still joined the Catholics, but we still consider you, you know, a friend of ours, and your book is in our library, and his eminence is Reddit and all that.
Because I really appreciated that, because I've said to many people, the accident of me being Catholic or Orthodox is not what any of this is about.
Right?
And I think they appreciated that.
And Mary belongs to the world, not to Catholics or Orthodox.
Orthodox, in Monathos, they consider her the whole object of the veneration that the mountain is dedicated to, which is why women to this day can't go—and I think this is misguided, just to put that out there—but women to this day cannot go on Monathos, step foot on Monathos, because it's dedicated completely to Mary at the exclusion of all women.
As I said, I think this is veneration that goes too far.
But the point of it is to emphasize how fundamental Mary's history and role is—
Have other visitors or pilgrims experienced Mary that explicitly, just like you there at Monathos, specifically?
Yes, yes. And I can't enumerate their examples, but I know it's not a unique phenomenon. So much so that I would say, like I'm having with you, Jesse, this is highly unusual to have an easy conversation on these subjects, right?
You can do that. Most people can't. What's been very gratifying is that I never bring it up, the subjects, any of these subjects almost, except the just, you know, obviously the intelligence and all history and all that I do, but any of the religious or focus on God with anybody who doesn't bring it up.
And then I usually bring it up, and I found some very fascinating takes or additions that people have to make on what I've said that they've experienced.
Like a really close friend of mine, I would never have expected this, came to me especially to say he's had very vivid dreams of flying after reading about that part of my book.
And it's very gratifying to hear. I've also had more basic things of people saying, you know, why would you join a church with all this that you describe yourself in your book as having all this sex abuse and this and that?
And I said, well, I said, I never give up on the church like I never give up on your faith.
But those kinds of conversations have been the great gifts of writing the book.
So while you're at Mount Athos and you're this character, Odios Maximus, what do you feel like it is?
So you feel like it's your mission to get closer to God by sort of detaching yourself from the contemporary world in some ways?
And so what are you doing on a day-to-day basis?
You're fasting and you're praying or what's your day-to-day life like?
And again, this feels as real as you waking up, you know, in, you know, Maryland where you live, right?
Yeah, well, I remember feeling a bit of a contradiction of feelings.
On the one hand, being there and doing things like tending to the grapes and cleaning the dishes, you know, until I become a recluse.
But then it's just trying to survive in the wild and, you know, that kind of thing, doing like continual prayer or that kind of thing.
But up until that point, I'm thinking, I mean, I'm also miserable.
I want to go home.
So I never lost the feeling I wanted out.
Do you feel stuck?
I felt stuck.
Yeah, I said that a few times.
But I felt very stuck when I was in the recluse phase.
But I understood without any, like, there was no messaging or voicing or, which I've never heard, by the way, with mystical experiences, any like audio.
It's interesting, real audio, real talking words.
But it was the idea that I needed to do this to go home.
I needed to go through these different levels of this experience and the dream before I could.
No one said that.
But I knew it.
I knew that until I had gone through the different levels of what was expected, I couldn't go.
It was almost like it was a spiritual training.
I mean, the Jesuits call it their spiritual exercises that they go through.
This was much more intense than the dream.
How old were you as Rolf when you went back, when you time-traveled as Odeus Maximus?
How old were you?
In my real life?
Yeah, in your real life.
So it's 1991, and I'm born in 54.
So it's, what, 40?
Yeah, 37.
Interesting.
Yeah.
And so you're communing with Gabriel and the other monks as well.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Did you ever tell them, hey, like, I'm kind of trapped here.
Oh, I, the only, yeah, no.
I actually exist in the future.
No, no.
It was like a cover.
I was living my cover.
Until, at the very end, near the end, after, you know, in one of the times I wore the brown suede shoes in my dream within a dream, and then they were suddenly under my hut.
So they're in the dream now.
They had gone from the dream within the dream to somehow peering in my dream, and that was very discombobulating, right?
And at that point, when Evagrius came back on another, to check on me, make sure I hadn't plunged off a cliff or something, I told him.
And I told him who I really was, and I remember the reaction.
I had to, by the way, I never knew exactly all, some of the things I said, but I knew that all of it was consistent.
So when I had to create dialogue with Evagrius on this scene in my book that I don't remember exactly what the dialogue was.
As with waking memory.
Right.
So I did with my best.
So I don't want anybody out there to think I've got this photographic memory or anything, but it's very close.
So what did you roughly say?
The main thing I remember that I based the dialogue I created on was, and to be true to that, was the idea that Evagrius was wise beyond his years.
He was a young, spry little monk, wise beyond his years.
And when I told him the reality, I did it because I knew he was wise, and I needed somebody to tell, and it was him.
He was a someone I could trust.
And he reacted in a way that redeemed my idea that this was a good time to do it by basically reacting as I would have hoped, which is, I hope you get back to your family and keep praying to God and God will take care of you.
And in a way that I suddenly felt a sense of peace, knowing this wasn't going to go without somebody knowing what had happened to me, and maybe I will get back, because I think this guy would offer me some wisdom and insight into that, and he did.
Did he freak out at all and say, what, you exist in the future?
No, no, no.
Did you say, there's this place, it's called America, or the United States, and it ends up breaking off from England in 1776?
Did you have to go through any of that?
Or he just kind of took it on its more spiritual dimension or something and kind of ran with it?
Well, Jesse, there was one thing.
No, I didn't do any of that, but I made a big slip up early on that I realized, and nobody called me on it.
I think they knew there was something really wrong.
Going back to my presentation of my credentials, so to speak, to Gabriel, when I said I was Odeus Maximus and all this stuff, I'm not who I was.
But I did say something really absurd, where I said, you know, I'm an American mystic, because I knew I had to present myself as a mystic, because I wouldn't be able to go through any grilling on doctrine or theology or stuff they might expect.
So I had to play the mystic card, and then you maybe don't, or you can grunt, or I was going to fake it in a way that I knew I couldn't if I had to actually explain my knowledge of liturgy or anything else.
And they saw through it, and he did, but he had pity, right?
That was the earlier description.
But I said at the time, I'm an American mystic, thinking I came from this continent, that didn't exist, right?
At least in their minds, nobody said anything.
And so when I presented the story at the end, my real name and future, I'm from the future, to this monk, he seemed to take it all in stride.
And it's really interesting, because if there are people, I think, who understand the notion of future time travel, there's no super religious, no, super spiritual person, at least in the Christianity, I think all of them.
Honestly, and the monotheistic religions, who aren't able to separate time from discussion in a way where they're comfortable with the idea of past, future.
Because for one thing, the most credible witnesses to what's going to come and what the past means are the prophets, right?
It's Ezekiel, Daniel, Revelations, John, it's Christ, who talked about the raising of Jerusalem.
It's the history of the church is in question when people—in fact, even Christ himself said he can't predict when the future ends, or that's up to God.
So there are limits, and I don't look at prophets as soothsayers in the, you know, sort of Shakespearean tradition of Ides of March, or—no, prophets are those who concede into the future what happens.
They don't influence it, if that makes sense.
Do you think, right now, as we speak, Rolf is also Odius Maximus, living in 15th century Mount Athos, Greece, trying to, you know, commune with God?
And, oh, wow, that's those—see, now we're getting into fun stuff.
But, I mean, everything I've said is a product of—
You could speculate, you know?
And I will, and I'll just say as a preface that everything I say on this subject is not—is really philosophical science.
It's drawn from my greatest love intellectually in the world, which is philosophy, which is what?
The love of wisdom, right?
The love of knowledge.
And so, in that spirit, I think that it's possible.
And my experiences bear this out for me, that the dreams we create are as real as the physical reality we're in, which means the answer to your question would be yes.
Because if I dreamt it, and I created it—
And it felt real.
It didn't feel—
And it felt real, and I created it.
Now, the more you get into whether you're taking a trip, so to speak, in reality versus—like, I make this great distinction, which I'm not sure is as great a distinction in as bright lines as I make it, between when I met the Virgin Mary and when I've had interactions.
Just like when you pray to God and you think you're getting responses and telling—versus actually, like, meeting God.
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
But let's go a little deeper into this Odius Maximus example.
Do you think that that is a real historical figure?
Yeah, I know he is.
That was one of the ironies.
So, to my great shock—great shock.
This was, like, a wonderful shock.
I went—when I went back to Athos in—so, one of the things Mary said to me at the end of the experience in Paris in 1998, I neglected to mention it the first iteration, she said, we will meet again, like a reassurance, we will meet again.
So, I said, oh, this is so great, you know, because this is like—this is the highlight of my life kind of thing.
And part of that would be, come back and visit me at Mount Athos again, where it all started.
So, it took me a long time between 1998, took me about seven years to go back.
I said, what, seven years?
Isn't that interesting?
And I went back to Mount Athos, and back at the Holy Mountain, only because I felt the Virgin Mary would now be my tour guide.
So, I did something kind of extraordinary.
I got the Greeks to allow me.
I knew the—I was still, like, with CIA, like, associated with CIA.
I was at the Department of Energy at that time, by the way, head of intelligence there.
But I still had all my contacts and friends at CIA, including the guy who was head of our office in Athens, right?
And I lined it up with him.
He's a close friend of mine, and he's also, interestingly enough, a religious scholar as CIA officer.
But he lined me up with a month-long visa.
Now, normally, someone like me, I could only get three days.
And I'd gotten one, and I'd never get another one.
But he had his contacts, and he explained my past, and they were like, oh, this is good stuff.
And I got a month.
So, I knock on the door, carry us.
I feel like—I feel a little like Alice in Wonderland or something, and sort of my mentality, right?
I'm going back, and just like, I'm just going to soak it all in.
And I feel guided the whole time.
And unlike most people, I didn't have to register what monastery I went to, what nights.
I just go one of the 20 of the monastery, and they have a number of what they call skeets.
Skeets are like miners.
They're not considered monasteries.
There are one or two monks there, and they're safeguarding a specific tradition or history of monathos.
So, for example, it was one—and I wandered and ran into these things.
It's a huge peninsula if you look on the map.
But I was wandering around and running into these things like I was being guided, and I felt like I was, going from place to place, showing up unannounced, spending a night going off into the woods.
By the way, just as a hiker-adventurer, it's like one of the most wonderful places on the planet.
So, I end up at St. Anski, which is where St. Anski is named in honor of Mary's mother, Anne.
I didn't even know that historical fact at that time.
Now, later, I would—many things.
So, I got into biblical archaeology and lived in the Middle East.
I got into all of this stuff.
And just as an aside, I didn't just do biblical archaeology of meaning Christian.
I did Old Testament, Judaism, Islam.
Did you try to find certain relics of that?
Oh, I tried to find all kinds of—but anyway, at St. Anski, they claimed to have her bones, some of her bones or whatever.
So, I mean, I'm kind of fascinated with that stuff, too.
And then the next day, I take off from there.
I said, well, I've been introduced to Mary's mother.
That would be something she would want.
And so, I take off from there, and I go down the coastline.
I catch a boat, go around the corner, the horn of Mon Althos.
And I end up at this bottom of this pier with a big walk up the side of a mountain.
And coincidence, right?
Coincidence is this monk walks by with a donkey who's going to go up there.
Little monk, and I've got my big backpack.
And so, come there a month, I've got a big backpack, one backpack for the month, but that's, you know, I've got everything in it.
And he goes, hey, why don't you take my donkey to the top of the mountain?
I said, this poor donkey, you sure you want to do it?
He goes, oh, he's used to it.
So, the guy just slaps him in the rear, and off we go.
And I'm sitting straddling this donkey up this cliff, afraid, like, I wouldn't want to let the monk down.
I was afraid I was going to go off the side and off into a cliff, an abyss, you know.
It's that kind of a thing.
And then it starts raining, and it's getting very steady donkey just up the mountain.
Get to the top of the mountain.
There's nobody there.
There are no pilgrims.
I walk into the entrance of the skeet.
And this guy comes out, greets me, a young monk, probably, you know, in the 30s.
He's the guy, caretaker there.
And he goes, well, let me tell you this history of this skeet.
It's called the Skeet Kaflosovakia, Kasasovakia.
I said, well, that's hard to say.
It's a mouthful.
He goes, yeah, this is named in the honor of one of the saints we have here, Saint Kaflosovakia,
who was known as Maximus the Monk.
He was not odious, Maximus.
And he was known as a flying monk, and he burned his huts, and he had these miracles,
and they were sightings of him flying.
I almost lost.
I mean, not lost is not the right expression, but I had a gasping for air just at the thought.
I hadn't made this up.
So crazy.
This had a historical connection, and I was there.
Normally, you could go a month at a month off, because you never run into this place.
But here I was, standing right at the front door, so to speak.
Well, you were meant to have that running.
Well, by now, I'm not doubting things like that.
You can take, by the way, I don't want people to go now think everything that happens to them is not by chance.
But you also have to be attuned to the possibility things aren't coincidence.
It's not believing everything is not a coincidence.
It's getting the right—being able to make a right judgment of when things aren't just coincidence.
Yeah, I think discernment is viewing patterns and synchronicities as possibly very meaningful and being attuned to them,
but not always taking them at face value.
But, I mean, yeah, you could literally right now Google Maximus Katsikovia, and this is this flying monk from Mount Athos,
and he was known for burning his huts.
And so it is fascinating that you went back in time not having any—you had no context.
No idea.
And then you find real historical corroboration for this through happenstance, and this is just online.
Like, people can search this open source.
That's pretty remarkable and interesting.
Do you think this was—you know, people talk about, like, past life regressions.
Do you think this was, like, a past life for you?
Well, I haven't really thought of that.
I don't think of—I don't say—I don't believe in reincarnation, but nor do I reject it.
I just—I mean, I don't know.
I don't have—I do have a fairly strong discipline in submitting everything we've talked about to a high degree of scrutiny,
to the point where—and you and I have talked about this—where sometimes I'm reticent to say the full—to provide the full effect of what I think I've learned or what I experienced,
because I don't—I don't want to—the one thing I can't do is misstate any of this, because that judgment comes down on me from God.
Yeah.
And God knows.
So you go through all this trouble to tell a story about your devotion to God and how you fulfill your destiny as being to fulfill God's will and do the right thing and do right by people, which is what it all boils down to, really does.
I can't misspeak on that.
You know, so I'm not going to inflate or add to an experience.
So the idea of, like, I love exploring with you.
I'm just being careful for your listeners and others.
We could talk about that over a beer or something.
I'd go way farther.
I don't know.
I think there's evidence out there that's like all the things, all the phenomena you research, Jesse, it should all be researched.
We should be very chery of drawing conclusions to things that are—that we don't have really solid evidence for, but nor should we be so respectful of conventional wisdom and science that we don't explore it.
And you should also give yourself the grace to speculate.
A, you know, everybody has a game of telephone they're playing in their mind where they don't remember anything accurately that's ever happened to them one-to-one perfectly.
But also the ability to speculate, which I know you do.
Oh, I do, I do.
And the thing about these experiences that I've described is that they do form a pattern, and the pattern becomes a major part of their authentication, you know, as being genuine.
And truth-related things, not truth-seeking, rather than self-focused or self-fulfilling.
I think part of the dreams at Monathos that I experienced was a necessary part of my own faith-based development that I would—the more you discuss or try to convey a belief in God, the more you have to remove yourself as the object of your intentions.
This is one of the most important things I can say.
If you're, you know, one of the apostles who followed—and I'm not, I'm not putting myself on any level with the people I'll describe—you have to be willing to be a martyr to pull that truth forward and become part of human history.
Because God needed, Christ needed them to go out, as they did all over the world, in the way they did.
And they needed, in a way, one of the proofs they were willing to do is lay down their own lives for the truth.
And it's easy to say, lay down your life for the truth, but, you know, it's a harder thing to do it.
And the other thing is to not do it for their own benefit.
Because you can even lay your life down for the truth because you think it's to your benefit, but it's not even your goal.
At some point, you try to eliminate yourself.
The object of—the paragraphs I wrote of my time at Monathos in my dream, I tried to be very, very careful to describe the essence of what I was experiencing in the dream, which was this process of shedding myself.
It's the reason, when I read Meister Eckhart or somebody like that, he talks about looking down at God, not up.
It's a psychological thing, you know, ashes to ashes, dust to dust.
The more you can remove yourself from any honor or glory in faith, the closer—the more responsibility God will give you, if that makes sense, to promote the faith.
Because it can't be about you.
And there's a—yeah, well said.
There's a Yale professor, who's very well-respected, a religious studies professor named Carlos Ayer.
He wrote a book called They Flew, and it's all about flying saints and monks.
And St. Joseph the Divine, St. Joseph of Cupertino, is probably the most famous example.
I think he was 16th century.
You have Teresa Avila, who also seemed to experience, you know, bilocation and all these sort of other paranormal things.
Even St. Francis of Assisi, by some accounts, might have levitated.
And so this is actually—and this guy went into this research thinking, oh, you know, this must have been written about sort of historically in this sort of metaphorical way.
And he came out of it being like, no, there's enough eyewitness testimony around these flying saints to call it history.
And it's well beyond the threshold of evidence we'd need to say that, like, the War of 1812 was fought or whatever.
And I think he truly believes that.
And, you know, I have a friend named Diana Pasulka who's a religious studies professor at UNC Wilmington.
And she's gone very deep on St. Joseph of Cupertino, and she has gone through a lot of his files, and she agrees with that.
So—and it's across, like you said, it's across different religions.
So maybe this is a real phenomenon where you do shed the baggage of individual ego, and you become one with God, and you fly.
There's even, in fact, Jeffrey Kripal, who's a religious studies professor at Rice University in Houston, he was giving a lecture on flying saints at MIT.
Oh, wow.
And a guy who I've met, actually, who runs revolutionary technologies at Skunk Works, their most advanced R&D division, obviously, of Lockheed Martin, and he's running their most advanced R&D division of Skunk Works.
He attended the lecture and was very interested in flying saints.
That's so great.
It's interesting.
Yeah.
Well, I don't think there's any question that once you start believing in certain mystical experiences, either because you've experienced them yourselves or you've heard such compelling tales.
Like, I read Virgin Mary, which I didn't know, as I stress a lot, really the history of those appearances until now, of course, I sort of study them to look at the similarities, to hear the different descriptions, see how close they were to mine.
And then what's very reassuring is I see sort of so many similarities and commonalities.
But the point is, to your explanation, yeah, you've got to be willing to believe all kinds of manifestations, what I would call the holy, meaning things that are not of human construction, whether it's our minds or even what we call the laws of physics.
They come from something else.
What's the physics of that or where is that?
The where might even be, you know, not a real question because it may not be anywhere in that sense.
We understand location, right?
Because what's location outside of distance and motion and it's really nothing, right?
So is it over, under, or aside?
I'm sure it's relevant.
But then you're getting closer to all the mystics.
Because when they get together, I've read, you know, some really cool stuff and I'd love to be in one of those gatherings when Merton used to have them in Asia and you had Buddhist mystics and you had Islamic mystics and poets.
Hafiz, for example, one of my favorite, talking about his love of God.
And the heretics who were burned and things for going too far with things that were mystical, they couldn't help themselves because they were just devoted to the truth.
Their crime is always, which is why Elijah was sought in half, or is speaking truth to people who don't want to hear it.
Or sounding enigmatic because their prophecies or what they see in the future don't accord with the conventional wisdom of the day.
That's usually the problem.
Is there some version of that you think you have, some truth that from all of these mystical experiences you've come back with that the average person might have kind of an allergic reaction to or might not want to hear, might be an uncomfortable truth?
Well, I think, I think, frankly, an average person is probably uncomfortable with all of this.
Yeah.
Right?
I mean, let's be honest, right?
And it's the idea, well, who do you think you are?
It starts with things like that.
And it's, the mistake, of course, is over, over-interpretation or look, because I've realized also, this is just something I've learned, because I continue to occasionally have enigmatic dreams.
I don't mean anything as vivid as in the past, in fact, with age, it's less, fewer and fewer, which I, when I was living in the Middle East, I once went to my Jesuit priest friend, friend more than any, more than a spiritual advisor, and said, you know, I just don't know what my purpose is anymore now that I'm not meeting the Virgin Mary.
I said, I don't want to sound, you know, like I should be meeting Virgin Mary, but I sure miss it.
And he goes, well, have you tried praying to her?
I said, well, I don't really pray to the Virgin Mary.
I feel her presence.
But I pray to God, and I pray to, you know, Jesus Christ.
That's it.
I don't pray to other people or other things.
But he said, well, you can pray, but just don't get hung up on the word.
You can interact.
You can talk.
And so I asked, I said, well, you know, Mary, what's my, why am I here?
Like, why am I in the Middle East?
I have the sense I was praying or thinking that there's a reason I'm here, and that you brought me here, because why would we be here?
And I was spending all my time in five years in the Middle East, 2011 to 16, spending all my time on the road.
I did biblical archaeology.
I did, you know, went on tour.
I went all over everywhere many times over.
Then later on, you know, in Saudi Arabia, et cetera.
And I said, there's got to be a reason for this.
So I used to say, just, just tell me so I know what I should expect kind of thing.
And got back kind of a, again, nothing verbal or just an answer, which was, you're here to be here.
And it put me at ease.
It was the idea, okay, this is almost like, I don't need to overthink this.
I think in other messages, she says, don't, to you, don't strive, don't try, don't reach.
This was in, well, 1998 was when I, seven years after I met her at Mount Athos, I met her in Paris, met the Virgin Mary.
So that, none of this discussion would be occurring if I hadn't actually met the Virgin Mary.
And we call it the apparition, and I mean the Virgin Mary.
So I had a, was in Paris on a work trip for CIA.
I was doing actually Russian things.
I was heading up a lot of our Russian, CIA's Russian activity at the time, 1998.
And so I'm in Paris for those discussions with one other colleague.
And he, we both went, you know, we, we, we signed up at a big boutique hotel, five minute walk from Arc de Triomphe kind of, you know, place.
And no, not from Arc de Triomphe, from, from the American embassy down in the southern part of the, that lane, Arc de Triomphe down there, Hotel Crayon area.
And we're in the, I'm in the hotel.
It's a nice little room.
And it had a bed with a old fashioned hotel, really old.
And it had a table in front of me and had a light switch on the wall, but small room, typical French style.
And as I went to bed, thinking nothing in particular, except maybe my last thoughts before going to sleep was going through my notes in my mind of what we were going to raise the next day.
And, uh, as I like to joke, I didn't have any weird food or anything else and went to sleep and immediately was there, like in one of those dreams again.
And I knew it right away, but it was a dream.
I knew I was dreaming.
So I'm by a river bank.
So I'm thinking of the river dream from way back, which was a more raging river.
This is a nice, gentle, almost stream type river.
And I'm sitting at a river bank of grass, lush grass.
It's a beautiful day.
Again, balmy, nice weather.
I'm sitting on the top of the little, little mound that goes in, goes down into the stream and there's nobody around.
And I'm just thinking, just relaxing.
And then an old woman comes dressed in a brown, uh, brown cloak with a hood up and sits almost within touching distance, but just outside my reach.
And sits there and stares, looks ahead too.
And I didn't want to disturb her.
So I didn't like introduce myself or say anything.
I just thought, uh, maybe wait for her to say hi or something.
I won't do it.
And so we're just sitting there and then it starts sprinkling.
And it was, the sun stayed up.
The sun didn't go away.
So I thought it was just a little sprinkle when the sun's out.
And it's, as it's hitting my skin, I remember hitting my arm and hands first.
I see brown, like oozing brown dirt.
And I thought, wow, this is really kind of strange.
And then I looked to see what reaction the woman was having to this strange rain.
And, and I, at that time she, when turned towards me and I felt this kind of ease, I felt really at ease and I felt kind of backwards, like almost like, whoa, into her arms.
And then I realized it was a Virgin Mary.
And I thought at that moment, I thought, okay, it's a dream.
Um, and I think this rain is like, I don't know, purifying me or something.
I just had that weird thought.
So then I wake up, so I wake up in my room and I get up to turn on the light because I need to clear my head.
You know, it was very jarring.
It was very jarring in a nice way, but very jarring.
How did you know it was the Virgin Mary in the dream?
I just knew it then.
You just knew it.
I just knew that was the Virgin Mary.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Unlike the other things I said.
Where you weren't as sure.
Where I wasn't as sure.
This, I knew right away, this was a Virgin Mary.
Because I had had the one experience too in Portugal where I met the Virgin Mary, but not in the flesh and in the mind kind of thing.
So this was like completely normal to me now.
The dream, that I would have a dream like this.
It was not no longer some, maybe what all this was, was preparation, right?
Because all along the way, I was getting more and more used to the idea that this wasn't strange.
None of this was strange.
This was all part of a sort of a process in a way.
So I get up on the, from the chair, I hit my shin.
I forget, I hurt my shin bone as I got up.
And that's how I kind of knew I was awake.
And then I saw this, like, like we're sitting in a room here.
It was in that corner coming from the top of the corner, a light coming down like this.
Radiant light.
And Thomas Merton described the light better than I could when I read it in one of his books.
Because he had some of these experiences.
It was a light so bright that it bore no resemblance to visible light.
If that makes sense.
So it didn't shy, you'd have to look away from it, it was very bright.
And it came and sat straight in front of me when I was standing up.
I was still standing up where the curtains are, like right across from me when I'm standing there.
And off the ground was the full image of the Virgin Mary.
Wow.
In your room?
In my room.
Wow.
So she was in the dream and then she comes into your room?
And I knew, as I was standing there, I specifically had the realization, clear, absolute realization, this is not a dream.
In fact, I kind of pinched myself.
This is reality as opposed to, and the dream must be preparation.
What happens next?
So she's in your room.
She's in my room and then I don't have any conversations, but I can read her mind or she can read my mind or vice versa.
There's an exchange.
There's communication going on at a nonverbal level and it's very intense.
I'm feeling combination, you know, at the one time a rushing sense of grief that she's feeling at the same time, the hope of the message she's conveying that in the end it will all come out fine, but there's this tremendous pain and suffering.
And she said it when, like, said, I knew the message clearly, got the message, write a letter to the Pope.
No instructions what to write or what you've seen, seeing me, but no other specific instructions what to say or why.
No explanation, but just write a letter to the Pope.
Then I was looking for some form of greater understanding, I'd say, and she sensed that.
And I think she sensed I was, like, still shocked, in shock, right?
But I went into a state of ecstasy.
So I've never had that.
Only time in my life, 71 years old, that I was in a state of ecstasy.
I could, I remember my teeth chattering.
I remember that.
I remember the sound of them going, and my head going back, like, it was like, and it was incredible.
It was like an incredible orgasm of, like, beyond that, without a real orgasm, obviously.
But it was, like, more than, it was just an incredible feeling.
The bona fides of the moment, so to speak, were right there.
I mean, this is absolutely what it was.
And then I saw it, like, more of a, if I'm so graced to be here in your presence, you know, I've sent, you know,
then there must be something specific you want me to do, other than the letter to the Pope, and that sort of thing.
And then little things came out, like, for example, a sense of tying together.
There was no numbers, but I sensed that it was all related.
I just sensed that it was all related to this.
Plus, my encounter I'd had with her in Portugal, where I hadn't met her, but I felt her mind and thoughts.
She was explaining when she told me there, deliver the message, write what you see.
Whatever you do, you do in sin.
That was specific.
I wrote that down after Portugal, which was a few years earlier.
Said, keep all that in mind as you go forth on this mission, or you go forth to fulfill God's will.
And she made it clear everything is God's will, not her will.
There was a major distinction.
I wasn't doing anything for her.
However, this was all in accordance with her serving God, the same way she was asking me to, or anybody else.
Now, you asked earlier, at this point, I had never read anything about her encounters with the Virgin Mary.
But I became, of course, a student of that as well, great detail.
But the thing that you mentioned earlier, I think she sensed that I was, not losing it, but needed further reassurance in some way that I could do this.
Because the first thing anybody has is an expectation of getting any mystical experience that's genuine is, well, why me?
There's no reason, the answer to that is, there is no reason, it's you.
I wasn't being singled out because I was noble, or worthy, or no such reason.
When Paul was on the road to Damascus and he was struck down by the light of Jesus standing over him, the light, the divine light of Jesus saying,
Paul, why are you persecuting me, he turns from a person going to kill members of this Jewish sect to the leader of that sect because of the mystical experience with Christ.
Without that, none of that would have happened.
And so, you know, I'm very well aware that these aren't only real, but they're incredible, important moments in human history every time they happen to anybody to continue to gather them up.
And as you're saying, tell, relate the story.
So at the very end of the encounter, it was, you know, it's funny, time kind of like, I got lost in time.
I don't remember, it was just minutes, the whole thing.
I know that, where she said, like encouragement again, this was the important part.
Don't reach, God lies within you.
Don't want, you have no needs.
Don't strive, there is no purpose.
And it was incredibly important guidance because it reminded me of things I thought I knew, but then I got, you get lost, right?
Particularly the one of, don't reach.
Don't go out and try, you know, it's all there.
It's all inside you in the end.
And even the experiences going on the mountain with the monks and going back in time, all that was a way of intensifying that it's here.
And being confident in that.
Did your life change after that?
Did that fundamentally change as a person?
Yeah, yeah, it was the, it was a culminating moment.
It was a culmination of all the dreams in a way.
Because in her, the images I associated with her presence in the room, there was the idea of war and conflict and apocalyptic things.
I could sense the wars and things of previous dreams all being present with her as well.
So it was her great suffering, you know, particularly of women and children in war and conflict, lives being lost, that kind of level of concern and need to get people do things to minimize it or to end it or to be part of God's will in writing the course of human history.
She visited you every seven years, three times.
Is that right?
So 1991, 1998, and then 2005.
Well, then she didn't visit me in 2005, but it's one of the coincidences that ties the connections together.
In 2005, I didn't have an experience with the Virgin Mary, but I found myself through the chief of Europe at CIA.
I was back in Paris, probably the first time since seven years, maybe.
I don't know.
I didn't go there that often.
But I'm back in the same hotel, Creon, which is two blocks from the one I was in.
I remember thinking, this is odd.
I'm so close to where all this happened because by now I'm intensely aware and thinking and looking into what all that was meant for me and what should I do.
More from a practical, I didn't need evidence.
I just needed to know practically what to do now that I had these experiences.
So on that particular seven years' fulfillment of things was the night that John Paul II died.
And it was the idea that this is related to that, the explicit idea.
Of course, I had to write a letter to the Pope, and I sent that letter to the Vatican, and I got a response from the Vatican, actually.
What was the response?
Well, it said His Holiness had appreciated the gift, and I suppose they sent some of these things.
But it seemed like it had a personal touch to it.
What did you say to the Pope?
Well, I put the letter in the book.
So the letter I sent to the Pope, I put in the book.
And I want everybody to read what I said because—
Go check it out.
Did you say just high level?
Did you say, the Virgin Mary told me to write to you?
Yeah, yeah.
Wow.
Yeah.
And I put the experience—I put all the numbers in it.
I mean, all the numbers are in the book.
Because, again, the idea is—
The numbers from the original download you got at West Point.
Yes, yes.
Seven, four, seven, and all the numbers.
I've seen the numbers.
Yeah, so if you read the letter in two pages, two and a half pages, it's a whole story in a way.
Whoa.
I met her in Portugal.
I met her in Monathos.
And it's the same letter I shared with the Orthodox Church.
Because it's not about me.
Yeah.
I mean, it is my story, but to the extent the story serves a purpose or is relevant.
So you were just relaying your experience mostly to the Vatican.
So it's 2005, Pope John Paul II dies.
You're in Paris.
That night, yeah.
Ironically, at the same spot that it's almost this like Nietzschean eternal recurrence or something.
Well, that satisfies your sevens.
You know, we have three sevens here.
Three sevens.
Yeah.
Exactly.
So that seems significant maybe for the numerology aspect.
So you're there.
You're in Paris.
Right.
And then what happens as far as your third experience with the Virgin Mary?
Well, the third experience preceded the first Paris.
It was the one in Portugal.
Okay.
In, no, wait a minute.
No.
Gosh, I'm losing the date on that.
But yeah, it was before the Virgin Mary appearance because it was in Portugal where I was
encountered her in, in, I already told you what that conversation was all about and what she
relayed more guidance at that meeting.
So there again, it was idea of a presence, not seeing anything, but I realized this presence
is continuing and it's, I'm getting more in, if you will, aware of what I should and shouldn't
be doing related to, to all this.
And in between all this, you know, there's.
But in Paris, you see her again.
Yeah.
And what's, what's that experience like?
Well, there's only, the only one time I've seen the Virgin Mary was in 1998 in Paris.
Yep.
But in, in 2005, you see her again.
No.
Oh, you don't see her again.
Okay.
Got it.
No, as I've got down there, there were, there were only one, only one.
It's, it, it tied everything up where she appeared in a way that, you know, you examine
phenomena, right?
And I like to present this in various ways.
One is, as phenomena, I have to know for my own satisfaction, I want to know, I should
say, I'm not supposed to want, but I do want to know the explanation of the, you know, physiology
or the, the, the, the reality aspect of what was she, where did she come from?
Uh, she, there's a, there has to be some where she came and went when she retreated back into
the, cause she, at the end, she went back into the top corner of the wall and, uh, and
she was gone.
So that's a, that's an event.
That's a real thing.
So I have talked, we talked some about it, Jesse, cause you do a lot of inquiring research
into, to these subjects.
There's a, there's an explanation for it in fit based in physics, just like there has
to be an explanation of what heaven and hell are in physics.
Do you have a best explanation in physics for kind of metaphysical or spiritual?
Well, I have one that I, I have one that I favor and I, I'm, I'm hesitant to share
it, but I want to give a direct answer to a direct question because I don't know.
I mean, I don't know, but, but to me, the, the most sensible explanation is that things
we describe as divine or part of a permanent, uh, things that aren't prone to being affected
by time anymore, meaning they're not in the physical universe in motion because time is
a function of, of, um, motion and, uh, math matter, right?
Mass and motion.
So without those things, if you had a universe at rest, then what we call heaven and hell,
God presides over everything, including our universe and including where angels might come
to give us messages or how prophets get their insights because it doesn't come from our
universe. It doesn't come from the big bang universe. It can't come. The idea, I think
if the great thinkers like Thomas Aquinas and you pick your favorite pondering the theological
basis of God, even someone like Leibniz, a mathematician who said, God has to create the
best of all possible worlds, which is one I love because I think he's absolutely right.
But that's because God isn't in our world. God to be perfect, to be great, to be everything
we ascribe, including indivisible, so massive. We can't even contemplate it. It can't be
rooted in the big bang universe in motion because everything in our universe is relative.
So it's like there's an alternative universe that's at rest. That's more
primordial or a universe that I don't know. I use the word alternative. Well, that perfectly
valid. I'd say a universe that lies beyond or above or in which our universe is just a
small part.
And you're saying the big bang universe because that is the proverbial kind of, you know,
first prime mover event that scientists now herald as, you know, definitely true that
then kind of deterministically kind of, you know, you get this entropy from there and then
you end up with this, you know, what a lot of scientists would now say this happy accident
of, you know, our earth and the world and the universe as it is. And you're saying that
there is something next to that or outside of that?
Well, the only explanation I can come up with, which is, you know, I'm embarrassed almost
to say these profound things when there are so many scientists and physicists and philosophers,
but I mean, the simplest way I think of it, it came to me kind of as an insight of, as a
possibility, was sitting in my porch with screens all around my porch and picturing the big bang
for the first time in my life. I'm God, I'm sitting in my chair and picturing the big bang
as being a ripple in that space, time in that room, in the corner of the room, just a little
ripple. There's a, starts with a little tear in the corner and just goes, spans out. And
you're God, you're looking over at that, but it's just, to you, it's just a ripple.
Everything we take is the ultimate reality and the, the, the accumulation of all things is
just possibly a, a very small sideshow occurring in a big room.
Is the implication of the title of your book, A State of Mind, that your mind can get to this
universe at rest, this timeless universe?
Yes. And so the, the clues, because it's not completely just a stab in the, in the dark
of, of the big room. It's as much as to say, you have to have an explanation of how people can
reliably, this doesn't just happen to a few people. This has happened throughout his human
history, being able to see into the future and sometimes claim to go into the past. So
there must be a way of, if you will, overcoming time, which means time can't be an absolute
in our equation. And you have people like Einstein saying time is but an illusion, which Harry
Hiller said to me in my book when I went to Monathos. And sure enough, he proved it was
an illusion because I kept going back in time. So in a way, the dream was a manifestation
of a very basic potential truth, which is time is just an aspect of space time that we create
in the big bang because we're all in motion. There's nothing not in motion. But who is to
say that there's not a universe at rest? Because I don't know how you can have something called
everlasting life. If Christ went somewhere, he didn't go somewhere in the big bang after
crucifixion and resurrection. He didn't stay in our earthly realm, even if we extend that
meaning to the whole universe as we understand the universe. You know, it stands to reason
then that every species, intelligent species in the universe would be beholden to this rule,
not just humans.
Yeah, I, you know, question a lot of people who are more fundamentalist in their beliefs on
these things. If Christ is, you know, immortal, like, where is he now? Like, he should
be on earth. And they often talk about like an ascension body, you know, that they're,
they exist in maybe the ascension body is where this other sort of universe lies or something.
I don't know. I'm speculating here.
Well, I mean, I think you got another clue that's a really fascinating one. And I don't
want to overstate any of these, but they're just things that come to mind. The transfiguration
of Christ, which for many people, they don't know what that is. There was a period after
crucifixion where he appeared to the disciples in a form where he wasn't yet in heaven or
wasn't at earth. And that's where he had the famous Doubting Thomas putting Jesus saying,
if you doubt that it's me, because you're not supposed to be here, put your finger in
my wounds. And it is, and he's called Doubting Thomas. But if you look at that beyond as a
religious kind of story, you know, it has to be true again. If they witnessed Christ in
some form, then what is that? How would you explain that in physics? I think you can. I
think it's an, it's a deliberate staging of before reaching the next period. I absolutely
believe as a result of my religious experiences and growth and that we don't die when we die.
We just go pass, we pass, it's better word would be a passage. There's a passage from
this state. I think if you believe, truly believe in Christ and really you have to believe
that. And as I always say, it doesn't matter how often you go to church and how much you
donate to this or that. What matters is, do you really believe the heart and soul of what
the faith is about, which is there's life after death. So once you posit there is life after
death, you're not really trying to determine like, what is that? Like Dante's stages of
hell, which is kind of like fun to think about. People deserve the different levels of hell.
That kind of explains why you're a little sinner, you go here, you're a big sinner, you go down
here, but it's all silly, right? It's silly. The idea of hell as a place is silly. Now the
idea of hell as being the absence of God, from God, being separated from God. Ah, now we're
getting somewhere because God doesn't exist in the Big Bang world. God exists beyond it.
So the closer you get beyond the Big Bang world to a world not in motion. So maybe when
we die, we pass to a world at rest. We pass to a world where time no longer exists, which
then creates consequences of what you've done in your life because you're suddenly aware
of them. We can't even accurately go back and recreate any moment of our time, much
less replicate it again. It happens, we have memories of it. And all our memories are fading,
all of them. But there is a place where all the memories are the events themselves, if that
makes sense. All the events are occurring always as they occurred in what we would describe
as this year, this place, this time. Because in that world, none of the time exists. That's
all. It's a very simple concept. And all it presupposes is that physicists have told me
where we've discussed this, and I've learned a lot from good physicists, especially young
ones I find that are really into this subject like you are. They're really interested in
constructing ways of thinking of metaphysics in ways that aren't just traditional physics,
where if you can't prove it experimentally, forget it.
Yeah.
No, of course not.
Yeah, that can't be true. If something is phenomenologically real or experientially real,
it's not fake because you can't experimentally reproduce it in a lab. That's an absolutely
ridiculous thing to say that is the epitome of the hubris of enlightenment. But time in physics
is also extremely weird. General relativity is a theory of gravity. But even in general
relativity, you have time dilation. You have time moves based on the speed of the observer,
which is really weird. Gravity itself is really weird on a macroscopic scale. You basically
are justifying the weakness of gravity with dark matter, which seems like this undetectable
mathematical placeholder. And time and gravity are kind of super linked. You know, the more you get
closer to kind of a dense gravitational source like a black hole, time seems to slow. And so,
you know, if gravity is kind of weird, you know, and then gravity is obviously weird on a, you know,
it's irreconcilable with the other forces on a quantum level. And then time is also on a quantum
level. It's taken as this sort of classical, classical axiom and something like Schrodinger's
equation. So it's just time seems like this not super well understood thing. Like at most, maybe you
can think of it vis-a-vis the movement of bodies on a macroscopic scale and on a microscopic scale,
maybe the oscillations of an electromagnetic wave or something. But it's, it's, you know, it's the most
commonly used noun in the English language, but it always has to be defined with respect to other
things. Right. And so it seems a little bit like the eye seeing the eye or like that David Foster
Wallace, you know, Kenyan commencement speech where he's, you know, this is water. And it's like, if
you're a fish talking to another fish and you're in water, we're all in Zeno's arrow of time. You can't
really get out of that sort of epistemological framework. But simultaneous to that, you have all
these interesting thinkers in, in physics, like you cure Aronoff or Kramer, where there's like a,
the present is a handshake between the future and the past, which is, that's a legitimate
interpretation of kind of quantum mechanics. And, um, you know, you have ideas of retro causality
and the future sort of causing the past or the, the present being constricted and the, there being
probable futures and probable fast, probable past. Schrodinger talked about, you know, if you measure a
particle in its present, you might affect its past, you know, they're all, it's, it's, it's way
trippier than sort of meets the eye. I even think, you know, even position momentum, super
positionality, spooky action at a distance, which Einstein grappled with till the end of his life.
You have spooky action over time as well, where, you know, it looks like if a double slit experiment
is performed in the future, it looks like the measurement of that double slit experiment is
affecting someone that's done the present or the past, which is crazy. Right. And so, you know,
it's almost like quantum mechanics implies, uh, you know, people say it implies, you know,
there, there, there's an issue with position and momentum measurements. That's Heisenberg's
uncertainty principle, but there's also level of energy and time quantum indeterminacy as well.
And what if the Schrodinger's equation, which is more position and momentum based,
what if time super positionality is causing the position and momentum super positionality?
And just like, you know, you can place Newton within Einstein, but Einstein better describes
Newton than Newton. What if you could place Schrodinger within some time agnostic modality
equation that describes Schrodinger better than Schrodinger? You know, we don't know the answer to
these questions. No. And, and the hard, hardest part of exploring them is separating the influence
of scale from, from, from the actual reality. So because we are at the scale, we are, everything
we measure is, uh, measured proportional to our scale. So, and that's not, we can obviously go beyond
visual and we have lots of ways to measure things other than our senses, but we can't avoid is our
scale. So if you go up in scale, the cosmic level or down to subatomic levels, you got the same
problem. Your ability to measure anything gets less and less. And then the worst, your worst ability
to measure anything is when time changes on you, you get into black hole physics or whatever, where
suddenly you realize mass, you know, go, it goes infinite and, and time stops. But that's a clue.
It's another clue. The, the idea again of time being a variable that we take is in a way an absolute
reality, even though it changes, but the existence of time I'm talking about isn't necessarily real. It's
real for us in the big bang world. But if you, if you stop everything, which we don't contemplate because
we can't, we can't, we can't at least in science contemplate a world at rest.
So why don't we, we'll, we'll kind of, you know, take a page from the book, so to speak,
and, um, can weave in and out of some of these more mystical experiences and your more prosaic
life. What were some of your early missions?
So I would say in the early years, uh, it, there was no mission there other than basic conclusions I
drew. Like, okay, I'm drawn to Russia because it's, it's the action. It's, it's, there's no
better place to be in the CIA than the belly of the beast. So I had those kinds of connotations
early on, but nothing, nothing explicitly, you know, linked to religion or, or faith or apocalypse
or nuclear weapons or any of that. It was very, just a kind of basic career until the things I
described that happened later.
Yeah. And so, and you taught, you have a lot of story. I mean, you were, you were almost overrun,
right. Uh, in the Yeltsin coup. So there's this attempted coup against Boris Yeltsin.
1993, correct.
1993.
And you're back and you're the Moscow station chief for the CIA. And it seems like you're
kind of, you know, in this very dire situation, they end up having, they end up helping you,
right? Is that, is that right?
That's correct. I mean, it's one of those things where the idea of a liaison relate, we call
liaison relationship when, when we cooperate with other countries intelligence on the face of
it. There was nothing really to cooperate between the CIA and the KGB. You read all the
story. They're all true. As we say, there's a lot of blood in the water. Uh, we kill, you know,
not kill, but their agents, our agents end up dead, killed, executed sometimes imprisoned. Uh,
so it's a very ugly history and we weren't going to be friends. But the idea was when I laid out the
first CIA directors that ever went to Moscow for, to visit the, or even visit Moscow, much less deal
with the Russians as partners. It was Bob Gates was the first when he was CIA director. And I'll
never forget that trip in 19, except the fall of 1992. He came there and laid the groundwork by
giving a great toast. We had a dinner. Russians love toast. They love dinners and you got to win.
You got to, you got to be good at the whole heart of toasting. And so I learned a lot about that,
but his essentially was around the theme of we're not friends. We're not here because we're ever going
to love each other and be, be, be real partners. We're here because our countries demand that we
put aside some of our differences and cooperating meaningful ways for the security of our countries.
That was when Yeltsin had just emerged. There was the hope then, right? But it was a realism
attached, he attached to it. That was very important, needed to make it real. Because if
otherwise you would have, you know, been pretending and playing games, which there's no point to play
games. If you're arch enemies, you just do what you need to do. So a year later, it all culminated
in this coup in Moscow when hardliners tried to overthrow Yeltsin. But the one thing it showed is that
at a time of extreme need, we could work with the Russians because we had a common interest to keep
Yeltsin in power. Russian intelligence decided they weren't ready to overthrow Yeltsin through force
and violence. They ended up doing that. This is 93, it was eight years later, of course, when Vladimir
Putin came to power, legally, the right way, if you want to call it that. And the Russians don't like coups
and violence any more than we would like in our own country. So we worked together. And it was
astonishing. I didn't know when I first called Russian intelligence chief and said, hey, we need
help. We need you to protect us. It looks like we're going to be taken hostage. When I was leading a
detachment of people outside the embassy and coming under fire from coup plotters, snipers and things,
I called them for help. And I didn't expect any help. In fact, it was the ambassador at the time,
ambassador Tom Pickering. He's the one who's, I called him in desperation, say, there's no way
you can help us, is there? Because I, because of the embassy, all, everybody in the embassy was
underground in the, in the embassy compound, except for us. We're out doing reporting and things like
that to tell Washington what was going on. Otherwise they wouldn't have known anything going on at the
time. All the news networks had shut down and- And you end up like holed up in an abandoned
building or something? Well, we, we holed up, everything was abandoned, but we were in the ambassador's
residence, which we opened up and used just for, as a command post, which I think that started as
five of us. I think we ended up with seven or eight long. I put the whole, like all the details
in that. I was a little surprised that again, it was nice to see they, they had no problem with
telling that story. Cause I think it's important that I, the, the purpose of the story and the purpose
of me describing it is that, you know, intelligence is almost always unexpected and it's, it's greatest
value is proven in the most difficult times pro and con. And, and you, you can't fear or avoid
the difficult circumstances. You have to kind of run into them and embrace the, the, the difficulty.
So they, they ended up sending a team to protect us from being taken hostage. And the only rules we
had, I'll never forget the phone call from the director. He said, okay, Rolf, there's very
extraordinary circumstances. We're going to send you a team of heavily armed guys to try to keep you
from getting captured. But here's the deal. One is do not commingle. Our guys and your guys are
separate. We'll do our work outside your perimeter or whatever. So don't mix. And he goes, if you are
stormed or they take, get in a firefight or whatever happens, die in your separate foxholes.
And he didn't have to explain why he, cause however that day turned out in Russian history,
didn't want to leave any evidence of who would work with whom along the way. Cause it was in doubt.
I, I, the one thing I learned personally in a way that helped me even with the spiritual stuff later,
miss this mystical experiences is history is not inevitable. History isn't, history comes together
because of the decisions people make. And when you're experiencing it live, like in a war or in
a coup or in a change of government, you realize it could go that way. If these things are done and
goes that way, if another thing is done. You've been in the room with Vladimir Putin,
what's your impression of him? Well, it wasn't as extensive as so many of the people,
you know, obviously in the U S government who have had a lot of interaction with them. So I don't want
to put it on. So I just happened to have a fairly unique one-time thing where we met in his first
foreign trip. I was in Norway. I'm Norwegian American, as I said, so it was a great honor for
me to go back to Norway. And I happened to be there again, one of these things I thank God a
little bit for the privilege of to be there during the last meeting of what was called the Oslo peace
accord process was started in Oslo, Norway and now was culminating. So this was, uh, in the November
19, 93, 93, no, no, 1998, 1998, the last meeting. Oh, okay. And, uh, the last meeting was one amazing.
No, no, I had no role of any appreciable, nothing. I was there as, as literally a appreciation gift.
Some, I knew the prime minister and other people in the Norwegian government, they said,
invite, invite me and my wife to the, to the dinner. But at the dinner was president Clinton
came of course, um, Vladimir Putin's first foreign trip as prime minister. And then, um,
of course, the main ones, Yasser Arafat and Ehud Barak, who was the prime minister of,
of Israel at the time. Now I had never met Arafat, Ehud Barak. I had met Clinton just,
you know, kind of like formalistically, uh, but, and Putin. And, and I got to see them all in this
kind of, as an observer vantage point where if anything, anybody would say, well, who's this guy?
Cause everybody there was more important than me. Literally everybody at the, at the dinner,
but that was great. I, there was no pressure. I could literally just observe, uh, Putin and
others. And it was just amazing. I was, there was a moment when, after dinner, when everybody got up
and mingled, went to the King's library to visit the castle in his library to have cognac and
chocolates. And everybody's walking there and I'm going to catch everything on the way. And I see
Clinton literally grab Arafat in the middle of the room. And Clinton was, whatever one thinks of him
political. That's not what I'm talking about here. He had a presence, right?
Oh, well, everybody says that everybody says the most charismatic guy.
He just had a natural charisma. He didn't do anything. He just stands there. Right.
Sure.
So he grabs Arafat who also in his weird way had a charisma to a presence, right? Cause he's
the iconic head wrap and et cetera. And he says to Arafat, take the deal. Yes, sir. Take the deal.
It's your last best chance for peace. And I remember listening to that thing. Wow. So like
important, but I just heard, I thought it's very important. And I just felt so depressed as I knew
it was no, no, no, no, you know, foreshadowing or future. I just like instinctively, my gut was all
this is not going to turn out well. And of course it's turned out terribly.
Well, it's turned out terribly. I mean, partially. Yes, sir. Arafat would speak out of both sides
of his mouth and he would speak to his own population, say certain things and then speak
to the West and say other things, but also Yitzhak Rabin also, uh, you know, taken out
by, by his own, you know, people and Haredi, you know, Jews who are just really extremists
and wanted, you know, to cede nothing at all costs. And, you know, I think in, in many
ways that whole, the middle East, you know, uh, conundrum quagmire has been, has been
so stuck for so long and maybe we, you know, maybe we've made a little bit of progress in
the last year, but it's been so, so stuck, uh, because of kind of extremists on, on both
sides and because in many ways the incentives of the leaders are to like actually maintain
the conflict. Yeah. So unfortunate. It is. It is. It's a factory of, yeah. Well, my, my,
my, but then watching Putin, just to the point of your, your question was I already had the
impression that he would be more consequential than I thought he might at the time by any
standard of reasoning or what I knew about him. I, but I just had, he had the presence
too. He was boring, the gray man on the corner, but that in itself impressed me because he
wasn't trying to fit in. He wasn't trying to like speak loudly to be heard. He, he was
way too self-assured, you know, for, for that kind of a reaction to the situation. And I
respected that. I thought, okay, this guy could end up being way more of his own man
than we, we think he might be going into that time period. One last thing on, on the, cause
it's, it's ties to Russia and the Middle East again, five years earlier, 1993 again, after
the coup and all that, I was meeting with the Russians. Yevgeny Primakov is his name. He
was the head of Russian intelligence. I got to know him very, very well. He was, we'd meet
almost every week and had all kinds of discussions about everything. We've talked almost like
we are, Jesse, about all kinds of big subjects. And he was a guy who felt very comfortable.
I thought he was a brilliant, brilliant man, actually. And he probably would have been
a prime minister before, instead of Putin in the mid nineties, after Yeltsin left, had
he not passed away from health problems and old age, et cetera. But at the time he was always
musing with me about what, what can we do to be serious people? There's a Russian expression,
serious, not a Russian. It's the most important thing to a Russian. It can love you or hate
you, but you got to be a serious, a serious person, serious professional, serious about
what you do. Don't give me bullshit. And he says, you know, we got to do something, but
I can think of one thing that would be unbelievable if we could find a way to do it. I said, what's
that? He said, well, you have your means, meaning CIA. We have our means, meaning the SVR, which
is the foreign intelligence component of Russian intelligence. And we have them in the Middle
East. So let's apply all our efforts in the Middle East where we really need something
to happen to break this longstanding stalemate problem. Our goal will be to keep Arafat alive.
Your goal will be to keep Rabin alive. And I thought it was genius. Of course, I sent it
in and everybody thought I was insane. And I never got a good explanation as to why it
really wasn't even considered. Maybe you just offered it.
Yeah. Yeah. Right. Yeah. It's tough. I mean, I mean, we've talked about this, you know,
too, in our last interview, you know, where, you know, people always talk about a deep state
and, you know, it's, I think clearly there is no sort of cabal in a back room smoking
cigars or something, but there are, there is, not only is it conspiracy to say that there
are all sorts of misaligned incentives when it comes to big bureaucracies and that's any
institution. And so, yeah, no, just going back to like, you know, why would somebody senselessly
say no to a thing like that? Or, you know, I, I am sympathetic to a lot of the John Mearsheimer
arguments as well that like, you know, we've totally reneged on Putin a million different
times and, you know, we've, we've encroached a lot on, on, you know, their, their territory
and, you know, not, not to at all, you know, uh, uh, apologize for a lot of his wrongdoings,
which are very real, but, um, yeah, there's, there's the, the incentives are often wrong in
these organizations. Well, when you talk about people like Mearsheimer or others who try to
express a different way of thinking of our policies and their impact, I mean, there's,
there's a utility in those points of views. I don't agree with him on a lot of things, but
I think he should be saying some of the things he's saying and it's helpful. The biggest thing
we habitually do wrong in terms of follow through on policy, some of our policy ideas aren't so bad,
but it's usually the, the huge flaws in the implementation usually. And, and it's not so
much the underlining motives that line up with as much as people think they do with sort of deep
state agendas. It's just either a mixture of incompetence or I'd say more the idea that we,
we mirror image too much. So our biggest problem in understanding, for example, the Russians.
Now, what I'm saying is not acceptable. It's not accepted, uh, thinking, but it's widely accepted,
but some people understand it is our biggest mistake is not seeing things through their eyes
and it doesn't justify what they're doing or thinking, but it's understanding it.
And if you want to know why we are where we are with the Russians, you have to understand,
see the world through their eyes. It doesn't mean you accept that view or more importantly,
what they do is a consequence of what they feel, but at least understand why you're there and don't
be surprised about it. Isn't there a, uh, Kenan quote about understanding the Russians or something?
It's like, once you ascend to the top of the mountain, you know, you, you end up equally
confused as to the Russian motive motivation or something. I'm totally paraphrasing and botching
this, but there's something like that. I don't remember that, but I, I suspect, yeah. It's like,
they're always mystical, confusing. There's no way to ultimately understand what they're up to or
something, which feels somewhat right. You like, you know, the, the idea of a pull at borough is
like this, you know, concealed, sealed off hermetically, you know, uh, enclosed sort of
organization that, you know, you can never fully sort of understand. And Putin's always keeping the
people around him on his, on their toes. And so it's this really hard kind of hermeneutic game of
reading the tea leaves at all times with, you know, governments like that.
I think you read tea leaves and see everything as being unscrutable when you don't have any real
depth in either living in the country or having enough experience with the people of the country
where you can understand where they're coming from. One of the biggest mistake we make with Russia or
Xi Jinping in China or anybody for that matter, all the leaders, even some of our friend, friendly
countries is, is, uh, not understanding that the country's not the leader. So the thing I'll never
do is think of Russia as Vladimir Putin. I've read too much, many, too much Russian history,
philosophy, uh, gotten into Russia. I've known too many Russians. I lived in Russia for, for enough
years where I think of Russia first as the people, right? And then you can assess what Putin's doing.
And the most important way you need to assess it is not what impact it has on the U S but what impact
is it, what he's doing, having on the Russian people. Now I would make an argument that what's
happening now is very damaging to the future interests of ordinary Russians. The same way I
might assess what different presidents impact has on America. I don't, I don't care so much about
how the president's policies affect the stock market as I do how the president's policies affect
ordinary Americans. So I think we have to look at foreign countries the same way.
If you look at China's meteoric rise in the 20th century, you're not compelled to think of China
as an enemy or right, deep rival and everything that's progress in China is being antithetical to
our interests. Look what they've done for the Chinese people over in a remarkable period of
time. That's not all good, obviously, but start from a more solid basis to understand why the
leaders do what they do in their own history, traditions, culture, environments, and religion.
If you look at the reason I've always said, and a lot of Russia experts disagree with me on this,
I've always said Russia can't embrace, cannot be a democracy like the United States. The Yeltsin
years were a mirage. They weren't a missed opportunity. There was never an opportunity
for Russia to go West. Even when famously, you know, Peter the Great talked about Western
orientation, it had nothing to do in the context we would like to ascribe it to, like he wanted to be
more connected culturally, et cetera, with the U.S. Russia is what Russia is, which is a deeply
orthodox, homogeneous country with a very rich history and very rich, they're very smart people,
they're very educated people. And they want what they want. They don't want what we want.
Yeah.
And I think that's a big mistake of what we try to impose, not so much our, any way of controlling
countries, but our idea of imposing our culture.
For sure. Well, they had, you know, under Gorbachev, you know, last leader of the USSR that
disbanded it. You had Glasnost and you had Perestroika, and you had, you know, open minds
make open markets or whatever. And, or open markets make open minds, right? And I think
what a lot of neoliberals sort of like miscalculated is that you'd inevitably, you'd get this like opening
up of markets and then, you know, you'd end up with all of the amazing things about liberal
democracy in the West, you know, in, in both China and Russia. And that's just not happened
at all. And like, it took us a long time to, I think, update on that. You know, it was this
neoconservative sort of hubris of like, you know, this would just happen on its own. And
that's just not, you also have things like, you know, with Putin, I think there's this guy,
Vladislav Surkov, who I think, you know, is this advisor who wrote this book, Almost Zero.
And it's like all about like performance art and how that has to play into like your, you know,
your, how you do politics. And so it's, I just find it so fascinating, you know, that whole,
that whole world, it's just so different. Or even like, I think this is to a true, you know,
Alexander Dugan, who I don't think he's, I don't think he's that close with Putin, actually.
Like, I think people think he is. But I mean, it's, Putin is, I mean, that whole world is
definitely trippier than we, than we, you know, realize. Like some of these guys are like,
they're more esoteric than, you know, we might realize. And so it's like, how do you really
understand how they make decisions at all? Right, right, right, right. Yeah. No, it's, it's,
I think it's a little like our previous discussions on faith and mysticism and analyzing
other countries and understanding what, more importantly than analyzing it is understanding
what's happening. Yeah.
Uh, what, what, what track are they on? What road are they on? Especially in a world where
our notions of individual identity are changing through, of course, social media and the internet,
our ideas of technology or, you know, it's blowing up around us in ways we don't really
understand. Now that's affecting all of us. The cultural reaction to it is different everywhere.
The thing it's testing most in my view is the idea of individuality and identity. So in a country
like ours, which started at the point of our creation as a nation, the idea of very unique,
historically unique, completely unique ideas of individual freedom and the role of individual
liberty identity in a collective society where the collective part was put way down.
I mean, the idea of a right, an intrinsic right to life, liberty, and not property like John
wrote, Locke wrote in his second treatise of government, but pursuit of happiness.
Yeah.
What a weird idea. Franklin came up with that. I understand when, when they were drafting the
declaration of independence, it was a change made edit to Jefferson's original. That's only
something Americans can come up with.
It's a very Western concept.
It's not even European Western. So when we're decrying and criticizing all the Europeans for
being socialists, my, I would maintain, we have no idea what we're talking about. I've
lived in most of those countries that whatever that you, I call that socialism. I want those
pensions. We make fun of the French cause I got a four day work week. Okay. Well, you
know, I like the idea of universal healthcare. Okay. You got to wait. First thing I always, American
will say about talk about Danish healthcare or Norwegian, I believe, you know, is, well,
you got to wait in line. Well, you got some healthcare, right? We're striving to try to
create some normalcy around the idea that citizens also have a right to maybe some form of universal
healthcare. We can't even agree on that really. So that's there. Then you go further, you go
to the Russians or the Chinese or pretty much anywhere in Asia. Just the notion of the individual's
place in society is far more collective. They're part of something. The idea of the culture,
the societal framework is that your individual rights only go so far and then you're part,
and most people feel that. And it's not a religious based thing where they're members of the same
church, because particularly in Europe or Asia, there's those organized religions don't hold as
much a hold on people as even they might in the United States today. But it's the idea of the
society itself was constructed with this idea of collective responsibility. So when the Russians
drew up their, the philosophers, the great Russian philosophers, I call the religious philosophers,
working with the political scientists after the breakup of the Russian empire, the czar,
which first yielded the Soviet Union and the Bolshevism, they were drawing up a system of
government that would resolve the question of how can you have a true democracy that wouldn't be
corrupted by special interests and foolish leaders who would be not up for it. You need more of a
Plato's Republic, a republic that was based on people having roles, which we all have collective
responsibilities. And you have distinct classes like Plato's guardian class that manage the government,
etc. Responsibility is conferred to individuals within their collective obligations. And we really
struggle with that. We've struggled that for decades, but it's really coming to a head, I think,
in a way where every country is sorting through that. But the bias in most countries is much more towards
limiting individual freedom for the collective good.
Yeah. Yeah. Well, does that make sense?
No, it makes total sense. Well, if you look at like Marxist dialectical materialism,
the individual has very little place at all. It's very, you know, the individual can go through a meat grinder.
And as long as the byproduct is social progress on the other side, whether it's, you know, Mao's Great Leap Forward
or, you know, any of the Stalin's initiatives, you know, to send people to the gulag, like that's, that's okay in their,
in their model. And so, you know, I think human, human suffering is inevitable in that, in that model.
And there are no individual rights and it's all about this sort of collective sense of progress.
And I think that is very alien and foreign to somebody thinking about Western liberal democracy.
I also, you brought up Plato. Plato himself, you could think of him as, you know, he's really obviously
deep, interesting thinker. I think he had all these kind of interesting ideas about
ontological truth and metaphysics, you know, which maybe modern scholars would disagree with me
on or something. But, um, also if you read the Republic, like it's sort of like this proto-fascist
book. It's like you're separating the kids from the adults and like, you know, you have this guardian
class that's like pretty hierarchical and stratified. And, you know, it's, it's, it's not at all like a
nonviolent, you know, like egalitarian, like, you know, book at all. But, um, 40 was one of the
numbers that you got in your download as well. And something very interesting happened to you at
the age of 40, another sort of metaphysical experience. Do you want to talk about what
happened to you on, on the train?
Yeah. So, um, I've been, this is between some of the Virgin Mary things. And of course, many years
after the introduction to not only mystical experiences, but what they might mean in terms of
my work, my, my role in life and trying to reconcile the sacred. And so I was just on a
normal, I'd say everyday espionage travel trip in, in Europe from Zurich to Vienna and on the night
train. And I'm sitting on the train. I, I carried my Bible with me, uh, which was engraved in glossy,
my, my name, full name on the cover. We all were got this Bible when we were in our first year at
West Point and I'd kept it over the years, but I have a, I have a superstition. I have to carry it
with me everywhere I travel. So I stick it in my box. Well, then I have to have a cover story for
because many of the times I traveled over the years, I'm an alias, you know, alias person.
I've got a cover story. I've got even phony passports and things, um, for my, that the agency
provided. Right. So I may have to explain who this Rolf Maltlarsen friend of mine is. It's almost a
little bit like the odious maximus story. You know, I have to come up with a reason why I'd
have this guy's Bible with me. So I opened the Bible and I had a pencil there that I just used
to mark, you know, something. And, and I just usually just pick out something random, read
most times 10, 15 minutes. I wasn't, you know, I wasn't someone who spent pouring. I don't pour over
biblical texts or Bibles or things and never did then. And now, plus I'm very distracted by my
mission. I'm going to Vienna exchange documents and going on the next day. And so I, I look up at
the clock. There are very few people on this particular train in my car. Uh, so I'm not
paying attention to them. And I look up at the clock that's in center, Swiss train, right? Everything's
clockwork. And I look at the clock and the, the, the, the hands, the second hand is starting to like
get heavy. It's like, and I'm feeling like a weight. My body's feeling heavier and heavier.
Uh, I feel like something's like overwhelming me almost like I'm experiencing some sort of thing,
but I, it's like space and time are slowing down around me. And I remember thinking that even,
but I didn't say, wow, this is very strange. Is it like, uh, having an epileptic fit or something?
I mean, I was really kind of worried for a minute and then, you know, it's a slow down
my pencil. I was holding, I dropped it and it just crashed onto the Bible. Like
then I wrote, Oh, and then I just, and then it was okay. I had always said I was aware of God's
presence, but I didn't really know what, not in this way. God was like there, didn't see anything.
You know, like I said, it's not a visual thing. I just was aware of God was that close.
Do you get a message?
Well, it was a, yes. And, and, but the thing about the presence that time that was different
from just being aware is it was scary. It was really scary because it was like the almighty
creator who's also personal. I mean, great minds like Thomas Jefferson could never reconcile that.
He had to be one or the other, you know, I wasn't going to reconcile it on the train,
but it was the idea that it was not good to be in God's presence. That, that was my, my reaction to
the intrusion was, whoa, he could, I already knew he could hear, understand, interpret everything I'm
thinking or will do or might do because he's way ahead of me, you know, but it was just kind of
different. Right. So then I did hear, it was a very definite short. This was all very short,
but the started with, I am, have, the verb was interesting. I didn't, I'd never known, it was
one church, one church. So I grained that in my mind. Do not criticize my church.
The old and the new are one. Just old and new. I interpreted that to be a testament, but it was
old and the new are one. Swallow them whole. And finally, read it as a child. So I know that's exactly
what it was because I wrote it down exactly like that. I still have that original note somewhere
exactly that way. Cause I said, that's it. And that was it. What does that mean to you?
Well, it's pretty, I think it's pretty obvious. I didn't think it was obvious and it really did,
has taken years to just kind of like, in a way it's my Sunday school in a way, cause I never left
as a child because I learned more from this, what I think it is. But the one church means, you know,
don't think of a church as the various churches, Protestant, Catholic, even Buddhist. My church is
the church of believers, whatever they call themselves. Even people consider themselves
atheists or agnostic. I mean, labels are labels, even what you label yourself. What does God see?
God sees way beyond that. So that's how I interpret that. Do not criticize my church is make a distinction
between criticizing the sins or the crime of organized religion, which we have every right
to do from dating from the inquisition to the crusades to anything you want to take your hand
on. And you can get so obsessed by it. I know so many people do that you're incapable of loving God
anymore, being, being part of this community of believers. Cause you associate everything with
the fallen, fallen angel. Right. And then the really cool ones for me, cause I, I immediately reread the
whole Bible cover to cover after I heard about the old and the newer one, the inspiration that gave me
was to, for the first time in my life, I was 40 years old on the train, was to go reread the Bible
from cover to cover, just as a history. No longer, you know, is Jonah's whale really a whale? Is it a
metaphor? You know, Red Sea parting? No, just read the damn thing, but read it as a child, meaning have that
same receptivity to me. I've had the most, my own grandkids, like I said, I got nine of them, but
they're all have asked me the hardest questions on religion because they just asked the most
important, obvious ones. Where's God? Why did Jesus die for our sins? My daughter said that that
me when she's first time she went to the church of the Holy Sepulcher in Jerusalem and watched
Jesus's cross. And she was just standing there for a long time. She was like nine years old.
I said, honey, what are you thinking? She says, why did Jesus have to die for us?
That's a kid reaction, but that you need to read, you know, kind of like recharge completely on the
Bible that way to think of it in that kind of a, we're given this document is what it is. There's
nothing holy about the thing itself. And there are things in there undoubtedly that are wrong. And it's
a language. As soon as you got a language, you get misinterpretations, reinterpretations,
everything else, but don't think about all that. It's like a lot of the other things we've talked
about, Jesse, don't overanalyze it. Just let it go and think, read it. And so I, I did, I did.
And do you think it's a coincidence that this happened at the age of 40 and that you received
40 in your dream and that, you know, it was 40 days of Jesus?
I don't, I don't think it is. I don't think it's a coincidence.
Hmm. And 40 days of the desert or 40 years in the desert for the Israelites as well.
There's almost 40 years of being away from God before you experience a communion with God. And,
um, in, in your case, 40 years of maybe more nihilistic, less believing youth or something.
And then you, you experience this Gnostic direct connection or something.
Right. That's a good explanation. I can't, I can't say it's definitive, but I mean, I,
I love your fascination with numbers. I think the really interesting thing you do is
not just my numbers, but the idea of tying numbers into a deeper understanding of reality
itself and how that can help us tie together disparate kind of fields that we think of as
separate. And one of the problems we have as human beings is when you get too deep into
the specialization of, of, uh, different, you know, faculties, uh, you tend to think of them
all as standing alone and needing to justify themselves. So the, the number of people I've
run into who can speak across various disciplines in that way to tie them together in a meaningful
way, that's pretty unusual itself.
Hmm. You also, you have another dream, final dream we'll talk about, but you have a dream
about the order of the broken cross, which is this apocalyptic cult in Jerusalem. And you
have to sort of fly in there behind enemy lines, be a CIA case officer and recruit some
spy. And then you, you kind of infiltrate this order and systematically, you know, figure out
what's going on with them. And then you, you give their information coordinates or something
to the, to the West, and then they end up getting, getting bombed and they, you know,
the apocalypse is sort of saved or whatever. Is that symbolic? Like now after having led
a long life of trying to, you know, being anti-proliferation of WMDs and, you know, going
after people like Zarqawi and stuff. So do you think that in some ways you are like this,
like almost like biblical prophet, like character who is your, like your mandate or your mission
in life is to stave off the apocalypse and that the instantiation of the apocalypse in
the modern day is in fact just the proliferation of biological weapons and, and, you know, WMDs
and that sort of thing. And that, that, that that's your kind of divine purpose, if you will.
Yeah. I think I can say this in a way that doesn't sound too grandiose, but it certainly
not a personal mission that I feel I'm on that if I don't do this, somehow we fail as
a species or I'm very, I'm just very aware that all the work I've done, particularly
in nuclear and proliferation, I've gotten into trying to stop networks from trafficking and
nuclear materials and doing, which by the way, a lot of people do. And that's a lot
of my solace or, or I take comfort in fact, there are a lot of really great people working
on this with or without a sense of divine purpose. I mean, and I never expressed or carried
into my, my work, the divine notion of purpose that I feel because I do keep that separated.
I'm a very strong believer in separation of church and state and not just as a way we think
of ourselves as, as a country and a society, but as a principle of, of keeping that separate.
I have to unite them in my mind though. I have to, to reconcile them when there's conflict.
Uh, I learned at West Point duty, honor country, uh, which is a very high minded principle and
difficult to, I say, it's the greatest thing West Point gave me was a sense of principle
of having honor, doing your duty and doing it with integrity and, and understanding country,
not being the president, but country being the people and our history and what we represent.
So I, that's almost religious, right. To do it right. And so there's not that big of a gap,
but when it comes to the apocalypse and, and, and those ideas, yeah, I'm very aware of,
I became a very aware of it. I was, I didn't start aware of it except through my dreams.
Typically all my dreams and the sequence of things I've described here today, Jesse, are,
are, are, are ways of saying I, I was conditioned, preconditioned, uh, prepared for both my work and my,
my, my, my spiritual growth and growth and faith the same way. They were assets to me to have some
ideas what this was all about. And I had to connect it still. And I was sometimes reluctant
to do that. It took me a long time to write the letter to the Pope, uh, that Mary told Virgin
Mary told me to write and it should have done it the next day. And there's a whole story there that
I think could guide a lot of people. We're always reluctant maybe to do the things we know we should
do. I'm no different. Yeah. You know, I'm, I'm certainly no warrior, you know, that's out in the
lead of everybody and stopping the world from being destroyed by nuclear weapons and proliferation.
But I'm one of them, I'm, I'm there. And fortunately there are a lot of people like me
and I think people should take great comfort that, uh, I have found that most people in public service,
which is a counterintuitive conclusion to come to in today's world, uh, are, are amazing people
and, and do great things. And the best people and including a lot of the scientists in the
department of energy and our nuclear labs, things like that could get a lot more money, not working
for the government or working on the outside. So for them, it's like, for me, it was never about money
or fame or recognition, uh, reward. And you mentioned the department of energy. What was
your exact title there? I was the director of intelligence and counterintelligence of the
department of energy. And you gave me this, uh, it was a department of energy, uh, office of
intelligence and counterintelligence. And it says, we keep the real secrets. And it's a little,
a little gray alien. Um, now, uh, you know, as you know, and we've, we've spoken about this,
you know, I've run into all these connections between UFOs and, and, and, and, uh, and, and
aliens and, or I don't know if they're aliens, but some sort of like non-human presence and the DOE.
And, um, you, you mentioned actually like in your book that there was some sort of like hazing ritual
brief that you got. Is that right? Yeah. Because it's such an obvious thing to pull a thread on.
We like to do a thing, which I was introduced to. I didn't create it, which we took a director
level. So deputy director, secretary of energy was involved and several other big wigs and me as the
director of intelligence. And we take a newbie, the newbie would be a political appointee, very high
level, maybe, you know, deputy secretary or assistant secretary or some level who had just signed up
and gotten their clearances and were taking their jobs. And we bring them down to the bowels of the
department of energy where some of the most secretive things are guarded. And you know where
those are kind of already whispers when they come by and you pull them into this back room, like
Maxwell smart and the old, old TV shows going back through layer and layers of secrets back into the
vault and you get back into the deepest vault in the DOE and you bring them back. So the person's
back there and they're already, and you have a briefer and you have about six, seven people,
seniors sitting around a table looking very grim. And the hazing ritual is to explain to them that we
really did have aliens. We covered aliens. One was injured, one was not. And we got the alien
space technology through Roswell, you know, et cetera. And it was a real thing. And the briefing
is so good. It's got all the real DOE, what we call tickets, you know, we call secret access program
saps they're called and things on this to make it seem as real as possible. And then the briefer goes
through and says a very convincing story that he is now this person that's come in, is being brought,
brought into this ultimate secret access program, SAP, ultimate one as a member of a very rare team that
transcends all the different presidencies and parties. Cause you can't obviously brief every
president coming in on this. You gotta be very discerning and only bring in people when they can
contribute. And you're going to be part of the expedition that goes to, we hired you. In fact, you were
hired for this job, but you're really going to go on this expedition to this planet. We've, they've
helped us develop the technology to travel to their, their location and greet us when we get
there. So it's got all this and there's, you know, obviously there's a corpses on tables and stuff to
make this all look. At what point do you tell them it's a joke? Well, somebody cracks up and it,
it, it, it, somebody can't keep it in any longer. We betray our own, our own. And the secretary of energy,
the secretary of energy is literally in on this. It's a deputy secretary who's, who was in my case
was in the room. But yeah, so we raise it to the, the highest level. And, and what's funny is there
are, there are, but there was a serious side to that chapter I put in the book. I wanted to first
take a lot. I want to take a break from some of the subjects. It was a writing, a writing technique
involved, but part of it also was to, to raise a bigger point. That is something you are doing a lot
of inquiries into and others. I don't know what secret that I don't know myself. I don't know
everything. Obviously I used to know in CIA, it got so paranoid at one point, got so paranoid. I
couldn't pass a polygraph anymore. And I, they actually let me publish a chapter on that, which
I was really surprised when I was failing the polys, uh, because I knew too much. And I was one of the few
people that knew everything about a certain subject that, uh, that, uh, I couldn't even tell the
polygrapher. I didn't trust a polygrapher. Let's put it that way. So you get to this, uh,
uh, wilderness of mirrors. It's a famous poem, but there's a famous book on it too, about espionage,
where you start looking at everything, everybody and everybody being, knowing something you don't.
And the fact is I used to marvel at people walking around the halls of CIA that thought they were so
smart on everything. They used to talk smack and I don't, you know, they don't know what I know.
And then I thought, well, there's probably stuff that this guy over there knows that I don't know.
So you start looking that way. And DOE is even worse. Cause I, I tease my CIA colleagues and
friends. I said, you know, I learned some of this nation's most important secrets at DOE, not CIA.
DOE does stuff that, man.
Do you feel like that is true?
Oh, I know it's true.
You know, it's true.
I know it's true.
What years were you DOE?
2005 to eight.
Now the point in the story though, is it's a valid thing to wonder, does the president know this has come
up a lot in UFO history. It started with really Reagan and Gorbachev musing about, um, they can
need to get together. So when the aliens come, the U S and Russian Reagan mentioned that he was
joking, but it was, it was on his mind. Right.
And then later it was president Clinton. I know was interviewed by somebody and said, do you believe
that we have signs of alien life and we've hiding her? There's a program or something. And he basically
said, I don't think they tell me even though I'm the president, he said that. So it speaks to
both the dangers of secrecy really. Cause you can't get to that point. You can't get to the point
both of the, that you're don't want to share secrets because you just, they're secret or you're
thinking you've got to withhold this from the president. I don't think you can go there and
have a small group of people. That's when you could get into your deep state. If groups form
around subgroups form around the real government and start to do things, the real government's not
aware of. Well, that's kind of the textbook. I don't believe in the deep state. I've been since I
was 17 years old and I'm 71 now and I'm still very connected. If there's a deep state, I want to know
who's in it and where it's operating from and what they're doing. Cause I have no idea. But when you
get to something like this, somebody would say, and I told you it would be me. If I knew that we had
evidence of extraterrestrial visits to earth, I'd go to the press.
What about if we just had evidence of some sort of anomalous phenomenon around our
nuclear sites that we can't explain? Well, see, that's intriguing. You've, you've talked a little
with me about that and that's the first I heard of it. Yeah. Interesting. Cause you, if you Google
or even chat GPT, like, uh, UFO incursions to around like, you know, national labs and nuclear sites,
even in that time range, 2005 to 2008, you'll see stuff. You'll see. Right. I believe you.
Effie Warren, you'll see Malmstrom base and you'll see literally people, missile security officers
who've signed affidavits saying that they've seen incursions. And this is, there's a great
journalist. He's a friend of mine named Robert Hastings. And he's written a book called UFOs and
nukes. And it is ubiquitous. He has 167, you know, top TS, you know, secret cleared, you know,
missile security officers, radar operators, guys on the PRP program, which I'm sure you're familiar
with where you have to report if you're on ibuprofen, you know, cause you're, you're,
you're guarding the crown jewel secrets of American defense and they just see saucers,
tic-tacs, orbs everywhere around our nuclear sites. And in some cases, these sites are getting shut
down. There's a 2010 case in Effie Warren where literally Obama gets briefed because it was down
for, you know, they say it was 59 minutes, but I think, so this Bob Hastings back channeled with this
retired missile technician and he was in touch with some missile technicians on site and they
attribute it to this cigar shaped object that literally, you know, um, this, this sort of
tic-tac thing that shut down the base. And so you, did you not hear of anything like that?
Well, I can, I can say completely openly and transparently when I was in DOE and I was director
of intelligence, I never was briefed on any of that. Uh, so it doesn't mean it didn't occur.
And I take very seriously what you said. I, I, I think in all likelihood, a lot of those reports
are, are true, or at least being truthfully reported. Yeah. And, uh, I don't know if it's
because they're handled somewhere else, which gets to kind of some of the big questions or whether
because they're individual things that never get resolved there, they don't go anywhere, but we can
never resolve it because we don't know what's going on. I would believe that. Cause I, I, I guess I
would work. I worry if the head of intelligence and counterintelligence for the DOE isn't, isn't
hearing about these encourage, like that's, that seems so fundamental to this, you know,
the safety of, and maybe that's why it's impossible to talk about on the kind of the civil side on the
open side or something, because how can you say, you know, these things are flying with impunity
over our sites, but I don't know. I wish there was some better way to talk about it.
I think, you know, I'm not, obviously I'm not the president, uh, or, you know, anybody who would
be in that decision-making, but I think it would be a, a strategic mistake of historical proportions
for a body of government at any given time to conceal that truth from the American people
thinking we can't handle it or somehow it compromises. If our security is being, or national
security is being compromised that way, I can't think of a scenario where it's better that the
people don't know it than if they do know it. Because if there's a problem, we need everyone
to know, kind of have some things to go on. Uh, and I, I don't believe in like the mass panic
sort of things and stuff like that. So it's really a question of trust. And, and, and when you get to
trust, the government has very little trust. The whole, the whole deep state phenomenon is rooted
in mistrust of government. Right. And the assumption that we don't, if we don't know what
the government's going on, we don't believe what we're being told. There must be something really
bad going on. My experience is really kind of the polar opposite. It's been, you'd be very
disappointed at times if you knew what we're doing because it's not always very good. And sometimes
it's malicious and bad, just bad, wrong, illegal. Yeah. Because you're getting, if you're doing a
certain amount of things, some people are going to do illegal things. Like it just,
inevitable. I think the, the public on this issue is probably so confused by the government's
messaging because you have people like James Clapper, Jim Semivan, guys who are like, you
know, James Clapper's DNI. I know them all. Yeah. You know them. Exactly. Yeah. Jim Semivan,
very high up at the CIA. Yeah. So like, have you, if you, if you know them, you know, they're
out in this movie age of disclosure saying, you know, this is non-human intelligence is real.
We're in an arms race with China and Russia on this stuff. We have a reverse engineering program
with UFOs. Like, have you called them up? Hey guys, like, what are you talking about? Like,
this isn't really like. Right, right. Well, it, no, I haven't called them up specifically,
but I certainly, and you've helped not only whet my appetite, but give me some things to work with
in terms of broadening my, I'm open-minded on it. I truly am. I, I'm not dismissing it at all.
I think that's a big mistake. Uh, I was more going to the, the idea of that we got in our
hazing ritual is how do we handle these things? And are, are we actually prepared for the reality
that could come to us at any time? You talk about your ultimate, we, intelligence, the thing we worry
about most as intelligence community is the fear of, uh, surprise, strategic surprise. 9-11,
collapse of the Soviet Union, Arab Spring, aliens coming to birth and we not being able to have a
clue. Yeah. I mean, I, every time there's an interstellar object coming now and you've got
this astronomer saying it's nothing and this one's saying, I don't know though, not so fast. I mean,
I pay a lot of attention to that as a reader because I think one day one of those things won't
be just a comet. Do you, do you, do you think nothing happened at Roswell or do you have it,
do you have a take? Well, what we know is happened at Roswell, maybe then, or certainly over the years
is I suspect something happened. Right. And, and so the, the question is, is it something
we created and contain like experimental, uh, flights or, or development of our new aircraft? I mean,
the whole history of, which is a lot of CIA's history is on the technical side of the SR-71 and
all these different, uh, aircraft, secret aircraft. The whole, the key to that is secret, you know,
to be, to be ahead of everything on that so we can fly them around the world and not be seen.
So the idea that we're doing exotic testing and their accidents and crashes and things that much,
I'd, I'd be surprised if there's not more of them any of us know. But, uh, and again,
I wouldn't know that at CIA cause I wasn't in those, you know, those, those, those, uh,
saps or whatever you call them. Uh, the thing that did surprise me at DOE for all the incredible
secrets, many, some of which were nuclear related things is just how few of them related to this.
So again, that could suggest two explanations. One is it's done somewhere else. And even I was,
was hazed by, by, or, or, or, you know, there's less to it for the more banal reason, or I'd call it
that, that no one's pulling it together. You know, you talk to someone like Jim Sammy, Sammy Van Good
call. By the way, the people you mentioned, I have immense respect for. Yeah. So why would they,
cause yeah, I, I wouldn't imagine they would want to lie about this topic. No, no, I don't think,
I don't think they're lying. Okay. They don't, they have no motivation to lie about it. Yeah. So I think
it's well, I think it's sincere and well-intended, uh, statements you take it. But you wouldn't put
your money on them being right. Um, I don't know what being right is. See, one thing I haven't been
able to get from, we had congressional testimony, we've had this movie, which I haven't seen yet.
So, so I'll defer judgment on the, on the movie. But the one thing we haven't heard from any of
them, and the question I would ask Jim Clapper or Jim Sammy Van or anybody, if I called them up
as, as old friends is to say, okay, you say this and that. I've never heard that before. You say
that before. Like what, why don't you then say exactly what you mean? What, if, if you have that
as a statement, you've say a summary of what you think, you're not going to provide any like
specifics of what you mean by that. Right. When, where, how, where is it now? What does it migrate?
I understand it might be deeply classified. They provide some specifics. They talk about
Roswell as a real event. There were beings that came out of, I think they say four beings
that came out of this craft. You know, I think they even mentioned one surviving or something.
So they do, they do mention some specific details. Yeah. So, you know, I don't know there,
those are real claims. Yeah. I mean, I, like I said, I see no reason to discount the people
you mentioned among some of the other people I've heard are in it just because they don't have
the proof. Um, again, I, I, I implore the government to think hard about what they're
trying to do here. What's, what's the purpose of, of not disclosing? Yeah.
Of non-disclosure. You know, secrecy, one of the things I've always felt strongly about is
there's too much secrecy in the government. Yeah.
And it's this kind of insidious secrecy that's disruptive. It's kind of corrosive to democracy.
Yeah. And, and this is coming from me and my community. I just too much, too much. And
there are damn good reasons not to talk about certain nuclear data or who's a spy. And when
you have evidence, you know, you're starting to pick up evidence of a spy in your ranks
or you're going to compromise the thing and lose it. But other things we, we just keep secret
way beyond its time for no reason. I won't even say apparent, which is a qualifier. I just
say I could, I could state categorically. We, we just can't think the UFO thing could
be an example of that or.
Well, I, I think it is not by virtue that it wouldn't be revelatory. Therefore, somebody
would say, keep it secret. Cause it's like, who's going to change our whole impression
of life in the universe. Okay.
Yeah.
But that's the reason I would say they got to declassify it.
You can't keep something like that secret.
Yeah.
You know, you can't, you, you got to share that. Everybody in this country ought to know
if the U S government has concluded that there's life on other planets because we have evidence,
not because we've seen, you know, Tic Tacs or I get all that, you know, the, there, and
there's still the big joke, of course, which, you know, all this better than I is, you know,
why are all these images always fuzzy, but it's, it's the idea that.
But they even have explanations for that. They say it's like, you know, gravitational
lensing and blue shifts. The guy who talks about that is this guy, Hal Puthoff, who's
at university of Institute of advanced study, Austin. And he, you know, is I think a long
time CIA guy as well. And he talks about Stephen Hadley in the Bush administration is going through
this whole exercise of should we disclose or should we not disclose? And them reading the
three body problem as part of this exercise to figure out whether, you know, uh, and this
is this Chinese science fiction novel that involves this, you know, try solarian alien
race or whatever. And, uh, the aliens having a lot to do with frontier physics as well, clamping
down on our physics, because that's our tip of the spear ability to defend ourselves as
the human race. And, um, so, and he says they go through this whole exercise and they come
out saying, you know, it's actually, it's not worth it to, to, to disclose. And, and
Hal Puthoff said this on, you know, Joe Rogan on like the biggest podcast in the world. And
I'm like, what's going on? You like, you have on the one, you have this indetectable, undetectable
dark matter. You have on the one hand, people like Elon Musk, like yourself who like, you
know, super like amazing bona fides, extremely respectable, like highly intelligent, you know,
know a lot of stuff. And then you have Jim Semivan, Hal Puthoff, Jim Clapper, and they're
all like, so pro UFO and they have like discrete stories of these things. And I'm like, what's
like, how do I make sense of this? You know?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's so confusing.
Well, I think, I think the way you make sense of it is to keep, keep pushing it and keep
interviewing and, and keep.
Do you think Hadley ever went through an exercise like that? I mean.
Yeah. There's really no, I'd put no value in my, in my judgment, except to say, you know,
I know Steve Hadley and I respect him too.
Yeah.
I've never heard anything like that.
Never heard anything.
No. I mean, I, I, I said, you know, I just want you to know one thing.
Yeah.
I don't know. And if I knew, I probably would, I can't say categorically, I know I would,
but I can't see why I would keep that a secret, even at risk to myself.
Yeah.
Of being punished in some way.
I just, I, I feel that fervently.
No, I appreciate that. And I also, you know, I think if that weren't the case, you probably
wouldn't come on the show because I, I could throw, I mean, like, I mean, I, and I, and
I, you know, I'm not, I won't belabor this too long, but like, there's so much, it's like
a whole ontology that has basically you can, you can create around the DOE being like holding
the crown jewels of US foe stuff. There's transclassified foreign material and, you know,
special nuclear material from the, you know, 1954 atomic energy act where you have restricted
data. Anything that could be radiological in nature is immediately born secret upon sort
of retrieving it.
I know that. Yeah.
Yeah.
I'm sure you're familiar. So like, there's this idea that that is sort of this Trojan horse
for UFO material and that, you know, nest nuclear emergency support teams. Like, you
know, I spoke to, um, my buddies, uh, UAP Gerb and, and then this other guy, um, David
Grush is this whistleblower before this. And they were talking, you know, about those two
things. And so you, there's nothing that you know about any of that stuff.
No. And, and I, I, you know, hasten to add, you know, when I think back at myself, you
know, in, in, uh, all modesty, some guy coming in from CIA to head up intelligence for three
years, um, obviously the intelligence shop is not the place to go for this information
or having access to it. Now there might be one person they trust with it there. And it
is a, it is an organization, do we, that, that you could easily imagine because I described
the, the, the, going in through the, the multiple vaults back deeper and deeper into the recesses
of the building to the point where there's not a sound coming in and out of there other
than the people talking in the room. So you, you, you have a culture where this is all
very possible. Yeah.
And I have known other subjects, a few that I've got roped into where there was a very
exclusive group of people, um, looking at it. Uh, and to the point where this was even
at CIA where we didn't put anything, well, specific, very specific thing, not generally
done and very highly unusual, irregular, I'd call it, or nothing pertaining to that was
even put into any kind of a record.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. So anything's imaginable.
Yeah, it's possible. Yeah. I mean, I, at the soul foundation, there's just a Stanford, um,
organization that's dedicated to UFO research. Um, these NN, NNSA guys, national nuclear security
administration guys showed up. And so it's like, why are you interested in this stuff?
And then there's this news nation, which just covers UFOs a lot. There's this slide that was
like, uh, advanced gravity propulsion research. And it was a guy who had incurred some sort of
Havana syndrome, like, you know, biological effects, but it was, you know, it was like,
that was his title. And so I'm like, okay, DOE is doing this exotic gravity research.
Well, that doesn't surprise me at all.
Okay.
No, no.
But the UFO stuff surprises me.
Well, there's, there's, there's a major distinction here, you know, looking into,
I would call all forms of materials and advanced propulsion techniques and, and, uh, energy related,
you know, when people think of department of energy, just to, for a very quick, very quick
explanation of what it is, which most people don't know is department of energy consists
of really three main components that are been, it's a hybrid that shouldn't exist together,
but it's a product of a lot of politics that created DOE. The one side, there's the energy
part, which contrary to a lot of, a lot of common belief is not just gas and oil and fossil fuels.
It's also advanced form of renewables. It's for nuclear power. And of course it's for looking
into advanced energy forms, some of which we don't gravity magnets. So all that's in the
energy department and there's an overwhelming thought. It's just, you know, Jimmy Carter
created it during the crisis with the middle East over gas and oil. So that's no, but it's
all this other stuff that's strengthened by the second major component of DOE, which is
the science part of DOE, which a lot of which does pure science. So the pure science part
of DOE is some of its research for ongoing needs of the U S government. Some of it's just
advanced things. I've met some of the most fascinating people who do things like chaos
theory and look for numbers. They're looking for the equation, you know, the equation of
chaos, or it got me on a whole track of thinking of my philosophy and my beloved philosophy in
a totally different way, which is, wow, what if every human decision like in history is
just permutations of choices we make freely, but no matter what we do, it's to determine
outcome because all those choices inevitably, because they're driven by an equation of human
nature. So they all drive you to the same result. Well, I got some of those ideas from DOE scientists.
So who are, who are doing, and some of them are into that esoteric, those esoteric kind
of aspects of their work. And again, wonderful people to talk to some of them, you know, very,
very eccentric or whatever you want to call it. And then the third part is the national nuclear
security administration, which is almost like I describe as an autonomous Republic within,
within the DOE because it's got some independent status because
for a time, the NNSA was seen as not getting the attention and freedom of action it needed within a
dysfunctional DOE. It's not dysfunctional anymore. DOE is quite functional, but there was a period,
as I refer to the politics. So you had those three, many ways, complementaries, but in some ways
independent. And then the national nuclear security, our national laboratory complex serves those
three things, energy, nukes, and pure science. And they, they're, they're proportioned in their work
and what's required, what the basic priorities are. Have you ever seen a one of one material,
like the, a super unique material that's never, you've never seen elsewhere? No. Okay. I would
remember that. The other, the other, you know, common attribute is you realize how vast what I just
described is. So the probability that I know a lot of it is small and, but it's prescribed. So
by that, I mean, I don't, I'll be kind of vague, but everything that's exceptional. Yeah. Typically you get
read into individually. Yeah. It's not just yours as a result of the job you hold. Yeah. If it's important
enough, then you get like, someone will tap you on the shoulder and you have, you know, specials,
things happen, things happen that are different. So it's entirely possible that there are very few
people that know a lot about all the most important things, if that makes sense, because
they're divided. Yeah. And I could easily see things like we're talking about being in a separate
category, which is even curtailed further by people who really need to know. Because the ultimate,
the need of the chapter that I have in my book for this is called need to know. So the other,
I'm trying to also illustrate a principle. I've never been entirely comfortable about intelligence
and government secrecy is the idea that need to know governs it all. Well, that's fine.
If need to know is perfectly interpreted. Well, I think the public needs is, is, is, has a need to
know for the ontological truth, the basic, you know, it's just like nuclear science is taught
at every university, but nuclear trade secrets should be classified. I think that should be
applied to this, if it's at all real. And to me, when people ask about, you know, my conviction in
UFOs, I always say you have to view everything probabilistically. The idea that we're in some
reverse engineering arms race, I would probability weight much lower than I am sure that there are
these objects showing up around nuclear assets all over the world. Not even, there's a town in Japan.
We have our American alchemy Japanese shirts here. There's a town in Japan next to the Fukushima
prefecture, which is their civilian energy grid that has a muse. It's this mountain, Sengan Mori. They
have a whole museum dedicated to UFOs and all these geomagnetic anomalies and they're obsessed with UFOs.
So I do, I do think that is this ubiquitous, you know, commonality. And, and that, that is,
that is the thing I think you can be most high conviction in a UFO world. But, um,
Well, then I can also see that the tie, there's just such an obvious tie in with, um,
other than worldly life forms or intelligence and our highest forms of intelligence or most destructive
things like nuclear. I mean, cause there, again, the, the whole idea of, I've, I've tried to get
accustomed or adapted to the reality of nuclear weapons and nuclear secrets my whole life.
Even having spent by, by accident as I unfolded, it unfolded as a big accident. But when I look back
on it, yeah, it's like nuclear here, nuclear here. And there's always, it's a little bit like your
appearances are all the nuclear sites. It's like, it keeps coming to me. And you could even make a case,
if you wanted to write that script, that some of these appearances were, um, a divine awareness
in sense of messages and of the need to warn in the, because the essence of the Ezekiel warning
as a watchman, the watchman is a specific type of, you know, it's not a messenger. It's not a prophet.
It's a watchman. Only responsibility is to warn. So specifically in biblical terms, the idea of
the watchman warning, the people will be held accountable, not for if it's true or stops,
whatever's going to happen from happening. That's not the accountability. The count of
explicit accountability of being a watchman is to warn your job is to warn. So when you ask me,
did you prevent, or you, you'd have to banish that idea from your mind that you are going to prevent
the apocalypse or shape it in some form? Cause I don't think any human being is going to have
that responsibility, but it's pretty hard just to do the warning part. Yeah. Cause like you said,
if people genuinely believe that this is part of it and maybe you're a watchman for, for, you know,
shining a light on so, so much on this factor, particularly depending how things turn out.
Yeah. Yeah. We'll see. I'm curious to see where this whole topic is. Um, you know, in the, in this,
in this kind of hazing ritual brief that you had on UFOs, do you remember the date of Roswell that they
gave you? Uh, no, not off the top of my head. I think I had it in the, I think I wrote it in the
book, but it is in the book and it's July 7th, 1947. Yeah. Do you think that connects with your
download seven, four, seven? Oh my goodness. Good. You know, that's the first time I've ever
thought that, that it might. Are you, are you trying to tell the audience in coded fashion
that you might know? I'm being as what I've tried to be throughout the complete and it's even better
in complete honesty, which didn't even cross my mind. So I couldn't possibly have fabricated that
to make it more compelling. There's one other one. That's a really interesting. There was a, uh,
this will fit your, you need to look this up if you don't already know it. Yeah. So one of the
scientists at DOE kind of knew my, my stuff with numbers and this may have been a red,
explained to me the famous Vela. Have you heard the Vela incident? Nuclear explosion. It's,
it's called, uh, the seven, they labeled it at the 747 incident. Whoa. And it's a nuclear test
that South Africa made. Right. But the suspicion is they did it on behalf of the Israelis.
It's a suspicion. I'm not saying to your viewers, you know, this is, but this is the,
into the murky secrets of the development of the Israeli bomb, which of course the U S kind of
gave the big thumbs up handshake deal to, you know, you know, you need this kind of thing.
At least that's what I, what I've heard. So the, the point being there is, boy, that's a very
Vela 747. Look it up. Fascinating. Yeah. I don't know. I, I, I think there's something
very ontologically interesting about nuclear and it's some sort of energy unlock that if I were
some sort of concurrent civilization, whether it's extraterrestrial, you know, which the people who
deny UFOs at the highest levels often say extraterrestrial, because I think it's a,
we don't have evidence that it's extraterrestrial. You know, I think it's, it could be like,
you know, some sort of non-human or even ultra terrestrial, some past civilization on earth or
something, but that it seems like they would want to monitor nuclear. Like that just seems like this
really important unlock. And it, that seems to be corroborated by all the evidence, but as to what
that means, I just don't know. That now you're thinking of other people looking at us maybe way
past this point. There's some secret we may bump into. I don't know that there is worried about us
blowing ourselves up as we, you know, what they probably have no reason to worry too much about
that. But what if they're worried we're going to cross a threshold of knowledge that they're
already aware of and that has grave implications for them. That's really interesting. I mean,
it's like the building blocks of life or if life is, if you think about the universe is like
information theoretic, like maybe you're getting into the root access or something.
Well, you know, but it adds another element to this that isn't, I don't think well enough
understood or absorbed by the public is we take for granted the kind of the expression of
this incredible God's secrets, we call it, as manifested in our discoveries of those secrets.
And yet in every domain, whether it's AI or nuclear or biological life sciences, in every one of those
domains, our knowledge is so limited of what we're dealing with. And if you go to, we think a little
about the implications of AI, and I've heard some in various places, I've heard talks and even by some
of the top guys on this, and it scares the hell out of me.
Well, yeah, it does.
They don't know what they're doing.
Well, it's, it's, it's a, you could call it a process of like umwelt hacking or something. So like
umwelt is like, um, this is my old colleague, Eric Weinstein talks about this, where it's like,
you get to deeper layers of ontological truth, the more, the better your measurement instruments
are, or there's even a physicist who's at CERN for a while, Ken Wilson talks about, um, uh, phase
transitions in materials. And the more you put them under duress, you know, that you get these whole
new properties, like, you know, as you put them under duress. And so I wonder if, you know, it's kind
of what we were talking about before, it's quantum indeterminacy between level of energy
and time. If you have particle accelerators or nuclear blasts, you might get weird ontological
weirdness around those events.
Of course. Particularly as little as we know the physics, you know, and especially since,
uh, the people at the top of those fields are guiding all of us. And it's the same with
these other fields. Right. And that's the, I mean, cloning.
Yeah.
Stunning.
I never, I never thought I had a dream once on cloning.
Yeah.
Long before clones.
And I thought, oh, that's never going to happen in my lifetime. Well, you know, pets are being
cloned, brought back to life. And that in itself, we're, we're playing God. So we're at the point
where we're in a way we've earned this as the only by in biblical terms, again, we're, we created
in the image of God. I was always seized by that. I, I, at an early age, even I recognize this is
special image of God means really, it's a two way thing means God has a responsibility for us
in a way that I'm sure God will fulfill. And that's been the essence of everything we've
talked about. God's going to send messengers. God's going to send his own son. God's going to
do X and Y, send a prophet mom, but all the things that, and with, with the typical characters
behind him, always the same people, Angel Gabriel, and they're always the same people, always the
same entities, right? Behind all. And then all that's going to be his way of guiding us, making
sure we don't screw up entirely before, you know, in the end, we'll, okay, I'm going to give some,
some reassurance, which sounds awful, but judgment day and apocalypse, that things are going to turn
out because that's really what it's about. It's not about punishing us. We punish ourselves.
It's about reconciliation. It's about judgment, meaning you, there is a reward and a penalty for what
you do in your life. You're not, you're not here anonymously. Like that was the thing on the train.
It was like, I'm not, God's aware. He's there right now. He's like standing there. That's why that
is in the book. Cause I'd never had that feeling before or after it was the one time it was that
deep. And, and so the same thing applies with handling God's gift. So we're, we're entitled,
we're given access to things that we, in a way have no right to have access to, but we're not,
there's no point to give us freedom in the whole garden of Eden story, unless it's full freedom,
which because of the way we're wired, we're going to screw that up for the most part.
And so that's all known.
You can write your equations now.
God is, God knows.
It'll play out how many Hegelian dialectical histories you want to write. They all might be
different, but guess what? They're all going to end the same way. But when it comes to how the
handling of the power of God turns out, that's the unique test. And that's what,
so I never get into prophecy. I don't prophesize anything, but predict when's the apocalypse,
when's it start? Like one of the things about my dream was that I specifically remember was 2060
in the chameleon dream of the future, where I was trying UFOs and going out and trying,
I was already in an apocalypse of going back and forth. The new part of the world had been
destroyed with the great nuclear war of 2034. And I was going back and forth, trying to find
people, trying to make bombs. This is way before I did the terrorist bomb stuff, by the way.
Whoa.
Yeah.
You had a dream about that.
This is the dream that you asked me about in 1981.
And you said you were flying on what the DOE would call UFOs.
UFOs. Yeah. And I had the dream in 1982.
And, and, but this was, these were our, like, crafts, like American crafts.
Our crafts sent from CIA.
Yeah.
From, all managed and all connected to a massive supercomputer.
We would call it quantum. I didn't know that back then.
In, in the bowels of CIA underground.
Do you think that we have propulsion modalities that transcend chemical combustion?
I don't know.
Yeah.
No idea.
But in the dream, certainly.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
In the dream, certainly. I, I, I didn't know what it was. I just was flying around like
it was all known, but my dream didn't reveal to me how it, but it was a, it was a manifestation
of Reagan's Star Wars thing, Star Wars, which before Star Wars. So he gave the great Star
Wars speech, I think in 84.
Mm-hmm.
And my dream was in 82. So I was already anticipating, I'll call it that, this idea of a shield.
So my dream was basically the world had been divided in two, the world in the shield, the
world out of the shield. And the whole point was to keep, of the UFOs and intelligence was
a global intelligence service that would keep out, keep out the people trying to break through
the shield.
Well, yeah, that's fascinating.
So now we're into what? We're into exactly what you're talking about.
Yeah. And that, that, in fact, the Bluegill triple prime thing was, it was a high altitude
nuclear test, but it was a defense against, uh, Russian ICBMs and Soviet ICBMs. And there's
even a Rand corporation paper a couple of years before it was pulled off around speculating
as to how that would be done. And Malmgren was at the Institute for Defense Analysis at
the time, and they've been involved in every missile defense, you know, system since then.
And, and he directly ties Bluegill triple prime to star Wars and to, um, you know, um, a strategic
defense initiative. And so then there's, again, there's this like weird question of like, is
there some dual use around UFOs for that or something? And like, I don't know. And you
have the golden dome now, you know?
Well, I think one of the questions I know people are asking, but just like when you're
hearing us talk, muse about this is we're sort of due for another big transformational
change. I mean, we've had, of course, the industrial age and then we had more recently
the internet age. And it just strikes me that we're due for something like this, this idea
of something propelling us into a future. We really haven't anticipated as over in a way
overwritten on everything, every possible permutation of our future, something that's going to change
all that. We're going to say, well, it's not that future after all.
It feels like we're on the verge of a paradigm shift for sure.
It does.
And it feels like, at least for the stuff I'm investigating, it feels like the dam is going
to break because there are, if, if the, uh, kind of incumbent, you know, um, uh, current
paradigm is like, you know, inside of the dam or whatever, there are like 15 different vectors
of like holes in the dam. And that thing is just, it's about to burst. Like it, when I hear you,
you know, uh, talk about all these different things that you're working on too, that's the
immediate reaction I had is what we just said there with, with one another is just, we're ready
for a big paradigm shift. It's probably going to be something we've never anticipated based
on something we didn't see coming. And the most important thing of that is it's happening
at a time. And I think very few people understand this. I'm not trying to, I don't want to talk,
be condescending, but I just, I myself struggle with this a lot, uh, where time and scale is,
time is rapidly shrinking on us. Everything is more accessible so fast. We can't process it much
like make, make good. Back in the day when you mail things and you set cables and you mentioned
how easier you could contemplate things, you can make it. Even then it was rough making good
decisions. And at a certain point we reached a happy medium where this, where speed increased
to the point where you can better decisions faster. But now we're at the point, I'm sure
of this in government or even maybe the private sector, I think, where the amount of things
we have to decide at the speed we have to decide is overwhelming us at the scale it applies
because of population growth and how everything's interacting and the way the internet is tied
everything together.
Well, that's what that movie, Age of Disclosure, felt like. It felt like the government trying
to get in front of, uh, all these kinds of truths coming out and figuring out a way to frame
it or something, you know, proactively.
That would be good.
Sure. Yeah. And, but you know, it feels, it does feel like that is inevitable. Like this
stuff is, is sort of, uh, coming out. And I wonder in some ways, like you, you believe
in angels, right?
Yes, I do. Yeah, of course.
So these, all these things have literally happened to you. And I wonder if like, it's like
the Age of Disclosure has their veneer of like extraterrestrials. Your veneer might be angels,
demons, eschatology, the Bible. If I were like, would you believe that angels might show up
around nuclear sites that might seem more plausible to you?
Well, in a way, in a way. And I'm, you know, I told you, I'm so hesitant to link UFOs to
faith and mysticism.
Sure, sure, sure.
So with that gigantic caveat.
Yeah, yeah. And I'm sorry.
No, no, no, no, no. Don't apologize. It's fun. It's fun. Right?
Yeah, yeah.
I don't, I don't think it discredits religion or faith or in any way insults.
Well, it's trying to figure out some underlying truth between, you know, the, the way you're
describing what's happened to you personally. And then these, you know, all these other
intelligence officials who are saying we are not alone, you know?
Right. Well, I think, I think where it ties, I was getting to the, my big, however, you know,
is, is if you believe the one, like, like, like you said, I'm utterly, there's not even any doubt
on my mind about all these things. And also the existence of angels like Gabriel. And now what,
how you describe that or what that reality is, whether, you know, obviously the wing figure
coming from is, I think, symbolic of a messenger from a different state of reality.
But now we're getting very close to being visited by life forms in our own universe that are,
that technically shouldn't be much intersection with us. It's, I've never really doubted the,
the, the sort of actuarial realities that intelligent life must exist in the universe.
I've really never questioned that. What I've, I want to see is the evidence of it and begin to
understand what that means for us. But I've also wanted to understand how space time makes that
work because everything is so distant from us that even with advanced forms of Star Trek forms of
travel, which I loved that show when I was growing up, it's hard to imagine we're going to
intersect at precisely that moment of advanced development of our civilizations in this place,
in our place. Uh, that would be a very low odds, not impossible, but, and then, but then when you
introduce something that we just talked about as being some breakthrough of truth somewhere that
changes entirely our notions of reality, we already know we haven't unified physics. Well,
that's a big one right there. Yeah. There's a reason for that. And I don't think Einstein just
got lazy after, you know, his earliest part of his life when he was at his greatest, I will, I will
sort of reinforce one idea though, is I, I have a much greater belief in younger people like you and
others pushing us into the future than I do my generation. And not so much because we've done
achieve what we want to do, but you know, your minds change. You don't, you know, I, I don't deserve
to be the person I was getting all the insights and things to guide my life and my work that I,
now that I had then. So if I want them now, it's more for my own, you know, satisfaction and that's
not good enough. Right. But, but the idea behind this is that, that we need
people who don't consider themselves experienced or informed through dance degrees and all this
to think like you and others think and to push us. That's where the inspiration is going to come.
I mean, Einstein was a clerk when he was doing his greatest work and there's so many scientists
who were like that now. Yeah. Maybe he's a genius, but yeah. Yeah. Yeah. No, it's a,
yeah. It'll, it'll be interesting to see what happens. It feels like there are all these kind
of heterodox threads of science that weren't taken seriously at all, you know, for the last 30,
40 years. And, uh, increasingly they're kind of in vogue and being taken seriously. And in certain
cases, I think they've been behind, you know, walls of secrecy or stigma, you know, things like,
like documented is, you know, the, the CIA's efforts in remote viewing and parapsychology. And,
you know, that's, I think a well-respected intelligence modality and, you know, at Langley,
uh, but, um, you know, only until the last few years, you know, that was, that was kind of
rested out of the government with the freedom of information act request in 2017. And only in the
last few years are people saying there's something clearly here. And I think that the problem I have
with the super anti UFO people are like, they, you know, say, Oh, this can't be possible. This
observable thing that you've seen a million different times with all these credible people
coming out and saying it can't be real because of the physical, this physical, because of our
current physical model of the universe. But if you were to bet on the anomaly historically and against
the physical model of the universe, you would always be right. You know, you're always wrong if
you bet on the physical model of the universe. So I do think we're on the precipice of something
exciting.
Well, yeah, I agree with you totally. And I hope it's very positive. I, I worry on one,
one aspect that I think as we learn more about the reality we're creating rather than the reality
that exists, we need to make sure we continue to make that distinction. And that can, that can take
the smallest form of knowing when you're a virtual reality, uh, figure in, in an app you're playing on
your iPad or if you're a kid, making sure the kids, you know, don't lose their minds in, in, in, in a,
in a fantasy reality. And I, this is coming from someone who's had these very vexing, disturbing,
disorienting dreams that I've had. And who am I to talk? And, but it was a problem for me in some
respects too, that I've outlined. And then there, it goes up one level from that where you have people,
you know, relying on chat GPT to be their girlfriend or boyfriend or give them life advice.
I'm saying, wow, this is, this is more than dangerous. People are, you know, the idea I, I,
I said at one point, we talked about identity a little bit and how culturally that was different
from people who are more individualistic societies versus say common, common bond societies that depend
on one another, have a perception. They're more involved with one another, but think about it from
the standpoint of, of how that changes. Uh, when you can create a reality that doesn't exist and
replace your reality, cause it's not a very good life you're leading. Yeah. Right now you might go
buy opiates or do something because you see no hope in your future and you don't have a good health
care. You don't have a good job. You don't really have any hope. You're going to break out of this
terrible cycle. We put some, we, I think that's a we thing personally. Yeah. Some people bring it on
themselves, but we as a country owe more to people than we've given them. This isn't a now problem
that we've created. This has been a growing problem for decades. And, and into that environment
comes the temptation to create alternative lives and realities. Um, I wouldn't, you know, watching,
uh, Zuckerberg and Mark Zuckerberg and others trying to create this idea of having people, why do they
want to do this? They want people to come on these virtual realities so they can buy imaginary plots of
land so they can make money off it. I mean, wow. Yeah, no, it's dystopian. That's part of the reason
I'm into the UFO thing, because I think it's, if our life is, if this is somewhat of a simulation, I think
there's a life affirming version of the simulation where we're in a platonic cave and you can ascend
outside and see the light that's lighter than light and, and, you know, um, witness great things in this
reality. And so why would you go into this sort of bit compressed reality? And so that, that's what
motivates me when I'm trying to close this gap between, well, super well-respected people like
yourself. And then these other people like, you know, Chris Mellon, deputy assistant director of
intelligence for, you know, under Bush and Clinton, he even, he just said, he was like, you know, um,
we want to put the CIA's director of science and technology. I think it was the, one of the last
ones, he was like, we need to figure out what she knows about UFOs. And so I'm like, I'm like,
it's maddening to me. Like, how would, how would you advise that I figure out what's going on?
Well, I think you're doing a good job of it. The best thing you can do is what you're doing is
interview credible witnesses, avoid drawing conclusions until you have to, but by the same
token, I think most of the, most of the mind shut phenomena, whether it's UFOs or frankly,
a lot of traditional things, there's a whole massive number of people I can name any, but I
won't embarrass people, uh, who, who just flat won't deal with terrorists having nukes or big
biological weapons simply because they want to think that, you know, men, men wearing rags, you know,
you can't, can't do it. And, but it's the idea though, that you just miss something because,
you know, you want, you underestimate them and that's what you're not doing. And you,
you can't underestimate. And the people who tend to do that and dismissive, dismissive people on
anything I've ever dealt with, there's a group of dismissive people because you're usually placing
your bet on probability basis. Yes. Not impact basis. Yeah. And, and the real risk equation for
any good national security person or someone doing what you're doing is to assess risk as intent
times capability times consequences. Yeah. So we sometimes assume intent. That's typical.
That's done a lot. Assume intent. They can, they don't want part of our failure on 9-11, frankly,
as an intelligence community was we didn't assume they had the intent to do that. And then the
capability you don't even really look into, you don't see it because you haven't really ascribed
that intent to them that they do something that audacious. Yeah. And then of course the consequences,
all they're really looking for. So yeah, you, you, you multiply those things out, but it's the same
thing with UFOs. You see, it's like your, your best bet as an observer trying to maintain some
credibility. Yeah. Like astronomers who cast judgment on every new visitor to our solar system
is to dismiss it as anything. And then if the day comes at some point when it's a real thing,
oh, they, they're, they're nowhere to be found. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I, yeah, exactly. No, exactly.
Yeah. Did, did you know Glenn Gaffney at all? Yeah, I did. Cause he, this guy, um, I really,
I like him a lot. He's a nice, he's a good guy. He, he was, um, he's I think currently on the board
of Arrow, the all domain anomalies research resolution office. I didn't know what he's doing. He was the
director of science and technology at the CIA. And there's a couple of people, one of which was
under oath in front of Congress said he blocked the transfer of UFO material from, uh, Lockheed
Martin to Bigelow aerospace. Do you know anything about that? No, but it's pretty specific. It is
specific. It's a specific. Yeah. Anyways. Well, okay. Uh, well, I appreciate you indulging my
crazy question. No, I'm not indulging. I'm burning and it's fascinating. I, I will say one more thing
about, I wasn't when Glenn was the head of director of science technology, but I, I've had a lot of
interactions with them over, you know, the decades. And one thing I did learn from the interactions is
that most of what they do, most of what they do, I hadn't, I wasn't privy to, I had no, no reason to
be brought into from a need to know perspective. So there's all kinds of things I probably don't know.
So you, and you swear to God, you know, nothing about UFOs. Oh yeah. Yeah. I swear
I swear to God. Okay. Wow. And I know that means a lot to you because you're, yeah. I, you know,
it's, it's, it's, it's a whole different conversation, but I try never to be deceptive
or lie. That's what it would be. Even when I'd have a reason, like you, you're given an alibi
because, oh yeah, you're told not to tell. So you can lie. No, I'll find a different way to
not say it than lie. Yeah. And I've learned that actually it's extremely important being in a
manipulative business, which you can't deny intelligence can be. It's even more important
to maintain your personal integrity and, and, and ability to, to be credible with people. So
if I'm dealing with the Russians, we've had some stories about that, or I'm, I actually, there's a
chapter in my book where I'm dealing with Syrian intelligence or any other intelligence service in
the world or country. Um, my credibility lies in not lying to them. Yep. Uh, and because then what
I tell them is suspect. So then I've contaminated whatever CIA has to offer that. So I, I make it a,
not only a habit, but my, my personal integrity. I, I also believe, and I've given lectures on this,
um, there's no contradiction or conflict between recruiting agents and running them. And there,
we obviously use aliases and things that's not deceptive. If your goal is to protect the agent,
the agent, knowing your real name is bad for the agent. Sure. Yeah. Those kinds of things. Yeah,
of course. But when it comes down to a real litmus test, how far am I willing to go for the agent
versus what the agency tells me to do with the agent? I will defer to the agent's welfare because
this is a human being. So ultimately, um, I'll find a way to reconcile the two. I don't like to
flat out defy headquarters if I can help it, but I have done it. And then the test is a different
test when I flat out say no or defy them and don't do what I've been told to do, which I don't
recommend to everybody out there. But in those cases, I'll, I'll, I'll, uh, own up to it.
Usually before I'll say, no, I'm not going to do what you just told me to do.
Then there'll be a discussion. Yeah. And this is, again, a test of the, uh,
integrity of your organization, whether it's CIA or any other in the U S government,
what, how does an organization react when you've done something you think is either
you're told to do something that it's either illegal or immoral or, or both. How do you handle
it? And it's a test of the organization, whether you're asked to do that. Now, what I personally,
I've said to myself personally, over all my careers, and I've never had to go to the mat on
it to the point I quit, but I would have, if I can't reconcile that, um, I will do what I know
is the right thing to do. Yeah. So we did some bad things, but I understood the reasons for it.
And we did it for not doing the wrong thing, but just because things, sometimes you're faced
with a terrible choice and you don't have an option, but I just wanted to stress that because
it's, it's come up again in, in recent times, you know, you just to be very careful about work
through the whole, for example, uh, uh, forgetting his name, Edward Snowden defected to China and the
Russians. And he's been described by people as a whistleblower and, and there was a whistleblowing
aspect to his motivations and tensions and actions, but it was far exceeded by the damage
he set out to cause to the U S government for no whistleblowing reason. So you have all
this. It's complicated with him because on the one hand, I do think it's important that
the public know that the NSA is a backdoor and every big tech company, they have these programs
like prism and bull run and they can just spy on you through your smart TV and your phone.
And like, that's a, that's messed up. That's not, it's not that simple. Okay. No, it's not
that simple. Okay. But the other, the other part of the answer to that question is, um, the
government should in fact have done maybe some things different than he alleged. And so he
had, there was a, but he went far. Well, he definitely, uh, you know, compromised beyond
that. Sure. Sure. And things that had nothing to do, that just pure immense damage to national
security with no whistleblowing benefit. So he knew exactly what he's doing. And then you
look into the whole background. Now, why do I single him out? I'm not trying to make him
a particular, you know, target of my wrath or ire is that this is, this is the problem in
a nutshell is citizens, individual officers, integrity, everybody comes together on trying
to maintain the integrity of what we're doing. And the more it's secret, the more it's dark
and deep, the more we have to, to do it. And the more disclosure is necessary at the right
level. And we've talked so many ways about how we limit it, where we limit it, you know,
this kind of thing. Do you think anything's going to happen further on the UFO front? Do
you think more is going to come out or? Yeah, I can't imagine it's the end of the story,
right? It's just almost in a way feels like it's just beginning. Yeah. Yeah. I mean, I,
yeah, that would be my expectation as well. I mean, I like in the world in which we have
reverse engineering programs, material, all that stuff, it is actually like a serious national
security issue. If the left hand's not talking to the right, you have these bigoted special
access programs that are like unqueriable, not answering to any sort of civilian organization.
There's zero congressional oversight. And then you're competing against Russia and China who
have these central bases where they can just, you know, pluck scientists from wherever and place
them there and get them to work on whatever they want. Like if in the world where that's real,
it's, it would seem like a dire issue just for you. And like, I always say that as a dog whistle to
the national security people, all I care about is the truth. I care about the truth coming out and I
give her the truth, but like the watchman. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Well, one, one, you know, more thing on
that, I think it's, can't reach a conclusion, but when you start thinking area 51 and the crash and
you've, you've said this, I haven't done that research and I haven't looked into aside from,
and you've been to area 51. Yeah. And you've never seen any UFO, alien UFO type. No, no, I'm sure
that, but I mean, there are kind of two explanations. One is it's our testing crash and we're covering that
up. And two is it intelligent life was there watching what we're doing. And that's an area
which you would be in at that point with all the nuclear tests. I think it's that because they're
over, you think maybe it was that? No, it's plausible. I don't dismiss it. Cause in, in 1945
over Hanford plutonium base, you have this guy, this pilot, Bud Clem falling this like, you know,
ball of light around. You had, you had stuff happening super early in 47. I mean, uh, Robert
Goddard who was a rocket pioneer in the U S had just been testing V two rockets at right
at Roswell. So it's like, I don't think we were testing super advanced propulsion. You
know, there was some interesting stuff happening in Nazi Germany to that effect, but you know,
you had Kammler stop and you had these interesting scientists doing some stuff in that, in that
world. But I think what happened at Roswell was, was otherworldly. I do.
Yeah. I, and I, that's why I wanted to reinforce the possibility. I, I, I don't see how you can
dismiss it unless you know, it's not. In other words, if someone, this is another reason to
declassify because if there was an internal experiment or, you know, something, maybe it's
the problem with that. If even if you then declassify and, and, and, and put it out there,
then there's this possibility we've continued over the decades to work on whatever we were
working on it. And it was an early miserable failure. There's always that explanation why
we won't release.
Yeah. Well, that's also maybe my take. I don't think we've done much with what we've
recovered. I think it's like, uh, you know, um, caveman with a USB drive. The caveman doesn't
understand you, you know, uh, information theory. They have nothing to plug it into. There's
no interface. It's not like an iPhone, you know, that, that would be my guess. So.
Well, when you consider the fact that probably one of the most, at least plausible
continuations of our species over the next hundred years is that we evolved to the point
where the AI crew we create doesn't want us around anymore per all the, all the movie.
But that, that seems so plausible. The problem with being so clever as we are on, on, uh,
artificial intelligence is, it's easy to imagine us out programming the reality of our, our lives
in, in ways not, they will lose control aspect of is, is just one thing, but I could easily
see humans deciding that the perpetuation of the species and the continued evolution of
human beings will no longer follow the, the script of what might've started as a, a biblical,
uh, kind of, uh, idea. And to the point where the one thing God would have want to preserve
in the evolution of not just human species, but all life on earth, if it's a God, God plan
is the idea of mutation and the idea of the weak, uh, moving on to take over the earth as
it goes in a definition we wouldn't think of as the stronger and the superior. And even the
idea Darwin laid out of the survival of the fittest, I kind of, because of my faith look
entirely the opposite now, which is really that is, it's, it's the idea of sacrifice
drives everything. And certainly if there's truth to the idea behind Christ, it's the
idea he came to sacrifice and therefore the way forward is sacrifice. And then all the
truly great people, almost all of them, we would call great people who we don't emulate
by the way. Nobody emulates Christ mainly, but also people like Gandhi or Mandela or people
we admire, you know, who took the path. Tolstoy was one of the greatest pacifists in, in, of
world history, the way he wrote and thought, uh, we don't really follow that, that lead.
We, we kind of respect it, but we're in a completely different path.
Yeah. On, on, on that note. Yeah. I think it should, you know, everybody out there should
try to imitate, you know, sacrifice and, and be, be, be Christ-like. And, um, yeah, I mean,
it's, it's fascinating model of human evolution is, you know, your, your, uh, upward path through
natural selection is actually selflessness and it's not, it's not the, it's not the Richard
Dawkins selfish gene. It's the, the, the selfless gene or something.
Yeah. Well, I mean, you think about it, human beings are at this point at the apex of, of,
of the global domination on the basis of what's really our conquering aspects, our, our, our
animalistic side. And we have this other side we're aware of that's more charitable and
sacrificial, but we have a choice whether to obey one or the other. And the, the, the way
forward looks like it's domination, looks like it's control. And in fact, I've always felt,
but even more so as faith developed that I don't look at world history as sort of Marxist
Leninism versus capitalism and all the rest of that at all anymore. I look at it as even people
whose, whose life's committed and dedicated to making money is for control. It's all about control.
And the opposite of what God gave us all was to let control go and allow us to explore creation on
our terms. And, and we spend human endeavors to enslave everybody again. That's it. That's an
upshot. It's almost like that's my sermon on the Mount.
Right. Well, that's a beautiful note to end on for off Larson. Thank you for, uh, taking the time
and sharing your remarkable mystical experiences and indulging my UFO questions and, uh, for being
here. Really appreciate you.
Thank you, Jesse. It's been a great, great session for me. I appreciate it.
It's been an honor. All right.
Thank you.