And I'm beginning to get the brilliant blue of sun rising in the east.
Bright blue band
underneath all this haze layer.
I can see the haze layer.
And the right band of light demarcation coming underneath it.
Quite distinctive.
There's a faint
to it
is where there are clouds, apparently.
Roger and White, A7, reading your loud, clear.
Roger, A7, reading you loud and clear.
Roger, understand.
Roger, I'm just small in forward,
180 degree yaw, approaching sunrise.
Over.
Roger.
These small luminescent particles drift away from you.
Small in forward.
In this light, they appear brilliant white.
Without seeing it all in them.
They appear to move on out.
Over around, back towards the flight path.
The guy in here, I don't think.
Roger, you haven't seen the beacon at this time.
Negative, I still haven't seen the beacon.
Sure.
There was considerable noise, though, as if something were departing.
Again, 7.
There was considerable noise of the little doors.
It sounded like the little doors blowing open,
so I assume the beacon has departed.
Roger, understand.
TM looks real good on the ground.
Roger.
CR for cleared.
Okay, you confirm. TV control switch to off.
Roger. TV control is off.
We had a slight decrease in the two links on DC current. Would you give us a readout?
Roger. DC current.
Roger. Main bus is 24. Isolated 28 and a half.
Roger.
Okay, go to this.
This is Wally. Did you have anything to eat?
Uh, negative. Not yet.
I'm planning to shortly here though.
Uh, let's view information. Systems last complication is on fuel at Hawaii.
at Hawaii gave you 8-8 auto, 9-8 manual, which is somewhat better than you're indicating on board.
Roger. On board, I'm indicating 9-6 and 1-0-2.
Oh boy, what a beautiful shot of Florida.
Roger. Looks good from here once in a while, too.
Roger. The whole state is clear. I can see I'm just about off.
There's been a beautiful view coming over Florida.
How is it full of horsepower?
If you have been PRESIDENT, where are they, I have lost.
On board, there gonna be a busy area of ability to make loss.
Have someeremian efficient gear?
Thank you.
I'm at last daylight going in the dark.
I've been looking for the flashing beacons.
505-18 now.
2-8, I'm sorry, not 1-8.
It's light in sight.
It is below me.
There's quite a brownish, reddish-brown and considerable altitude above the ground.
I'm looking for my fiery pitch-down thruster.
I get a shower of these little fireflies.
It is flashing now.
It is the light.
It's quite bright.
Quite discernible.
1-2-3-4-5-6-7.
Right.
There's to be about...
There's to be about 10 to 12 miles away.
I'm keeping it directly in the window.
At the order of a second magnitude star now.
All right.
What is rolling there?
We're going in for 10 videot live.
Good here.
That's nice to have.
I think, this is some of the flavors.
What are you doing?
You wish me.
I'm in the UAE.
If you kind of see one place and catch one difference
us in the SMALL Africa Exchangerine.