There's no way for you to visualize a five-dimensional object in its true form,
and yet when you smoke DMT, you do.
It's an extremely intense experience.
It's very fast and very, very short.
It's not Terence McKenna implanting the idea of machine elves into people's brains.
These are intelligent beings that go back thousands of years.
They will perform beings like elves or harlequins or jokers and jesters,
and they will display these impossible, higher-dimensional, beautiful objects
that kind of morph in front of your eyes.
Can we show that we're actually interfacing with some kind of intelligence that is non-human?
If a lot of people are seeing these architectures outside of their own reality
and they're all consistent, that seems like it would be really important.
If they want to communicate with us, they're going to do it through our brain.
Do you think that elite members of society have been systematically accessing
these other realms, helping to shape our reality?
Oh.
Why don't we repurpose a technique from anesthesiology
called target-controlled intravenous infusion, but with DMT?
Whoa.
So we send in mathematicians, we send in geometers, or topologists.
Yeah.
We send in linguists.
Whoa.
Before we dive into today's episode of American Alchemy,
I want to give a quick shout-out to today's amazing sponsor, Ground News.
All right, let me show you how I've actually been using this thing.
Take this headline that's been all over my feed lately.
Why MAGA can't move on from the Epstein files.
Now, say what you want about the headline, but few stories cut closer to the core of power,
secrecy, and public amnesia than this one.
This is where Ground News genuinely shines.
It pulls in 141 different sources on just that story.
You get a bird's eye view of what the mainstream media might be pushing, like,
there are no Epstein files, stop asking, and what independent outlets are suggesting, like,
maybe Epstein was a global honeypot for secret science programs.
Maybe he had financial leverage on all of our elites.
Who knows?
I choose to believe the latter, but maybe I'm a crazy conspiracy theorist.
You also get this coverage bar showing who's reporting and who's mysteriously quiet.
The bias distribution visualizes how each outlet frames the story,
whether they're steering you toward a left or right narrative or ignoring the real questions
altogether.
The factuality meter helps you separate solid reporting from whatever half-baked blog your
conspiracy cousin swears by, which, let's admit, in the UFO space, there's also a lot of
bullshit circulating out there.
And then there's the ownership tab, which shows you who's bankrolling each outlet.
This, in my opinion, is the most important feature, whether it's a hedge fund, a media
conglomerate, big pharma, or some other big corporation.
Obviously, personally, I follow topics like UAPs and breakthrough science.
And breaking stories hit my Ground News feed without the algorithm shoving celebrity gossip
or Reddit drama in my face.
It's great.
It's an amazing detox.
If you want that kind of clarity, go to ground.news slash jessemichaels,
Michaels with no A, for a limited time only.
You can also find that in the description or hit the QR code on the screen.
If you do that, you'll get 40% off the Unlimited Access Vantage plan, the same plan that I use.
Or you can gift it to someone who still thinks that Jeffrey Epstein just ran a hedge fund.
Again, that's ground.news slash jessemichaels, Michaels with no A.
I only promote tools I actually use, and Ground News is one of them.
Don't miss out on these important stories.
Now let's get back to the show.
Andrew Gallimore, thank you so much for being on the podcast.
I have been a fan and follower of yours for a long time now.
You've written a couple of great books that I'm aware of, Alien Information Theory,
and you are coming out with Death by Astonishment, which is sort of a title,
is an homage to William Burroughs or Terrence McKenna.
And I'm just really excited to talk to you because I feel like a lot of the alien stuff
dovetails with psychedelics and psychedelic experiences.
And I think a lot of people use that to sometimes discredit the alien thing as objectively real.
I think the psychedelic thing is a really important part of our everyday waking epistemology,
as I'm sure you would agree.
And so I'm excited to dive into that with you.
Fabulous.
Good to be here, Jesse, in Austin, Texas.
Absolutely.
My first time in Austin.
All the way from Japan, which is, I was always like, you know, okay, I'll visit Andrew when I go to Japan.
I wanted to do a little Japan tour, so it's cool to, thank you for coming out here.
You're welcome.
Why don't we just start there, actually, with the kind of alien DMT connection?
I was actually listening to you on my buddy Michael's podcast, Third Eye Drops,
and you were talking about John Mack and alien abductions
and how a lot of these alien abduction experiences really connect or seem to pattern match to what people experience on DMT.
Yeah, I mean, they're not the same, but really, well, from the beginning of DMT research back in,
so DMT was discovered in 1956 by this Hungarian physician called Stephen Zara.
This was when Hungary was a communist state.
And from the very first study that he did, I mean, at first he injected himself.
I mean, this was kind of the good old days of science when scientists injected new drugs into themselves.
Yeah.
So he discovered after injecting it into himself that it was quite clearly very, very psychedelic.
This kind of rush of highly complex geometric imagery that kind of overwhelmed him, seized control of him.
So he knew then that this was something special, something quite different to the drugs that were known at the time,
LSD, mescaline, psilocybin.
This seemed to kind of transcend that and transport you to some alternate reality.
So he started injecting with the drug into people, colleagues, basically, who worked at the same hospital.
And even in those very first studies, it was quite obvious that these individuals were not just being transported to other worlds,
but these were populated worlds and that there were what seemed to be kind of intelligent beings,
including little diminutive creatures, multitudinous creatures, lively beings that now we would recognize as elves or machine elves in Terence McKenna parlance.
But when Rick Strassman picked up the mantle in the early 90s, and he did a much larger study with 60 volunteers of various, various doses of DMT,
and a not insignificant number of these individuals reported experiences that would not raise an eyebrow if they had appeared in books by John Mack.
So kind of alien abduction type experiences where people are brought into some kind of highly sophisticated technological environment
where there are beings, often a number of like orderlies, less senior beings who were kind of performing the work and, you know, analyses and measurements, scanning and all this kind of stuff.
And then often there was one, like Top Dog, who was kind of in the background, but had a very strong presence, kind of overseeing or supervising the procedure.
And then they'd often be taken on kind of a tour of this craft or technological place,
meetings with highly intelligent, highly advanced, non-human beings, and then brought safely back into the normal waking world.
And this, if you, this kind of scenario is precisely what John Mack's abductees or experiences, as he used to call them, were kind of reporting.
So it didn't escape John Mack's attention.
I mean, people were asking him, you know, have you heard about DMT?
Because what you're, what you're talking about sounds a lot like what people are reporting under the influence of DMT.
And I think, you know, Rick Strassman also said, you know, if, if we removed all references to DMT in many of the reports from my volunteers,
would anyone be able to distinguish them from the reports of alien abductees?
And I think towards the end, you know, as, as John Mack progressed through his abduction career, if you want to put it like that,
he's, he, he was, he became less convinced that this was a purely physical nuts and bolts phenomenon where people were actually being removed from their,
their beds at night and taken onto actual physical crafts.
But he started to feel like this was some kind of non-physical process.
Yeah.
These, many of his subjects reported going to old environments that weren't, that didn't seem to be physical.
So places that were had kind of higher dimensional spaces, beings that were very similar to the types of beings that people encounter in DMT.
So he, he kind of shifted towards a more spiritual or metaphysical or non-physical explanation for these abduction experiences.
And a little context for the audience, John Mack was the head of the Harvard psychiatry department in the nineties.
And he was actually childhood friends with a guy named Bud Hopkins, who was documenting a lot of these sort of abduction experiences.
And he started to take a deep dive.
He was actually friends with Thomas Kuhn, who wrote Structure of Scientific Revolutions.
And he was like, I don't know, maybe some of this alien stuff is real.
And Kuhn was like, yeah, this, you know, basically you should, you know, try to maintain the null hypothesis for as long as possible.
But even though you sit on a respectable perch at Harvard, you should actually dive into this.
He started to dive into it.
He started to take it very seriously.
He was like, these people are reporting events that they feel are very, very real.
They have no mental health history prior or after.
And so it's interesting that you say that he sort of, you know, starts to view them as more spiritual or taking place in maybe a realm apart from the physical.
He was also very inspired by Stanislav Grof and holotropic breathwork, where the goal is actually to, I think, endogenously release DMT or something at the end of the breathwork.
And so if that's inspired Mac to that extent, and then Mac would use that in his practice with a lot of the abductees in order for them to recall their experiences, maybe that adds to your point.
But I will say that some of these abductees have physical marks and things and implants and stuff where it's like, do you have an explanation for that?
Have you thought of that?
Yeah, I mean, I think the line between the physical and the non-physical is not always clear.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Right?
So it's like you can't really, it's hard to get at.
There is obviously what we would consider to be a physical aspect, but there also seems to be a very non-physical aspect.
And I just don't think we, as humans, we really understand.
I think maybe if we were able to observe this from a higher perspective and kind of an overview, like a bird's eye view of reality, it might be obvious what's going on here.
But I just, I just think it's useful to be able to distinguish between the physical.
It's kind of instructive to distinguish between the physical and the non-physical, but actually sometimes you point out it's maybe a combination of the physical and the non-physical.
And I feel like people, like if they were to point to a dividing line where the physical and the non-physical sort of divested, it would be Descartes or something in the kind of proverbial, you know.
But if you look at Descartes, like how that divestiture actually occurred is he was talking about, he was doing thought experiments about a demon controlling your entire perceptive epistemology in some almost, you know, proto like VR headset that could be reality.
And all you could know is that your own thoughts were yours or something.
Yeah.
And so that's a pretty trippy thought.
It is.
And I actually, that's kind of an interesting point because Groff actually, in one of his books, he said, look, if there are advanced intelligent beings, you know, aliens that are kind of non-physical, discarnate, everywhere and nowhere,
then the way that they would appear to us would be dismissed as hallucination.
They would kind of interact with our brain directly.
They wouldn't have to kind of materialize, so to speak, in a true quote unquote physical form, but they would interact with us directly with our brain.
And I think that's actually what's going on, whether it's Descartes' demon, but I think when you smoke DMT, for example, what I think is happening or what I've come to believe or lean towards an explanation for what's happening,
is that you have these intelligences that don't have a physical form, they don't have a form that could even be represented in any kind of visual form.
These are completely non-physical discarnate beings, but DMT somehow gives them access to our neural machinery.
And so they are, I believe, directing the visions.
I believe the DMT world to be what I call a directed world.
I don't think you're going anywhere.
I don't think you're peeking through into another world because that's not how perception works.
Perception works by your brain building this model, which is then tested against sensory inputs from the environment.
You never have direct access to the so-called external world or the environment.
And it's the same in the DMT experience.
You're not seeing the DMT world, whatever that might mean.
You're simply giving access to these intelligent agents, giving them access to your brain.
So you don't break through.
I always say you don't break through into the DMT world.
It's the DMT world or the intelligences within this space that break through into you.
They seize control.
They kind of commandeer this world modeling machinery in your brain.
And they direct your visions.
Do they have, in your opinion, and this is maybe a philosophical question,
do these entities have control prior to you taking DMT and then you are able to notice it through DMT?
Or are you like, do they take control like when you take DMT?
Well, I'm going to give the optimistic answer, which is to say it's DMT.
I mean, what DMT does is it generates this very fluid and dynamic state of the brain, of the cortex,
this outer layer of the brain that constructs your world model.
And some very recent neuroimaging data actually show that DMT makes the brain much more sensitive
to being perturbed by external sensory or other types of input.
So it becomes primed, if you like, to be commandeered, taken over in this way.
So I'd like to think that they don't have access in the normal waking state,
because that's kind of a horrifying thought, right?
But in the presence of DMT, they gain access.
Your brain is in a much more vulnerable or susceptible state to being commandeered by these intelligences.
And that's clearly what happens.
People describe this massive, overwhelming rush of information that floods their brain,
complex imagery, mathematical imagery, blueprints,
and just completely alien stuff that has no relationship to their normal waking experience.
And I think that is kind of the hallmark of them basically saying,
you know, we have control now for the next five minutes or so.
And then they kind of show you what they want to show you,
which is sometimes a performance.
They kind of say, look at this, look what we can do.
And they will show these.
They will often display these impossible, higher dimensional, beautiful objects
that kind of morph in front of your eyes.
Or they will hold up screens with these impossibly complex imagery.
They will perform beings like elves or harlequins or jokers and jesters.
And they will kind of, they will say, look, look at this.
This is impossible.
And yet we're doing it.
You know, they're doing it with your brain.
Your brain is like the stage that they are using for this performance.
And then in other cases, it's more serious.
There seems to be some kind of agenda.
People often describe like they were waiting for me.
And they knew, they weren't surprised.
I was very fucking surprised.
But they weren't surprised at all.
They had a place ready for me.
And they slotted me in.
And they started working.
There's scanning and lights flashing and beeping.
And just, they knew exactly what to do in the short time available.
So, yeah, it's, um, so this brings up a question of like discernment.
Like if, I don't know, you're talking about harlequin jesters and, you know, tricksters
and stuff.
And, um, you know, on the other hand, you know, there's things with serious agendas for
you.
Um, how do you, uh, go into a trip like this and be able to, and fend for yourself and go
in with a specific intention where you're not, you know, the product being used, but you,
you have a specific goal or intention, or I don't know, it can be heel, very healing for
a lot of people, for example, maybe, maybe that's the, the sort of positive outcome version
of this, or how do you, how do you sort of dictate that?
And is it, is it inherently very risky?
You don't dictate it.
If you try to dictate it, then you're in trouble because there's no way you cannot dictate
it.
I mean, that's the thing.
You have to surrender.
I mean, you can go in with intention, um, and people do, people will go in.
They will, you know, they might suffer from, I don't know, chronic headaches or depression
or something that they're, they're seeking a solution to something.
And they go in with that intention.
And very often they will find that these beings will get to work on them, literally on their
brain.
Uh, and they will feel their brain being reprogrammed, um, rewired by these elf like beings or other
or insectoid beings.
These are the kind of two of the most, um, common types of, uh, of, of, of being.
And they will, they will often achieve great relief from that, you know, their headaches stop
happening, you know, or, or they feel more positive about life.
And they feel like their, their depression has lifted.
So that's certainly possible.
It's not, it's not like it's, um, you kind of have to accept that you get what you get.
Um, but at the end of the day, yes, you kind of do have to accept that you're not going to
be able to control this thing.
And if you try, that's, I think when bad experiences happen, when you go in there with a sense of
self-assured, uh, arrogance that, you know, we humans are the top of the, the intelligence
tree, you know, that DMT will obliterate any, any kind of, um, this anthropocentric belief
that humans are the center of reality and that we are the most intelligent thing and that
we've got it all worked out.
It'll humble you.
Oh, it'll humble you within seconds.
It gives you what you need, not what you want when you come in, like, uh, you know,
I've dabbled a little bit and I don't do much, but, um, and I, I did, I did ayahuasca once.
So I've never done DMT, but I've done the ayahuasca is DMT in some sense.
It's a kind of gnarly version of it.
I don't know.
I feel like the failure mode for me would have been like the universe showing me that, you
know, some sort of like ultimate Fibonacci sequence that like, you know, cause I'm, you
know, kind of a truth seeker in that sense.
And instead it was like, no, just walk and carry water.
You know, your, your, your job is like, like you're way too grandiose about all this stuff.
Like shut up.
Like your family is all that matters.
And it was like, it was great because of that.
Um, but it was not what I wanted.
You know, I wanted, I wanted some, you know, ultimate secret or something.
Everybody wants the blueprints for the time machine.
That's right.
And they said, why don't we get that?
Why don't we get the equations for the grand unified theory?
I think humans, we, we have this, this very human centered belief that we know what, what
we need.
Uh, and, and these beings, they have no interest in that.
They know kind of, they know what's going on and we have, we haven't got a clue what's
going on.
Um, we don't know shit, uh, really, uh, and that's the most important message that we need
to get.
First of all, before we start getting the other messages, I think the first one that
we need to take to heart is that, yeah, we haven't got a clue what's going on.
We don't know shit that we're not, we're not even close.
We don't even register on the scale of intelligences, um, that you can encounter within the DMT.
I would agree with that, but you are a human who has dared to create kind of an ontology
around both psychedelics.
And it's really awesome.
And it dovetails with a lot of my instincts where, um, you have this alien information
theory.
I want to, I want to start with that because I love that book.
And it, it, um, it goes into like these, I, this idea that, you know, these beings could
be in some sense sort of simulating our current reality, but it also talks about, you know,
their myths from, you know, jinn and Islam to angels and demons and Christianity or,
or, you know, Judaism and, uh, these things sort of having a full wholesale control over
our, our realities.
And then, yeah, there's some sort of a bridge that takes place with DMT, but you even get
into, you know, the information theory components of, of this and how they're maybe more pure
information theoretic, these beings, and you talk about John Wheeler.
And so, um, yeah, maybe, maybe just for the audience, I'd love, I'd love for you to kind
of go through that kind of whole ontology.
Yeah.
I mean, the book alien information theory, people read it and think that this is kind of
what I believe it's, it's not what I believe it's, it's a, it's a work of art.
It's a work of metaphysical speculation.
I'm simply trying to show people that the world could well be, and probably is something
or reality probably is something that we completely different to what is normally presented to
us by the theoretical physicists and the mathematicians and the astronomers and the
astrobiologists, et cetera, et cetera, and that actually reality is probably, you know,
as Terence McKenna used to say, you know, stranger than we can, suppose.
Yes.
Um, and I think that was Arthur C.
Clark, but it was actually, it was, uh, JBS Haldane originally said that he used the word
queerer, uh, than we suppose.
Um, but stranger than we suppose is probably better these days.
Um, but yeah, anyway, and, and I think he's right.
I mean, 30 seconds after you inhale a lungful of DMT, it's quite obvious that the reality
is far, far stranger than you could possibly have supposed or anticipated.
Uh, and the book was really to present one particular way of looking at reality.
You know, maybe reality could be something like this.
Um, I don't think I got everything right.
Um, but I think the idea, which I think is broadly correct or could well be broadly correct,
um, is that this reality, our lower dimensional reality, our three dimensional plus one, um,
reality is, is really a thin slice within a much larger higher dimensional structure.
So we're kind of embedded within this high dimensional structure that we never normally
have access to.
Uh, and for reasons that we don't quite understand, DMT grants us temporary access to this, um,
high dimensional structure.
And so you, you, the world you kind of unfold into is, I guess is one way of describing it.
Your brain, um, kind of unfolds into this high dimensional structure.
And this is why people describe entering a world that is not just strange, but is literally
impossible in that it could not exist within our three dimensional world, world in which
there are more dimensions.
What appears to be a very higher dimensional space, a kind of reality that our reality,
our three dimensional world could only exist within, but it could not exist within our
reality.
If that makes sense.
It makes total sense.
Yeah.
I think, and at best they're little ports or bridges where they connect or something.
Right.
And you talk about it like, it's like Carl Sagan had this great clip where he's talking about
platonic solids and he talks about a tesseract and you would never see the tesseract.
You'd see a shadow of the tesseract, but there's a great, um, book, um, by Sir Edwin Abbott
called flatland.
Yeah.
Or it's like a 2d people and how they'd interact with 3d creatures.
And, um, you know, maybe there are ports or whatever, whereby, you know, they can somehow
connect to the 3d reality, but they're, it's extremely limited.
We're, we're seeing sort of the tip of the iceberg.
We're not seeing, you know, the iceberg itself.
Yeah.
We are kind of trapped within that flatland.
Um, and you know, as Carl Sagan said, you would only in this world, we would only see
the shadow of the tesseract.
When you go into the DMT space, people do describe seeing tesseracts and they will describe
them.
I saw something that was impossible.
It was a four dimensional cube or five dimensional cube, which is completely impossible for us
to comprehend only.
We can only imagine it in the, as a mathematical abstraction.
We, there's no way for you to visualize, uh, or to, to see a five dimensional object in
its true form.
And yet when you smoke DMT, you do, you enter these worlds that appear to be higher dimensional.
And I think, yes, rather than the portal, well, it is kind of a portal, but I would say it's,
it's gating the flow of information from, so rather than only receiving information, let's
say from this 2d flatland, if you're in the flatland, you start to receive information from
the third, the third dimension.
And so you're, the brain temporarily effectively becomes a higher dimensional object.
The world that it's constructing is also higher dimensional.
And so you're seeing more, you're literally seeing a greater expanse of reality than you
can, uh, in the normal waking state.
Oh, it's so fascinating.
This episode is brought to you by my favorite new product, Masa chips.
Here's a quick history lesson before the 1990s, all chips and fries were cooked in beef
tallow.
Then the big food companies swapped this ingredient out for cheap, highly processed seed oils.
Today, seed oils make up 20% of the average American's calories, and they're linked to
all sorts of bad things like chronic inflammation and metabolic issues.
Masa decided to rewind the clock.
They make tortilla chips with just three simple ingredients, organic corn, sea salt, and
a hundred percent grass-fed beef tallow.
No seed oils, no weird additives.
And honestly, they taste way better too.
Masa chips are crunchier, more flavorful, and they don't disintegrate in guac like the usual
ones.
But the real difference is how you feel.
Light, satisfied, no crash, no bloat, and no weird craving spiral an hour later.
I've been snacking on them nonstop while working on these shows, and they actually keep me sharp.
Masa chips are beloved by tens of thousands of customers and have been endorsed by industry-leading
health and nutrition experts like Ben Greenfield and Gary Brekka.
So ready to give Masa a try?
Go to masachips.com slash jessemichaels, Michaels with no A, and use code jessemichaels for 25%
off your first order.
That's masachips.com slash jessemichaels, and use code jessemichaels for 25% off your first
order.
You're really helping the channel out when you use that code, and this is a product I
love and consume just about every day.
You have different models of the brain that might involve quantum biological processes.
Like we have this burgeoning field of quantum biology where birds use it to locate the magnetosphere
of the earth and navigate home, and enzyme creation.
And you have, you know, photosynthesis is another example.
And then you have Roger Penrose saying the brain might, you know, these microtubules use
sort of, you know, quantum biological processes.
And that would make sense in this sort of model because that would explain a lot of this sort
of pre-sentiment where you sort of have, you know, some sort of access to the future and
you see traces of the future or the remote viewing stuff, all these sort of non-local
quote-unquote experiences of consciousness would be maybe explained in a model like this.
And so even Schrodinger, who's, you know, developed, you know, the wave function that governs
all subatomic behavior in quantum mechanics.
He had a lecture series called What is Life where he talked about aperiodic crystals in the
DNA.
And he was basically like, these are like ports of like higher consciousness or something
like, like there's like some sort of tesseract that like we're tethered to.
There's something higher than us.
And we're like, we're a low level port within what our prism within which this higher thing
is, it has to be sort of, you know, reduced into like the body is a reduction valve.
Yeah, I think like one of the questions that often comes up when I describe this idea that
DMT is allowing information to flow from some other place, the question that always comes
up is like, how does that work?
I mean, we understand how information comes through the sense organs from the normal three
dimensional environment.
But how does that information come from this other place?
And I think the answer is at a very low level.
So quantum, subquantum, maybe even much deeper levels that we don't even understand.
I think it's coming from wherever, however, we are connected to this broader reality structure,
this broader higher dimensional structure, wherever that connection is, is obviously going
to be kind of at the ground of reality at the quantum or the subquantum.
And so the explanation or the kind of the model that I describe in alien information theory
is this idea that the information is coming from the very deepest levels of reality and
flowing upwards through the quantum and then the subatomic and the atomic and through into
these complex networks and ultimately to this highest level of the brain where your world
model is constructed.
So you have information always kind of flowing, welling up, if you like, from the deepest level
of reality.
And that process is somehow gated by the presence of DMT.
Yeah, well, Niels Bohr would always say, you know, if you think you understand quantum mechanics,
you definitely don't.
It's like extremely confusing.
And then if you look at all the forefathers of quantum mechanics, they all flirted with
the idea that the mind had something to do with wave function collapse, often going back
and forth on that issue.
But it wasn't completely like heretical like it is sort of today.
Yeah.
And there's a guy named Hal Puthoff, actually, who's known to be at the forefront of like
all the alien research.
And he was just on Joe Rogan and he ran the government psychic spy program for the CIA.
He's a super interesting guy, like, but also at the tip of the spear of sort of exotic propulsion
modalities, longtime NSA CIA scientist who worked at Stanford Research Institute.
And he has a model of extended electrodynamics that involves vector and scalar potential.
So these subquantum sort of phenomena that might have something to do with dictating wave
function collapse.
And maybe, you know, if aliens were to communicate, they'd probably communicate like this because
apparently they propagate either at one over R, not one over R squared.
So like you don't get the attenuation over space time that you do.
You don't get the drop off.
And it seems like they, you know, you get like, you know, effectively like really, really
fast, you know, communications and stuff with them.
And so, I don't know.
It's fascinating.
I wonder, I wonder if we can break any ground on this stuff in our lifetime.
And if we, or if we get a new model of physics in our life, like, do you think, do you think
physics in some ways is sort of, sort of breaking?
It feels like all the string theorists are admitting that they're, you know, not, not
really getting anywhere.
Yeah.
I mean, I'm not a physicist, but I have spoken to physicists.
And the problem I think you get is as soon as you start talking about discarnate intelligence,
advanced intelligences, the eyes start to roll.
And it's like, they already, they've already decided what's possible and what's not possible.
And the idea of these advanced super intelligent agents that, that you somehow interface with
in the DMT state, it's too far from what they can accept.
Well, because they turn science into an all encompassing sort of religion.
But if you think about if they really what they're calling science is two things, it's
predictably useful and it can turn into sort of instrumentalizable technology.
That is it, right?
It is not an ontological map of reality.
And so when you say I've experienced these beings in a DMT state, when we could say tons
of people, like a statistically significant amount of people experience the same things
in the DMT state, they can just write that off because you can't turn it into math and
you can't make it repeatable in our sort of waking reality.
But I think that whole mode has limits and that, that itself is going to break like the,
the, that, the very idea that that is sort of a satisfactory explanation of all, you know,
metaphysics, our reality itself has to break at some point.
Yeah, I mean, I think, you know, what I, I've been studying DMT for 20 years and my approach
has always been to, first of all, take the explanations that I'm given by the kind of
mainstream science.
These are hallucinations.
This is a type of dream imagery.
These are, you know, archetypal symbols that come from the collective unconscious.
And I have to basically deal with them.
I have to analyze them, deconstruct them and show why they fail before I can say, okay,
we've tried all the explanations that you've given.
We've tried to kind of make them fit and they don't.
They leave the vast majority of the DMT experience completely unaccounted for.
So can we now please start to think about explanations that would have before seemed to be untenable?
And when you do that, you actually find that the idea that there are advanced intelligences
that are non-physical, that have transcended the physical, what I've often referred to as
post-biological beings, that's not far out anymore.
I mean, there are very mainstream scientists that are saying, okay, you know, how does a
intelligent civilization progress?
Okay.
It reaches eventually after maybe millions of years, it reaches a kind of technological age,
the kind of age we're in now, a digital computer age.
Then it starts thinking about transcending biology.
And people are thinking about that already.
And many scientists are saying, look, we're probably now maybe only a few hundred years
away from dispensing with the biological paradigm and shifting to a post-biological paradigm.
And you can see it in, you know, you have to kind of ignore, in my opinion, anyway, this
climbing the Kardashev scale, this kind of Elon Musk idea that we're going to be colonizing
Mars.
This is a very human idea that we have, that we're simply going to be expanding out into
the cosmos and kind of populating other planets and moons or whatever as humans.
I don't think that's what it's going to look like at all.
And actually, if you look at the anti-Kardashev scale proposed by John Barrow in the 1990s,
where he said, look, we spend, okay, we spend a lot of money sending objects into orbit or,
you know, to distant celestial objects, whatever.
But we spend much more time going not outwards, but inwards to smaller and smaller scales.
If you think about the Large Hadron Collider, this is aimed at trying to understand and
manipulate smaller and smaller structures, not larger and larger structures.
And so it seems that a more likely trajectory for an intelligent civilization is not to go
out into the cosmos, but to go deeper and deeper levels until you reach what Barrow called
the Omega Minus civilization, which is able to manipulate the fundamental structure of
space-time or the fundamental structure of reality itself.
This is where we're going to be, or this is where intelligent civilizations are going to
instantiate themselves, not by spawning across the cosmos, but by instantiating themselves at
the deepest level, the fundamental computational substrate of reality itself, that's where
they're going to go.
And once they do that, once they make that leap, they disappear.
They become everywhere and nowhere.
They become completely transparent to normal modes of communication.
And yet they are literally right here, right now.
And I think the idea, if they want to communicate with us, they're going to do it through our
brain.
That's obvious.
Why materialize in a physical form?
That makes no sense.
Maybe they can do that, but it makes much more sense for them to interface directly with
our brains.
So that idea isn't far out.
It doesn't stray too far from modern scientific discourse.
Um, and that's exactly what I'm suggesting happens with DMT is that you are gating access
to some kind of advanced intelligent agent to your brain.
Could it be one of these post-biological beings that had, um, vanished into the fabric of space
time long before we arrived on the scene?
Maybe.
Could it be beings that exist parallel to our universe in some high level of reality?
I don't know.
But what I'm saying isn't, it's not mystical.
It's not magical.
It's actually perfectly in line, in my opinion, with what scientists are already talking about
in completely different fields.
Yeah.
I love that.
Well, yeah.
Even Richard Feynman, famous physicist, well-respected by all, you know, conventional or not, said,
you know, there's room at the bottom.
That was his famous sort of line.
So it's much more room.
Much more room.
At the bottom.
I mean, orders, many orders of magnitude.
Yes.
Space down there.
Down there.
And that's what he meant is what you were taught.
It's sort of this, you know, similar to the anti-Kardashev scale where, you know, we have
to go inwards and not, not just outwards.
And even the Elon Musk thing involves all sorts of, uh, convoluted, you know, uh, logic that
makes no sense because he'll say at the same time as we need to, you know, colonize Mars
and then go interstellar and like, you know, endlessly float through Cartesian space to
like, you know, make the whole cosmos, our empire or whatever.
He'll say that.
And then he'll say, we live in a simulation.
Right.
You can't believe if like, if you think we live in a simulation and you have to think,
how can we ascend outside of the simulation?
That needs to be your first order thing before anything else.
But he's basically saying, no, we have to accept the simulation as it is, and then just
float through it and find some exoplanet.
And it's like, what are you talking about, dude?
Like find the computer code.
What do you, it makes no sense.
So, um, yeah, I find that interesting.
And, and another kind of cut at what you're saying with, you know, kind of, um, large hadron
colliders and, and finding, you know, really small, you know, subquantum, you know, quarks
and that sort of thing is the human being.
We take the human out of science.
Like we're not, we are not allowed to view ourselves as a measurement instrument.
So it's like the double slit experiment where everybody's always like, it's the quantum
detector.
It's not the person or whatever.
And, you know, the, the large hadron collider, which is like, it's a, it's like a, you know,
an empirical, like objective thing that we can do.
But what about, what about an individual's like epistemology and especially over, you know,
you're studying this stuff systematically.
Like, can you discount all of that?
If, if a lot of people are seeing these architectures outside of their own reality and they're all
consistent, that seems like it would be really important.
Like it's the three, you know, the three body problem, this Chinese science fiction novel,
like it's so great where it talks about like the farmer and the shooter.
If we are these 2d things on flatland or whatever, and they're like, you know, metal, metal sheets
or something, and you have shooters who are in 3d space shooting at the metal, you see these
little craters.
We just think they're little, you know, holes, little caverns in our, in our flatland.
We have no idea that there are literally like people who are like, you know, grading the
metal and like, you know, forming our world that are, you know, they're sort of responsible
for it. Um, and it's completely at their discretion. And the whole thing is that they literally
have particle accelerators that like get different results. And it's like, it's kind of like the,
the physics itself is at the discretion of these like tri-Solarian aliens. And it, it's a real
mind fuck because there's nothing a conventional physicist can say that's like a hundred percent
debunking of that possibility.
Yeah. Yeah. And, and, and they develop, you know, when they see these little pockmarks
coming, they have, you know, mathematical models for how these arise that are completely
wrong, of course, but, but they kind of maybe hold together and they develop more sophisticated
models to explain how these pockmarks appear. And they just have no idea that it's, it's some
other intelligence that's generating them. And I think, you know, I, I strongly lean towards
the either idea that that's the kind of reality that we live in, that we have all of these
models of what's going on and all models are wrong, but some are useful. Um, and I think
sometimes it's having useful models, which we clearly have useful models because we have
all of this technology. So we clearly our models, they're not nonsense, but the idea it's
important not to, to mistake a useful model with a true model and that we're actually
getting to the act, the actual true nature of reality. Cause I don't think we can say
that at all.
Yeah. It's the map is not the territory.
Exactly.
And it's like, you have, that's why I think string theory is such BS. It's like, I don't
need to be a super well-respected physicist. I'm not a physicist, but if you have two bad
maps, general relativity and quantum mechanics, which are just heuristics for creating technology
that's adaptive so we can, you know, do cool stuff in the world, create, you know, uh, you
know, uh, create in the world. Um, why would you put the two jagged maps together with abstract
math? That's never going to work. Like if you just think about that high level, it doesn't
make sense.
Right. Exactly. I mean, I'm not a physicist. I don't want to start, you know, getting into
Ed Witton's territory and things like this.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. I would lose in a debate to him, but like, but like, again, you
just, all you need is that high level common sense thing. Like heterodoxy and unorthodox
thinking doesn't scale with IQ. You can have a hyper specialized, extremely intelligent person
who is bled into a BS cul-de-sac like sheep to slaughter. And that, that happens all the
time.
Oh yeah, absolutely.
So there's, there's intelligence is, it's a really finicky, hard, you know, thing where
it's like the, the, the ability to think in a sort of a variant, you know, non-consensus
way, it doesn't necessarily scale in this perfect way. Like, like mathletes are not necessarily
doing that thing, you know, and there's a place for both, but like, I don't know.
Yeah. Yeah. But, um, do you think that, you know, there have been, uh, groups, you know,
Graham Hancock wrote the, the forward, uh, to your new book, the death, uh, death by astonishment,
uh, which I recommend everybody go by. And, um, he, he, Graham's a really interesting guy
because he kind of oscillates between writing about kind of, you know, more conventional
archeology, but just kind of, you know, his like contrarian views, you know, things like
a Beckley Tepe and the younger dress impact theory. And then he writes these other books
that like, people don't talk about as much with like Robert Bavall about like secret
societies, like controlling earth and stuff. And like, you have, you know, the Freemasons,
I think in acacia leaf or something is like in there, like, you know, symbology and you have
the Eleusinian mystery rituals. Graham also wrote the forward to Brian where rescues book,
you know, about, you know, called the immortality key about these mystery rituals. Do you think that
like elite members of society have been systematically accessing these other realms
and either on behalf of, or in conjunction with these quote unquote entities or machine elves
helping to shape our reality? Are there, are there myth makers?
Oh, that's a very interesting idea. I mean, I, the short answer is I don't know,
but it's quite clear that there are, there are, there have been civilizations going back
thousands of years. I mean, Graham wrote this wonderful book, Supernatural, which is not one
of his most well-known where he, he examined, um, the, uh, cave art going back tens of thousands
of years and made the compelling argument as have many other anthropologists. It's not just Graham here,
um, that these civilizations 30, 40,000 years ago during the upper paleo, upper paleolithic,
if I'm getting my periods, right. I don't know. But anyway, um, they were, the cave art clearly
showed beings that were non-human, that were non-animal, or that seemed to be some kind of
combination of humanoid and animal form, uh, in these pitch black, deep, dark caves. Um, and
the question is why, why, why, you know, were they interfacing? Did they discover a means of,
uh, interacting with these intelligences all, all those thousands of years ago? Um, the darkness
darkness is very interesting as a kind of, as an aside here, um, in that many people who like modern
day, um, darkness retreats where people go into these pitch black rooms for five, six, seven days,
many of them describe, you know, after the fourth, fifth day, describe experiences that they say are
DMT experiences. Aubrey Marcus, I was on his show a few months ago, and he's very experienced with DMT.
He's also very experienced with darkness retreats. And he said, this wasn't like DMT. This was a DMT.
I had a DMT experience whilst, you know, after the fourth or fifth day in, in this darkness retreat.
So we're actually doing a study now, um, uh, we're, we're kind of initiating a study to actually test
this. So myself and New Nautix, um, the group that I work with in Florida, we're funding a study
where they're going to send people into these darkness retreats, dark rooms, and then take
urine samples or saliva samples or blood samples at intervals and see, do these DMT spikes?
Do we see DMT? That's fascinating. Well, you know, there, there were even
pre the Eleusinian and other mystery rituals where they would take ergot, you know, this sort of,
you know, LSA, you know, psychedelic substance. Um, there were caving rituals. There are pre-Socratic
caving rituals. A guy named Peter Kingsley writes about this where they would literally
go into a cave for long amounts of time and they would presumably have some pretty transcendent
sort of experiences. So that's really interesting. So that could be what's, what's going on. And so
this is just another technology or another technique that they, they had discovered. Um, and, and you see
throughout history, whether, you know, it could be the, the Eleusinian mysteries where they discovered
this ergot preparation. Now, whether it's just ergot, whether that other synergistic plants being
added, some people speculate that, and Brian Mimoresco speculated there are other things going in that
enhance or catalyze, um, the experience, but still it's the same thing. You're somehow, you're using
some kind of technique, whether it's a molecular technique or darkness or breath work or whatever,
some kind of technique to manipulate your, uh, neurochemistry in some way, such that you can
access these intelligent beings that you couldn't access otherwise. And so, so the fact that these
civilizations have been working with these intelligences for thousands and thousands of
years, you have, you kind of have to take that seriously and to just dismiss it and say, oh, they
were just deluding themselves. They were just having hallucinations. No, I think that's, that's,
it's kind of insulting. Um, the, the Amazonians who developed ayahuasca, for example, you know,
this is a true pharmacological technology. This is not just an infusion of a plant. This isn't,
this is, this is a technology that requires both the DMT, which is orally inactive, plus, uh, this plant,
banisteriopsis carpi, the ayahuasca vine, which contains the mau inhibitors that allow it to
become active. These have to be brought together. Um, uh, and so this is a pharmacological technology
they have developed and they develop relationships with the beings that they, uh, interact with in
their ayahuasca state and also with other plant-based preparations, epena, uh, Yopo and others. Um,
they develop relationships with these beings. Um, they have names for the different types of beings.
They see them, um, as members of their tribe. They don't see them as spirits. They don't call
them spirits. They say they are not human. They are not animal. They are other. Um, they see them as,
but they see them as beings that they can develop relationships with, um, that will protect them,
um, that they can communicate with, that they can seek answers from, um, and to dismiss all of that
and say, oh, they're just, you know, they're just hallucinating. I think it's, it's, it just speaks
to the, this, this self-assured cocky arrogance that modern post enlightenment humans have that we
have it all worked out. We have a handle on what's possible. Yeah. What's not possible. We know what's
real and what's not real and I'm sorry, but that's not real. I'm afraid you're just hallucinating.
It's just a kind of dream. No, I'm sorry, but that doesn't stand up to scrutiny. Um, and it's kind
of insulting to these, uh, cultures that have developed these technologies. And I almost think
it's a credible technology. Yeah. It's amazing. Yeah. Yeah. It's so, it's so fast. And just the
likelihood of combining those two things, you know, in the Amazon forest are like, if you run through a
bunch of pure permutations or whatever, the likelihood of getting that combination is very
low still. Exactly. Like it's, it, it had to have been that itself had to have been sort of
downloaded or something as like a recipe for this. And that's what they will tell you. They
will tell you, if you ask them, how did you discover this? They will say, well, the plants
told us, you know, when they say the plants, they mean these intelligences, which reside within
the forest, they told them how to, how to do this and who are we to say.
And they talk about people from the start. It's funny in the Western context, we have
disclosure and we have, you know, uh, uh, you know, government reverse engineering programs.
And there they're like, yeah, obviously we have these people that we communicate with from the,
you know, they come down from the stars. And I also find it interesting if you were to go to any
Western academic, you know, philosophy department, you know, there's a famous quote. I think
all philosophy is a footnote of Plato or something. Right. Yeah. And we think of Plato as like the
father of, you know, modern Western rationality, like pre enlightenment. And then you like, look
back at like what he was doing and it's like, he went to a Lucis and he was tripping on Urgot
and like probably experiencing some like primordial soul version. You know, it's, there's a word
for it, noesis, the version of himself. And then he writes about all of that stuff in the Republic.
And we ignore that. And we talk about it. Like it's some like myopic governance manual. And it's
just like, what is like, it's completely retracing the past with our modern kind of disenchantment
epistemology. Yeah. Alan Watts used to say that the modern philosopher would wear a white coat if
he thought he could get away with it. Right. Yeah. Think of themselves as like signed is doing
philosophy. They'd come in with their briefcase and they put on their white coat and they do
philosophy. Yes. They take themselves very seriously. Yeah. Uh, that they're getting to
the, the nitty gritty, the truth of the matter. Yeah, exactly. That's exactly right. And I think
there's this like desire for people like Steven Pinker, Richard, Richard Dawkins, or all these
people to like defend the status quo. Like, I think the big rift between people like that and like,
maybe you and me is like, I don't think we, I don't, we think that we don't have any of the
answers. Like you and me, I think they think that they do. And like, we are putting the final period
at the end of a very long sentence of, you know, this enlightenment project. And, uh, we're at the
end of history in some ways, like the final rule in the game of chess is yet to be figured out. Maybe
that's string theory. Maybe it's some, you know, other thing, but like, we pretty much know how
reality works in their, in their model. And that is insane to me. It's insane. It's the ultimate
hubris. Well, they were saying that I forget who said it. Uh, maybe it was like the 19th century
that we have based all of physics has now been worked out with. It's not now a matter of increasingly
precise measurements. Right. And then came relativity and quantum theory and it's like changed
everything. And, and, uh, but we, we make the same mistakes even now, you know, many people,
not everybody. And, and you have to be a little bit careful, uh, because there is a lot of, for
want of a better term, bullshit, um, that, you know, within this kind of field, right. There
are a lot of grifters, uh, and there are a lot of bullshit artists. And so you have to, it's
really difficult. You have to kind of tread a fine line between not being, there's this
tension I always find. And one is pulling you back towards standard materialist, orthodox
mainstream science, um, and kind of thinking, yeah, we've got it all worked out. These are
just hallucinations, nothing to be concerned about. And then you've got another, this, this,
this, uh, from the opposite direction, you're being pulled into just a steaming pile of bullshit.
Right. Uh, and it's like, how do you, you have to, it's a constant struggle for me to try and
separate myself from the bullshit while it's not being too far out from the science.
If you're engaging in that struggle, then you're doing it right. Yeah. It's right. It's a
Scylla and Charybdis between excess dogmatism and excess skepticism or to put it in your, the
way you just framed it. Um, new agey kind of solipsistic, you know, everything is everything
mushy brain thinking. And then on the other hand, uh, you know, complete, uh, uh, radical
cart Cartesian skepticism or something like there has to be some middle path. Exactly. And that,
that, that is a treacherous place that you find yourself very alone because it's much easier
to snap to grid on either. There's the tribal dynamics exist in a way that, uh, you know,
things coagulate on either end of that kind of, you know, barbell. Yeah, exactly. So that's what I
do. So I, it's, it's a difficult path, but it's the only path I think, um, when you're faced with
something like DMT, which is so strange and it's so, in my opinion, mysterious and inexplicable,
you, you're not going to be able to explain it by just snapping to, um, the usual explanations
because, because they fail. Yeah. Uh, and that's what I found is that they fail. So I tread
carefully. I keep one foot firmly planted in the scientific arena and I, and I then reach
out with an outstretched hand into other territory, but I'm very careful about what I say, what I
do and that I try and rationalize and explain my thinking every step of the way. I don't
just say, Oh me, maybe these are spirits from the astral plane. Yeah, that'll do. You know,
maybe these are spirits of the departed. Yeah, that will do. Yeah. Um, because you can, anything
goes and you can't, yeah, I tried to trace it back and make just, just to kind of convince
people that I'm not just nuts, I'm not just kind of going with whatever, but I do explain myself,
I think kind of carefully and rationally, you know, piece by piece, step by step.
Yeah, no, I, I feel the same way. And it's, it's tough because like YouTube, for example,
doesn't do nuance well. No. So I, you know, I have a show and people think it's like an alien
show or whatever. I'm like, I don't know if these things are aliens. Like, I don't know if they,
in fact, I would say that there are other hypotheses that better describe them than the
sort of, you know, classic extraterrestrial hypothesis, but it's this meme that people
can't seem to transcend or something. And so it's, it's, it's wild. But, um, on that note of like
wanting to keep your, your feet sort of firmly grounded, we were talking before the camera about
Christopher Timmerman at, at Imperial college, who you sort of devised some of these extended DMT
experiments that he's, you know, executing. We were also talking about, uh, a mutual friend.
I haven't talked to him in a long time, but this guy, Anton built in who was thinking of giving people
DMT, putting them in adjacent Faraday cages. So there, you know, there's no way of like, you know,
traditional signals being communicated, you know, electromagnetically and seeing if they can
telepathically, like, you know, transport image, communicate images between them.
Are there any experiments like those two or anything else that you are particularly excited
about that brings this stuff out of the realm of speculation and more into the scientific mainstream?
Yeah. I mean, so the DMT, the work that Chris Timmerman was doing at Imperial is what's called
extended state DMT or DMTX. It has come to be known for sure. So this was a model,
a proposal by myself and Rick Strassman back in 2015, because as everyone knows, who knows anything
about DMT, it's, it's an extremely intense experience. You know, you're trying, you're kind
of hurtled into this alternate world. You look around shocked, bewildered, aghast, um, at this thing
that's just appeared in front of you, uh, and that surrounds you and overwhelms you. And then you're kind
of dragged back again very, very quickly. It's, it's, it's not a great drug used in that way,
you know, vaporized or injected. It's not a great drug to kind of explore. It's not a,
the state is, it's very fast and very, very short. Um, so I was kind of looking at DMT. DMT is a weird
drug, not just in terms of its effects, but it's, it has these pharmacological peculiarities that set
it apart. Um, so unlike other drugs, for example, LSD or psilocybin, if you give someone LSD,
they will have a certain intensity of experience based upon dose. If you then give them the same
dose, let's say a day later, it will be slightly diminished. And then a day later in it, you, you,
you rapidly build up tolerance. The same with psilocybin with DMT, you don't, uh, and it's
not fully understood why. Um, but Rick Strassman, there've been reports going back decades that,
you know, you can use DMT in quick succession, uh, and not experience intolerance effect. And Rick
Strassman studied this during his 1990 studies. He would inject someone with DMT and he'd measure the
intensity of the experience using a special rating scale that he developed. Then he'd inject
them again, 30 minutes later with the same dose and they had the same intensity of experience and
on and on. So there was no buildup of tolerance. Um, it's also, of course, because it's so short
acting, um, it's, it's removed from the brain, it gets into the brain very, very quickly. And it's
cleared from the brain very, very quickly. It's, it's just this, it's like an engine, almost like
it's engineered with precision, uh, but to kind of slot into the brain's machinery and kind of
cause these highly dramatic changes in the structure and dynamics of the world. And so it,
it occurred to me that, well, why don't we repurpose a technique from anesthesiology called
target controlled intravenous infusion, um, where you, if you want to keep someone in an anesthetized
state, what you do is you don't just inject them with a drug and kind of let it kind of get into their
brain and then metabolize because you can't control how long they're, they remain unconscious
for. So what you do, you, you inject them with a very short acting anesthetic and you infuse it,
use a special infusion device, which is programmed based upon the, uh, the, the metabolism and
distribution, all these kinds of properties of the drug that you can, you need a mathematical
model for. Um, so you infuse it into their, their, uh, their veins and you able to maintain this
fairly stable brain concentration of this anesthetic drug. And you can manipulate how deep they are in
the anesthetized state for as long as you want. Then you switch off the machine and they will
come out fairly, fairly quickly. So I thought, why don't we just use this technology, uh, but with DMT.
Whoa. And so I wrote to Rick and I said, I kind of have this idea. I think this might work,
but we need to kind of show that it, that it could work. Um, and for that, we needed this,
what's called a pharmacokinetic model, which models how DMT is distributed and metabolized
so that we can, we can just show that, yes, this should work. The DMT, the properties of DMT make it
amenable for this technique. And so Rick had all of the blood data, blood sampling data from his 90 studies,
which he sent to me. And then we got to work and we wrote this paper, uh, which basically said, yes,
DMT seems to be amenable to this kind of technology. Um, and it got a lot of attention. People started
talking about alien communication machines and matrix and this kind of thing, the matrix machine,
uh, whatever. But then fortunately, um, Imperial college picked it up. Um, and they developed a much
better model than, than our kind of back of the envelope model. Um, and they implemented it in
humans and they were able to extend the DMT state, stabilize it, um, for 30 minutes. So instead of just
two or three minutes within the breakthrough state, they extended it for 30 minutes and, uh, it worked
very, very, very well. There was no physiological concerns. The heart rate, blood pressure was normal.
Anxiety levels kind of peaked at the beginning and then settled down. Um, the, the intensity of the
experience was perfectly stable, uh, throughout the 30 minutes. Um, and another group in Basel,
Matthias, Matthias Liechti, I think he's called, uh, has extended it for 90 minutes. Another group has
extended it for six hours at a very low dose level. So this is the technology, right? Um, this is,
this is how we go from, um, scuba diving to deep sea diving. You have this, like you're able to go
to the bottom of the ocean and stay there. You know, you have a direct line back to the boat.
You know, that's how I see DMTX. It allows you to explore, to navigate, to perform experiments
within the space, uh, and to train people, um, to actually spend time within the space.
And importantly, it's almost like lucid dreaming or something kind of like a little in control
and a place that typically out of control. Exactly. And so once you get into this space
and it stabilizes, then you can begin to think about establishing communication with these
intelligences, whatever you think they are, whatever you think about that ontology.
Okay. Okay. We can establish communication with them, begin to, um, think about, you know,
what can we learn from them? Um, and one aspect that I'm particularly interested in is the oncology.
Can we demonstrate that these are more than just fabrications of the brain, right? Can we show
somehow that we're actually interfacing with some kind of intelligence that is non-human and that,
if that was possible, and I think it might be, that's, I mean, that the implications of that is
almost beyond comprehension, right? The idea that we can use this drug to communicate with beings and
we can show that these are non-human intelligent beings. And I think that's, that's, that could be
possible. Uh, back in the early two thousands, uh, a guy called Rodriguez published his paper and he
said, why don't we give these entities, uh, why don't we give them mathematical problems so we can
say, okay, well, I'll give you a large number, Mr. Alien. Uh, I want you to find the unique prime
factors of this large number. I can't do this in my head, uh, but you're very, very smart. So you can do
that for me now. It's a nice idea, right? Uh, and if they gave them the correct answer, we'd know that
it was not happening in the brain, that there was actually interaction with some kind of intelligence.
The problem with this, of course, is that, you know, finding it's, it's, it kind of feels again,
a bit presumptuous that they're going to want to play our little prove your ontological status games,
prove that you're real. Here's some, you know, I don't see what the, it's very presumptuous to think
that they're going to want to kind of play along with that. So I don't think that's necessarily
the way to go. It's one way to go. Uh, but I think what's interesting about these intelligences
is that they betray, they can't help, but betray their intelligence. Everything they do is, um,
is, is, is a kind of performance and demonstration of their intelligence. You just need people who can
recognize it. Um, so I was speaking just a few days ago in Denver at the psychedelic science conference
with, um, uh, Andres Gomez Emilsson. So he's this very smart mathematician guy, but also very interested
in DMT. And he was telling me things that were blowing my mind. I mean, he was, he said, okay,
I go into this state, uh, the DMT state and these beings, they, they, they paint surfaces in four
colors. They do it repeatedly. Now to me, if I go in and I see an entity painting surfaces with four
colors, I go, that's cool. But he said, actually there's more to it than this because painting a
surface with four colors, like a map, yeah. A complicated map of shapes, right. With four
colors called the four color, color theorem. So if you have a map of shapes that are all kind of
tessellated, right. Um, you have, you have to color each shape with a color. So one of four
colors sets up, no two shapes have, um, the same color, right. So imagine a world map and you have
to color every country, but you don't want two countries having the same color, right. You can
do it. It's been proved that you can do it with just four colors, but if you were given a very
complex map and asked to do it by hand, it would take you a long time. I mean, Andres is a very smart
guy. And he said, it would take him all afternoon. Right. Um, so for me, that means it would take me
all day. Um, right. Uh, and yet these entities, they, they do it instantaneously, like less than
a second and they do it repeatedly. So they're, they're performing, you know, in short, they're
performing mathematical operations, mathematical algorithms that would take a human brain, um,
a smart human several hours. And they're doing it in a fraction of a second. And there are other
things that I didn't quite understand, but other operations, finding the distances between two
surfaces, weird stuff, mathematical stuff. Right. So most people, when they go into this space,
they go, ah, this is incredible. This is impossible, but they can't tell you why it's impossible.
When a mathematician goes into this space, they can say, yes, this is impossible for these reasons,
right. These are the mathematical operations required to construct these things. And the
human brain couldn't do that within a fraction of a second. So it just occurred to me that this
is how we do it. We don't kind of rely on them to play with us or to kind of, um, to cooperate with
our little prove yourself games, but actually they're doing it all the time. They're demonstrating
their intelligence. They can't help it. They love performing and we just need to send the right
people in. So we send in mathematicians, you send in geometers or topologists or whatever,
right. You send in linguists, um, who can look at the kind of, because code and language is also a
big part of the experience. And they can say, okay, this seems to be some kind of language.
And I can explain why it's some kind of language. It seems to be informationally dense or whatever,
you know, it adheres to these various rules of how languages are constructed and bringing data back.
So you're not just sending people in and going kind of what happened, man, right? The kind of the
Strassman approach was great for its time, but now we have this DMTX technology. We can send people in
with specific skillsets, specific, you know, high level expertise in very specific fields. And they
can say, okay, I'm going to come in. I'm going to describe the geometric structure of the space.
I'm going to describe the topology of the space. I'm going to describe the way that these
intelligences communicate and all this kind of stuff. It's hard to comprehend the implications,
I think, that we could actually demonstrate pretty soon, you know, or, or at least to a very
high level of probability say, okay, these intelligences are doing things that the human
brain can't do. What does that mean?
Yes. Yes. Do we have, you know, in the past we've had angel hierarchies, like you have St. Thomas
Aquinas with this angel hierarchy or Iamblichus, you know, who's the other guy? Dionysus of
Mariupagite or something, something like that.
Yeah. Like we have these sort of, uh, and they literally have taxonomies where they'll have like
attributes associated with these different beings, physical characteristics of the beings.
Do we have a taxonomy of the DMT world beings? Do we have categories, you know, like a, like a,
like an Excel sheet of these things, like a bestiary, right? Um, we don't, not a formal one.
Yeah. I mean, there are, there are attempts online, you know, to describe, and there's a book by David J.
Brown, uh, illustrated field guide to DMT entities, which is a lot of fun, uh, kind of describing the type
of entities that people experience. And there, there are clearly patterns. Um, so the machine
elves, by far the most famous residents of this space, they tend to be jovial. They're
multitudinous, you know, there's, there's so many of them bouncing around and they're jolly. And,
uh, they like to show you wonderfully strange, high dimensional objects. Terrence McKinney used to
call like Fabergé eggs, but in nine dimensions or whatever, you know, these kinds of beings that,
that tend to be more about a show, like a circus kind of thing, uh, more about performing and showing
you what's possible. Um, and then there are more kind of serious beings. So the insectoids,
you know, mantid kind of beings, these tend to be a bit more, um, uh, less jovial, shall we say,
uh, often. Uh, and they, they, they, those are often the beings that will perform kind of surgery,
uh, on you and on your brain or on your body and scanning and this kind of thing.
That's so common in alien abductions. So common. And there are always these sort of worker be
like often short grays. And then there's like a tall gray overseeing it, or there's a, uh, a tall
white, you know, when he's like sort of blonde Nordic looking beings overseeing that, you know,
it, there is this sort of hierarchy. Yeah. Always, almost, almost always associated with.
Yeah. I actually got, uh, last year, I got this email from this Korean guy. Now there aren't that,
I don't think there are that many Koreans who take ayahuasca or travel to Peru to take ayahuasca. So
I kind of, it piqued my interest when he emailed me, but he, he went to, um, Peru because he wanted
healing. He wanted to meet mother ayahuasca and the spirits of the forest. And he didn't,
he didn't get that. He got a full blown alien experience. He, he was taken by this, what he
described as the alien scientist through this extremely complex computational tunnel thing
into this, uh, spacecraft or some kind of highly hyper-technological environment. And these beings
were torturing him. They were happy with these smaller beings, again, the hierarchy, um, these
smaller beings that were kind of doing things to him. Uh, and then there was this alien scientist,
um, who was not like these little insectoid beings, but was much, much more powerful. Um,
and that, that he describes this being as taking out his soul. This being was torturing him at a deep
soul level. I mean, he came out of it thinking that his soul had been captured like a fish on a hook.
He described it, uh, by these beings and it went on and on. Um, first experience,
the aliens came second experience, more of the same third experience, more every single,
um, ayahuasca session while he was in Peru. Um, it just got worse and worse. They showed him
horrible things. They showed him humanity being destroyed and, uh, trapped in this matrix like,
um, structure or whatever. I mean, it was horrible. It was completely alien. It was nothing like he was
expecting. He was, he was expecting his brain was primed to see the spirits of the forest. He got
something completely alien and he was horrified by it. Um, and that's not an uncommon experience when
people take, you know, when you take DMT, whether it's in the form of ayahuasca in a forest or whether it's
in a, the university of New Mexico hospital in, in room five, three, one, where Rick Strassman did his
studies or in your bedroom or basement or back room. Um, you, you, you cannot, you cannot guarantee
the kind of being that you're going to be interacting with. And if you're lucky, you'll get some nice
performance from the owls, but there's a very deep, you know, not insignificant probability that
you encounter being more objectionable, shall we say. Yeah, for sure. Well, that brings up this
earlier question that we kind of touched on, but it's like, how, you know, is the, is DMT a bridge
to a world that is separated without the DMT from our waking reality? Or are they always like pre
enlightenment? If you were to say there are, you know, machine elves, not call them by that name,
but like little beings sort of like controlling the forces of, you know, reality and like, you know,
pre gravity and things like that, we'd be like, yeah, of course, like spirits controlling everything,
like literally pre Newton, that would have been the sort of conventional explanation. And, um,
I saw you on the Danny Jones podcast, which I loved. And I think you guys brought up Philip K. Dick,
right. And Philip K. Dick would be one of these guys who would extend this sort of DMT world to his
model of reality itself, where, you know, he gave this famous speech, uh, in Metz France,
where he said, I think it was called, um, you know, if you, if you think this world sucks,
you should see the others or something. And he's talking about the man in the high castle,
you know, where it's like the Nazis and the Japanese had like annexed, you know,
the United States of world war II went the other way. And he's, you know, then he's giving the speech
in front of all these like well-respected people or whatever. And he's like, you guys don't get it.
Like that world happened. Like that's real. Like that's an all parallel universe or something.
And so he goes into this whole, he has this whole ontology. My friend Riz Virk, um, who's written,
uh, you know, a couple of books about simulation theory is friends with his wife, uh, Tessa Dick.
And she talks about how he was just fully bought into the world being a simulation. You know, it's like
time froze in Roman time. Like we're still in Roman times. And this, this is all this just sort of modern
veneer, but maybe the most interesting book I think he wrote along these lines is this book
called the adjustment team. I don't know if you've heard of this, but it's a, it's a book about like,
if you had, um, a group that was in total control of reality and they like froze this, you know,
podcast and then they like, you know, moved the water like an inch or whatever. And then you'd get this
just like, you know, for rockets, like one degrees off course, you get this sort of air propagation,
you get this multiplicative butterfly effect that like changes timelines. And if you think about a
lot of what you're saying with these DMT entities, if they have any interface with our waking reality,
they would have that ability, like the color thing that you mentioned. So it gets into these weird
questions of like, are there time editing archons or beings that are like coming down, freeze framing
things, neuralizing us, changing a little variable here and there, and then letting things run their
course. And then, okay. You know, some other, some other thing happens where some, you know,
a nukes about to go off, they stopped the nuke or whatever, you know, which UFOs show up around
nuclear sites. Right. But they're like weakly entangled with our reality. All they care about are these sort of
cosmic scale timeline, minor, it's, it's minimal interference. Yeah. Minimal adjustments necessary
to like maintain certain timelines, but they are monitoring the timelines. I think we, you know,
I can't say whether that's true or not, but we can't rule it out. And when you, it's like
when you, when you use DMT and you're confronted with beings that are clearly
to say they're more advanced than humans, it just doesn't do them justice. I mean,
you're talking about beings that have, that appear to have that kind of cosmic,
cosmic, um, uh, cosmic abilities, whether that is indeed having, whether they are normally kind of,
um, linked to connected to, uh, have some kind of relationship with our, with our reality, but kind
of stay back. I don't know. But you, the fact that we have this, what I consider to be a molecular
technology that allows us to interface with beings that, that seem to have those kind of properties
that seem to be at that level of intelligence, a level of intelligence that really is beyond
our comprehension. We can't, there's no way for us to conceive of what an intelligence
like that truly is or its potential or its power or its abilities, uh, then we should use it. And, and
going back thousands of years, I mean, these, obviously these civilizations in the Amazonian
rainforest, they didn't have, they weren't talking about things you're talking about,
but they were describing the same types of beings, which they took very seriously. So they were talking
about, um, um, the Yanomami, for example, had these, these beings, which, which they called the
warusinari, insect beings, um, which sound very much, you know, very intelligent, very fearsome
creatures, which sound a lot like the insectoid aliens that people are describing in the 21st century.
Uh, they describe the Hekura, which are these multitudinous beings. You can never come to the
end of them. They say they come dancing and they're, they're singing and playing flutes.
And they're just beautiful dance, bounding around, uh, and jumping into your chest and filling your
chest. This is shamanistic mythos going back thousands of years. And then in the modern era,
people describe seeing multitudinous, giggling, lively, little beings, balls of light or whatever
that jump into their chest. Uh, and so clearly this is not just a, it's not Terence McKenna
implanting the idea of machine elves into people's brains. These are motifs, um, beings,
intelligent beings that go back thousands of years. And now we have a technique. We know how
to access them. Uh, and we need to start taking that seriously and not simply dismissing. You know,
my work is not so much about saying, I know what's going on. Uh, but really to convince people that they
don't have a clue what's going on and that they, they should stop simply assuming, um, that they
understand what DMT is. It's just your brain on drugs, man. Uh, this is just your brain making it
up, man, you know, that these kinds of explanations and they don't, they don't work. And I think we need
to, we need to certainly draw inspiration from these indigenous peoples who did take them seriously
and did see them as beings that they could have relationships with and learn from and, and, and
bring that into, there's a thread running from these indigenous cultures going back thousands
of years. And it's, it runs into the 21st century where we're now, we have much better technology.
Now we have, as I was just talking about DMTX, we have this technology where we can much more
reliably and stably enter the space. We're not relying on, um, drinking extremely bitter,
disgusting decoctions, nothing wrong with that. Uh, but we now have techniques the way we can
stabilize the state. We can go in there, we can send people and we can actually begin
to build relationships with these intelligences. Uh, and that might be what we need if we're going to
progress beyond, uh, where we are now, you know, we need to do that probably pretty quickly before we
kill ourselves, which is not, uh, that unlikely. Right. Do you, do you think, um,
you know, DMT is so fascinating. Do you think that there is something about the fact that it exists
in all organic matter that is sort of an important aspect to it? I mean, that's, that's, uh, again,
that's another one of its peculiarities, right? It's not, it's the simplest of all the naturally
occurring psychedelics. Um, it, you look at the molecule, it looks perfectly unremarkable.
There's nothing interesting about it. If I saw DMT and I didn't know anything about it, I'd say
probably not going to be that interesting. Uh, it's two steps, enzymatic steps from tryptophan,
this amino acid. Um, you decarboxylate in tryptophan, you get tryptamine, you add two
methyl groups, you get DMT. This is as simple as it gets. Uh, and as you said, it's not just
common. It's ubiquitous. Terrence, uh, Dennis McKenna, Terrence's brother says the nature is
drenched in DMT. Uh, he thinks, and he's probably right that if you looked carefully, you'd find it
in basically every plant. Some have higher concentrations than others. You can extract it
from, you can extract it. Right. So it's this, it's, it's this ubiquitous, very simple molecule
that just happens to, when you smoke it or inject it, just happens to get access to this
completely alien reality filled with highly intelligent beings. I don't buy that that's
just a coincidence. It seems like there is this message implanted in our reality, implanted in the
natural world. And it just takes, uh, uh, uh, an organism with a certain level of cognitive
advancement, right? You can't just eat plants. You can't just munch plants mindlessly and have a DMT
trip. You can't do that. You have to isolate it. You have to extract it. You have to learn how to use
it as the Amazonians did with ayahuasca, uh, to bypass this, uh, monoamine oxidase in the stomach,
that you need an intelligent being to do that. Uh, which is another interesting aspect to it.
You don't stumble across DMT. Uh, you have to learn to, uh, you have to discover it and learn how to use
it. And this is not, you know, the technology didn't end with ayahuasca. It didn't end in the 1960s
when we learned that you could vaporize it either. And it didn't end in 2015 when myself and Rick
Strassman developed the DMTX protocol. Um, I think we're still learning to use this,
this technology. Um, and I think so it is like a technology. It's like semiconductors are like,
you know, it's like electron differentials or whatever. It's like, this is like, you know,
another technology where you, if you figure out the key to extracting it, like you're, you're opened
up to a whole new world. Exactly. And what's also very interesting, of course, is that it's not just a
product of plant metabolism, metabolism. It's a product of mammalian metabolism as well. So it's
found in humans. So we're all carrying DMT at very low levels, which raises the question. And again,
this is something that I'm currently working on, um, with, with new nautics. We've, we've hired the
university of, uh, or contracted with a team at the university of Florida, um, to actually develop
techniques to hack the brain's endogenous DMT system, right? So we know that there is,
we know the human brain produces DMT, but in very low levels. And we think we found a peptide or a
peptide that was first found in the 1970s, but then forgotten about. What's the peptide?
We don't know. We know it's there. We know it, it basically, it inhibits
this enzyme called indolethylamine N-methyltransferase, INMT. Okay. It's the key enzyme
to produce DMT basically. Converts tryptamine to dimethyltryptamine. Now this enzyme, um, is
inhibited by this peptide we all carry, uh, and basically keeps DMT levels low.
Now we know this peptide is there. It's in cerebrospinal fluid. It's in mammalian brain.
Um, but we don't know how it works. We don't know its structure or its sequence or anything
like that. So we're working with university of Florida, new nautics, um, to basically to isolate
and characterize, uh, this peptide and try to understand the regulatory system that controls
DMT level. So what the switch or the slider, right? And so the idea being that, uh, we can,
if we understand this regulatory system, we can learn how to hack it. And so rather than giving
someone injecting someone with DMT, we rather, we can inject them with a small amount of a peptide,
for example, um, that will allow them to naturally slide into, be induced into the DMT state and,
and kept there for, you know, long periods of time. So we call this endo DMTX or EDMTX.
Is any of this playing with fire? Like, you know, I think about where, you know, we now can split the
atom. We, you know, know the genetic code of, you know, humans, or we're still discovering stuff there,
but you know, we're, we're starting to crack that. And then we have, we have the ability to,
if you find some peptide where you can, you know, just modulate this, and even with the, the, uh,
intravenous stuff, you know, modulated on and off. Is there something actually adaptive about
not being in control of it? And whoever set up, you know, whatever world we're in, you know, having,
having set it up in the, in the right sort of way, the sort of anthropic principle or something,
it's, it's, it exists in sort of perfect amounts. Well, you could take that. Many people think that,
right. And that's a very cautious attitude to take, but there's nothing natural about extracting
from the most hostilist root bark with sodium hydroxide and, and, um, and Zippo lighter fluid.
You know, this is, this is, this is a, you're employing chemistry, you're employing technology
to do this. So, so if, if that was the case, then ayahuasca would, you'd stop at ayahuasca and even,
not even ayahuasca because that itself is a technology. So then, then you're back to,
to, well, you're, you're back to not knowing what DMT is because you can't just ingest it.
So there's no, you can't just consume the, the naturally occurring source of DMT. There's no way
to do it. Right. You can't do it. Uh, you have to either combine it with, with this monoamine
oxidase inhibitor, uh, boil it down, or you have to extract it. And so I don't see why one particular
technology or one particular, um, way of using DMT should be seen as the, the be all and end all
of it. Um, so, okay, we can extract it. Um, this seems to me a stepping stone on the way to
further development. And I just think that the, that Rick Strassman's pure, you know,
pharmaceutical grade DMT injected directly in the bloodstream was a step beyond extracting plant,
um, smoking or vaporizing plant extracts. And then now I think that DMT X is just the next iteration
along that path. And ultimately I think, you know, I don't know where this is going, but I don't,
I've never got the sense that, oh, we need to stop here. This is the way to use DMT. I don't,
I think that doesn't really make any sense to me. Um, so I think in the future, who knows how we're going
to be using DMT and will there be combinations of molecules that we were using and will we be
dispensing, as I said, with molecules altogether with exogenous molecules and using, hacking our
own, um, endogenous DMT production system. And then you would, I can imagine a future where you're,
you lie in a pod and all of your bodily needs are taken care of. You're fed, uh, you might,
you know, your oxygen supply is managed and your body may be cooled down. Um, your waste products are
dealt with. Um, and you spend days, weeks, months, significant portions of your life
to anyone observing you basically asleep in a pod. Yeah. Uh, and to you, you would be interacting with
and yeah, you know, which is by the way, what we could be in now, right? Like that's, you know,
we could be in the matrix and we could just wake up and you're in some pod or whatever jelly and you
could have whatever the hyper expanded version of DMT that ports you into this world.
Or whatever. Right. So it's like you end up in this sort of babushka doll model of reality.
That's true. Or it could be that you're actually returning, uh, and that actually going to the pod
is the way to return to your, your back, back to the pod. And people, that's kind of interesting
because they say it's realer than real, right? Right. It's realer than real. So this is actually,
you're in a pod now that when you go into the pod, whatever, and raise the DMT levels,
you're actually wake up in back. And then it goes to Plato's cave where it's like,
all we're seeing now is sort of simulacra. In fact, in the matrix, the movie, he's looking at
a book and it's, I think it's Jean Baudillard or whatever, this French, you know, Baudrillard,
that's right. Um, you know, simulacra and simulation or whatever. And it's like, you know,
it's clearly the Wachowski siblings. They, um, you know, we're paying homage to this sort of,
you know, postmodern author that's writing about simulacra. It's just so, so fascinating.
Yeah. Yeah. And people do describe very, a very common feeling when they enter the DMT space is
one of, I'm back welcome. And they, you know, the lights are flashing and it's like, welcome home.
What do you mean? Welcome home. You do like a life review, right? And it's like this very strong
sense of deja vu. Like I've been here before. Not only have I been here before, but this is my true home.
So maybe that's what's happening. Maybe we are on a path towards the state where we return.
And does it, does it look like lying in a pod and closing your eyes and, uh, raising your DMT
levels in your brain through some technology? Maybe, maybe it's something else that we don't
yet. Yeah. I think, you know, consciousness is a sort of, it's a reduction mechanism on a default
state of greater omniscience or something. And so I think it's, is, is consciousness locally produced
or is it sort of transmitted and ported into a receptor that's inherently limited? And I would,
I would say the latter. Um, but it, you know, yeah, it does bring up all these, all these sorts of
questions, but it goes back to this sort of Plato thing where in all these sort of mystery rituals
across time and space, whether, you know, um, they deal with psychedelics or not. Sometimes
they just deal with sheer amounts of pain, like putting your hand in a glove full of bullet ants
or whatever you are temporarily. If the, if biology is a, is a collapsing function on a default state
of greater omniscience, you're killing that collapsing function temporarily. And the person
experiences sort of greater consciousness and awareness, and you'd expect this more sort of
muted, like, Oh, it all just shut off. And that now I'm back or I got turned back on, but it's not
the mystery ritual kills the collapsing function and you get this sort of greater, you know, ontological
reality. And then you come back and there, there's always this translation function issue. I think
William James was like writing in his diary about like, you know, some, some trip he had had or
something. And like, you, you end up writing mumbo jump, like just, you know, gobbledygook.
It's like impossible to translate. Yeah. And Terrence McKinney used to say a secret is not something
untold. It is something that cannot be told. Oh, that is beautiful. Yeah. Oh, that's beautiful.
Awesome. Wish I'd thought of that. Yeah. Yeah. But the un-Englishable and you have to,
you lit, you have to have the direct experience. You can't, you can bring back fragments,
lower dimensional projections of this space and talk about it to some extent, but you, you cannot.
And this is why it's so difficult spending my life talking about DMT is, is what I really should say is
just, just, just go there and then get back to me. Um, because people can't comprehend when I'm
talking about entities or strange other worlds that in their head, they're seeing this 1970s
science fiction movie with little green men on, on a globe. Um, they don't, there's no way for them to
even conceive of what's actually going on in my head when I'm talking about this thing, because it's
un-Englishable, you know, and so trying to English the un-Englishable to F the un-effable,
the ineffable to put it like that is, is, is very, very difficult. Um, um, but, but it's not a
completely hopeless time. At least I can explain to people why, okay, there are certain aspects of
this space that, that, that make it impossible. And that mean the, that, that, um, the only conclusion
we can draw from that is that there's more going on, there's more going on here than we can explain.
Uh, if people come away from my work with that, then I've kind of done my job and the rest happens
with a glass pipe and, um, you know, inhaling a couple of lungfuls of DMT vapor. That's the only
100% conversion. Sure. Conversion technique. Yeah. It's like, oh, I get it. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
No, there's no, it's like a lot. If you're studying any of these fields, the work is actually
in translating your ontology to the average person. It's not, it's, it's also in, you know,
working out the ontology itself, but it's, it, you have to do both. Otherwise you end up on an
island completely, you know, like, and there's just no interface with, you know, the rest of the world.
So is, is there something about DMT where, you know, I think it, it, it shows up right when you die.
Is that right? And then does it show up at the womb in the womb or around, like,
I remember reading Rick, Rick Strassman, uh, you know, DMT spirit molecule, and he talks
about it being maybe a part of identity formation. Is that, are these things possible or has that
been debunked? Cause this was, you know, like probably 20 years ago he was writing this.
Well, it's not been debunked. I mean, I think it's often the idea of, so the DMT, the spirit molecule
came from Rick Strassman's idea that it's released at the point of death. And he's like,
provides the conduit by which the soul exits the body and enters the afterlife. This is a very
obviously mystical, spiritual, uh, hypothesis. Um, but it's often, it's often repeated as if it's
fact. Um, right. There's, you know, DMT is produces dreams and when it's released in the small amounts
and then a large amount is when you die. Yeah. But both of these are hypotheses. Um,
so we don't know that we don't know that. However, um, the dream thing, I don't think
makes any sense because most dreams are not anything like DMT. So people who think they're
going to have a dreamlike experience when they take DMT, I'm sorry, but it's not going to be
anything like any normal dream. Um, so I don't, and there's no evidence that DMT is produced during
REM sleep. So that one, I think is just, that was just, again, a hypothesis put out by a guy called
Jace Calloway in the 1980s. Terence McKenna often repeated it, perhaps giving a, he was a little bit
more definitive than he should have been about that. Uh, but then the, the dying thing is more
interesting. Um, whether or not it provides the means by which you can enter the afterlife,
that's a different question. That's more of a metaphysical question. I don't think
science is really going to get to the bottom of that, but the idea that it's released the
point of death, actually there is good evidence now that it could be, I don't think it's the pineal
gland. The pineal gland is what Strassman thought. Um, the pineal gland is a very, very tiny gland. It's
about this big, the end of my little finger. It produces nanograms of melatonin. It's, it's not
set up to pump out large amounts of DMT, enough DMT to cause a breakthrough to experience. But as I
said, it's DMT is two steps from tryptophan. So, you know, other cells in the brain, potentially all
neurons in the brain could produce DMT. You don't need to rely on the pineal. And some recent studies
showed some interesting things. Firstly, that, um, DMT levels in rodents, this was, so not humans,
but still mammals, um, uh, DMT levels, uh, in, in awake living, um, rodents were about the same
as other neurotransmitters like serotonin and dopamine. So it's not tiny amounts. It's not a
breakthrough psychedelic level, but still produced in the same kind of quantities as of other neurotransmitters.
Which is kind of cool, right? So clearly the, the, the brain is diverting resources to producing
DMT. Why? We don't know. However, there's something functional. There's something functional there.
And, and what's interesting, uh, is that when they sacrifice these rodents, sacrifice is such a weird
word. They don't like put them on an altar and light candles. They kill them, right? So when they kill these
rats, they, they actually have a technique now called micro dialysis, where they're able to measure
in real time, DMT levels in a living rat, which wasn't available, you know, all these decades ago
when these hypotheses were originally proposed, but now they can. So they can measure DMT in the brain
of a rodent, uh, and then they kill the rodent. And as the rodent dies, DMT levels rise, they spike.
Um, now you also see this with other neurotransmitters, by the way, so it's not just DMT, but still.
Okay. DMT levels are rising. That's in line with Strassman's model. No, one's done that with a
human. So if you could get permission with somebody who was end of life, um, you know,
perhaps on a life support machine and during the dying process, could you get permission from them
or their family members to, uh, to draw their blood, that would be an experiment that could
be done ethically. It's difficult, obviously, but yeah, but it could be done. Right. Uh, and what's
interesting about DMT is that other studies have shown that when you take neurons, so neurons are
very sensitive to oxygen, they need oxygen, you deprive a neuron of oxygen, it dies. Um,
this is why strokes where you lose blood supply to certain areas of the brain are so devastating,
because if you don't restore blood supply very, very quickly, areas of the brain die and you end
up with severe disabilities or death. Um, what's interesting is that in a oxygen hypoxic, oxygen
deprived environment, um, neurons will survive longer in the presence of DMT.
Whoa. But they bind to a specific receptor called the sigma, sigma one receptor, uh, which,
you know, a few decades ago, we didn't know existed and, and has no other function. It's
called an orphan receptor and that it's a receptor that's there, but, but nothing binds to it. We
know now that DMT binds to it. So it's not a true orphan receptor, but it binds to an endogenous molecule,
DMT. So it binds to this receptor and it, it, it initiates a, a cascade of interest,
intracellular signaling that seems to somehow protects the neuron. Um, so you can imagine
during the dying process, uh, as your respiratory system is collapsing, blood supply to the brain is
diminishing. Your brain is being starved of oxygen. DMT ramps up and should you survive,
the DMT has protected your brain during that period where you were dying. Does that make sense?
Yeah. And now it doesn't answer the question of why. So like prolong it, like it bridges
the neurons to your survival state or something. Exactly. It gives them a little, gives them a
little wiggle room, right? Exactly. So the rest of the body can survive if you kind of resuscitated,
for example, um, or your heart restarts or whatever. Uh, but your brain, that one,
that's going to be in trouble. So it needs a bit of extra protection. So the DMT seems to be doing that.
So that's fits in with the dying process. So maybe that's why it's released during death.
It doesn't answer, of course, why send, why this molecule also just happens to
transport you to this alternate reality. So clearly there's a connection there. Does that mean,
um, that DMT has this kind of dual function? It's protecting the brain during the dying process.
Uh, but if you actually do die, it also allows you to directly, uh, move into whatever happens after
you die. You may be, maybe you are getting a glimpse. I mean, that's not a particularly nice
thought, the idea of going permanently into the DMT space. I mean, it's, you know, that,
I guess that's where the preparation comes in of working within this space, because it is kind of
shocking and horrifying for many people. Um, but maybe that's why it's important to work with DMT
whilst you're still alive, because you're going to, this is the kind, maybe this is where you're
going to go after you die. I don't know. That's pure speculation.
Yeah. But so, so in short, the whole DMT spirit molecule thing started as a pure speculation and
now, okay, it all seems to hang together. The idea of DMT being released during the dying process,
which is kind of cool. Yeah. It's fascinating. Gimo Borgigen at University of Michigan,
she studies stuff around, you know, endogenous DMT receptors in the brain and stuff, but she also
studies terminal lucidity, which I find very interesting. This idea that sometimes somebody
can be in like a coma for a long time. And then right before they die, they seem to sort of wake up,
be extremely alert and like back to their old selves or have dementia. And right before they did,
it's just fascinating sort of, um, phenomenology. Uh, does that have anything to do with DMT? I just,
I found it interesting that she both studies DMT and she looks into this, or is that just a coincidence?
I don't know if it's a coincidence. It might not be a coincidence, whether this,
um, this terminal lucidity has anything to do with DMT or with something else. I mean, it might,
DMT might be part of it. I mean, as I said, you get lots of quite dramatic changes in neural activity
and these electrical storms and, uh, increases in various neurotransmitters and neuromodulators
during the dying process. So it's, it's, you know, it's probably some emergent effect from all of
this happening and DMT is just a part of it. That's my guess, but I don't really know.
Yeah. Yeah. Very interesting. Do you think, you know, Aldous Huxley, uh, famous British,
British author, but also kind of psychonaut. He, um, he, I think at the end of his life was, uh,
was dying and he asked his wife to, uh, give him an extremely high dose of LSD.
That's right. And, um, he also said something very interesting, which I want to get your take
on. He said that in the 21st century, we would see a religion, uh, sort of induced by more mass
psychedelic use and people would have more of an individual connection with like almost a Gnostic
connection with God and the universe through these psychedelics. Do you think that that will happen?
You know, it's sort of the Timothy Leary, like if you had LSD in the tap water sort of thing.
Yeah. I mean, a religion, I'm slightly fearful of the word religion, um, and that it is a set of
doctrines, a set of prescribed beliefs. Um, so I would hope that this, this doesn't take the form of a
religion. Um, I, you, you see that kind of thing happening with DMT specifically, uh, where
certain groups of people often quite influential who have decided that they've got a handle on things.
They understand what DMT represents and they understand the entities and they understand how
it connects to reality and how we should use DMT and all of this. And then they bring in followers and
there are a number of small pockets. I mean, nothing ever become that's kind of consumed to the space
in any way, the DMT kind of community, if you want to use that word. Uh, but, but, but certainly,
um, I think the truth is that it's very difficult to not become, I wouldn't say religious, but
spiritual, mystical, uh, to accept that actually there's more to reality. And you, you, you are
confronted with that. It's undeniable when you take DMT, that there's more to reality. Um, and that
we are, but a very small fragment of reality. And when, when large numbers of people begin to accept
that, um, then the question is, is, well, what, what do we do with that? Um, you know,
what do we, what do we do with an elf? As McKenna used to say, like, how do we take that fact
and move with it? Does it require, does it require some kind of religious doctrinal structure
or not? I don't know. Yeah. I don't know. I mean, that's a question that, that, that bothers me.
Like what, what is this all about? Where's this all going?
It bothers me too. Cause I, I think I have the same inclinations as you, which is to directly
experience, to push the boundaries on these things and to sort of like really know stuff
for yourself to the extent you can. And then I wonder if it's sort of this horseshoe thing where
you start off like super ignorant, then you seek truth in some like more objective sense about,
you know, metaphysical reality. And then you realize there's like some overload or something
like this is actually not adaptive for like a single human to know. And it's really all about
like leading a good life on earth and understanding kind of the, the, the bounds of, of our, of our
lives and our epistemology. And then you become sort of religious and you realize how adaptive religion
is or something. Right. Yeah. I mean, that's, it's like the path will reveal itself. I think I try not
to think too far ahead of where this is going because I don't know if I'm being completely honest.
Um, but I think we just keep moving forward carefully, um, with humility. Um, and I think
the, the, the whole DMTX stuff in my opinion has, has been just another step along that path of using
this molecule, trying to understand it as much as we can, not going in with assumptions about what
we're dealing with or what the, what the, the teleology is, you know, what is the, the, the ultimate
aim of all of this. I don't, I don't, I speculate, uh, on what it might look like, but I don't know.
Um, I don't know if it's possible for us to know at this point, we've, there could be some kind of
phase transition that's necessary to take place before we can even comprehend. I mean, we don't
really know what the next five years is going to look like. People are speculating on with AI and stuff,
but I don't think anyone really knows where we're headed. I agree. It's always the sort of some
adjacent surprise or something. It's never the, whenever people make predictions, I'm always
skeptical of like these sort of quote unquote futurists that sort of grift off of some,
you know, for sure, you know, future vision that never, it never manifests the way they
sort of say, um, do you believe in God? Well, that came from left field.
Yeah. Talk about religion. Do I believe in God? Well, I'm going to give the kind of the obvious
answer, which is how do you define God? I'm going to fire that question back at you. You know,
how do you define God? And people say, do you believe in God? Well, the God that is in your head
is probably quite different to the God in my head. So I could answer that. Yes. I could answer that.
No, and be truthful in both cases, depending on how you define God. But you could use that sort of
postmodern breakdown of language to like, you know, retort any sort of question.
That's true. And I'm not trying to be an annoying postmodernist.
No, no, I get it. God is especially undefined. Or Jordan Peterson or something.
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah. Peterson's hilarious because he hates the postmodernists, but he is so postmodern in
the way he speaks. Right, yeah. He speaks, he's so like, he thinks that all that stuff,
you know, Foucault or whatever is the reason that like society is in decline. And then when you call
him out and you debate him on this stuff, it turns into this postmodern gobbledygook where he's like,
what did you stake your life on? I'm like, what are you talking about, dude? Like you're,
you are making no sense. But in this case, I think it's valuable because people do have different
conceptions of God. Now, if you mean, do I mean a higher being that created the universe that we,
that we, that we should worship, then no, I don't believe in that. But do I believe that there is
some kind of intelligence that is non-human, non-physical, that we can't directly interact
with normally, perhaps, that has been around a lot longer than we have? Well, I can't help but
believe that. I mean, I, when you, when you smoke DMT, you interact with such intelligences. Do I think
there's one grand intelligence that subsumes all of these? Maybe, maybe, um, maybe God is con,
you know, you could take the, the more Vedanta or ancient Hindu, uh, answer that question,
which is to say, well, God is everything. God is consciousness. God is the ultimate reality.
There is nothing that isn't God. I like that idea as well. And then you, we are all the million,
um, who was it? Um, GK Chesterton, GK Chesterton, uh, that talks about the million masks of God.
Um, um, and that's, we're all masks of God. You know, the eye with which I see God is the,
the eye with which I see God is the same eye with which God sees me. And they were all expressions of,
and we, there's no escaping that. We're all part of an expressions of, uh, masks of the ultimate
reality, which you might call God. I, a Hindu might call Brahman. Somebody else, um, might call
the ultimate reality that, which is, um, that idea. I, I, I kind of, um, sympathetic towards as
well. And I kind of feel like that. I think consciousness is fundamental in some very deep,
profound way. I don't think we're going to explain consciousness in terms of, uh, physicalism or in
terms of, um, neural activity or anything like that. I think it's beyond that. I think it's
absolutely fundamental. And so, yes, I, the answer to your question is, I believe in God,
but perhaps not the God as, as, as you might define it, but as the God, as I would define it.
What, what do you think about these, um, this buddy, Danny, who does these DMT laser diffraction
experiments, where I'm sure you'd get asked this all the time, where people take DMT,
there's some sort of, you know, laser intersection, and then they look at it and they claim to see
some sort of almost like code that they, I mean, that's their interpretation, like a code that is,
you know, um, the computation behind the universe or something. What, what do you think about this?
Well, do I think that he is, and other people are seeing the fundamental code that runs our reality?
No, I don't think that at all. I don't, I think the idea that, that reality is computational or is
some kind of code. Okay. That's possible. The idea that you could look at it and it would look like
characters that we recognize, like Japanese katakana and, uh, and Hebrew and stuff like this.
Well, that doesn't make any sense. Um, that's what they're seeing. And it's no coincidence that
the matrix movie we're talking about, I mean, the code rain, that famous green running digital
imagery that's built from Japanese katakana. So that seems like a little bit on the nose there,
a little bit. So no, I don't think, I think it doesn't make any sense to me is, is the broad thing.
And I also think the problem is that lasers, it's an inconvenient coincidence, shall we say,
that when you shine a laser on a wall without DMT, um, uh, it exhibits some very unusual optical
effects. So it forms this interference pattern, um, on the retina that looks like kind of a matrix
of speckles or matrix of points of light that can appear to extend beyond the surface. This is all
without DMT. Now, when you add DMT to the mix, you see this matrix of characters and geometric
forms that appear to extend well beyond the surface. And you have to believe that these
are completely unrelated. That's just a coincidence. If you are to accept that you're seeing actual code
here. Um, so I think my working hypothesis, which might well be wrong, uh, is that, but needs to be
eliminated, uh, is that this, these, this matrix of sensory and you've basically got a matrix of
points of light, which on the retina, which act like a sensory scaffold around which in the,
on the influence of DMT, you, you see complex forms and characters because characters are very common
in the DMT space, uh, as are complex geometric structures. So I think it's a very interesting,
fascinating phenomenon and very important one in that it allows you to isolate a particular
fragment of the broader DMT phenomenology, the, the, the, the reporting of code and geometric,
uh, forms that I will get on board with. Uh, I think it should be studied. Do I accept,
do I think that it, that fundamental code that is somehow stumbled upon, um, the, the, the way,
a way of seeing this fundamental code of reality, which just happens to look like code, uh, as we
would imagine code. I mean, you imagine code, you imagine the matrix and that's kind of what
it's looking at here. I think I'm not ready to make that leap yet.
Yeah. That, that seems unlikely to me too. I think the thing that is interesting about it is you are doing
a repeatable physical thing and then people see, you know, ostensibly similar, you know,
a similar phenomena in the form of whatever these symbols are, whatever, which is like, that's cool.
I mean, even that is sort of somewhat unprecedented.
Yes. But then again, the, the, the laser light is providing a very regular pattern of sensory
inputs. Sure. Um, so that account and the fact that these, but you don't see the symbols when
you're not on DMT, right? You don't see this. Exactly. Exactly. So that's cool. That's interesting.
That's interesting. Yeah. Um, but then again, are people seeing, people say the line that you
always hear from these, these laser people is, uh, everyone sees exactly the same thing.
Hmm. Now, what does that mean that everyone sees code or everyone sees characters? Fine. Does
everyone see exactly the same characters in the same order at the same time? No, we don't know
that. There's no way no one's demonstrated that it's not even possible. It's not even known if that's
possible because they apparently they move very, very quickly. So are people seeing the same thing or
are people kind of seeing the sort of the same thing? But because again, the language problem,
um, I can't take a, you can't take a photograph of this code. And so you can't compare, you have to
rely on language and you have to rely on little sketches and things that people do. But, but there's
no way so far to demonstrate that two people, even at the same time, are actually seeing exactly the
same code. Uh, and people, as I said, people have been describing code and digits and characters, uh, in, uh,
in the DMT state for four decades. So it's like, what's unique and interesting and important about
this is that it allows you to kind of isolate that particular aspect of, and reliably, uh, uh, view
that particular aspect of, of the broader DMT visual phenomenology. Uh, but anything beyond that to make,
you know, deeper, deep conclusions about the fundamental structure of our reality, that you're
seeing the code that runs our reality, I think that is a very, very large, uh, leap. And I don't think
there's any, uh, there's nothing in the, the effect, the phenomenon that would, would lead one to draw that
conclusion. You have to start by eliminating lots of other more mundane hypotheses, which takes time.
It takes money. It takes very careful experimental setup and, you know, performing of various
experiments to be able to eliminate, um, the influence of this laser interference speckle effect,
as it's called. Uh, but that needs to be done because otherwise it's going to be private revelation.
They're going to be people who do it and believe, and they're going to form a group, um, who all
believe in this, but they have no, they're not able to demonstrate or prove that this is what
they are actually seeing, but they all are, have convinced themselves. That's what they're seeing.
They're seeing the fundamental code of reality. And you, you'd get, it forms a kind of religion,
if you like, uh, where you have the believers and you have the non-believers. Um, I'm not ready to
kind of fall in with, with the believers just yet. Yeah. Well, what do you think of modern, uh,
UFO disclosure? Do you track that at all? Do you think it reduces down to these sort of altered
states of consciousness or do you believe we have saucers and, you know, hangers at places like Area
51? Well, I mean, the Area 51, I mean, that's cool stuff, right? I mean, I don't, I'm not an expert
on it, so I don't, I follow certain things, right? When Bob Lazar speaks when he's on Rogan, I watched
that. I thought it was fascinating stuff, but I don't know. I don't know what to make of it all.
Um, um, and so I kind of focus on my thing. My thing is the, not the, the shimmering metallic
discs in the sky, which might not be physical, of course. I mean, they might also be, they also
seem to kind of occupy this space between the physical and the non-physical, the forming feats that
seem to be, um, beyond what a physical object could achieve. And I think that's perhaps gives
us a clue as to their nature. And, and we might be dealing with intelligences that don't necessarily
exist, you know, as physical wet-bodied beings on other star systems and are traveling through
vast distances to reach our planet, but actually occupy some kind of space that is lying parallel,
hidden within amongst whatever orthogonal to whatever our reality, and that they can interface
in certain ways with our, or physics is information theoretic, like you write about, you know,
John Wheeler or whatever. And, you know, a bunch of people sort of contemplate, if you have all this,
like a Wolfram physics and stuff, computational physics, then what if they are just the programmers
of our reality? Like they, they, they, they understand the source code in a way that we know.
Exactly. And there's a lot in physics that kind of points to that. There's like,
you know, you have, um, what, like Heisenberg's uncertainty principle where, you know, you can't
measure position and momentum, you know, simultaneously in very accurate ways. Like one gets more fuzzy as
the other gets more accurate. That almost looks like a, like a computational caching function or
something where only so much can be stored in local memory, you know, or like anthropic principle
where if Plank's constant were slightly different, like we wouldn't really have an atmosphere on it.
Like there are all these sort of weird Goldilocks or like Fermat's theory where like, you know,
light between two, you know, points or whatever, it takes the most optimal computationally efficient
path. There are all these things like that. Fibonacci sequences and golden ratios and stuff.
It's like, well, how do people code? They just transport, you know, code library. I mean,
now it's probably mostly like co-pilots and AI, but you know, back in the day it was like,
you'd like find like libraries of code and you would, you know, you'd transport code chunks or
whatever. And like, that's how they, so it's like, you would reuse geometrically efficient patterns,
like over and over again, like that's just exists like across nature. Exactly. So there's so much
in the brain as well. I mean, the brain again, is this, you have these repeating computational,
the fundamental, these columns, you know, the brain, it's like this, the cortex, you have all
of these cylindrical columns, which is the basic computational unit of the brain and you stitch
them all together. Um, and, and all of the, the, the function, uh, of your, of your cortex arises
from the interaction of all these basic, uh, computational units. So it's at every level,
at every level you see that, uh, of stitching together of, of, of simpler units that from which
higher order behaviors emerge. And that goes all the way down perhaps to the ground of reality itself.
Yeah. And you have these very simple rules, um, you know, and it might, you know, running a universe
might be extremely simple if you know the rules. Yeah. Or if you find a way to run all possible,
this is something I explore in alien information theory, the idea that if you, if you, if you know,
all possible rules, which is just, you know, the permutation on all possible rule, all possible
rule sets, you just run them all. You have the computational power, you run all of them. And
some, most of them do absolutely nothing. Some of them do something a little bit interesting and
then die out. And then maybe a tiny, tiny fraction, um, you start to develop layered complexity,
emergent complexity. And we just happen to be in one of those hundred trillion trillion or whatever
universes where, where the rule set gives rise to interesting information.
Yeah. Well, Wolfram has this, you know, Stephen Wolfram has this sort of institute where he studies
these computational versions of physics, and he has this idea of computational irreducibility.
And there are things that you cannot take as first principle, you know, a priori concepts.
You need to run a program in order to get that result. And you have cellular automata,
Yeah. Conway's game of life and all of these things where if you set some initial conditions,
yeah, maybe you end up with some final branch that works or whatever, but like,
there are a lot of branches that don't. Um, and then you have to ask this like meta question of if,
you know, is our earthly conflict, you know, Trump just took out, you know, uh, uh, three, uh,
Iranian nuclear sites with, with, you know, some B2s is all of that existing, you know,
against some sub Rosa backdrop of like some timeline adjustment conflict or something.
Like, is that the true cosmic, you know, that like Upanishad style war or whatever,
where, you know, if you really think about like, what's the most scarce commodity, it's not gold.
It's not like, like, you know, the last 50 years of American foreign policy has been like sort of
dictated by like, you know, crude oil or whatever. Like, it's not those things, right? It's, uh, it's
time. Yeah. And it's timelines and it's like literal, like, you know, macro, like events that,
that occur on, on, on macro scales. So like, is, are these entities sort of fighting over that or
something? It's answer that question now. I don't know. Yeah. Yeah. Who knows? Well,
thank you so much for, uh, I'm just going to end on that absurd question. Thank you. I really
appreciate this man. And I, I, everybody should go buy your book, death by astonishment and anything
else you want to plug or promote or. Yeah. I mean, so death by astonishment, that's the book about
DMT and describes the history of science has struggled to make sense of it. So if you're
really interested in what DMT is about and why it's such a enigmatic and mysterious molecule,
read death by astonishment, but also if you're anyone who's interested in DMT X, uh, the moment,
it's like, it's a small number of academic institutions that are running DMT X, but we
actually are developing a retreat center and a research center in the Caribbean. What's it? St.
Vincent and the Grenadines. That's it. Um, so we have a re research center and retreat center
that we're developing now. Um, and the idea being it's not just doing research with DMT,
but also allowing anyone who wants to, to come and experience DMT X, uh, in a beautiful tropical,
you know, five-star environment with all of the preparation, uh, perhaps several different doses
do at those levels before the, the kind of the breakthrough DMT X experience, all of the setting
is just beautiful in the integration afterwards. It will be a unique institute. Do you have any
adverse experiences with DMT X? Anybody? So far, so far, um, all of the subjects at Imperial College
got through it. Um, there was no major problem. It was very intense. Yeah. Um, maybe some of them
didn't kind of like it and didn't do the full set of, of experiments, but no, like severe, you know,
physiological adverse effects. And I mean, of course we've no severe mental, no, like this really
fucked me up. Nothing like that. And of course on the island, we will have anesthesiologists,
we have psychiatrists and nurses. Uh, so if people want to sign up, they can go to newnautics.org,
n-double-o-n-a-u-t-i-c-s, newnautics.org. Uh, and they can find out, uh, uh, uh, more about it
there or a lucid mind. So lucid is the actual name of the, um, um, of the retreat. So it's like,
that's bringing the new elusis, the new elusis. Uh, yeah. So elusismind.com and they can also,
you know, have a look at what the retreat center is going to look like. So, so yeah,
that's kind of an exciting thing to be able to, to kind of bring DMTX to anyone who wants to kind
of experience it. Super cool and exciting. It's funny. I think, you know, Albert Hoffman,
who discovered LSD, Stanislav Grof and Carl Ruck all, maybe this is a rumor, but I think they wanted to
create a new elusis. And so it's cool that you're naming it that. Yes. It won't be with ergot. Uh,
but we do have a weird, we have a license from the government, uh, in the St. Vincent and the
Grenadines to work with any drug that we want. So we, so it's not implausible that we might think
about, you know, uh, you know, ergot alkaloids and perhaps recreating, um, the, the true illusinium
mysteries. And there are people now working on actually reconstructing that and trying to work out
the exact chemistry involved. I think Brian Orescu is really trying to, that's a sort of follow-up
journey. Exactly. And there are people that followed on from his work as well, chemists and
pharmacologists. So it's, it's an exciting time to be interested in psychedelics and an exciting,
very interesting time to be alive more generally, of course, but I agree. Everything's spinning out
and getting weird, but it's interesting. Um, okay, Andrew, I really appreciate this man. This is a lot of
fun and, um, go by death by astonishment and alien information theory. And, uh, yeah, hopefully we
can do this again at some point. Awesome. Awesome. Thank you. Thank you.