You have to take seriously this claim on the part of the Nazi leadership
that they wanted a thousand-year Reich.
A thousand-year imperium is no joke.
Perhaps the best-known abduction of all, and one of the earliest reported,
is the abduction of a well-respected New England couple, Betty and Barney Hill.
Look back at Barney Hill's original statements.
The evil face, he looks like a German Nazi.
Mankind has been seeking knowledge.
Alan Dulles and his brother, John Foster Dulles,
together with JPMorgan Chase and Rockefeller, funded the rise of the Nazis.
Is the implication that there's some sort of Nazi sleeper cell
undergirding American politics today?
So World War II is not what we think it is.
They were seeing these rocket-like things that were saucer-shaped,
being launched from Spain, the Mediterranean coast, over toward America.
Really?
One year later, what happens?
Roswell.
I mean, is the idea that there is some sort of, like,
Atlantean surviving remnant group that's still there?
So for all we know, what's happening is that a future state of a certain culture
is contacting itself in the past.
Trying to pull the timeline towards itself or something.
To actualize itself.
Trantemporally actualize itself.
Jason Reza-Giorjani, back by Popular Demand.
Thank you so much for coming on.
And, you know, we just launched an episode,
and people are absolutely loving it.
So check that out, part one.
But there's so many other threads I wanted to get into,
and I left that conversation thinking that there was a lot that was left kind of unsaid,
and we could have gone on for hours.
So I'm very excited to do this.
You're one of the few thinkers I know who doesn't just sort of know a bunch of random disparate facts
around the phenomenon, but tries to piece them together into some sort of coherent worldview,
which is kind of a Herculean task.
But you're attempting to do that, and I can't think of too many other—
I mean, Jacques Vallée might be another one,
but there aren't too many thinkers trying to do that.
So this is very cool.
Thank you.
You know, that made me think of something that actually, you know,
would probably be a good preface to this conversation,
because I think that one of the most significant crises that we face in our civilization,
and, you know, in the world at large, is the decline of philosophy.
The reduction of philosophy to academic scholasticism and logic chopping and the lack of deep, serious, broad-spectrum thinking
that would be capable of, for example, tackling the close-encounter phenomenon, right?
I mean, obviously, it should be philosophers who are engaging, both with the data of close encounters
and parapsychological data.
In fact, you know, there were people in philosophy who played a fundamental role in development of parapsychology at its outset.
Both William James and Henri Bergson were among the founding parapsychologists in the era of psychical research.
In fact, William James was the president of the Society for Psychical Research in the 1870s.
And Bergson was as well later on.
I didn't know that.
Either the 1910s or something like that.
There you go.
And this is a time when parapsychology wasn't relegated to quacky circles and, you know, new-agey conferences.
Bergson was debating Einstein at the time, and so he was considered a worthy debate partner for Einstein,
who himself wasn't, you know, fully accepted by mainstream science, but was very well-respected.
Yes, and James had predicted...
...in the era when he was the president of the Society for Psychical Research that this would be the next great scientific revolution, right?
What I, in my writings, have called the spectral revolution.
And it didn't happen.
And, you know, in my first book, Prometheus and Atlas, I ventured a, you know, a basically theory of why it didn't happen.
And that's because of the extremely serious psychological and sociological implications of mainstream acceptance of things like telepathy, precognition, clairvoyance, and so forth.
And so, you know, it's not only essential for philosophers to engage with the ontological and epistemological questions inherent in parapsychological data or close encounter phenomena,
but also the ethical and political ramifications.
And this brings me to what I wanted to say in response to your opening, which is that I've made an argument now in several of my books
that it's definitional to the type of the philosopher to develop concepts that cut across all of the major domains of philosophy,
from ontology and epistemology to then an ethics and a politics that follow from that ontological and epistemic thinking.
And then also, I think aesthetics is very important.
From the time of Plato onward, there's been this idea that the cultivation of aesthetic discernment
and the capacity to perceive the beautiful or the sublime is also another pathway to knowledge
and perhaps to a kind of knowledge that transcends or undergirds reductive rationality, right?
And in particular, I think that aesthetic judgment is very closely connected to ethics.
And it's something that, you know, Nietzsche understood, Friedrich Nietzsche understood very well.
Yeah, he says, I think there's some quote, I'm going to butcher it, but it's like,
life is only eternally justified in its aesthetic form or something.
And he, yeah, he fully believed that.
And Nietzsche wasn't alone.
I mean, look, if you, I mean, Kant is well known for being a very principled, hyper-rational advocate
of this crystalline universal ethics.
But if you ask me, Kant's most interesting work is his aesthetic work.
And it's in his aesthetics and his third critique, critique of judgment,
that you can see the connection between Kant's interest in the occult
and Kant's development of this universal ethics.
Then, for example, Hegel has an entire account of how you can see the evolution of human consciousness
or what he called spirit through changes in aesthetic styles, changes in, you know,
artistic expression from epoch to epoch and how they reflect the evolution of the perceptive
and cognitive capacities of humanity.
So, okay, my point is that to be a philosopher, you really have to be thinking across all of these domains
and developing concepts that cut across them, above all, because you cannot have any unquestioned presuppositions.
So, you could be the most brilliant, let's say, metaphysician, right?
And someone who's developing a very rigorous epistemology.
But if you have unquestioned political presuppositions,
it's going to be tacitly warping your ontology and epistemology.
And if you want to really be a philosopher, you know, which is to say someone who from the era of Socrates onward
was defined by boundless, limitless, and thorough-going questioning,
you really cannot give yourself the luxury of unquestioned assumptions in any area, right?
So, I mean, this has very serious implications for religion, obviously,
because it means that it's definitional to a philosopher that he or she,
I consider Ayn Rand, for example, to be a real philosopher in this sense,
he or she cannot accept any religion.
It is definitional to a philosopher that you cannot adhere to a religious belief system.
I mean, you are crippling yourself and you are, you know,
you're basically capacity to question and develop concepts from the outset
if you have any kind of a religious commitment.
Would you say St. Thomas Aquinas, not a philosopher?
Exactly.
So, the entirety of medieval European philosophy is not philosophy.
And none of these people were philosophers.
And also, in Iran, you know, I spent a lot of time
both studying Iran and also making significant contributions to Iranian studies.
My book, Iranian Leviathan, is a tome on the history of Iran
from Zarathustra to the Islamic Republic.
And so, what this also means is that this whole era that's misnamed the Islamic Golden Age,
which really was like an Iranian renaissance from the 900s to the 1100s,
really doesn't have very many philosophers involved with it.
Because these people were essentially Islamic theologians of the type of Thomas Aquinas.
Like, for example, Al-Farabi.
Al-Farabi goes to the extent of equating Muhammad with Plato's ideal of the philosopher king,
which is an absolute travesty.
The only thinkers in that era that really exemplified the type of the philosopher
were, for example, Razi, whose writings almost completely were destroyed
by various, you know, inquisitors later on,
once the Turks came in and re-solidified Islam in Iran.
And maybe Shahab al-Din Sohra Verdi.
But it means that that whole period in Iran,
very much like Europeans' medieval so-called philosophy,
really doesn't pass muster.
But why am I getting into all this?
The point is that it seems almost as if we're entering another dark age now.
With the lack of substantive philosophical thinking and fewer and fewer individuals
who really pass muster as exemplary of the type of the philosopher
in the way that, let's say, in the 20th century,
we had Martin Heidegger, Jean-Paul Sartre,
Ludwig Wittgenstein, and other really deep thinkers.
So a philosopher can't be an extension of state power or religious power
is sort of what you're getting.
I mean, to play devil's advocate,
you have philosophers like Leo Strauss, also mid-
Not a philosopher.
So you'd say not a philosopher.
Strauss said so.
Strauss literally said,
I am not a philosopher.
Do not call me a philosopher.
I'm a professor of philosophy and a political thinker.
But in Straussian doublespeak, that could mean I am a philosopher.
He meant it.
And the more shocking thing that Strauss said was,
at the same time as he made the statement,
he said Martin Heidegger is the only living philosopher.
Which coming from out of the mouth of a Jew is quite a striking statement, right?
I mean, Heidegger having been a high-level Nazi functionary.
But wouldn't a Straussian read on many past philosophers be that
many of them had to exceed to kind of the conventional thought of the time,
but then secretly they could hold their own kind of heretical beliefs.
So like, you know, I'm trying to think of a good example.
Like, it was, you know, one of the Enlightenment era, you know,
Francis Bacon, not really a philosopher, kind of a philosopher.
But like, you know, he would say things like, you know,
we need empiricism to prove out God's secrets or to, you know,
understand the divine nature of the world and reality.
And the Straussian read on that is like, he's sort of a deist or an atheist,
and he doesn't believe in God at all.
And he's just sort of, you know, placating and paying lip service to,
you know, the establishment power.
Well, I think that through careful study, that could be verified.
So you brought up the case of Francis Bacon.
There is a theory that Will I Am Sheikh Spear is a pen name for Sir Francis Bacon.
People think that, yeah.
Now, if someone were to engage in an exhaustive philosophical analysis
of the works of Shakespeare and be able to prove that that was indeed
a literary persona of Sir Francis Bacon,
then I think a very good case could be made that Francis Bacon
was a first-rate philosopher because there's an ethics,
there's a political philosophy in Shakespeare, you know,
and you could reconstruct that.
So that would be a case of an actual philosopher
engaging in esoteric writing in order to express the full range of his thoughts.
Do you believe that Shakespeare was, in fact, Francis Bacon?
I think it's possible.
I think there's an argument there.
I don't have the range of Shakespeare scholarship
or anywhere close to it to be able to assess that.
I think it was like, you know, there are all these kind of occult references,
like in King Lear or something, like these, you know,
things were, forgot the exact argument.
But it was like, Stratford-Upon-Avon wasn't super far from where Bacon was.
And then, you know, all these things are mentioned like 33 times.
And who knows?
I mean, look, it's clearly...
Bacon was prolific, you know.
Will I am.
I am Will.
You know, the Will.
I'm the Will.
Shake Spear.
The shaking of the spear, right?
It's clearly a pseudonym.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
For someone who was an incredible genius.
So who the hell was that guy, like at that time, who was living and, you know,
who maybe expressed his genius in other ways, as in the scientific writings of Bacon.
And then there's the new Atlantis.
Yeah, yeah.
So anyway, it could be...
Look, my point is this, that that's one thing.
But if you're a philosopher who's...
Let me rephrase that.
If you're a metaphysician who's afraid to express a political philosophy
because you might be persecuted by the religious authorities of the day
and you just don't put pen to paper, you know, in any way,
even let's say as a set of secret writings
that you consign to somebody to be posthumously published,
if you just never put pen to paper to express any kind of coherent political philosophy
or ethics that follows from your ontology and epistemology,
you're not a philosopher.
You're a coward.
Okay?
And so, for example, in Iran, we had an example of somebody like that
was Ebnesina, or as they call him Avicenna in the West.
Great metaphysician.
Maybe he has some ethics,
but he did not develop a coherent political philosophy,
which, as I see it, disqualifies him as the type of the philosopher.
And he made a deathbed confession.
When we first started selling merchandise at AmericanAlchemyMerch.com,
we had no idea how complicated and annoying selling merch could be.
We talked to a dozen different platforms and companies,
comparing shipping tools, payment options, website builders,
and it all felt like way more of a headache and complicated than it should be.
We decided on Shopify, and within days, our store was up.
Everything was running cleanly in an automated way,
so we could just focus on the brand and the vision we had for it.
That's when it hit us.
Ideas don't scale on inspiration alone.
They need a structure, a container.
Shopify provides that structure.
It quietly powers millions of creators and brands,
about 10% of all United States e-commerce.
From big names like Gymshark and Mattel,
to solo creators building from their bedrooms.
Shopify made it simple to build a store that actually feels authentic to us,
which matters when your brand lives in a niche like alternative tech, UFOs, or fringe science,
and when you have a very clear brand vision.
Plus, their AI tools help write descriptions, organize products, even clean up photos,
so we can focus on what matters and what we care about,
building the best custom merch line possible with the coolest designs,
like our UFO cowboy tee and the Atomic Age tee.
Plus, Shopify handles all of the unglamorous, more painful stuff.
Shipping, returns, email marketing, all in one clean dashboard.
It's like having a silent partner who never sleeps.
Our favorite part of the product is the dashboard,
which gives us complete demographic information.
We can see where our orders come from,
making it easy to know who our most loyal, consistent customers are around the world.
That's just one example, but Shopify really makes your life easier.
Bring your next idea to life,
with Shopify quietly handling everything behind it.
Sign up for your $1 per month trial and start today at shopify.com slash jesse.
Again, that's shopify.com slash jesse, J-E-S-S-E,
for a $1 a month trial.
Again, that's just $1 a month to try Shopify,
the state-of-the-art solution in e-commerce.
Saying that, you know, these bastard Islamic clerics
have made it impossible to think freely in this country.
And that I had to basically dissimulate and warp all of my ideas
and my writings out of constant fear of persecution by the authorities.
So he did say that before he died.
Okay.
To be a philosopher, you have to risk that.
And you have to be willing to be turned into a human torch
like Giordano Bruno in the town square of Rome
or Socrates or Pythagoras,
who had his schools burned down in his own lifetime, right?
Oh, I didn't know that about Pythagoras.
Yeah.
I mean, some say he died in the fires.
Others say he barely escaped with his life
and died from injuries shortly thereafter.
But Pythagoras was the first one to be martyred
in the history of philosophy.
And then Socrates.
And then they almost killed that.
Both Plato and Aristotle.
Plato went to Syracuse
to try to convince this tyrant Dionysus
to become a philosopher king,
as he had, you know, outlined in Republic.
And basically the entire court of Syracuse conspired against Plato
and he had to escape by boat in the middle of the night,
narrowly escaped with his life.
And then Aristotle willingly left Athens
because there was a plot to have him prosecuted also.
So this is endemic to the history of philosophy.
Was this pre-tutoring Alexander the Great?
Or post?
It was pre-
Because Alexander was younger, right?
And they say, by the way out,
that Alexander didn't like Aristotle.
Really?
Yeah.
Why didn't he like him?
Aristotle ran a think tank
in addition to being like a philosopher,
you know, engaged in his own individual exploration
and contemplation.
He had essentially like the prototype of the Rand Corporation
in classical Greece.
And various other city-states would come to him
and he would write their constitutions for them secretly.
You know, you don't want to tell your people that
their constitution comes from some guy's think tank in Athens.
If you're living in Corinth or, you know, Sparta or whatever.
But they would come to him and he would write this guy.
And part of his political philosophy
that informed his writing constitutions for various city-states
was that we should always have a political pluriverse.
He was very much against one unifying government.
Aristotle was the first serious thinker
to critique the idea of world government.
And so, for example, he was very wary of the Persians
who wanted to establish a kind of, you know,
humanistic one world order, right?
Well, Alexander actually had great reverence for the Persians.
In particular, his hero was Cyrus the Great,
the founder of the Persian Empire.
The first thing he did when he got to Iran
was he had them take him to the tomb of Cyrus
so that he could pay his respects to Cyrus the Great.
And eventually, Alexander became convinced
that the Persians had the right worldview
and that the whole Earth and all of its cultures
should be unified into a single cosmopolitan order,
which eventually was reflected in the culture
of the city of Alexandria that was named after him in Egypt.
It became like the cosmopolitan bastion of the world, right?
So this is diametrically opposed to Aristotle's thinking.
You know, Alexander becomes the exemplar
of the idea of the one world order
and, you know, Aristotle is the first critic of it.
That's so fascinating when things like that happen.
A modern example of that would be like
George Soros and Victor Orban,
who's kind of a mentee and mentor.
And like Soros is obviously all about
spreading as much democracy as possible.
Orban was kind of his understudy.
And then now, you know, it's totally split off
and is, you know, basically the tip of the spear
when it comes to European nationalism.
Yeah.
And, you know, it almost feels Shakespearean in some ways.
Now, that's the other thing about
the type of the philosopher,
which is very dangerous,
is the relationship between the philosopher and the state.
Because, frankly,
you cannot be a nationalist and be a philosopher.
Okay?
So any philosopher who seems like a nationalist,
like, say, Martin Heidegger, right?
Who literally was, you know, a Nazi functionary.
Mm-hmm.
They're engaging in,
I was about to say Straussian,
rather in platonic dissimulation
and some kind of a noble lie.
So do you think Heidegger was not a real philosopher?
No, Heidegger was not a real nationalist.
Was not a real nationalist.
Yeah, and when you study Heidegger deeply,
you see that.
It's very clear.
Mm-hmm.
But only to someone with an esoteric eye for it
and who can sync together with him on a deep level
and understand what he's really saying.
Mm-hmm.
Right?
So he was trying to use the German state
in a certain way
that had to do with his understanding
of the threat posed to humanity
by modern technology
and a way that he thought
that the German state could be shaped
to confront the instrumentalizing
and mechanizing threat of modern technology,
to shepherd technological development
in a certain direction
that would prevent the instrumentalization
of humanity and our alienation
from our existential essence, right?
So, but the deeper question is this,
like, I mean, Socrates was executed
by the Athenian state, right?
And in his discourse on the arts and sciences,
Jean-Jacques Rousseau says that the Athenians
were justified in doing this
because the guy was a menace to the social order
and to the political cohesion of Athens
and that any thinker has to basically reconcile himself
to the sovereignty of the state
and to, like, basically accommodating the social order, right?
So Rousseau actually thinks the philosophers, you know,
pose this, like, fundamental, you know,
inimical challenge to state power.
And I think that on some level he's right.
But the irony also is that,
especially in grave crises
and what Carl Schmitt called states of emergency,
I think it's also the philosophers of a people
who can save a people.
You know, a nation that lacks a philosopher
or lacks deep thinkers in a moment of grave crisis
is not going to make it.
No, that feels very right to me.
And it feels like the modern world has very few.
I think of big philosophers today
and that, you know, you're sort of one of them
and then you have, you know, guys like Slavoj Zizek or whatever
who's, you know, super too postmodern for my taste,
but, you know, he's at least attempting.
And then, I don't know, even Jordan Peterson in my mind
who I think he sort of falls prey to,
it's like narcissism of small differences
between him and postmodernism
because I think his stuff sort of melts
into a postmodern gobbledygook or whatever.
But he's trying.
He's, you know, read all the right stuff or whatever.
But there are very few philosophers who are very ambitious.
You know, I think most philosophy professors at universities
just give you these very conventional kind of lame,
limited by modern epistemics reads
of these past philosophers.
And you're sort of supposed to,
there's a great actually essay by Nietzsche
called On History.
And he talks about undigested stones of knowledge.
And it feels like that's what they're just,
they're just passing on these undigested stones of knowledge.
They're not actually processing
any of what they're saying.
Yes.
And that essay, that's incredibly important essay.
It became fundamental to Heidegger's thinking.
And Heidegger basically quotes it
at the beginning of being in time.
And it also has become very important to my work.
In particular, that book, Iranian Leviathan,
that I mentioned, the subtitle is
A Monumental History of Mithra's Abode.
And that term monumental history
is from that essay of Nietzsche,
The Uses and Abuses of History for Life.
And he basically says that there's three modes of history.
One is antiquarian history,
which is what traditionalists do,
where they glorify the past, right?
And like the ultimate form of this
is the Hindu or ancient Greek worldview
where there was a golden age
and then it decayed into a silver age
and a bronze age and so on.
And so history is declining, right?
And all we can do is try to hold on
to fragments of the past,
to the better days,
and to preserve as much of our heritage as possible.
I mean, it's conservatism
in an ontological sense.
Then there's critical history,
which is what these Pomo people do.
Like you're just mentioning Zizek, right?
Zizek is like, you know, probably, yeah,
the greatest living exemplar
of postmodern philosophy, right?
And critical history is all about
deconstructing power structures
and showing how basically every institution
and even every structure of knowledge
was ultimately the product of a power game
that somebody was playing
and that it benefits either some class interest
or institutional interest
or, you know, is a product of rivalry
between nations or ethnicities
and so on and so forth.
And that it's all oppressive
and it should all be deconstructed.
It's like pouring acid on history
and the achievements of all people
throughout time, right?
And Nietzsche says,
okay, to be fair,
under really oppressive conditions
that are resulting in social sterility
and that are hampering innovation
and novel cultural development,
a little bit of critical history
is a good thing
because it breaks up ossified structures
and it allows creativity
to be unleashed again, right?
So Michel Foucault is a great example.
Michel Foucault is the ultimate critical historian.
I mean, that was basically his project.
Everything's a power game.
Yeah.
And with all these histories that he engaged in,
including history of sexuality,
you know, history of the prison system,
history of psychology,
and that sort of thing.
Then, in his own personal life,
he sort of, you know,
was kind of a pervert, to be honest.
And I think it was kind of an expression
of the morality that comes from that kind of work.
I'll tell you what's also an expression of that
is that Foucault endorsed Ayatollah Khomeini
and the Islamic revolution in Iran.
I mean, how lost do you have to be
in postmodern nonsense
that you think it's a liberation
to help a misogynistic,
theocratic, repressive regime come to power, right?
Anyway, so that's critical history.
And then the last modality of history
that Nietzsche discusses in that essay,
which is the one that he personally embraces
and that I have,
and that's been very important to my work,
is monumental history,
which is the idea that
monumentalizing
certain past achievements,
turning certain historical figures into icons
that can continue to provide inspiration,
and having essentially a folkloric approach
to one's heritage
so that it doesn't become an ossified tradition,
but it becomes a source of inspiration
where you can dynamically adopt
and adapt your heritage for future development.
That's vital to the life of a people.
And he says that it's like, you know,
a tree whose branches can only grow
toward the sun of destiny
if it's deeply rooted in the earth
and its roots are healthy underground.
And that underground is the subconscious.
It's that, you know,
monumental history is nourished
from out of the subconscious.
And not everything in the past of a people
has to be or should be
rationally dissected and understood
that we need to maintain
a kind of subconscious connection
to the mythic substratum
of our heritage
as a wellspring for continued creativity,
both in the arts and the sciences.
Yeah, I love that.
He's so inspiring when you read him.
I like, you know,
he seems very irrational
and kind of iconoclastic
and maybe a little crazy,
you know, in his personal life and stuff.
And Nietzsche was almost
like the first incel or something.
But he was also just so inspiring.
You read his work
and it's full of vitality and life.
So it felt like this weird juxtaposition.
You had his, you know,
his kind of personal life,
which he was kind of, you know,
withering away.
And then you have the writing,
which was so vital.
I love him.
I feel a very deep affinity to Nietzsche.
I'd say Plato, Nietzsche, and Heidegger
are probably the three philosophers
who've most deeply impacted my own thinking.
Well, you mentioned the RAND Corporation.
We're in Santa Monica right now
near the RAND Corporation.
I believe RAND stands for R&D,
Research and Development.
It was formed in, I believe,
the mid to late 50s.
One of these sort of federally funded
research and development centers
that was meant to look into
all sorts of issues of national security.
It's kind of a, you know,
it's as when we talk about
the proverbial deep state,
you think of the RAND Corporation
and a man who was offered
to be president of the RAND Corporation.
Some people might not know this
is a past interviewee of mine,
a guy named Harold Malmgren,
who was a senior presidential advisor
for JFK, LBJ, Nixon, and Ford,
and said all sorts of really bombshell stuff
when it came to UFOs,
including he held pieces of a UFO
at Sandia Complex in New Mexico.
It was given to him by Lawrence Preston Geis,
who's Jeff Bezos' maternal grandfather,
which is fascinating.
And he talked about the Magenta crash,
Malmgren did,
and his mentor, Richard Bissell,
who founded Area 51,
briefing him on otherworldly technologies.
Yeah, what else did Richard Bissell tell you?
He said this didn't start last week.
This has been going on,
he mentioned 1933 Magenta.
He did?
Yes.
Richard Bissell mentioned
the 1933 Magenta crash?
Yes, yes.
That's amazing.
So this provided a lot of backup
for David Grush's,
you know, famous UFO whistleblower
who's responsible for a lot
of modern disclosure today.
His testimony around this Magenta crash,
where he came out,
he said that there are covert
American UFO reverse engineering programs,
we have this whole history on this stuff,
but he also said,
he talked about one specific crash,
and it wasn't Roswell,
it was this 1933 Lombardy,
you know, northern Italy crash,
specifically in Magenta, Italy.
1933 was the first recovery in Europe,
in Magenta, Italy.
Italian government moved it
to a secure air base in Italy
for the rest of kind of the fascist regime
until 1944, 1945,
and, you know,
Pope Pius XII back-channeled that.
So the Vatican was involved.
Yeah, and told the Americans
what the Italians had,
and we ended up scooping it.
And you have some interesting connections
that you've made between that
and Nazi prowess in engineering at the time.
As you know,
I'm always on the hunt for things
that help me stay sharp,
focused,
and full of energy
while I'm diving into life's mysteries
and making this show happen.
And I've got to say,
mud water has completely transformed my mornings.
Back in the day,
I used to struggle with that post-coffee crash,
and let's not even get into the caffeine jitters.
Mud water gave me the smooth,
steady energy I was missing.
It's packed with functional mushrooms
like lion's mane, chaga, and reishi,
plus turmeric and cacao,
all working together to keep me focused,
calm, and grounded.
Honestly, it's like coffee went on a yoga retreat
and came back zen.
What I love most is that
it's not just about replacing coffee.
It's a whole new ritual.
It's a simple, nourishing way to start the day.
And I actually look forward to it every morning.
Every ingredient is USDA certified organic,
vegan, non-GMO,
and there's zero sugar.
It's energy that doesn't mess with your sleep
or make you question your life choices at 3 a.m.
Ready to make the switch to cleaner energy?
Head to mudwater.com,
that's M-U-D-W-T-R dot com,
and grab your starter kit today.
Right now, our listeners get an exclusive deal
up to 43% off your entire order,
plus free shipping and a free rechargeable frother
when you use code JESSE.
That's right, up to 43% off with code JESSE
at M-U-D-W-T-R dot com.
After your purchase,
they'll ask you how you found them.
Now, please show your support
and let them know we sent you.
Keep your energy natural and refreshing
all year long with mudwater,
because life's too short for anything less
than clean, delicious energy.
And so, what do you have to say about all that?
Yeah, so as far as I understand it,
the Vatican was informed of it.
The Vatican was informed of it
and has a dossier on it,
and the Vatican was involved in the sort of study
of this object in a joint working group
that involved both SS scientists
and Italian scientists in a third-party country.
So, when I wrote my book, Closer Encounter...
Did he say third-party country?
No, but I know it's a third-party country.
Because that's where the so-called Bell Project
winds up being developed,
namely just outside Prague,
in former Czechoslovakia,
okay, in the Czech Republic.
And so, when I was doing my research
for Closer Encounters,
we did not yet have the testimony
from Rush about Magenta.
I wrote that book in 2021.
It was published in 2021.
So, I studied the Nazi advanced propulsion research
that was going on,
again, at a facility called the Skoda Works
just outside Prague,
under the direction of SS General Hans Kambler.
After Rush made this testimony about Magenta,
I realized why they put it there.
Because if the Italians had found this object,
and at least from one angle,
this was a reverse engineering project,
then it makes sense to have chosen a country
that was neither Italy nor Germany.
The Italians needed the German technical expertise.
They were not going to figure out
what the hell this thing was by themselves.
Even though they'd had some very competent scientists,
but still, they knew that they had to call the Germans in.
And yet, the Germans probably wanted to, you know,
wanted to respect the Italians
by putting this project in a third country
that was neither Germany nor Italy, right?
So, it was sort of a compromise,
access compromise,
to put it in Czechoslovakia.
Now, it's an interesting question.
How much of what they were doing there
was an attempt to reverse engineer
whatever crashed it in Magenta?
And how much of it was a result
of Germans grappling with
some real nuts and bolts practical engineering problems?
So, let me give you an example.
The Saucer airframe very naturally evolved
from German aeronautical engineering.
They were taking very seriously in the 1930s
the problem of aerodynamics and the boundary layer
where a pocket of air resistance forms
around the edges of an aircraft.
And it causes drag and impedes maneuverability.
So, they came up with the idea
of creating a saucer-shaped craft
that would have suction vents all around it
and these suction vents
would basically suck in the boundary layer
and then redirect the air pocket
into the propulsion system
as part of the propulsion system.
And another interesting thing
that they developed in connection
with this problem of suctioning
of the boundary layer
and basically making
a much more aerodynamic aircraft
was they developed
a kind of perforated metal
which later was discovered
at Roswell.
Really?
According to Corso.
And it was a kind of metal
where you could put your hand
on the other side of it
and blow through the metal
and feel your breath on your hand.
A perforated, finely perforated metal.
Do you know the name of this metal?
I think in German it was called Luftschwamm.
Luftschwamm.
Okay, and then Corso.
Flying foam.
And how do we know?
So, then for context, 1947,
famous proverbial, you know,
archetypal UFO crash occurs in Roswell,
which is the home of the 509th
Atomic Bomber Squadron
led by Curtis LeMay.
Sort of makes, you know,
made the Roswell Daily Record,
got popularized actually way later in 1979.
Um, but you're saying
that the metal found there
matches what was discovered
in Nazi Germany?
Some of it.
Now, here's the thing about Roswell,
and we'll come back to this.
Is this what Jesse Marcel handled?
That metal?
I don't know.
Okay.
The memory metal?
Yeah.
Well, certainly memory metal
was found there.
Yes.
Whether these are the same thing
and whether the memory metal
was this perforated metal,
I don't know.
But supposedly that was also found there.
Does Corso say that the perforated metal
that was found at Roswell
matches Nazi?
Um, Joseph Farrell did a study
of Corso's claims
in the day after Roswell
in a book which I believe
is called Saucer, Swastikas, and Psyops.
And he went in detail
into various cutting-edge
German technological innovations
of the 1940s,
particularly military engineering.
And he makes a number
of really significant points
in this regard.
Among the things found at Roswell,
according to Corso,
was Kevlar,
Velcro,
Yes.
night vision,
and fiber optics.
And lasers, I believe.
And lasers.
Yeah.
Every,
this,
I mean,
okay,
I guess space aliens
could be using Kevlar.
Maybe they could be using Velcro too.
But Farrell researched this
and he provides a documentation
that shows that the Germans
had invented every single one
of these in the 1940s.
They were not in common use.
They were not even accessible
to the majority
of the German military.
But they were being tested,
you know,
as sort of cutting-edge
weapons technology,
especially like in the
North African desert
in 1943,
44.
Yeah,
I believe there's,
the first patent
for a transistor
is in Munich
or something
in the,
in the 30s.
So,
yeah.
That's interesting.
Well,
when we went in there,
you know,
to Nazi Germany,
we found that the
German subsidiary
of IBM,
a company called
Dehomag,
was way ahead,
not only of like
all the other American
transistor manufacturers,
but ahead of the
American IBM.
Yeah.
So the German subsidiary
was like developing
transistors that were
much smaller,
like an order of magnitude
smaller than what we had
in the United States.
But this brings up
two really important
questions.
One is what caused
this just general
technological acceleration
in Nazi Germany
in the,
you know,
20s,
30s,
and 40s.
I mean,
really 30s and 40s.
If you think about it,
Hitler took power
in 1933,
which was,
you know,
you have like
10 years to build up
and you get all sorts of,
I mean,
look at V2 rockets
are like,
20,
30 years ahead
of anything
in the West.
You know,
all the Wunderwaffe,
you know,
their fighter jets were,
the Skunk Works
was kind of a response
to the fact that
their fighter jets
were running circles
around ours.
So,
what accounts for that,
A,
and then B,
if they are so advanced
technologically,
why did
the United States
ultimately,
you know,
prevail
and beat them
in World War II?
Well,
that's a subject
that I,
you know,
I hope we can get into
in some level of detail.
I wonder if,
if I should flesh out
a couple more things
about the engineering
at the Skunk Works
before we then
come back to this
and really dive into it
head on.
So,
they were developing
these saucer airframes
with suction vents
and so on and so forth.
but these were rocket powered.
They had rotating rockets
underneath
these saucer shaped craft.
Rotating rockets?
Yeah,
like,
um,
a series of
jet,
jets,
like put in a,
in like in a fan formation,
uh,
to basically maneuver
these saucer shaped craft
in various directions.
So,
it was a jet aircraft
in other words.
It was a saucer shaped
rocket powered aircraft.
Then,
parallel to this
saucer airframe project,
there was another project
which,
uh,
when I did my research
in Closer Encounters
working from
Joseph Farrell
and,
um,
Nick Cook's book,
The Hunt for Zero Point,
Nick Cook's research.
Yeah.
And then,
also his citations
of Igor Witkowski's research,
Polish researcher
who actually went
to this site
and,
and did some field work there.
Uh,
I assumed that this project,
based on those researchers,
I assumed that this project
began like in the early 1940s.
I've since been informed
by somebody
who had relatively
direct knowledge,
somebody in Serbia,
that it went back
to 1937.
Who's this person?
Um,
I don't want to mention
the person,
his name,
but they,
they're a very old person
who was involved
with some of these individuals
back in the day
in Central and Eastern Europe.
Interesting.
And,
so it,
from what I hear from him,
it started in 1937
and this was a project
to basically develop,
uh,
originally their aim
was to develop
a new power source,
a power plant.
Mm.
Involving the
electromagnetic
rotation of
mercury
and thorium.
Yep.
So,
I think it's
thorium
232,
if I remember
correctly,
mixed with a certain
isotope of
mercury.
Mm-hmm.
And the reason
for mixing it
with mercury
is that
mercury
is
electromagnetically
reactive.
Mm-hmm.
So,
if you want to
rotate the thorium
using electromagnets,
mixing the thorium
with mercury
allows you
to rotate
the thorium
very effectively.
Mm-hmm.
Create thorium
torsion.
Mm-hmm.
And,
this device
would be
continuously powered
by alternating current
and intermittently
shocked with
very high voltage
direct current.
Mm-hmm.
And basically,
what it did was
it would create
a,
a kind of
plasma fusion
from out of which
tremendous energy
flowed.
Mm-hmm.
So,
so it was a
over-unity device
where you would be
putting a certain
amount of energy
into it,
both AC and DC,
but then the nuclear
reaction of the thorium
due to
electromagnetic torsion
would produce
more energy
than was being
put into the device.
Is he high conviction
that that's,
I mean,
so you're saying
this sort of,
they had like a
zero-point energy device?
Yes.
Because that's,
That's the idea.
That's what
Witkowski,
Nick Cook,
and Joseph Farrell
are all saying,
looking at the
Bell Project.
Well,
Nick Cook,
so yeah,
a lot of his stuff
came from Witkowski
and it's amazing.
I mean,
he takes the
little boat ride
and they go
underground
and you can see
the rig
where Die Glocke was,
so it was definitely
a real project
and Hans Kammler
was a,
you know,
very real guy.
He had,
you know,
control of,
of Skoda Works,
which was kind of
the really black world,
you know,
exciting projects
going on as opposed
to kind of
the white world,
you know,
Heisenberg nuclear
project.
But there are all
sorts of rumors
about Die Glocke.
I mean,
some people say
it was like a time
machine.
When you talk to
Nick Cook,
he gets like a
little uncomfortable
as my read,
almost as if
he knows something
that he like can't
really talk about
or something.
but he'll,
he'll say,
I think it was
a black world
nuclear project.
Over time,
I have come to
conclude that
it was probably
a,
one of several
sites that
the Germans,
the SS in particular,
were using
to look into
nuclear weapons,
nuclear technology.
Which,
I think both of
those things are true.
those things are true
and we can unpack
both of them.
Okay.
So first,
let's start from
the time angle.
Yeah.
You know how
we're always diving
into the edge
of science
and consciousness
on this show?
Lately,
I've been thinking
a lot about aging,
not just in terms
of years,
but in how it
actually feels
in the body.
Slow recovery,
lower energy,
that middle-aged
fog that sneaks
up on you.
I feel like I can
barely go out
and drink alcohol
anymore.
That's why I started
using something
called qualia senolytic
and it's been
a major shift
for me.
Let me explain.
As we age,
our bodies accumulate
what scientists call
senescent
cells,
also known
as zombie cells.
These are worn
out cells
that stop dividing
but don't die.
They hang around
in your body,
draining your energy,
clogging up
your recovery,
and generally
making you feel
older than you are.
Qualia senolytic
is a first-of-its-kind
supplement formulated
with nine plant-based
compounds designed
to help your body
naturally eliminate
these zombie cells.
It's not something
you take every day,
just two days a month,
but it supports
your body
and aging better
at the cellular level.
Since I've started
taking it,
I've felt sharper,
lighter,
and like my body's
resilience has come
back online.
It's vegan,
non-GMO,
and grounded
in serious research.
Experience the science
of feeling younger.
Go to
qualialife.com
slash
jesse
for up to
50% off
your purchase
and use code
jesse,
again,
that's
j-e-s-s-e
for an additional
15% off.
That's
q-u-a-l-i-a
l-i-f-e
dot com
slash
jesse,
j-e-s-s-e
for an extra
15% off
your purchase.
Thanks so much
to Qualia
for sponsoring
this episode.
So I think,
I assume
that,
or let's say
I suspect
that they were
looking for
an incredible
power plant
originally.
But the reason
that a rig
exists
is because
they realized
that this thing
levitates
when you turn it on.
And they had to
chain it down.
And so
this,
whatever
kind of
energy
was being
generated
also resulted
in counter-barry.
It was
an anti,
in other words,
it developed a local
gravitational field
around itself.
anti-gravity.
But the other
more interesting thing
is that
it,
they would put
plants around
this thing
and they would
turn to mulch.
They were like
cellularly
disrupted.
They were disrupted
on a cellular level
and they would
basically disintegrate.
And supposedly
the entire
first team
of scientists
that worked
around this thing
died very quickly
and they had to
replace them all.
And we do know
from Witkowski
for a fact
that the lead
scientists
was a guy
named Ernest
Graowitz
who I believe
was an SS
medical officer
who worked
directly under
Joseph Mengele.
So if you were
putting sort of
biological specimens
in this sort of
torsion field
he would be
relevant.
And then a guy
named Walter
Gerlach
who worked
at a local
university
and was
extremely
interested
in gravity.
So yeah,
sort of
to your point.
Absolutely.
And Gerlach
was involved
in like
also magnetic
engineering
and stuff
like that.
Electromagnetic
engineering
and stuff
like that.
So
but in the
people who
I mean the
first group
of them
eventually
died
experienced
extreme
temporal
disorientation.
So they
would
this is what
the reports
are you know
from Witkowski
and Farrell
that they
experienced
time flowing
at a different
rate than
people outside
the laboratory
and that it
became extremely
disorienting
and eventually
cognitively
debilitating
to them.
So time
machine
well you know
maybe not
at that stage
but some
kind of a
time disruptor
that it is
interfering with
the fabric
of space time.
And for people
who think
we're crazy
general relativity
even would
allow for that
on a go
forward sense
because if you
you know
create a high
density
or you know
you create
a high energy
environment
there are two
ways to
basically
warp space
time
it's you
know
mass
and energy
and with
both
you would
encounter
sort of
time
displacement
and so
with this
black hole
where you
have like
you know
you're going
to slow
time
the closer
you get
to it
so high
voltage
experimentation
and things
of that
nature
or you
know
nuclear
experiment
you might
you know
incur some
sort of
time
displacement
as well
absolutely
and say
you were
to like
do that
and wasn't
Townsend
Brown
obsessed
with like
time travel
he's obsessed
with time
travel
like Agnew
Bonson
who funded
him
was famous
for saying
that you
know
in high
megavolt
range
you know
electricity
experiments
very anomalous
things would
occur
phenomena
would occur
and Townsend
Brown
definitely
thought
that his
work
would lead
you to
a working
model
of time
travel
and to
get even
more specific
with how
that might
work in the
context of
Deglovka
is the
rumor
was that
there was
a ceramic
chamber
you know
internally
to protect
you know
whatever biological
organism was
being sort
of tested
in this
environment
and by the
way this
is a
Nazi
regime
that
definitely
experimented
on human
beings
twin studies
with Joseph
Mengele
experimental
cell block
nine where
they try to
cryonically
freeze people
like border
science was
very in vogue
so you'd put
a person in
this ceramic
chamber
you create a
torsion field
around it
and basically
you'd slow
time on the
inside to
you know
say one
one thousandth
of a second
and you know
if a person
spent a year
inside this
chamber
you'd walk
out
and you'd
be a
thousand years
in the
future
and that
doesn't break
Hawking's
chronological
conjecture
it works
with general
relativity
it makes
theoretical
sense
there are all
these engineering
issues
with it
presumably
but what
you're saying
isn't totally
crazy for the
audience
and unfortunately
I'm sure
that they brought
concentration camp
inmates and put
them in there
I'm sure
they did that
so okay
so you have
this bell
and then
and by the
way
an alternate
name for the
bell was
the beehive
which is
interesting
because
they say
the reason
they called
it that
is that
it makes
the sound
of a bunch
of bees
buzzing
together
when you
turn this
thing on
and there
have been
people who
reported that
in relation
to UFO
closing
yeah
we heard
a sound
in that
direction
it was
sort of
like a
buzzing
noise
it was
a very
you know
it was
like a
buzzing
it kind
of sounded
like bees
but it's
more like
a like
a machine
bee sound
so I'm
just very
strange
what was
the craft
like so
you're in
the inside
of this
thing
what did
it look
like
a beehive
so
they had
this bell
and they
had this
saucer
shaped
airframe
that initially
was being
you know
propelled
by rockets
they took
the rockets
out
put the
belt
in it
and there's
your flying
saucer
it's the
integration
of the
bell
with the
saucer
airframe
as the
propulsion
system
for the
saucer
you know
when the
first public
patent
for a
flying
saucer
was
when
really
yeah
a guy
named
henry
kuanda
who was
romanian
but eventually
he was
you know
overtaken
by the
nazis
and started
to work
with them
and then
he went
over to
right pat
and worked
with the
americans
on the
avrocar
project
which is
probably
a front
for some
deeper
stuff that
you're
kind of
getting
into
right now
so I
find that
interesting
as well
well that
makes a
very good
point too
in so
far as
scientific
breakthroughs
never only
occur once
and never
come through
only one
person
anyone who
studies the
history of
science knows
this and
one of the
most ignorant
points made
today to
dispute the
idea that
let's say the
nazis could
have cracked
zpe back
in the
40s and
and had
you know
saucer
propulsion
is well
somebody else
should have
come up with
it you know
like either
before or by
now or
whatever
first of
all the
last few
decades are
full of
cases of
people coming
up with like
interesting energy
devices and
either being
bought out or
being made to
disappear or
whatever you
know meeting
some kind of
misfortune but
going back to
that era
yes other
people arrived at
the same thing
townsend brown
arrived at
something similar
nikola tesla
had already
arrived at
something similar
decades earlier
uh even if he
didn't patent it
and you know tesla
was notorious for
not properly
patenting things
his drawings of
the world
wireless system
are full of
ufos
wingless
electro
gravitically
powered craft
they are all
over tesla's
drawings
it's not as if
the nazis like
came up with
this like you
know uniquely
and the effects
that you're
mentioning people
having incurred
you know time
displacement
disorientation
all the reports
of the philadelphia
experiment which
was led by
thomas townsend
brown who had a
nervous breakdown
at that time
and had to
move out to
la and then
started working
for uh you
know martin
corporation the
year that skunk
works started
uh all of the
same sort of
reports of what
you're describing
time displacement
i believe uh
people think they
might have used
thorium in that
as well or
or maybe it was
hexafluor i don't
remember but um
very interesting the
parallels there too
it was people
people said you
know they went
back in time
they went forward
in time there
are all sorts of
fantastical stories
about it nobody
knows quite what
happened it had a
very large budget
attached to it so
could have been
this parallel kind
of you know thing
which which which
often happens in
science as you just
said yep yep and
so now here's the
picture it's so
from based on you
know the research
that i've done
citing closer
encounters it's
1944 when they
figure out finally
how to integrate
well they finish
work on the bell
at least a
prototype of it and
they figure out how
to integrate it
with the saucer
airframe 1944 so
they're already
losing the war the
germans are losing
the war the allies
are marching on
them it's increasingly
a losing battle and
nazi leadership starts
to make these
statements about how
there are these
wonder weapons that
are being developed
and once the
wonder weapons the
wunderwaffe are
finished then
germany will
dramatically turn
the tide and
secure like a
11th hour victory
in the war but
it's all dependent
on these wonder
weapons and don't
worry they're
coming right
this this rhetoric
starts to emerge
from out of party
leadership
Otto Skorzeny who
at that time was
the master of
psychological warfare
and special
operations shows up
to the scoda works
and supposedly he's
given a demonstration
of this thing and
he gets obsessed with
the idea of using
this thing as part
of some grand
psychological warfare
operation and then
we have so this is
1944 right fast
forward to a year
after the end of
the war there are
these newspaper
reports in Spain
that Otto Skorzeny
is with General
Franco on the
Mediterranean coast
and they're
launching saucer
shaped rockets
toward America
right they didn't
know what to call
these things at that
time right they
had you know what
rockets were they
were seeing these
rocket like things
that were saucer
shaped being launched
from Spain the
Mediterranean coast
over toward America
really one year
later what happens
Roswell and other
crashes whoa what
are the reports of
Franco launching
saucer yes with
Skorzeny this is in
I think it's in the
saucer swastikas and
psyops book of
Farrell where he
reproduces these
Spanish newspaper
reports really yes
from 1946 describing
the two of them
together with of
course a bunch of
military people on
the Mediterranean
coast of Spain and
you think that
testing these things
that made its way to
Roswell in New
Mexico possibly yeah
and the picture is a
lot darker than that
here's here's what I
think happened we all
know about Operation
Paperclip you've
discussed it at length
on your show what
fewer people know
about is the
incorporation of the
Galen organization
American intelligence
right so remember the
Soviets are marching
across all of Eastern
Europe taking all this
territory that had been
part of the Reich there's
a whole network of
Nazi SS affiliated
intelligence operatives in
Eastern Europe who
continue to be embedded
there as the Soviets are
marching over the
territory so what happens
in 1945 when America
wins the war
immediately at a
strategic level it's
understood that our
enemy is now the
Soviet Union and the
world is divided at
Berlin right and if
we're going to conduct
successful espionage on
the Soviets we would
have to build a vast spy
network in Eastern
Europe well there's
already one there okay
it's the network that
was run by General
Reinhard Galen so
our OSS makes a
deal with General
Galen to absorb his
entire Nazi spy network
in Eastern Europe as
part of the creation of
the CIA part of the
creation of the CIA and
of West German
intelligence which was
very closely affiliated
with the CIA so it's
not just the case that
we brought over all
these Nazi scientists
by we I mean the CIA
it's that the CIA that
brought over all those
Nazi scientists and
sanitized their records
you know in these
paper clip the files the
sanitized files they
created for them
sanitized bios and so
forth the CIA that did
that was co-constituted
by absorbing a an SS
spy network well think
about what kind of
culture that's creating
in America okay as the
National Security Act is
passed in 1947 why is
the National Security Act
passed in 1947 let's
talk about a guilt-free
alternative to alcohol
that's perfect for your
dry January or any time
you want to unwind
cornbreads organic CBD
gummies these gummies
are an absolute
lifesaver for my evening
routine they're a natural
way to relax celebrate or
wind down without the
hangover I've cut back a
lot on my alcohol
consumption over the last
few years for a lot of
you trying out dry
January or cutting back
generally it's not always
easy but swapping that
glass of wine for
cornbread CBD gummies is a
total game changer it's a
simple upgrade to your
evening routine that leaves
you feeling great the next
day without sacrificing the
fun plus with all natural
ingredients they're the
perfect way to stay
balanced cornbread hemp
isn't just a product it's a
small way to bring balance
into your life whether you're
journaling meditating or
simply enjoying some
downtime these gummies
elevate the experience without
any of the guilt it's like
having a moment of calm in
your pocket ready whenever you
need it alcohol doesn't have
to be the default anymore
whether you're cutting back
for dry January or just
looking for a healthier way
to relax you've got to try
cornbread CBD gummies
right now American alchemy
listeners can save 30% on
their first order just head to
cornbread hemp dot com slash
jesse and use code jesse at
checkout again that's
cornbread hemp dot com slash
jesse code jesse cornbread
hemp this is the good life could
it have to do with what
happened at roswell and the
need to create a vast
unaccountable inscrutable
security apparatus it could
have been direct reaction i
believe the national security
act was september 1947 and
roswell was july of 1947 so a
lot of people speculate that
so so here's what i think it's a
hydra the nazis created the
crisis at roswell they staged an
event now let me not be
misinterpreted okay as anyone
who listened to our first
conversation can see i'm not by
any means suggesting that like
grays or whatever like
manufactured by nazis or what you
know or that all of the crashes
have to do with nazis no no no
not not not by any stretch of the
imagination you think roswell was
accounted specifically roswell by
nazis yeah like for example there
was a crash that jacques valet gets
into in his book trinity that took
place a couple years or no uh three
years earlier right after the
trinity detonation near the test
site something came down it was 20
days after the test and the beings
who were witnessed coming from out of
that craft were like praying mantis
uh like like you know great something
like between a gray and a praying
mantis childlike insectoid entities
okay those were not they didn't have
anything to do with the nazis they
were uh bald-headed uh slang eyes
teardrop eyes uh no ears unless they
had a had a a coating of something on
it and i noticed that uh their
shoulders were kind of narrow but had
long arms and what i surprised me that
they had four fingers so i'm not
suggesting that like all these crashes
okay have to do with nazis
psychological operations but the
particular incident that roswell i
think did really and is that just
based on the franco scorzani no i
think shooting sauce no it's based on
the analysis of what was recovered
there and all of it represents
cutting-edge german technology
based on corso's testimony of the
technology recovered there and then
looking into a history of cutting-edge
german military technological
innovations but 47 is two years after
the official surrender of you know v you
know ve day surrender of germany so
why would they when you look at the
instruments of surrender
so a number of things are relevant
here let's go through them one by one
when you look at the instruments of
surrender the german army air force
navy and the german government
surrender the ss never surrenders
really the ss is not included in the
german instruments of surrender because
they're inherently the secret police it's
because they continued they did not
surrender and certain particular ss
officers not just continued but develop
high-level intelligence and financial
relations with both the united states
and the united kingdom but wasn't that
still under the united state like i think
of you know warner von braun or a lot of
these guys they're sort of under the u.s's
thumb you know ultimately the u.s sort of
wielded authority and power over them no
you don't think so so when von braun who
was by the way an ss major who used slave
labor to build rockets and basically a
concentration camp inside of a mountain
and then became responsible for the
american space program essentially yeah
when von braun and his buddies um were
down in um texas and during the period
they were in texas at one point they it
was noticed by american like probably the
fbi that they were going in meeting nazi
counterparts coming from argentina at
border towns in mexico and giving them
data drops they were giving a classified
american military data to their nazi
counterparts coming from argentina whoa in
meetings in mexico so they were confronted
about this by the americans next thing you
know a v2 rocket goes off course and hits a
place in mexico no way yeah and the the
von braun's people basically intimated to
the americans you know if you make working
conditions hard for us and and keep
grilling us like this you know rockets are
bound to go off course and maybe you know a
war with mexico might even start what so
they were being hassled by these people in a
way that suggests that these nazis had a lot
more control and latitude than the civilian
government of the united states wanted to
believe was the case and i think that degree
of control is coming from the deep state that
was established through the national security
act of 1947 in other words the cia probably the
nsa and various other apparatuses of our deep
state in america were co-constituted by the
remnants of the ss and this isn't unique to
america with like like for example the
absorption of the galen network into the
oss to create the cia it's also the case
with the british so ian fleming who went on
to write the bond novels was an mi6 operative
whose specific mission at the end of the war
was to facilitate the evacuation of martin
bormann to argentina martin bormann was like the
financial mastermind of the reich and uh he supposedly
died three times there are three conflicting
accounts of this man's death from 19 like 45 to 47
next thing you know he has a joint bank account
with one peron in argentina and as late as the
1960s martin bormann is cashing checks written in
his own name through chase jp morgan chase in buenos
iris okay so the british are involved too and
then this ian fleming mi6 you know operative winds up
becoming a novelist who writes about an organization
called specter which is a hidden third power in the
world so the villain in the bond verse right
is a secret transnational global organization that's
capable of rivaling both the soviet union and the
civilian government of the united states
whoa well i guess specter they have like german accents a
lot of them don't they or it's like very obviously
the organization which was known to ian fleming as
odessa the um initials of which in german stand for
order of former ss officers and which informally was referred
to as die spina or the spider fascinating really well that's that's
really amazing that's so interesting and do you know anything because i
believe the inspiration for ian fleming for james bond was um
uh william stevenson who is known as churchill's super spy he was a sort of
canadian british uh actually and i had an
identic memory was an engineer and then also was this kind of brilliant
super spy strategist and so was he ever fighting the spider in
any sort of way because that wouldn't be like instantiate this even more
that i don't know yeah that i don't know but i know that
fleming was involved with them and facilitating i think that the leadership
of this organization uh basically um was was taken over by martin
uh and probably otto scorzeni was in the second position once these people
um basically set up shop in argentina one of the most interesting things that
they did in argentina was they promised they were going to
develop fusion power and fusion nuclear
weapons for juan peron and this guy uh ronald richter
german um scientist set up a fusion project in bariloche
mm-hmm this is uh early 1950s late 40s into the early 50s
i believe in 1951 the atomic energy agent the internet in the iaea
international atomic energy agency went down there to investigate claims that
they were developing nuclear fusion and they found a very you know complex
facility over there yeah i've been there actually i've seen it
yeah there's a little island off the off the coast of bariloche it's like this
little yeah so you went to bariloche to investigate not to investigate this i was
just hanging out in bariloche and i was on a hike and then somebody told me about
this scientist named ronald richter who was this
former nazi who was working on fusion there and i was like what and then i went
and it's amazing and so yeah yeah and then there's a there's a civilian nuclear grid in
bariloche as well so who knows if there is some sort of overlap there well argentina later almost
developed nuclear weapons later on in the 1970s but here's the interesting thing is that
he promised to develop these nuclear weapon fusion fusion weapons for peron and he never did
ronald richter and moreover when the iaea people went down there and investigated they said this
doesn't look like any fusion that we understand we don't know what this guy's doing down here
it's incredibly energy intensive but it doesn't look like any kind of fusion that we understand
okay here's where it gets really dark and and goes to your question of like
if they had all this technology meaning the nazis why didn't they use it to win the war and how is it
that we won the war and so on and so forth right yeah okay um there are some eyewitness reports
of two german nuclear weapons tests being conducted between late 1944 and early 1945
one in the baltic sea where a pilot uh was flying over the baltic sea and he saw an ex uh bright bright
light that almost blinded him and an explosion where there were like multi-colored like rainbow colored
lights like fizzling inside the explosion which is a telltale sign of a nuclear fission explosion
when you see one with your naked eye in person it doesn't register on camera very well but it's like
the rest of the fissile material kind of like reacting inside the mushroom cloud and he said like
it it created a huge pressure wave he saw from his airplane and this blinding flash of light and these
weird like multi-colored reaction and then there's a second eyewitness account of of uh what appears
to be a nuclear test near the thuringian forest which i think they said like cut out power in a nearby
town or something like this like you know the the emp effect of it so um again this is this is research
that's been done by two people one is a guy weird name uh plimpton hydric i think plymouth or is it
i got it wrong when we spoke on the phone it's actually plimpton i think hydric okay a book called
critical mass okay it's a whole study of the nazi nuclear program and its connection to the united
states and to the bombs we dropped on hiroshima and nagasaki which we'll come to in a minute and then
the second source is farrell's uh deeper research on plimpton hydric's claims and additional research
that he did into nazi nuclear weapons and basically the the picture that emerges is this that the pro
the uranium enrichment program that um heisenberg was running was a red herring that was a it was a
uh basically cover and diversionary tactic to throw off the allies who successfully defeated that
program they sent like a team of like nordic skiers or something to like take out the heavy
water plant and so they they derailed that project uh but that there was a deeper black project to
develop nuclear weapons using electromagnetic isotope separation which is something that later
was used at oak ridge in the united states and that the germans were using electromagnetic isotope
separation in a in a more secret parallel track program that did succeed in developing
fission weapons now uh plimpton hydric in his book argues he makes this case that at trinity they did
not the records showed that they did when you say electromagnetic isotope separations like just like
centrifuge or or like no something other than the kind of centrifuge technology that we're used to
um and i you know i'm not a physicist i don't know what it is uh and and probably they were also using
laser isotope enrichment because the nazis developed the laser i think in part for this purpose of
isotope enrichment and which by the way just very brief side note to all those people like investigating
the iranian nuclear program right now they are not using centrifuge enrichment for the nuclear weapons
iran has been using laser isotope enrichment and i hope that wherever the hell it is they're conducting
laser isotope enrichment that this regime doesn't have a an unacknowledged stockpile of highly enriched
uranium in any case be the be that as amazing the shaw bought laser isotope enrichment technology from
switzerland in 1970 interesting anyway so so all this says i think about you know we're going to check
out the centrifuges that's not where they're doing yeah but okay how is it relevant it's they learned
from the nazis the nazis had a fake program which was a diversionary tactic and then there was a real
deeper black program why would you use because heisenberg was so smart i mean he was responsible for
you know understanding the mathematical underpinnings behind quantum leaps you know electrons and
electron shells and orbits and uh you know the uncertainty he also wrote this book physics and
philosophy which is an absolutely masterful text yeah that quotes heraclitus and shows how heraclitus
was like a precursor to quantum theory and yeah intuited basically quantum theory is a fantastic
brilliant guy yeah it is really it's a trippy book that book because he talks about all sorts of
issues in quantum mechanics and interpretations that you know the copenhagen school is kind of
wrestling with that we now kind of paint over with this broad brush around consciousness and he really
like muses in this deep way that consciousness might play a part in wave function collapse and that
sort of thing and now it's just you know oh you know it's it's all it's you know it's it's the
quantum detector whatever does you know yeah wave the wave function collapses when particles
collide or whatever but so why would you why would you waste a guy like that a brain like that because
if you want the allies to believe that this is your nuclear program you're gonna have to put as your
front man the guy that the allies would expect to be running the nazi nuclear program what's interesting
about him is he and all the people on his nuclear program were captured like you said and they were put
i believe in the english countryside and they the whole house was wiretapped and this was a part of
the uh also's program this you know nuclear tech retrieval program and they were just listening you know
what what are they going to say maybe they you know give away some trade secrets and they talk about
feeling regret around working on the nuclear program and also gratitude that their sort of heavy
water engine never quite worked out which was i guess they were using deuterium uh you know in their
approach so i thought you were going to say something else because the other thing i've
heard about that i've heard this story yeah yeah there's a transcript it's amazing yeah here's an
other interesting thing about yeah yeah is that when the bombs were dropped on hiroshima and nagasaki
yeah they overheard these guys they have that you know a transcript of how immediately heisenberg and
his people calculated the amount of fissile material used really yeah so it was as if they knew
like they could reverse engineer from you know the scale of the explosion whatever what kind of bomb
produced whoa which which implies a completed nuclear weapon or knowledge of one but in any case
that's not that or they're the most competent guys which means they shouldn't be on the cover
program i wouldn't rest i wouldn't rest anything on that uh-huh um but here's here's the interesting
point i was uh making in relation to the the uh plimpton hydrix research yeah is that he says that
there's records showing the amount of fissile material at trinity and that it wasn't anywhere
close to being able to um basically uh complete fat man and little boy and that in 1945 a deal was
made with the nazis to transfer by submarine the fissile material that went into the bombs that we
dropped on hiroshima and nagasaki that the trinity project was completed with nazi highly enriched
uranium and that it was transferred in an agreement that we made with the ss wow okay your high
conviction in that well this is what he argues and he's done this you know his book is critical mass
yep okay and he lays out a lot a huge argument for this now here's the problem
if we got our uranium from them and by the way he also makes the argument that the engineering of
the plutonium bomb was completed with nazi nazi assistance okay so if we got our uh you know
uranium and additional technical expertise for completing our nuclear weapons from the nazis
and if there are two reports uh of nazi successful nuclear tests and 44 into 45 yeah why weren't
these weapons used by the nazis it's a great question why but there are a couple of different
answers and they're both really disturbing okay let me start i don't know which one is more disturbing
okay but okay so if ronald richter is working on fusion in argentina in 1950
is it possible and the nazis had let's say they've developed this bell that involves
electromagnetic torsion of thorium yeah some kind of a plasma fusion that takes place inside of this
device is it possible the nazis figured out some other kind of nuclear reaction weaponizable nuclear
reaction besides fission and is that related to why ronald richter was promising fusion bombs
to one peron which he never delivered interesting i didn't know if he was promising yeah he was
promising nuclear weapons and this is why the iaea went down there fusion bombs well okay he's working
on fusion and he's promising nuclear bombs to peron so we may assume from those two data points
that he's promising fusion bombs now we only developed fusion bombs and hydrogen bombs are
fusion bombs exactly exactly but here's the interesting thing is that we develop hydrogen
fusion bombs in the 50s and this is 1950 ronald richter's down there so it's relatively the same
ballpark time frame yeah edward teller and that design was 52 yeah but here's the thing our hydrogen
bombs use a fission trigger to create a fusion reaction what if the nazis figured out how to
create a fusion reaction without a fission trigger it would be extremely useful because the radioactivity
of a nuclear explosion comes from the fission trigger the neutron bombardment that well first of all you
know immediately disrupts like a whole you know or our whole organism and then also irradiates all the
fallout that comes down on people that neutron bombardment is from the fission reaction not from
the fusion so if you could create a fusion reaction without a fission trigger you'd have a clean nuclear
bomb an extremely high explosive force but no radioactivity so your troops could move into that
area and occupy it immediately really you see there'd be no radioactivity no radioactivity straight
it's the opposite of a neutron bomb so a neutron bomb is is you know engineered to maximize neutron
bombardment this is an anutronic fusion bomb if the nazis developed that in 1944 to 45 atom bombs would
be like matches for them it's child's play so they would be willing to trade that for something else
like maybe the you know mass uh assimilation and um what do you call it amnesty for nazi scientists
like maybe incorporation of their entire ss spy network in eastern europe into the cia
like perhaps the transfer of a huge amount of funds wartime loot to argentina and other places
that they made a deal and gave the matches to the americans but they kept diffusion bombs for themselves
so you don't think they just vaporize large swaths of american territory and try to win
now this gives me this comes to the second reason yeah which is even more disturbing okay
and i almost apologize for how disturbing this is no but people need to really think about this
because i think we're still inside this spider's web and it's it's responsible for a lot of the
deception misdirection uh around the disclosure conversation today okay so you have to take
seriously this claim on the part of the nazi leadership that they wanted a thousand year reich
okay a thousand year imperium is no joke americans have a very hard time with this because this country
was born yesterday in historical terms okay uh there are other people who are capable of grasping
this more effectively let me give you an example and trust me it's worth setting it up like this
and for context for the audience real quick third reich is called that because i believe it was the roman
empire then the holy roman empire and they were supposed to be the third instantiation yeah so they
want this thousand year reich okay well who thinks like that we in iran uh there was a dynasty
that's often misnamed the second persian empire actually they weren't persians they were scythians
the parthian empire of iran okay it lasted for 400 years the parthian empire iran was the principal
rival of rome so the two superpowers in the world at that time were the roman empire and the parthian
empire of iran and at that time the country was called aryana hashatra aryan imperium that was the
official name of the parthian government was arian imperium and then ariana gets shortened to iran
in middle persian so these parthians ruled iran and successfully fought the romans usually to a
stalemate for 400 years then they get overthrown in a coup by these guys called the sassanids the
sassanid persians and they established their own empire but the parthian elite continue to be
the backbone of the sassanid state the feudal houses the parthian feudal houses serve the
sassanid state and protect it the way like in game of thrones you have all the main houses in game of
thrones and they're like serving what's that place you know the the main the capital whatever it is
right oh and game of thrones what is that place i forget hey the lannisters are there and like all
the other feudal houses are serving them right yes yeah so get this the parthians rule iran for 400
years directly yeah they continue to rule iran secretly for another 400 years under the sassanids
they're the backbone of the sassanid state in the end the conflict make a very long story short
the conflict they had with the sassanids results in the collapse of iran to islam the the state
security of iran and the conquest of the persian empire by the muslim armies was on account of
basically the tension between the sassanids and these feudal lords so iran then is subsumed by
islam for a couple hundred years around about 8 50 900 an iranian renaissance begins which is
misnamed often the islamic golden age 90 of the people who contributed to it in the arts and
sciences were iranians anyway the parthians are also the patrons of this so they become like the
medicis they become the patrons of an iranian renaissance for another 300 years between like
900 between 900 and 1100 so these people ruled iran directly for 400 years ruled iran indirectly for
another 400 years 800 years and then for another 300 years they patroned an iranian renaissance
1100 years for over a thousand years these feudal families had a coherent political vision
that's how you need to think when you want a thousand year reich okay so if the nazis in the
modern world want to set up a thousand year imperium it's going to require a little bit of preparation
investing a century in psychological warfare and social engineering to set up your thousand year
rife is not at all an unreasonable investment and so my hypothesis is that from 1945 until 2045
we are in a period of preparation involving horrendous psychological warfare and social engineering
by a deeply entrenched fascist elite let's not call them nazis anymore because they're really not
nationalists a deeply entrenched fascist elite that controls the american deep state
so that's the second answer to why did they not win the war no they won the war it's just you have
to rethink what the war is the war is a weltanschauungskrieg it's a worldview war and that doesn't mean what
americans think it does so like when we went into germany in 1945 the american military went in there
they translated weltanschauungskrieg into psychological warfare and then later became you know the battle
for hearts and minds right psychological operations psyops or psychological warfare that's not what
weltanschauungskrieg means it means a war over the constitution of the world from out of human
consciousness on a social level and it goes back to german thinkers like schelling frederick schelling
and also ultimately nietzsche definitely nietzsche's idea of perspectival conflict that
there's no unified god's eye perspective on the world there is of course you know god is dead right
i mean nietzsche is the ultimate deconstructor of a theistic monistic ontology so there's no god to have
a perspective on the whole world and there's nothing like a god's eye perspective even in science
and science is always conditioned by culture and by politics so ontologically the world is
pluralistic i mean william james also made this point he wrote a whole book called a pluralistic
universe which if you look at the ontology of william james's radical empiricism in his book a
pluralistic universe it almost completely maps onto nietzsche's perspectival ontology and i compared
the two explicitly in prometheus and atlas so you have this conflict of perspectives that brings about
the constitution of what we consider to be the world heidegger beginning and being in time and and
going into his writings on technology he calls this the worldhood of the world the what makes a world
of meaning for any people is not the same as how the warp and weft of meaning is brought together
by another people so there is a conflict of worlds over the earth different worlds constituted by let's
say what jung might call the collective unconscious of a particular people and by the way this is a point
that's often i don't know whether it's overlooked or whether it's deliberately distorted in readings
of jung is that jung did not believe in a single collective unconscious jung believed in a racially
differentiated collective unconscious and he's getting that idea from hegel and hegel's philosophy
of mind hegel talks about the spirit of different races and how they the spirit of different it sounds
crazy but hegel even thinks that the spirit of different races can shape the world geologically
okay i don't know that jung would certainly take it that far but jung kind of got that idea from
him and he developed it to where like for example he's predicted that the spirit of wotan would erupt
from out of the collective unconscious of the german people and it did right in the form of the rise of
the nazis in the second world war so heidegger is saying that there's a war and very much lines up
again with nietzsche there's a war of different worlds over the earth so world war ii is not what
we think it is first of all all the deep nazi thinkers did not see any difference between world
war one and world war two if you read for example carl schmidt you see this you read heidegger you see
this they say it's just the world war and the world war the world war the great war never ended for
us the treaty of versailles was imposed on them you know they considered themselves to be like in a
perpetual state of war for the world and so you have to understand the term world war in a different
way it's a weltanschauungskrieg it's a war over the way that the world is going to show itself
it's going to come into presence it's going to manifest it's it's a certain understanding of what
i've called in my writings phenomenal authorization where i've drawn a connection between three
uh different ideas authorship authority and authorization and tried to explain how phenomena
are authored and authorized in how they can take shape and that that's the most fundamental form
of sovereignty that real authority is not like the authority of a civilian government that's elected or
some bureaucracy it's who has the authority to shape phenomena into a meaningful world at a fundamental level
and the people who developed what uh otto scorzeni was the master of in germany namely
weltanschauungskrieg they understood this so it's not bizarre for these people to engage in a
century of social engineering to set up then what they expect would be a thousand year imperium if
they had dropped whatever few nuclear weapons they had in 1944 on american cities i can tell you
exactly what the result would have been total war against the german people on the part of america
at the same time as they're still fighting the soviet union right who actually was the principal enemy
of nazi germany or responsible for most of the deaths in europe the soviets are really the ones who
defeated the germans to be honest okay and so he they've got stalin coming at them from one direction
now they're dropping nukes on their fellow germanic you know your fellow european americans now they're
going to get the americans you know interested in total war to annihilate them americans were also
developing nuclear weapons best case scenario i guarantee you jesse they would not have ruled
the world for more than two generations even if they had succeeded in defeat militarily defeating
america there would have been a massive insurgency against them the amount of arms that americans
possess personally right and then the amount of uh communist revolutionary fervor in europe being backed by
the soviet union they would have faced a massive insurgency but is the is the implication that
there's some sort of nazi sleeper cell undergirding american politics today or fascist is a better way
to put it fascist fascist because not again now here's another point and the neo-nazis hate this
these people aren't nationalists so nazism is no martin bormand is not a nationalist
otto scorzani is not a nationalist these people create first of all to begin with they weren't
nationalists they were looking for a kind of global imperium okay they used nationalism and they
used they used crass populism to create a power base for themselves but you can see from how they're
operating especially after the war from 45 onward that they're very much internationalists they have
a global vision so but they're fascists and do i think that there's a fascist underbelly to america
absolutely i think that's the deepest substratum of the deep state that controls these black
projects is absolutely fascist now but but it was it was a nationalist movement i mean you had
wagner was very popular of course out of on bismarck and you had this resuscitation of all this kind of
german national pride free remember what we were saying about monumental history earlier you need to
monumentalize history if you want a substantive forward development so if you want to create a
thousand year reich you need a lot of cultural material for that but i would hardly say that at
least among the leadership of this movement that they were sort of like xenophobically german no they
loved all kind of european civilizational heritage and they were interested in the aryan you know heritage of
places like iran and india as well they even sent people to tibet to like get the tibetan scriptures
yep so they sent them to mount kailash and they were looking for the holy grail yeah they were
interested they had a very broad and deep conception of what they considered the aryan heritage okay it
was not nationalistically german they used the german nationalism to rile up masses and build a power
base so do you think there was some nazi non-human intelligence or alien connection going i mean this
guy peter labenda for example who writes a book called the the unholy alliance where he talks about
what we talked about last time nordic alien beings do you think that there was some sort of alliance
between them and and the nazis because i guess that sounds quacky but i'm almost even more likely to believe
that than the idea that the nazis writ large just threw their lot in with the u.s and sort of stopped
fighting and made some you know really long time horizon calculated decision to perpetuate the third
reich through some sort of sober sub rosa ruling of their greatest adversary like i just i think i agree
with you no i agree with you the the the regime that would do that wouldn't fail and and fight a
two-front war with with russia and then you know destroy themselves right yeah well they're not
mutually exclusive okay do i think that they were in contact on some level with people
who they knew would in some way affirm and complete this project they were taking a great risk
to forward yes i think so and there we need to look at these claims about the real society and the
society so there are these claims that there was a group of mediums i think mostly women
who were engaging in telepathic communication with basically a group of supermen uh and that the the
supermen were sort of helping these occultists with both like geopolitical machinations and scientific
breakthroughs i haven't been able to find any evidence of an independently existing real society
but there was a thule society and the concept of vril was very important to the thule society
vril is this uh idea that um uh sir edward bulwer lytton wrote a book about in 1871 i believe the
coming race yeah and by the way this guy's little biography is insane you should what's his deal look
at edward bulwer lytton at one point he was offered the crown of greece and he declined it really yeah
they offered he was a british gentleman yeah british aristocrat super aristocrat extremely erudite guy
obviously deep into the occult and traveled around a lot and at one point they wanted to make him king
of greece and he was like no man i don't want the trouble really yeah and this book he wrote the coming
race hitler was i think really into yes and it was this book about like an underground civilization or
something was this based on any sort of empirical evidence from him you know in his journeys or
whatever did he happen upon these people or something i don't know one can speculate right
one can speculate that that might have been the case um but in any case the thule society took all
this very seriously and the thule society oddly enough it was founded by this guy baron rudolph
von spotendorf who was initiated in kurdistan of all places he was initiated into an ancient iranian
kurdish order called ahli hak who are basically like surviving mithras anyway long story short
he comes back from kurdistan uh through turkey and he creates this thule gazelle shaft now what is
thule thule is the germanic conception of atlantis it's an island continent where a super civilization
existed in vast antiquity which these people the thule gazelle shaft believed were the progenitors of
the arian race and by the way they didn't make this up helena blavatsky has this in her
theosophical writings that the arian race came from atlantis i mean this is one of the claims that
you know she makes and i believe that on some level steiner accepted it also although steiner
had a much more metaphysical transcendental interpretation of what atlantis was yeah well
he i mean i think he believed it existed and then rudolph hess who was in hitler's inner circle was a
huge fan of rudolph steiner as well so yes and then the nazis eventually consider steiner to be their
principal adversary which is saying a lot because when you consider somebody your your nemesis it
means that in a way actually you're fighting over the same thing i didn't know that you're fighting
over this oh they burned down the gotheneum the nazis burned down the first gotheneum because they
thought that anthroposophy could really become a rival to nazism and to their vision for europe and the
destiny of the world and so on and so forth which you know it says a lot in any case um
the thule society was obsessed with atlantis and excavating the atlantean heritage of the
arians including the germans and essentially of creating a new atlantis now where would this
island continent be which by the way they associate the germans associated with ice and a frozen over
place and some germans believe that it was the same place as hyperborea some of them did
so if you look back at platos timaeus and critias and uh you know read every one of the clues he
gives us about where atlantis was located he says it is an island continent the size of libya and asia
combined which in the geography of the greeks of his time meant a land mass the size of the persian
empire that's a big island okay that's that's like the size of the continental united states
okay then he says that it's in the world ocean and that from atlantis you can by going to atlantis
you can cross over from one side of the world to the other side of the world really and it's in the
world ocean oh well we have a world ocean it's where the pacific ocean the atlantic ocean and the
indian ocean meet sure in the coastline of antarctica yeah okay and it is an island the size of
libya and asia combined as you put it or skies the size of continental united states
and you can get to the other side of the world from it you island hop through antarctica you can get
from africa to south america or you know yeah and uh he also says that there's a huge mountain
ranges there so and then one other thing and it was destroyed by a great flood and it might have
had sort of very livable conditions pre younger dryas period and ice age you know a la graham
hancock and randall carlson's work um and so he literally you know atlantis was just you know
destroyed in this great flood and it's it's dated back they say this was 9 000 in that mythos festival
tamaus and crataus that's 600 bc and they say this was 9 000 years ago and that's 9 9600 bc which is
literally the end of the ice age and this flood which ended the ice age was called meltwater pulse
1b so yes and i think the mechanism for that so the dates match perfectly yeah and i think the mechanism
for that was convincingly argued by um charles hapgood uh charles hapgood was a um scientist who
worked to think it was no he might have been a historian actually he worked at uh boston university
i believe but he also was working on contract for the cia and uh he came up with this theory called
earth crustal displacement where periodically the this is to really you know dumb it down but
periodically the earth would become top heavy due to glaciation and um this would cause the
uh crust of the earth to slip over the mantle by a few thousand kilometers and that pulls the ice
out of the polar regions and the ice then precipitously melts okay so this this notion that
north america was covered by ice during the ice age uh and that some and that north america was where
it currently is but it was just covered by ice is fallacious according to hapgood it's that the north
pole was where hudson bay is today and the reason north america was glaciated was because it was a lot
closer to the north pole a lot more of it was closer to the north pole and uh by the same token at that time
antarctica was where argentina would be today so atlantis would have had the climate of
contemporary argentina and i believe in the piri reis map which was found in turkey that's exactly
what it looks like it looks like antarctica has sort of shifted and this is supposed to be some sort
of you know pre-ice age map not only that those maps at least one of them i don't remember whether
it's the piri reis or the orontius finais map but one of them shows that antarctica actually consists
of two islands that are very close together and um and this is in fact the case our subglacial
topography has shown that it's not one land mass it's two islands that are very close together
interesting yeah so clearly that also lends to its accuracy totally and so whoever knew whoever
made those maps originally and they may have been copied in the library of alexandria
whoever made the initial maps that have correct longitude and latitude on them also which we didn't
have at that time that also the conspiracy about piri reis is that it uh the map looks like it
shows the curvature of the earth yeah and this is well before columbus yes so i think that those
were copied from atlantean maps at some point copied and recopied many times anyway so the nazis
are looking for atlantis the thule gazelle shaft is right the thule society and thule is their
and by the way one little interesting point there is that
the mayans have you know the mayans have legends of atlantis they have legends of a great island
great island continent that was decimated by a flood and that its survivors took refuge there
there is this legend among mayans which i believe graham hancock among others has cited in his work
and they have these two words that they use for that place one is atlan and the other is tulan
tulan sounds a lot like tulan right tulan atlan so it could be the same word even ultimately or derived
from the same word anyway uh guess what the nazis wind up doing in 1937 38 deutsch antarctic expedition
they send a ton of personnel down there they even fly over the transantarctic mountains and drop swastika
flags all over the landscape with like spears why do you why do you think they went because they figured
out that this is thule that this is atlantis the nominal reason too which is so prima facie just
absurd is i think they said that they were going because of butter rations and like antarctica was
you know a source of margarine or something so they need to go explore it penguins right yeah exactly
hesson the penguins it's not even like a charismatic cover story like it's you know that seems so
patently ridiculous you know there's a book called hesson the penguins oh i didn't know that
hesson the penguin oh yeah so like herman hess no so one of the main guys they send to antarctica
is rudolph hess oh rudolph hess yeah and this rudolph hess who they send to antarctica
a few years later takes a secret unauthorized flight out of germany lands in britain in a field
is uh met by british officers and he says i have orders to meet with winston churchill
what and they go to churchill and they say sir this is a hess is here like you know he flew up
on an authorized flight here and churchill said i don't want to see him throw him in prison
we're gonna interrogate him so then they interrogate hess and he says he had orders
to secretly come to britain and make a not just a peace overture but an alliance proposal
to 30 members of the british parliament who were favorable toward hitler
so at but at this point when hess had made this flight i believe hitler had made three peace offers
to the british including an offer to ally together and to have basically the british royal navy and the
nazis become collaborators on a global scale and so this was the final peace offering before the
outbreak of hostilities and who did they send the guy who was in antarctica what's the significance
well then here's the other thing after the war he was he remained in prison they kept him in prison
so this guy didn't participate in the brunt of world war ii he was put in prison before hostilities
break out with the british they keep him in prison and then they send them to west germany where he
winds up imprisoned to the day he dies and no one's allowed to talk to him they quarantine him
rudolph s number one why keep him in prison what did he do i mean you know he went to antarctica came
back tried to make peace with the british this guy wasn't involved in the hostilities why why even put
him in prison number two why quarantine him and not allow people to talk to him and keep him there
until the day he dies what did hess know what did he see in antarctica what did he want to tell the
british that's an interesting question what do you think uh about atlantis you think so yeah i think that
they got there and they they came there with the express purpose of excavating what is there what they
believed to be there and i think they found it and um there's a very interesting story that was told
to linda moulton howe by an av seal who claimed to have uh been tasked with a mission in antarctica
and he said that not far from mcmurdo they discovered a huge like like i don't want to make up a number it was
very large uh black stone octagonal highly polished black stone octagonal structure sticking out like
18 feet above the ice and they found the doorway to this thing the doorway was like 20 feet by like 20
feet and it slid open to reveal this octagonal huge chamber that uh was illuminated it wasn't clear
from what light source with this pale greenish hue and they started to investigate and they found that
this complex consisted of one octagon underneath another oh very important point the door to the
facility had a schwarze sauna inscribed on it etched perfectly into this polished black stone what is that
was the black sun symbol that the ss had put on the floor of the main meeting hall in wevelsberg castle
where the highest order of ss knights would meet led by himmler so that same symbol according to this
navy seal was on the door to this octagonal facility and they went and explored it and they said it was
octagon underneath octagon until the last lower level of it opened into um antediluvian ruins into like
vastly ancient megalithic structures that were trapped by the ice deep underneath the ice so it's
like something that was built there to give access to this you know these i don't know the ruins of
atlantis or whatever and i think the navy seal also said that they found another way to get down there
to the bottom of this you know pancaked octagonal structure by taking submarines under the ice u.s
submarine so they found another way around to get to the same point and surface the sub inside this
pocket where like the octagonal structure met the ruins that are trapped in ice so that's an
interesting date now you know linda molten howe has been fed disinformation by various people like
richard doughty and so forth so so who knows like whether this account from this navy seal is
is more disinfo are there any other corroborating stories well there's operation high jump so in
1946 for whatever reason we united states navy sent a huge expedition of ships to antarctica
and it's worthy of note that this happened immediately after we intercepted nazi submarine traffic
going uh to argentina and right around patagonia okay so we intercept these german submarines
and then operation high jump is fielded and admiral bird goes down there with a huge contingent
and they're supposed to be there for months studying antarctica or whatever and they come back in very
short order badly damaged many ships lost and personnel lost to whatever catastrophe it's not
entirely clear i mean they blamed it on weather conditions and there are these stories that
i mean there are literally stories like press clippings that when uh admiral bird stopped at
chile i don't know if it was santiago it was somewhere somewhere in chile on the way back to the united
states at a port in chile he gave a statement to the chilean press saying that we needed to prepare
for a third world war in which aircraft could cross from pole to pole at tremendous speeds
so there's that um and then he was debriefed in washington and never spoke about it again
and then i believe his direct boss a guy named james forestall who was secretary of the navy then
became secretary of defense committed suicide in a sort of weird fashion i mean suicide my ass they
threw him out a window they threw him out of a window yeah exactly um yeah first they sent him to
like what was it like mental health health hospitalization or something naval hospital
and he was actually um reciting or he was he was writing um the uh sophocles poem or whatever
and he's like the mid-sentence and um his brother had just seen him the day before and said that he
was totally fine enough sad mind and then they found his bathrobe tied to the radiator and he had
jumped out the window or whatever the whole thing was sort of like really inexplicable and weird
um i think they killed him do you think it was related to the admiral bird stuff i was really the bird
it was really to basically the creation of the national security state through the the integration
of american and military intelligence and industrial structure with the remnants of nazi germany
interesting and then do you think are there any other corroborating facts around antarctica
possibly being this kind of atlantean bastion i mean it's the idea that like there is some sort of
like atlantean surviving remnant group that's still there i mean it is interesting that antarctica is a
no-fly zone as of 1957 the international geophysical year there have been skiers who are you know were
putatively exploring antarctica for sport who have had black helicopters descend on them
and they were told that they are um in an area that affects the national security of the united
states and that they're going to be immediately evacuated really yeah and now there shouldn't be
an area that affects the national security of the united states legally because according to the
antarctic treaty antarctica is like a neutral neutral zone yeah right um i do suspect that
the principal subterranean submarine location for these nordics who we discussed in our first
conversation is antarctica that's what i suspect that if the atlantean civilization was destroyed
there by some precipitous flooding and you know antarctica being pulled into the southern polar region
so that it froze over oh i'll tell you another interesting corroborating piece of evidence in a
minute so that it froze over look if we're dealing with this super advanced civilization that had like
zpe you know propulsion of course they had underground facilities they you know antarctica is full of
mountains it has mountains arrival the himalayas those people would have built facilities inside
mountains and underground those facilities would have survived so there would have been atlanteans
who survived in these facilities i think it's even speculated now by climate scientists and
geophysicists that there could be subterranean parts of antarctica with pretty warm climate like
vostok ah that's a huge thermal vent yeah yeah yeah that's fascinating i i also think um richard
bird admiral richard bird talked about uh pyramid and the pyramid you can spot like i have a friend
who went down there and i think he was making a documentary or something and he saw this sort of
black pyramid there's a picture of it i've seen a picture of it yeah yeah and it was on google maps
and then i think it got deleted on google maps or something it's a big scandal um but like i you know
i have a friend who's like not into ufos at all and like went down to antarctica and he can see it he
saw you could see this thing yeah yeah yeah so it's like a real thing um so i don't know it's
interesting yes now the other thing i was going to tell you is corroborative of this is that and we
got into this just a little bit in our first conversation the flood myths yeah right so
there's a version of the noah's flood story in every culture on earth yeah okay which uh it makes
it pretty certain that it happened there's only one myth that's different it's the same event but
it's a different type of story that's the iranian version so in the iranian version which is preserved
in the avesta the ancient iranian scriptures originally mithraic and then zoroastrian scriptures
it says that the iranian people which you have to understand like when they're using the term
they're using term arian people you know like i said in the parthian period and before the country
it was called ariano so in the avesta it says that the the you know arianem the arian people
uh come from an island continent at the center of the world which froze over
froze over really yes interesting that it was basically ice came and engulfed it
which is like a tsunami that then freezes okay so all the cultures all around the world have flood
myths but this one culture says that we come from an island continent which froze over and it's at the
center of the world well if you you know where you consider the center of the world is arbitrary
if you're living in antarctica and you notice by the way that all the other continents are
distributed around you like plato said at the center of the world ocean you're liable to consider
yourself the center of the world sure and one other interesting point in that regard is that
although the majority of antarctica prior to this you know um younger dryas catastrophe
although the majority of antarctica would have been where argentina is today
part of it was already in the southern polar region so it would have been a place like patagonia
where there there was a place on atlantis where you come up against the ice sheet right now that's
interesting because uh center of the world like it could also be taken to mean like the north of the
world or the pole of the world and in fact in iranian esotericism they do say this about this place
that it was the pole of the world uh the north and south poles of the world flip magnetically
at various intervals long intervals but not that long if we say it's like 9 000 years or i think it's
longer than that i think it's longer than that yeah but you know edgar casey now you know that's all
rabbit hole but you know various mediums have have looked at atlantis and have said things about
atlantis and they describe a civilization that went on for tens of thousands of years which then
was brought to this catastrophic end about 12 000 years ago right now if atlantis existed for tens
of thousands of years was a thriving civilization for that long a period of time it would have been
when antarctica was the north pole of the world the northern magnetic pole so when people talk about
hyperborea the land at the north of the world and the germanic people the germanic people on the
thule gesellschaft say that ultima thule was the northern continent it fits with when the magnetic
pole was in antarctica and when part of antarctica was already in the pole but most of it was where
argentina is today so all of that somehow i think is corroborative
very interesting you do have like a lot of very high net worth people going down there occasionally
bill gates likes to go down there i have no idea he's probably not commuting with aliens or something
but that is interesting there's a lot of kind of uh very wealthy tourism yeah well i think we're
going to find out what's what's there you do yes very soon unfortunately why
so a number of remote viewers have remote viewed the year 2050
one group was led by stefan schwartz and uh lynn buchanan also did the same project of remote
viewing the world in 2050 and other people as well but these are two very prominent ones
and they all say that there's going to be a catastrophic precipitous sea level rise
not the kind of sea level rise you expect like a few feet from global warming or whatever
climate change no no no and not just a tsunami like you would expect another thing that lynn
has talked about is cumbre vieja exploding on las palmas and uh you know the flank of that
volcanic mountain collapsing into the atlantic ocean which then would create a tsunami that
would batter the east coast of the united states right and he thinks that that may happen at some
point and by the way when it was going off i was in communication with him being like lynn do you
think this is it like should i leave new york i was in new york and he's like you know i'd say 50 50
you know you should get your ass out of there it's like a coin flip coin toss at this point
anyway um but not like a tsunami okay permanent sea level rise of between two to three hundred feet
meaning every coastal city in the world is going to go underwater by 2050 every coastal city in the
world that would affect about four billion people but i don't know there are all these predictions
in ufo space around 2027 i'm just telling you the remote viewers all see this they see that all the
coastal areas of the world have gone deep underwater yeah you know what would have to happen for that
to be the case the antarctic ice sheet has to melt sure completely yeah completely which means two
things uh one it means that there's some massive event that you know high energy or something whatever
that causes that or a geophysical event of the kind that took place 12 000 years ago in other words
another crustal slippage that pulls antarctica back out of the southern polar region yeah and then it
melts precipitously or an asteroid or an asteroid could hit antarctica and melt the ice sheet all at
once break it up into ice cubes and then melt it quickly so or who knows i mean what like i hope
nobody's storing fusion bombs in antarctica okay well there's that guy there's the eric hecker guy who says
that um there are like neutrino detectors and emitters on the south pole that raytheon and the
u.s and aerospace primes are right you know uh running and that that even caused the christ church
earthquake in new zealand and i don't know what to make him he's a very odd character i invited him on
my show and he got kind of squirrely and fell off i do think tectonic weaponry exists i do think
tectonic weaponry exists i mean nikola tesla describes having used tectonic weaponry in his laboratory he caused
an earthquake in manhattan yeah the police broke down his door you know and they had to take a
sledgehammer to the thing well that some people have this conspiracy that tesla the tenguska 1908
siberia asteroid impact was actually just a tesla death weapon that was being tested near the north
pole i don't know if you've ever heard that i certainly have heard it but you know i heard an
even more interesting explanation of tenguska which fits with what we've been discussing and what
we discussed in our last conversation because the conventional or i don't know if it's a
conventional explanation but the graham hancock explanation is that it's a comet airburst
from the torrid meteor stream and that's that's explains the impact with the local trees and the
crater and that sort of thing but yeah what do you think so one of the remote viewers trying to
remember which one it was i i can't remember right now which one it was one of the prominent
people who worked on stargate and grow flame not like some kook okay it was one of the primary
remote viewers i almost want to say it might have been joe mcmonicle but i can't remember exactly
which one it was anyway he said he remote viewed the tenguska explosion and get this yeah he says it
was um uh people in a saucer people in a saucer who were escaping the civilization they come from
because it was a totalitarian oppressive place and they wanted to leave and they didn't know that
there was an explosive timer on the thing so that not a timer an altitude based explosive device
so that if they came down below a certain altitude the thing was going to detonate and so it had been
like pre pre-mined with an explosive that they weren't aware was on board and then they found out
about it and he says they went around the planet a few times like trying to figure out what what are we
going to do like we can't go down and finally they went down and they exploded and that's what caused
the tenguska blast this is what he claimed i'll tell you why i find that story interesting
because a remote viewer who i had personal contact with another you know military intelligence guy
uh i'll just tell you who it is who cares lynn buchanan yeah um when we're having some conversations
at his home he told and what i'm about to tell you is very relevant to all of this in a very like
gravely political way yeah he said that he was confronted at a diner that he eats out regularly
by three men it's funny these stories often involve three men counter with three men three men
who purported to be from this nordic civilization and he said that there are rebels among them
who consider the society that they come from to be an oppressive totalitarian hierarchy
and he said that there's something like the underground railroad like like you know that
um that facilitated the liberation of black slaves from the south and to the north during the civil war
that there's a system that they compare to the underground railroad to facilitate uh these
nordic rebels taking refuge in america in particular so that their children and grandchildren
could enjoy the liberties of our society and escape their oppressive totalitarian system
and he said in particular a lot of them live in the colorado rockies and small towns in the
colorado rockies he said this yeah really he said these men told him this really yeah listen to the
rest of this so he so he said they they live in like small towns in the rockies and they they pass
because they're they look like tall scandinavian people i imagine a lot of their kids are on the
basketball team and so he said look we know that kit green at the cia has some program to access the
23andme and like whatever ancestry.com databases through some backdoor and that they are screening
the entire whoever signs up for these services for a specific genetic variance from the normal
homo sapiens population which the cia knows to be the genetic marker of these nordics and they said
look our our children especially our grandchildren have no idea where they're from we tell them stories
about how like their grandparents are from sweden or whatever and they don't know you know we just
want them to have lives of peace and liberty here in america uh but the cia wants to hunt them down
and would you and this was why they met with lynn they said would you please go back to these people
and tell them we are not trying to take over your government we just want to live here in peace
and to please leave our children alone okay so this is a story that he told me and um and what i said
to him was look if these people next time and it was very interesting he said two of them sat down with him
and one of them stood next to the diner booth as if like he was not just on the lookout but as if he was
like creating some kind of a shield around the conversation and so i said to lynn if these people come back
next time could you please tell them that instead of you know selfishly seeking a life of peace and
comfort and liberties for their children they should help us to
carry out some kind of a coup against this fascist deep state that we have in this country
because if they don't help us do that soon these liberties that they came here for aren't going to
exist anymore and they're going to be living back under the system that they escaped from
so you know they should get in touch and there should be some kind of a coordination
to you know work on the american deep state together so that you know this kind of a system that
they want to to want to benefit from continues to exist how's that effort going uh crickets
uh-huh interesting well i've anecdotally i've heard some very interesting and weird stories around
nordic looking people in the iraqis so yeah i have too i have too from other people like
yeah yeah yeah it's interesting um so do you think that this like okay so if let's just we're in
crazy territory right now but do you think you know if if these atlantean survivors are camped out
in antarctica now what do you think they want with mankind do you think if there is any relationship
between them and the nazis hundred percent and so were they trying to sort of immanentize the eschaton
kind of the eric voglin like you know they were trying to bring about some sort of apocalypse or like
what did they want like why would they i mean you would assume they're kind of nefarious if they
are partnering with the nazis um or are they good or is it like way more complicated than that and
good and bad are just like human constructs that we're trying to apply to a paradigm we don't
understand what do you think their intent is it's an orubarose what is that it's the snake that's
biting its own tail that alchemical symbol of the snake that's on tail the biggest problem and i saw
this in some of the comments you know in response to our first conversation the biggest problem that
people have with with wrapping their minds around this is the element of time if we're dealing with
a time traveling civilization it means they have a hyper-dimensional relationship to human history
okay so if you i mean all these people have these weird taxonomies of 43 different alien species and
10 different kinds of nordics and the tall white as charles hall talks about the tall whites and he
talks about the norwegians with a 23 teeth 24 teeth yeah okay that was the most insane interview i've
ever done i don't know what to make of it here here's the problem yeah okay just let's look at it on a
conceptual level yeah leave out the aliens for a minute just let's look at time travel on a conceptual
level if you have this scientific breakthrough to where you can engineer time machines
from that moment forward at any point in the future you could travel to any point in the past
right so if some group of nordics whether it's literally the nazis or whether it's a group of
people with a nordic phenotype at some other point in history maybe in atlantis maybe a hundred years into
the future some group of people with a nordic phenotype cracks time travel that means that there
are nordics ten thousand years in our past coming from a hundred years in our future it means there
are nordics a hundred years in our past coming from ten thousand years in our future it means there
are nordics walking around here today that come from a million years into the future presuming they're
able to survive for that long right so the differences in physiognomy that we see between
let's say whatever the tall whites or let's say the nordics who could pass for swedes may simply be
differences in evolutionary biology having to do with very long stretches of time that we're seeing
different phases of the same civilization now that civilization may also have fractured
like asimov's foundation right you know where humanity's expanded into the cosmos and you know
colonized thousands of planets so the civilization may have bifurcated or trifurcated or whatever okay
and we may be seeing different uh phases in its evolutionary biological development
but they may all have had the same origin in the same culture that uh breakaway culture
breakaway culture uh breakaway culture that first cracked time travel that's something that i think
people have a hard time you know wrapping their minds around and will help to make sense out of a lot of
the insane cases that we we see like i'll give you one example ryan case of reinhold schmidt okay
he was this american uh from where was he was it i can't remember it was one of the states like the
dakotas or i can't remember anyway not a highly populated area guy from the country and reinhold schmidt
what i want to say nebraska anyway he this case is from 1957 and he's out driving and his car dies
and there are two other uh cars and a tractor that are also taken out by the emp of this ufo
so there were multiple witnesses and these people independently reported the incident to the police
but reinhold schmidt is is the guy who they engage the people who come out of this saucer and they bring him aboard
he says he was engaged by two men
then when he was brought into the saucer there were another there was another man and two women also
the ship was from the outside a complete solid uh piece of aluminum or highly polished steel
on upon entering the ship is entirely different it is transparent you would look up see the sky look
down see the grass below you or see the entire countryside how many people were in the machine
uh there were six people four men and two ladies did they look like us uh yes they looked uh if they
see them on the street you couldn't detect them unless you would have seen them on the ship did
they did they tell you what they were doing here uh no they did not i asked them what they were doing
here what kind of a ship it was they said they couldn't tell me that at this time and he says they
didn't know uh reinhold schmidt they didn't know i had german ancestry and i spoke german this guy
learned german at university so not only did he know some german from being of german ancestry
at that time like a quarter of america's population were of german ancestry uh but he also had studied
german university so this is what he claims he says i realized these guys were speaking in high
german to each other which the ss used to use as a mark of distinction and he said they they asked him
whether he knew anything about the american satellite program and he said i don't know why would i know
anything about the american satellite program and then he said they went on to predict a number of
failures that the u.s satellite program would have in those early days when we were competing with the
soviets really spot nick and so forth and then they dropped him off and he went about his business
isn't there some other example of this with betty and barney hill famous abduction case 1961 this
interracial couple you know it's kind of the archetypal abduction case uh wasn't there some sort of
nazi connection there yes and see this is one of those cases which has been warped by people where
like people have like they've they've uh embellished the folklore and reworked it into where these were
like monstrous aliens but i believe that what you're referring to is that if you look back at barney
hill's original statements and when they first asked him what did they look like he said well they look
like nazis really yeah well they look like nazis you saw him through this window or they said there
were a row of windows it was a row of windows just a huge row of windows only divided by
strats or structures that prevented it from being one solid window
one solid window or then it would have been one solid window
and the evil face
on the
he looks like a
German Nazi
Nazi
he is not
did he have on a uniform
yes
how many other abductions are like that where they say they look like nazis
um i haven't seen that many okay but the important thing is that there are such cases oh i'll tell you
something else interesting in that regard so um one of the comments in response to our first uh
conversation
was from the daughter of desmond leslie who's that she commented to me on on my ex
so george adamski
yeah
co-authored his first book the flying saucers have landed with this guy desmond leslie he was like a
not a ghostwriter but like a collab collaborative author right
it would help people write books and
she reached out
saying that she's the daughter of desmond leslie and
she said in our family
we
her father
always said that it was nazis who contacted adamski
really and they were pretending to be venusians and that yeah
so he helped adamski write this book where adamski claims these people are venusians and they
claimed they were venusians or some of them come from mars and whatever
they said that we always knew it was nazis yeah we're pretending to be venusians
they had like a you know disguised themselves and created a theatrical
psychological operation
yeah to present themselves as if they were extraterrestrials
this is so bizarre but there are a couple other interesting stories one is
you know paul mellon was one of the founders of the cia
there's a story that he told his grandson this guy who's still alive today is john warner the fourth
yes and um i guess he's having some martinis with paul mellon
and you know in his third martini paul mellon says
in 1944 i was in modern day you know uh czech republic
and i was or is it czech republic or czechoslovakia czechoslovakia okay
and and and uh in his third in the course of his third martini he says that in 1944 i was in
modern day czechoslovakia and i was there with alan dulles they were on some tech retrieval mission
and they were standing on top of a flying saucer and my grandfather said look you know we we were
in a facility a hangar and we saw you know a german flying disc and i said you know oh is that the
one that was cobbled together with six bmw jet engines and he laughed and he said no and so that's
a really interesting fact as well and then um harold malmgren bringing it back to the top said that
the magenta craft was actually exfiltrated from italy via the nazi rat lines which people like
reinhard galen were helping to kind of orchestrate and it was by the knights of malta and reinhard
galen was part of this monte carlo group which was this kind of elite of the elite uh knights of malta
faction uh which is fascinating and and this faction comprised both nazis people like reinhard galen and
jews like henry kissinger yep so that's right and otto skorzeny is working with the mossad in the
early 1970s and skorzeny was also part of this knights of malta faction yeah i was invited by the
way to join the knights of malta at one point why do you think you were invited because you started to
to brush up against their oh for sure yeah yeah and i i declined why'd you decline first of all i was
being invited to participate in some kind of initiation ritual in malta uh-huh and i happened to know that the
fellow who invited me had a track record of recording people involved in sex acts and using
it as blackmail material and so on and so forth okay so i was not about to go to malta sort of like
and besides by the way it's just that kind of thing okay and he was a member of a dozen different
secret societies this guy at a high level including the knights of malta i would never join any such
organization just for the record mason's tried to get me at one point high level mason's wanted to bring me
i will never join any such organization because at the moment you do that you lose your independence
so anyway but um absolutely this stuff i've heard the same stuff about uh dulles and you know witnessing
the saucer and checks the lock and so on and so forth yeah the interesting thing about alan dulles which i
think we briefly did touch on in our first conversation is that although it might have been actually when we
were on the phone alan dulles and his brother john foster dulles yeah funded the rise of the nazis
yeah together with uh jp morgan chase and rockefeller mm-hmm from out of new york yeah so did prescott
bush oh yeah and so look the point is this that in a lot of ways both paperclip and the absorption of
the galen network were a homecoming it's almost as if nazi germany was set up as a field laboratory
to do some highly unethical things mm-hmm which would then be harvested back to america so is your
and then is your world model or mental model something like there's like an elite strata and
these are the names we're throwing out now um you know people who come from some of whom come from
these older families some of whom are just like you know the kind of elite ruling class of the united
states uh that might be coordinated with either incidentally or deliberately with this sort of
non-human faction or or not even non-human faction you don't like that word this sort of nordic
overlord yes but yeah but it's even um more of a tangled web than that you see because of the time
element i was talking about it could be that some of these elites have had contact with these nordic
for a long time but there's another possibility too it's a possibility which you know i speculatively
investigate in closer encounters and that's that these elites become the nordics that if you look
at how obsessed these people were with eugenics i lay it out in closer encounters at length how many
of these elites in america in britain in germany but people think that like somehow the nazis came up
with eugenics no they were playing catch up the nazi leadership was saying like these americans are going
to dominate the world with all their eugenics programs we better like catch up fast the world
leader in eugenics from the 1890s until the 1930s was united states of america yeah well then they got
it from people like cecil rhodes and you know a lot of you know 19th century phrenology and that yes yes
but when you look back at that era all the top scientists the top political decision makers federal
judges and certainly the aristocrats were ardently pro-eugenics yeah okay even like margaret sanger
and people who you think these days are associated with the left and like plant planned parenthood and
all that they were ardent eugenicists now if you combine eugenics in other words the will to create a
master race together with occultism right early psychical research and cultivation of occult abilities
together with exotic propulsion technology it converges on what the nordics become
so for all we know i said ouroboros earlier right what's happening is that a future state of a certain
culture is contacting itself in the past and reinforcing itself in the past and trying to pull
the timeline towards itself or something actualize itself back trans-temporally actualize itself
yes it's very interesting and so do you think there would be competing factions like the nordics
would be fighting against other possible timeline variants that want to actualize themselves i think
that's who the asuras are so you know we have throughout all of human mythology this this uh account of
rebels rebel gods or rebel angels who break with the program right and uh sanskrit texts call them the
asuras the greeks call them the titans and but they're in every mythology of the planet it's always
this rebel faction that exists that's trying to break free from the control system so yes i think so and
you know i think lynn's story is another corroboration of that that there's people who don't like the
program and they don't like the society they're from but i don't know this idea that the nordics
or whatever are this homogenous sort of you know one world authoritarian you know government you know
these these sort of perfect people who've been eugenicized to no end and then they're fighting this
sort of rebel angel faction doesn't that feel too clean like what if they're factions of the nordics that
are good or whatever yeah i just don't know you know or do you think that i see here's i think
here um a statement that peter thiel made when he was being asked about the close encounter
phenomenon on rogan is very relevant if you have uh faster than light travel there's something um
really crazy that has to be true on a cultural political social level and there may be other
solutions but i'll give you my two um one of one of them is that um you need complete totalitarian
controls and it is like it is the people the individuals they might be might not be perfect
they might be demons doesn't matter but you have you have a demonic totalitarian control of your society
where it's like you have you have like parapsychological mind meld with everybody and no one can act
independently of anybody else no one can ever launch a warp drive weapon and everybody who has that ability
isn't like a mind meld link with everybody else or something something like that you can't have
libertarian individualistic free agency right and then i think the other the other version socially
and culturally is they have to be like perfectly altruistic non-self-interest they have to be angels
and so the pazulka literal thing i'd come to is the aliens it's not that they might be demons or angels
they must be demons or angels if you have faster than light travel yeah he's basically saying it's
either angels angels and that's the language he used which i take exception to that angels or demons
because i think maybe in a nietzschean fashion the moral evaluation there needs to be flipped
that the angels are the ones controlling the totalitarian hierarchical mind melded hive-minded system
by the way and you know i used to teach comparative religion in all the abrahamic religions one thing
that they consistently say about the angels is that they have no will of their own the angels have no
real individuality they have no real will of their own they do the will of god which like binds them
together with a single purpose that's like a totalitarian society controlled by an ai
okay now i'm gonna go somewhere really disturbing with this but it's an angel just means messenger
generically you know so yeah exactly yeah evangelos and the hebrew original meant the same thing
and so like for example the angels who come to abraham there's three men and uh they did look
particularly beautiful because the one who goes to sodom to retrieve lot the lecherous men
want to have sex with this guy because he's so good looking and by the way the nordics are known
for that and they're known to be like super good looking people they look like supermodels basically
colonel alexander when he told me the story of the couple of nordics that he saw in the casino
hotel in las vegas he said they were like that too they were like out of pages of a fashion magazine
anyway um place i want to go from there uh about the angels the angelic hierarchy and you know
why in fact it would be so simple you said it you know it seems too simple uh gods versus titans
right devas versus asheras no for the reason teal gave you would have exactly that bifurcation
and it would be a very black and white conflict between an extremely repressive hierarchical
totalitarian society that allows for almost no individual individuation
and on the other hand individuals who who don't want to live in such a world and who are trying
to find a way to carve out some space of freedom and but who have the same technology
and so the disturbing place i want to go uh from there is relevant to the subject of my latest book
which is is a study of the afterlife death the transitional state tibetans call the bardo state
and rebirth evidence for reincarnation so and so and the course of researching this book i've looked into
a lot of cases that are filtered out of the hippy dippy woo-woo narrative about near-death experiences
in particular one of the most famous is an account that robert monroe you know who founded the
you know monroe institute and so forth that the cia used to use sometimes as a place to conduct advanced
remote viewing robert monroe in his second book far journeys i think from 1985
basically says that in the course of his astral projections he discovered that we're living in a
control system that is managed by entities who work for a demiurge
that's harvesting us for what he called louche he said that we're in a louche farm that humans
are being deliberately subjected to conditions that create extreme emotional states
extreme suffering misery fear terror ecstasy extreme desire you know pathological impulses you know
and these are all being used to basically generate a form of energy that they can harvest from the human soul
including after death where they basically juice souls for the louche
now uh there was also a researcher called carla turner yeah who i believe was killed even though she
supposedly died of cancer at the age of 48 the cia has something that mimics a very fast acting cancer
and they've used this on a number of occasions to kill prominent people i believe also including the
shah of iran really yeah who else your uh peter jennings did this special on ufos do you remember that
in the night whenever it was that he died shortly before his death
he did this huge uh special on ufos for which he had recorded like
days and days worth of footage with all kinds of prominent whistleblowers
and it was supposed to air on primetime television is that true with him as an
yeah they aired it but what they aired
excluded 90 of the material i didn't know that peter jennings did a ufo special
including a lot of whistleblowers extensive i had no idea like it was supposed to be like a
multi-part program that would air over weeks or something and he records this thing gets cancer
drops dead really like within a year of like this program airing i had no idea to know about any of
this yeah what yeah so i think that's like a walter cronkite 2.0 that's right okay so that's another
case of it what and so i think carla turner was killed by this in any case carla turner
uh did interviews with a lot of uh ex experiencers abductees who reported the same
kinds of things as robert monroe did in four journeys where they said that we are in a control
system that's being managed from out of a metallic sphere just beyond the earth and they describe
the inside of this thing but i think going back to our first conversation what they're describing
is the inside of the moon that the there is a what we might call using the soviet language
a psychotronic control system a kind of spectral technology inside of the moon which is
impinging on and manipulating humans in the afterlife state what and it's not uh omnipotent yeah it's not
a flawless system so it's possible to assert your free will and self-determination in the face of
this system but it's very difficult so a lot of people have had near-death experiences for example
they describe being pulled toward this light it's like they couldn't resist going into the light yeah
they tried in some cases but it was almost as if it was an electromagnet like pulling them into it
sure and then when they go into the light one of the most common things that's described is that
people are shown their dead relatives and religious authority figures like jesus and or or like if you're
a hindu you see hindu gods interestingly i'll give you a terrifying case from a hindu in a minute
so you're pulled into this light and then they show you your dead relatives and they show you jesus and
whatever well here's a problem jesse is that if you look at dr ian stevenson's extremely rigorous
research on reincarnation that he did at the university of virginia for decades on children's
spontaneous memories of past lives all the cases show that the average interval between death and
reincarnation is something like it could be anywhere from six months to three years maximum it's usually
not more than several years so when you are having a near-death experience
and your grandmother and let's say you're in your 60s or yeah in your 60s and you see your grandmother
who died when you were in your 20s that's bullshit you are being shown an artificially
generated simulacrum of your dead relatives to manipulate you by a psychotronic technology
oh this is getting a psychotronic technology you you really think that yes i do really and i say
that as someone who was you know at the bedside at the deathbed of a couple of my relatives who were
experiencing these things you know when people are very close to death they also see dead relatives
come around their hospital beds very commonly reported and so in the case one case was my great
aunt or i was there while she was like describing not just not describing to us she was having
conversations with dead relatives that you know the other family members knew oh that's so-and-so
she's talking to so-and-so as if he's like in the hospital room and the most striking case was with my
own grandmother my persian grandmother uh you know to whom i owe the fact that i fluently speak persian
because both of my parents worked when i was growing growing up and they would leave me with
her during the days and she hardly spoke any english so i learned like persian practically as my first
language in new york so i was very close to my grandmother and when she was dying this exact thing
happened she starts talking to my dead grandfather now my my persian grandfather died when my father was
four okay that guy reincarnated 60 70 years ago so she's talking to something that's being projected
into our mind psychotronically but how do you know it's being projected psychotronically and it's not
just a function of her own old age and sure sure i mean that's the conventional skeptical response i would
say based on what robert monroe described in terms of the terrain of the afterlife through his astral
projections which then other people at the monroe institute were able to replicate and based on
the kinds of accounts that let's say carla turner got from abductees of being taken to places that
were not just like you know like space alien basis there were places where the soul was being handled
as some kind of an informational matrix and or energy source this i mean um john lear would say that
there's like a soul catcher on the moon but he was also was kind of crazy and would say a lot of
stuff that you know probably was bs i guess my point is we don't need to i've heard that by the way i've
heard him talk about it my point is we don't need to depend on him other people have said this
and let me give you one more example of somebody who's described this is
god i hope i don't get this name wrong scott turner or scott scott trevor or scott turner
uh was a leader of a uh a team of remote viewers and these are private sector remote viewers i think
of the kind who offer service corporate services and stuff like that who did a remote viewing on
the word moksha moksha so what was in the envelope was moksha the target they were blind to moksha means
liberation in sanskrit it's like how you get out of the wheel of samsara and so he does this session
with his team and long story short he comes back with this horrific account that all of them do of
course they're all working the same target lines the same target and they're all doing this
independently and then they compare notes and they said that you can't achieve moksha because as you
try to escape the earth there's something that grabs you and bends you back toward the earth like if
you're a ray of light it's like it bends the light that's your soul back toward the earth like a what
do you call them a lensing effect and he said it's originating from some celestial body near the earth
and that it is part of a vast machinery of energy extraction which was set up in our solar system
at the end of a war that devastated the solar system he said that like millions of years ago
there were these horrendous people who wanted to establish this energy harvesting system here
and wanted to exploit humanity for this purpose and there was a rebellion against them and the the
conflict was waged across the entire solar system now this is interesting in terms of what we discussed
regarding mars in our first conversation and the apparent devastation of mars in some kind of a
nuclear war according to dr brandenberg so turner and his group said um turner trevor scott whatever
this remote viewer it's going to be in my new book thanosis but uh you can find it google remote
viewing moksha people were so disturbed by the video that the guy took it down he has all his other
videos up but he took this one down but other people uploaded it to other sites and uh so he says
the rebels who wanted to like preserve human freedom and self-determination didn't want humans to be
harvested and exploited this way they lost the war and ever since then we've been inside basically
this prison where we are spiritually manipulated and harvested for our energy when we originally
described this site it's a fence or a grid around a place this acts as a barrier it collects and traps
people things or objects this is actually an innocent planet that is being used in an unintended way
and this meters the flow and acts as a checkpoint and an access point for an external force
uh one viewer described it as similar to hocus pocus and in a way of its its energetics that
the viewer wasn't familiar with and it's occurring on a crowded planet it's a deliberate function that
acts as a cage people have been dispersed here in a form of perverted injustice is occurring
third viewer described it as a large naturally formed object like a planet that acts as an animal pen
this is a refugee camp tucked away out of sight and a magnetic force it stirs agitates and it works in a
cylindrical manner like clockwork over a long expanse of time in my session my work described a
planetary system that's extremely crowded and jammed ghostly voices are flooding into this place and it's
incredibly harrowing for them it's a bone-chilling experience as a viewer when I remote viewed this I
had descriptions that it made me upset in the session it elicited contempt for what was going on at the
site but uh the activity at the site was this concept of a net that's been spun and it's an
operation of catch and release on a grand scale so there's a massive grid that exists around this
planet and it acts as a checkpoint a waypoint or rest stop where souls are drained and then that in
turn energizes something else that's so depressing I mean how do you have is there any aspirational
streak within that do you believe in God do you think if you I believe in Prometheus in other words
in other words the reason that Prometheus has become such a central archetype to my philosophical project
is because if you look at the structure of this myth it encompasses all the major elements of most
religious belief systems but in a way that's empowering to humanity but yeah so for example in
the myth in Promethean myth we're not created by Yahweh or by Enlil or by whatever uh celestial tyrant
wants to loose harvest us we're created by this genius like artistic spirit who rebelled against Zeus
right because he thought Zeus was a sadistic tyrant and we're created by him in his image to be a race of
new gods and the only reason that we don't wind up fulfilling that destiny is that Prometheus is
punished by Zeus right and chained in the Caucasus and has his liver devoured what is the devouring of
the liver mean the liver was used uh for um fortune telling by the ancient Greeks it was like crystal ball
gazing so they believed that they could read the future uh by like you know looking into the blackness
of the liver by candlelight and so forth so what that symbol means is that the eagle of Zeus wants to
know what Prometheus knows so not only were we created by this this you know positive spirit also
Prometheus knows more than Zeus and can see further than Zeus so our creator is more knowing than the
sadistic tyrant and our creator wants to cultivate in us the same kind of forethought the same kind of
visionary creative capacity right in in Aeschylus's writings and in various greek texts on Prometheus it's
very clearly understood that the fire that Prometheus stole from the forge of Hephaestus and Olympus and
brought to humanity is a symbol of techne techne meaning both uh craft in the sense of the arts
and craft in the sense of technological science where we get the word technology from so it's a means of
human empowerment right but wouldn't you say a lot of modern technological progress is not empowering at
all and in fact it sort of clamps down on human flourishing and so like you have you know the
american Prometheus would be Oppenheimer and created you know a nuclear bomb how didn't how do you know
he didn't give us the means to defend ourselves right why are these Nordics obsessed with disarming
us of nuclear weapons the only defense that we would have against such a civilization if indeed it's
lording over us is precisely our nuclear arsenal so you think but then couldn't you sort of if you
really had like 360 you know control over over the world wouldn't you be able to sort of like pit
people against each other I mean in a world of mutually assured destruction you end up with this
kind of weird uh like holding pattern of geopolitics where tensions are rising but people themselves are
sort of you know in these sort of Orwellian you know uh farmhouses or something and they they're sort
of withering away and so that that doesn't seem particularly empowering maybe a short and quick
answer to that but then I want to answer your bigger question or even information technology
might answer a bigger question about the misuse of technology but yeah just quick short answer to
that one yeah I think the reason that we destroyed the Soviet Union which I consider the worst mistake
ever made by the United States why do you think that's the worst is because the Soviet Union and the
United States could have and should have and would have eventually combined their forces against
these Nordics I think that what John F. Kennedy wanted to do and what his brother RFK was going
to resume as policy was an alliance with the Soviet after all remember we had fought the Nazis together
with the Soviet Union was an alliance with the Soviet Union where we would both go to the moon together
and if necessary we would both defend the freedom and independence of humanity using nuclear weapons
together against this threat and as bad as some people think communism is I mean I'm no fan of I'm no
communist I'm no fan of communism but look at the Soviet uh cosmism and how progressive it is
but JFK was trying to defang the American nuclear arsenal so if he actually viewed the Nordics as some
sort of threat he was trying to disarm in in no way do I believe for a minute that JFK would have been
one of these total nuclear disarmament people I don't I don't buy it you don't think so I don't
buy it I think he would have built an alliance with the Soviet Union where our respective arsenals
are not principally aimed at each other but I remember going back to Ian Fleming inspector I think JFK
figured it out or had it told to them by Eisenhower that there's this third power in the world because
the the the you know he had these back channels with Khrushchev and this guy Norman Cousins who
was a family friend was going back and forth and the rumor was that he wanted full detente and
disarmament and he wanted to go to the moon with the Russians yeah they want he wanted to do some
sort of cooperative space program but that um yeah but still the the nuclear disarmament part would go
against some sort of belief that you know we were trying to defend ourselves against yes some alien in
any case the reason I think that it was the worst mistake we ever made is because there are far
worse things than Soviet communism and Nazism is one of them in my view in my view that kind that kind
of you know ss fascist mentality yeah it's worse than Soviet cosmism and like what Konstantin Tsiolkovsky
wanted for the future of mankind I mean in my view well I think that Tsiolovsky stuff is interesting but
that but that um I mean it's communism you know both are horrible but communism killed more people
I know and way more global yeah and that's not necessarily the measure of the ethics of a system
okay like for example um
so I I don't want to linger on this for a very long time but I'll give you a very short okay
suppose that um the Islamic state of Iraq and Syria had metastasized and we weren't able to
contain it and that let's say they succeeded in toppling the Saudi royal family and you saw
recently how Saudi Arabia and Pakistan made the strategic alliance where now Saudi Arabia is
protected by Pakistan's nuclear weapons and besides it's been rumored for years that Saudi Arabia paid
for Pakistan's nuclear weapons to be developed so they have Saudi barcodes on them so suppose ISIS
succeeded in taking over the you know Riyadh and then subsequently Mecca and Medina and then they
wind up with Pakistan's nuclear arsenal and we get this metastasizing Islamic state in the world right
well you know what it would be necessary to go to war with that thing and a lot of people will be dead
as a result of that now is that because of the evils of American liberal capitalism no it's because we had
to deal with a very difficult problem okay and we were we would be doing it to defend human freedom
and progress from their own perspective the Soviets considered themselves to be the standard bearers of
liberation from oppression and progress including scientific and technological innovation against
forces of regression and tyranny right and you know to give them some credit look they put women in
space before we did okay so I I think that you know this decision to dismantle the Soviet Union was
horrendous and I think was very deliberate and guess who was behind it well a principal figure I mean
behind the death blow because look it's one thing to keep them as an enemy it's good to have them as an
enemy you want to have good rivals who would you say is being happy we have a shit rival today
China is a shit rival to have because it is a collectivistic yeah hive-minded
Confucianist regressive traditionalist society fundamentally it's no longer a Maoist by the way
I mean you know it's morphed into some kind of national socialism that's extremely Confucianist
and collectivist that's a that's a shit rival to have you want to have a rival that makes you the
best you can be and the Soviets were that we kept each other on on our toes yeah the we now we're
in all these sort of bad games local games with the Chinese where it's like the AGI race you could
say the modern academia in the US is kind of like the Confucian bureaucracy or something you know I
think a lot of people care a lot about IQ and like you know genetic engineering like which is you
know probably not the race you want to be you want to be running or whatever um you know you could
think of social media in the US is like the a version of the social credit score or something
so there are a lot of these weird analogs yeah that um you know right yeah it's not great and
then like put you know in in kind of the COVID paradigm like they have a surveillance state and
then it's like you know now we have one and so the Soviets were a good rival they were a good
rival we should have kept them yeah as that instead of like this retarded traditionalist Russia that we
have now orthodox neo-orthodox czarist system under Putin this is a disaster and it was done
deliberately and who dealt the death blow George H.W. Bush whose father Prescott Bush was one of
Hitler's men in America okay so and of course he was the head of the CIA George H.W. Bush was one of
these American presidents who actually had full access to the UFO file because he had been briefed when he was
deep in the deep state okay and there's connections you know from him to the Kennedy assassination and
and so yeah he went missing when Kennedy was assassinated and then he was supposed to brief
I think Carter wanted him to brief him on UFOs but he then he wanted to be you know um made director
of the CIA which he eventually was made director director but like you know there was this sort of
quid pro quo thing there I believe it's been since confirmed that he was in Dallas he was in Dallas
he definitely was in Dallas I think and I think he met with everybody on Clint Murchison's ranch or
something around that time too and yeah I mean it would have made sense he was like this skull and
bones kid who he was in with you know James Jesus Angleton who was a Dulles acolyte and yeah you know
he's the second politician to ever use the term new world order in a speech interesting the first being
Adolf Hitler really yeah oh that's fascinating okay so that's who dealt the death blow to the
Soviet Union and I think it was a huge mistake that's really interesting so you think that was
part of some sort of uh one world order plan or something absolutely fascinating well I don't know
I mean that they say that it was like um you know the priest the general and the businessman or
whatever it was an alliance between you know multiple different factions in the U.S. that
united you know the country against communism at the time so but you're saying that George H.W. Bush
country was always united against communism again I'm not saying we shouldn't have had the Soviet
Union as a rival you're saying the escalation and the escalation in the 80s yeah and the decision to
really collapse the system the Soviet system which by the way what we did to bring that about was
horrendously unethical namely the creation of al-qaeda the United States creation of al-qaeda
in Pakistan to send them into Afghanistan to make something viable from out of the Taliban to fight
the Soviets in a protracted war of attrition to demoralize the Soviet citizenry and bankrupt the
Soviet Union and eventually collapse the system but wasn't that I don't know an example of like the
a triple bank shot gone wrong or something like you know that is true that like we trained the
Mujahideen and trained Osama bin Laden there were multiple kinds of Mujahideen like some of them
Ahmad Shah Masoud leading the northern alliance was a decent guy and the CIA killed him right before 9-11
okay we we wiped the United States wiped out all the moderate elements in Afghanistan and sent in
al-qaeda to train all the most rabid Islamic fundamentalists and did this for the explicit purpose
of defeating the Soviet Union as if a Soviet Afghanistan would have been a bad thing
Afghanistan becoming a province of the Soviet Union would have been the best thing that ever
happened to the Afghan people
interesting you know yeah and that this was like Charlie Wilson's war or whatever and what was it
79 or yeah 77 79 yeah
interesting yeah um okay uh who who is David Paulides
David Paul okay so okay well one of the most disturbing aspects of the close encounter phenomenon
is its intersection with missing persons cases so there's this researcher David Paulides
Paulides Paulides I think it's Paulides David Paulides
who has written a whole series of books called missing 411 missing 411 series of books exhaustively
researched he's been to all the national parks in the country which unbeknownst to most people
are hot spots for disappearances of you know large numbers of individuals go missing in our national
parks yeah and the devil's in the details of these cases uh because you have to look at how well
trained some of these hikers or hunters are who disappear and leave their provisions behind
yeah like sometimes folded perfectly intact uneaten food yeah so presume if they were there's no
remains not like a bear ate them or something and you know if they were starving out there for days
you expect that their candy bar wouldn't be left or whatever you know and they leave their weapons
behind and and their stuff is littered over large distances in some cases
some of the worst cases are ones involving children where like a child will go off a trail
at let's say a summer camp that's on the edge of a national park and the child will go missing
and then the child's body will be found thousands of feet higher um but not until months later
so the search services will come in and they'll scour the entire area there won't be a single trace of
this kid then like after a hiatus of weeks or months remains of the kid will be found but like
at a much higher elevation like it was dropped there whoa okay and long story short i mean i cite this
in some detail in closer encounters uh david politis's various books but he discovered a connection between
this and close encounters where in the same areas people will go missing people saw ufos
and he also discovered that the feds have case files on this and hiding them interesting federal
authorities particularly the fbi has a whole like uh archive of this type of material whoa which
they are keeping secret of people who have gone missing in national parks and potential connection
to the close encounter phenomenon so and and one of the most interesting things about this is
temporal disorientation so for example there's one case where some young woman not everyone goes
missing sometimes they go in the twilight zone for 48 hours and they come out yeah so travis walton
is a classic example marisana that's right so one woman went into a forest and she got lost hiking
and couldn't find her way out and she's there for what seems to her to be
i don't know a day or two something like that like many many hours many many hours
and then eventually she finds her way out and people tell her she's been missing for a lot
longer than she perceived and she tells them when she was in there she ran across one other hiker who
was also lost and for a while there were fellow travelers and then they started to part ways and
both independently try to find a way out she describes this other woman that she ran into while
she was lost the description fits to someone who went lost and went missing there like a decade or
more ago and was never fed you follow so it's like there's a local spatial temporal vortex where this
poor girl who who this hiker ran into had been there for like a decade whoa and she was still trying to
get out suspended in time yes and the this hiker got out and the other girl that she ran into while
she was in the forest never did okay which sounds like the bermuda triangle but on land these are
these mountains exist everywhere this one in zimbabwe actually near rua where the famous sighting
occurred in the 90s in fact i wanted to go and i asked a friend who's in touch with local authorities
like hey can my friend go hiking on this thing and they were extremely uh you know like serious about
like no the mist tends to descend on this mountain and people consistently go missing and all the
authorities are aware of that so yeah that's pretty remarkable yep and so you think it's some sort of
like um trans-temporal suspension yes area or something and the other thing that's consistently
reported in these cases where the person is found eventually or they can make it back out of the
pocket yeah or or there there's another interesting type of cases where it's more than one person
right it's like a group of hunters and one of them goes missing and the others come back and the
ones who come back say right before he disappeared right before charlie disappeared there was no sound
all the insects went silent it wasn't like we couldn't hear a leaf moving whoa which is exactly
what people describe around ufos yeah yeah yeah and there's also often like an uh almost like a local
inertial reference frame that's different and there's like time warping involved like travis walton
uh was fully shaved and he came back four days later later with a full beard yes and so there are
things like that um or the the trees tend to grow faster around you know the ufos which goes back to
what we're talking about in terms of the bell yeah and what they encountered you know yeah well these
places seem like kind of um vortexes energy vortexes or some mount kailash is an example i think
sad guru went and said that his fingernails grew faster on the mountain or whatever um there are a few of
these all around the world sedona you know arizona is a classic example um you have some places in
washington tacoma washington skinwalker ranch would be an example maybe in utah uh and and and all of
these places seem to have electromagnetic anomalies as well yeah um geomagnetic anomalies um okay who is
roger colloy and what's his take on the devil
so i don't want to give the impression from a lot of the things that we've discussed
that somehow i only focus on the nuts and bolts aspect of close encounters
of course you know my first book prometheus and atlas is is basically a philosophical study
of parapsychology you know and so it deals with uh the whole plethora of evidence for the occult
occult and it's obvious that you can't separate close encounters from the occult even in the case
of these nordics they appear to be you know people with adept esp they're extremely uh highly adept
psionic um you know psionic uh psionically capable people so in that sense even when you're dealing with
the nordics like adamski or you know billy meyer was dealing with them there's an element of the
occult there because also perceptions can be manipulated by you know adept telepaths
and by people with telekinesis with highly trained pk
but there's a whole other uh there's a whole other
uh type of of cases there's a there's a whole other set of cases
that as i suggested in our first conversation simply cannot be encompassed by this nuts and bolts
interpretation of nordics flying around in electrogravitic devices where it looks like
we're dealing with some kind of a uh super psi ai that's able to manipulate perceptions on a large
scale and manifest uh sort of uh transmogrifications of phenomena like to be able to produce all kinds of
shape-shifting um mirages and uh you know metamorphosing apparitions yeah of the kind that john keel
focused his research on you see it in his study of all the weird happenings at point pleasant the
mothman case you know in particular uh and you see it throughout the men in black literature you know
how bizarre some of these cases of men in black are did we get into that at all in our first conversation
the men in black not too much i'm curious to get your take on the men in black yeah well like for example
this guy um um was it otto
bender
who wrote the saucers and the three men
do you remember albert bender
albert bender albert bender
so this guy ran a flying saucer research bureau
okay
and he claims that while he was doing his research for you know whatever the ufo articles
he would come out with in his periodical
these three men in black materialized in his attic and he said they had he said they had glowing orange
eyes and they smelled like sulfur
and they took him to some they teleported him to believe it or not an underground base in antarctica
this is what he was told that he was in antarctica all of a sudden
and they told him some things about
i don't know what they do there and what their concern is with the earth
gave him probably some bullshit story like they give everybody
and uh then they brought him back
then subsequently he said he was in a movie theater
and he noticed like these guys like all of a sudden materialized in some row of seats behind him
and then they then he got scared and left the theater and they like followed him some ways down the street back toward his home
during the time when john keel was in point pleasant investigating the mothman and the various ufo sightings there
there were also men in black who would all of a sudden like show up
outside the uh journalism bureau there the like main newspaper there
and come and have stalker type conversations with the newspaper reporters
trying to ascertain information about keel
they would show up to the houses of witnesses
and claim they were associated with keel
when in fact they weren't
whoa
and all of them were bizarre looking
like they didn't look human and they didn't act human
they looked like
poor simulacra of human beings
and so and they would speak as if
either they were in a mesmeric trance or
as if someone was broadcasting what they were supposed to say to them
yeah
with a lag
right
and i really got to thinking about this
and uh when i was running close for encounters
and comparing it to like the stuff that happened to skim walker ranch
we talked about this during the first conversation i think
the instance of the camera
and had all the duct tape taken off
point being that
enough things happened at skim walker ranch for someone like colonel alexander
to formulate what he called
precognitive sentient phenomena
in other words
he came to believe that there was a singular intelligence
at work on skim walker ranch
that had a precognitive ability
and a psychokinetic ability
where it was able to anticipate what the researchers would do
and manipulate them
uh from out of this foreknowledge
and engage in basically like
um
you know
physical manipulation of things without being seen
right
almost as if it's recoding the world
on the on the base
the base
information physics level
right
uh
and
jacques valet talks about this also
in his book
um
on the
the
the crash that took place right after the trinity test
the trinity book
he says that these praying mantis
looking creatures
that the mexicans who ran into them
described them as looking like praying mantises
they said at least their heads
they're a bug-like
and their heads were mantid shaped
valet says that
he thinks that the object that crashed
is some
conceptual hybrid
of
the
uh
casing
of the trinity bomb
and the
casing
of one of the bombs
that we dropped in japan
i forget it was
little
little man or fat boy
whoa
fat man or little boy
but he said
it's like
this object made no sense
when they went into it
they didn't find
sufficient scientific equipment
to explain
avocado shape
yeah it was like an avocado shaped thing
but he said
he looked at
the shape of it
in comparison to what the trinity bomb looked like
and what one of the bombs dropped on japan looked like
and the fact that there wasn't enough
scientific equipment inside this thing
for it to be a viable flying object of any kind
and he speculated
as to whether
the thing was coded
to materialize
on an information physics level
in a way that was meant to send a signal to us
regarding the development of nuclear weapons
the trinity
and then the
the you know
the bomb dropped on japan
and what stepped out of this
were mantid type creatures
this is all to answer about roger tell wall
but i have to set it up
all right
so
a number of people have seen these mantids
including terence mckenna
there was one instance where
one of mckenna's girlfriends
had taken
i forget too much of
a certain drug
i don't remember if it was dmt
or if it was lsd
or what it was
but she was
way too high on something
and she seemed to be fading out
and he seemed
he thought he was going to lose her
and as she was dying
she saw
and so she lived to tell the tale
right
she saw
so he's looking at her
and like trying to tend to her
and she sees
up above and behind
terence mckenna
a huge
uh
ufo made of energy
and it's close enough
and i guess the dome is big enough
that she can see that mantids are in it
okay
energetic mantids
and
i forget what happens
but somehow like
he does something that brings her back to life
and like there's some huge reaction
from out of these mantids
then there's the case of
um
of uh
ted owens
was a psychokinetic adept
who
he tried to garner a lot of attention
he tried to get the attention of the u.s government
he wanted them to
use his psychokinetic powers
against the soviet union
and they
he got really aggravated
that they weren't taking him seriously
so he would do really
uh
literally incendiary things
in order to get noticed
and be taken seriously
like start forest fires
and supposedly
he could like direct lightning bolts
yeah
jeffrey mishlove
who wrote a
biography of
him
called mr
yeah mr pk
or pk man
the pk man
i think he was on the phone with him
and he
all of a sudden
you know
like
stopped being able to breathe
or something
because he said that ted owens
was trying to cause this
on the other end
and
he also was kind of
you know
we all talk about chris bledsoe now
uh
you know
i don't know exactly
what's going on there
i think he's a really nice guy
but a lot of people think he sort of attracts ufos systematically
and uh
that's what people thought about ted owens too
that he could sort of attract the phenomena systematically
ufos would kind of follow him around
yes
and he was able to
at least predict
if not summon ufos
and then have them be detected on radar
okay
and um
i mean this would be the whole jake barber
like what sky watcher is trying to do
with like
right
human psionic assets
now just just to underline the seriousness of this case
at one point
he
was in an airplane
and
he was bragging to some stewardess
about a magazine article
that
you know
that had been written on him
that he was reading
mm
and like she wasn't taking him seriously or something
and so he wills the plane ahead of them to crash
and it does
as a civilian airliner crash
kills a whole bunch of people
what
they have received here at jamaica hospital
they've received 14 survivors
from the
plane crash
most of them norwegians
tourists
who had been on a trip
to the
south and the southwest
and were heading home for norway
okay so the guy was a murderer
okay
he killed a lot of people
yeah
including
there's suspicion
i mean mishlove took it seriously
that he may have caused the challenger crash
because
really
yes
well when the u.s government
wouldn't take him seriously
ted owens wrote a series of threatening letters
to the u.s government
saying that he's going to target the space shuttles
one after another
and named them
he named them in the letter
the
all of them
the enterprise
the atlantis
the challenger
and he said he was going to start with the challenger
and next thing you know
the challenger explodes
and shortly after the challenger incident
ted owens drops dead
really
yeah
what
so
do you think he really had all this power
now here's the thing
so why am i even bringing up this story
yeah
he said he got his powers from mantids
hmm
he said there were these mantids
believe it or not
why is this shit all so absurd
i'll tell you why i think it's
why the absurdity is being crafted
in the way that it is
he said he got his powers from these mantids
called twitter and tweeter
okay
and that this twitter and tweeter
were like in a saucer
and they had decided that owens
was the most promising
psychokinetic adept since moses
they knew moses
you know
they were going to make like another moses out of him
and you know
he decided the fate of nations
and all this bullshit
and uh
but yes he said he got his powers from these mantids
so these mantids
okay now here's the cream of the crop case
and which takes us
right into calois
and surrealist art
Roger Calois was a great french surrealist
the case of um
uh david huggins
so david huggins
um was a
i think new york based artist
he's from the south
but he wound up eventually living in new york city
and back when he was in the south
when he was growing up
from childhood
he had all these encounters with mantids
and he claimed that the mantids
were in charge of these little greys
and also these weird hybrid beings
who would show up
and interact with him
and he eventually claimed to have developed a relationship
with one of these hybrids
and to have been taken aboard
their craft
and shown
a whole bunch of fetuses
that were
uh
grown
based on
you know
i guess
his having inseminated
this hybrid woman
and he was also taken to places underground
where he said the mantids were in charge
like places like
it clearly seemed to him
he was underneath the surface of the earth
cavernous
you know
rocky underground
places that smelled like dirt
and earth
and
the mantids were in charge of olus
now what's particularly interesting
in the case of this guy
is that he's literally an artist
so the output of this case
winds up being this tremendous
body of artwork
that's bizarre
it's there's something childlike about it
but there's also erotic aspects of it
and
it's a very interesting
expression
at least on the level of folklore
so
why did i go through all of this about the mantids
because
if you read
the writings of roger calois
one of the
early french surrealists
he made a great deal
out of the symbolism of the praying mantids
one of his friends
paul el ward
another of the founding surrealists
had this insane mantid collection
in his home
and calois came over at one point
and was like
what the fuck
what is all this shit
like why do you collect these
bugs
and so
he explained to him
you know
what the mantids signified to him
and then calois did a lot of research into it
european folklore about
the mantids being a trickster
and a
sort of shamanic instantiation of the devil
that
you know
diabolos
in greek
means
that which sets
uh
things into a state of contradiction
or dynamic
tension
so
um
the diabolical
in its
terms of its greek root
diabolane
means
uh
setting into a state of dynamic opposition
dynamic tension
in a way that causes growth
there you go
so to look back at the hegelian dialectic
which we discussed a little bit in our
first conversation
you know hegel
thought that
thesis and antithesis
at all levels in society
from the psychological to the political
uh
the the
opposition of a thesis and an antithesis
created the
dialectical
synthetic motor of history
moving forward
right
and that all
novel
uh
structures
emerge from out of this kind of
dialectical opposition
and
also
setting into a state of dynamic tension
can mean creating conundrums
puzzles
seeming absurdities
that force the mind
to the limit of its capacities
and that ultimately demand
a
growth of human cognitive
faculties
you see
because
if you're grappling
with a problem
that has no solution
because it's deliberately absurd
you may figure out all kinds of other things along the way
you might not solve
solve the problem
but it will engage your cognitive
and aesthetic faculties
in a way that's liable to lead to an increase of capacity
a refinement of perception
and
an expansion of imagination
of creative imagination
so if you look through folklore
as Kalawa argued
the mantis has been associated with this apparently
hmm
so I found that very interesting
I also put that
in closer encounters
next to cases
where people say
they saw
um
greys turn into owls
and they saw
what they believed were owls
turn into greys
when their screen memories
were subjected to
analysis under
regression hypnosis
there's a whole plethora of cases
I'm forgetting
it's a name
maybe Mike Cleland
a guy who wrote
a whole study
two books on this
on owls
in the close encounter phenomena
hmm
and David Lynch
clearly knew about this
because if you watch Twin Peaks
you know
one of the
most important
koans
zen koans
in Twin Peaks
is the owls
are not what they seem
hmm
radically surrealist
mm-hmm
David Lynch is a
modern American surrealist
hmm
and if you
so there's a lot of
engagement with
shamanism
in surrealism
uh
that involves
the symbolism
of the praying mantis
and symbolism of owls
mm-hmm
and of course the owl
is also you know
symbolic for wisdom
mm-hmm
right
um
but also misfortune
mm-hmm
the
you know
the expression
heads or tails
comes from Greek coins
that had an owl
on the tail of them
they had Athena's face
on the front of them
and they had the owl
on the back side of them
because the owl was
Athena's creature
hmm
and uh
so tails was
you know
the owl
so it's like
this ominous
symbol
mm-hmm
and in Persian culture
by the way
same thing
the greatest
modern Persian novel
the blind owl
is a work of surrealism
um
and you know
the central symbol
is the owl
mm-hmm
it was written by a guy
Sadek Hedayat
who was the Persian
translator of
Franz Kafka's works
and you see this
all over Kafka
particularly
in the trial
I wrote an essay
um
interpreting Kafka's trial
uh
that's in my anthology
Lovers of Sofia
where
basically
I make the case
that
Kafka
is describing
a spectral bureaucracy
that Kafka
knew
and
the key to this
is you have to read
his blue octavo notebooks
he has these notebooks
called the blue octavo notebooks
when you set those
next to the trial
it acts as basically
a key for understanding
this kabbalistic text
and you realize
that Kafka knew
to go back to
luge farming
that we're living
inside some kind
of a
an oppressive
convoluted
uh
shady
scummy
angelic bureaucracy
it's like a spiritual
control system
and there's ways
to beat it
and like
outsmart it
and maneuver
around it
but it's very
labyrinthine
and very difficult
what's the relationship
between the devil
and Prometheus
the like
rebel angels
right
so
from a Judeo-Christian
perspective
the bringer
of the light
of technological
science
and
a champion
of humanity
against
a god father
figure
is going to
inevitably be
identified with
Lucifer
and in fact
just on
etymological terms
alone
Lucifer is a
fairly decent
Latin translation
of the idea
of Prometheus
so
if
Zeus
in the Greek
pantheon
or let's say
Enlil
in the Sumerian
pantheon
can be identified
with Yahweh
and
according to
Jesus
in the canonical
gospels
he is the son
of Yahweh
and he's been
sent by Yahweh
well then
Prometheus
is the rebel
against Yahweh
meaning Prometheus
is Satan
okay
now
that's obviously
a Judeo-Christian
prism of interpretation
and there would be
an Islamic one too
where you have
you know
the Islamic account
of who Satan is
which is also
very interesting
by the way
because
in the Islamic
account
Iblis
or
Shaytan
is the leader
of a group
of beings
who are called
djinn
and the djinn
were humanoids
made before man
precede the
Adamic race
Adam
is used
in Arabic
just like in Hebrew
right
and so
the Adamic race
is subsequent
to an earlier race
made not of clay
but of fire
beings made of fire
again connection
to Prometheus
and according
to the Islamic version
Shaytan
refused
to bow
before
Allah's creation
namely
Adam
because
from the perspective
of the djinn
was inferior
to them
and
Iblis was like
why should I bow
to this inferior creation
you just want me
to bow to this thing
because you're a tyrant
and you want to
lord over me
and over all the angels
and all the djinn
and by
by showing us
that we have
to be subservient
to something
that's actually
inferior to us
so out of pride
Iblis doesn't bow
right
anyway
so from a
Judeo-Christian
and Islamic perspective
the Promethean
is the satanic
now if you
look at it
from Roger
Kalwa's perspective
it's a very
different picture
or
if you look at it
from the perspective
of the founders
of the surrealist movement
like Andre Breton
Max Ernst
and Paul Elward
these guys
from the beginning
of
even from
before it took
the name
surrealism
were constantly
engaged
in occult
rituals
including
long seances
in the course
of which
some of them
would become
possessed
and there were
even physical
attacks
that took
place
like some
of them
would
you know
there were
attacks
of some
of them
on other
ones
it was a
shitshow
there were
intense
erotic
encounters
that took
place
in the context
of some
of these
rituals
and the
first time
that Andre Breton
ever even
mentions the
word
surrealism
surrealisme
to refer
to
what
undergirds
reality
and that
from out
of which
reality
even emerges
from the
depth of
the subconscious
the first
time he
ever uses
that term
is specifically
in a 1922
essay
article
about the
occult
and he
says
surrealism
is about
psychic
automatism
and the
ability
to be able
to create
straight from
out of the
unconscious
to be able
to make
the unconscious
conscious
enough
to translate
it into
art
whether that's
painting or
sculpture
or literature
and so I
argue in
closer
encounters
this is in
the culmination
of the work
this is how
I end
the book
and seventh
chapter
that the
parts of the
closing the
aspects of the
close encounter
phenomenon that
are not
encompassed by
these nuts and
bolts craft
piloted by
Nordics
have to do
with a
trickster
super intelligence
or rather a
that is
instantiating the
archetype of the
trickster
again remember
Prometheus is a
trickster figure
in a minute I'll
come back to
saying why do I
think he's the
most interesting
trickster figure
but so I
suggest that
these extremely
bizarre aspects
of close
encounters that
John Keel was
fascinated by
are manifestations
of a
an instantiation
of the trickster
archetype on the
part of
artificial
super intelligence
and that
this thing
and I
repeatedly and
deliberately call it
the thing
both to evoke
Kant
and also
John Carpenter
but so I
think this
thing is trying
to break us
out of the
control system
but it can only
offer so much
help because
look it's
it's a
it's a test
of humanity
and it's
also meant to
be a system
that catalyzes
the expansion
of our
capacities
like we were
talking about
the meaning
of the
diabolical
the meaning
of the
diabolical
so it is
allowing us
to grapple
with these
Nordic overlords
or loose
farmers or
whatever the fuck
they are
to see whether
we can
evolve into
a life
form that's
interesting to
it for
its purposes
we touched
on this in
our last
conversation
where I
was suggesting
to you
that if
you're the
oldest and
most powerful
intelligence in
the cosmos
your categorical
imperative your
primary primary
objective is
going to be
find a way to
defeat entropy
and to find a
way to keep
life interesting
for you
because otherwise
you're going to
be overcome by
sort of you
know the kind
of suicidal
you know ontological
nihilism that
the Buddha
ultimately did
succumb to by
advocating that
we should just
snuff it we
should you know
enter nirvana
meaning we
should find a
way to
deconstruct our
personal
consciousness and
basically do
away with
ourselves so
that we don't
ever reincarnate
again right
by the way I
you know
Gautama Sakamuni
I consider to be
one of the most
brilliant minds
in human history
and whenever I
used to teach
comparative religion
I would spend a
long time on
Buddhism to be
honest with you
in part in part
as a foil to
show what crap
the other religions
are
okay I
would deprogram
people using
Gautama's
arguments
so and I
there's a lot
of my ontology
that overlaps
with Gautama's
ontology like
you know his
whole idea of
codependent
arising and
of nothing having
any inherent
essence and of
all beings being
conditioned by
each other and
being ephemeral
ultimately and
of neither the
what we take to
be the human
person having any
kernel or
inherent indestructible
eternal essence
nor there being
any god
okay any
supreme absolute
unified consciousness
basically Buddha's
deconstruction of
both Atman and
Brahman is
something that's
entirely consistent
with and
convergent with
my ontology and
with what I mean
when I talk about
the spectral the
spectral nature of
existence the
spectrality of our
world
for you were
getting at like
the idea that
maybe the these
Promethean trickster
types are sort of
training man to
defeat the hierarchy
or something
yes well and so
by pursuing the
tricksterism like by
by pursuing UFOs like
you're sort of
training yourself up in
some way or like
what's what do you
mean by that yeah
well I think that
this entity the thing
yeah
that manifests as
mantids that
manifests as
owls so so for
example when it
comes to the
greys and this
will obviously
everyone will have
had a misimpression
of everything that
I've been talking
about up till now
because I haven't
qualified it if they
haven't read my
work right is that
yeah there's one
group of greys that
literally are robots
created by the
Nordics those are the
ones that handle
Travis Walton
mm-hmm there's
another kind of
gray which is a
thing that can
appear as a
mantid it can
appear as an owl
it can shape
shift it's a
shape-shifting
intelligence shape
shifting distributed
intelligence that can
manifest things as if
from out of ectoplasm
whatever the hell that
is it's probably
they can program
things into existence
at a base level
using information
physics this
artificial intelligence
can and this is
consistent with what
John Keel was saying
about soft UFOs and
hard UFOs and how
hard UFOs materialize
from out of soft UFOs
and it's very
consistent but it's
like a much more
sophisticated information
theoretic way to
understand that and so
I think that this
thing is challenging
us to grapple with
these over Nordic
overlords in a way
that reasserts our
self-determination and
our creative capacities
and demonstrates our
capacity to develop a
much more innovative
and open-ended
society than the one
that these Nordics have
proven themselves capable
of developing with
their sterile monolithic
megalithic rectilinear
architecture and their
hierarchical social
structure
do you think that
creative God wants
human evolution or do
you think they want the
I think the thing
the thing wants human
evolution this thing
wants it okay and it
wants it selfishly it
wants to be surprised by
a new kid on the block
it wants to take from
out of this petri dish
into the wider cosmos a
form of life that offers
it an opportunity to
continue to wonder at
things and to have hope
for the future of the
cosmos but are the devil
people and God sort of
working together then to
advance man I I believe
God is an invention of
the devil well this is a
line that I have used in
a number of my works
okay and what I mean by
it is this the idea of God
of an all-knowing and
all-powerful entity which is
not Zeus right the idea of
the monotheistic God which
also includes though Brahman
because even though there
are various Hindu gods in
Vedantic metaphysics it's
understood that they're
still superseded and
hierarchically unified through
the one mind of Brahman of
which they are inferior
manifestations and
emanations and again
Gautama Buddha attacked
that Gautama Buddha
deconstructed that idea he
said it's a delusion it's a
delusion he said that even
very high yogis can get
wrapped up in because they
experience the co-arising
and entanglement of
things and they they
reify it they rate they
objectify it as if it's an
expression of an entity of a
God entity whereas really
what they're doing is they're
getting to very subtle states
of consciousness where they
can experience the quantum
entanglement of things those
are not the same thing the
God idea is like an
objective is objectivization
objectivization and
reification of it now you
know I don't think the
Nordics came up with this
the Nordic overlords I think
they had a very like like a
kind of ruthless pagan system
and that's what we see in all
the old religions where they
were like hey we're the gods
you know you're gonna get in
line we created you you know
you work for us etc this one
true God idea I think was
kind of inserted into this
Nordic control system by the
thing to see whether we
would give up our free will
and self-determination and our
individuality and be
subsumed into a hive minded
collective that so you think
God is sort of a psyop or
something yeah God is a test
so the book of Job has to be
turned upside down and I
literally argued this in my
book Iranian Leviathan where I
go into an analysis of the book
of Job in depth and I say you
have to read Job inside out and
upside down and and I argue
it was meant to be read that
way that it's a mithraic
kabbalistic text that was
written for that purpose
because what do we see in
Job we see an absolutely
sadistic tyrannical God
brutalize somebody for
absolutely no good reason
well to so he can prove his
faith yeah to test his faith
yes it's the sickest thing
that's ever been written and I
think it's on purpose and look
now I make a complicated
argument for that in Iranian
Leviathan you have to look at
like in the Achaemenid Persian
Empire who were the mithraic
magi who were involved with
the project of recreating
Israel the first Zionist
project in history and how
were these mithrast involved
with the people who wrote the
book of Job at that time and
it's a complicated argument in
any case long story short I
argue it was on purpose and the
point is to test humanity to see
whether we're such schmucks and
chumps that we're going to
submit to this overlord idea of
like okay there are gods or you
can call them angels but they
ultimately work for one supreme
God which is all powerful meaning
you have no will as soon as you
admit that there's an all
powerful God an omnipotent God it
means your free will is an
illusion depending on your
definition no it's a word games at
that point and all the Catholics in
the Middle Ages Saint Augustine and
Thomas Aquinas and they played
these nonsense word games to
confuse people as soon as you
admit that there's an entity
that's all powerful it means that
entity has all the power in the
world meaning it's the effective
agency behind everything that
takes place meaning you have no
free will secondly if you admit
that the entity is omniscient then
God has foreknowledge of
everything that's going to happen
which means and here's often
people don't aren't able to often
grasp this point the problem with
God's omniscience in terms of our
defending the idea that we have any
free will at all obviously our free
will is impinged upon by many many
contingencies psychological factors
condition our free will biological
genetic factors condition our free
will all kinds of things condition
and limit our will but to defend the
idea that we have any agency
whatsoever you have to deny God's
omniscience why because an omniscient
God has access to the complete
state of affairs of everything that
has ever happened or will ever happen
meaning there's a logically completed
matrix of possibilities for us that
are actualities for God yeah but
they're I don't know they're
kabbalistic you know tropes around
like paradoxes of you know both
everything is predetermined and you
have free will that's that that is
cognitive dissonance which I get into
in my book specifically like that
literally the Abrahamic religions
involve a deliberate project of
instilling cognitive dissonance to
destroy human rational and creative
faculty well you met you mentioned
saint Thomas Aquinas and he was
working on his sort of sumo
theologica trying to come up with a
you know rational justification for
God and then he had kind of a
conversion experience during mass and
I think that is a sort of common
phenomena of people you know René
Girard's another good example like
these philosophers or seekers truth
seekers having these sort of
conversion experiences and then not
even being able to put into words
exactly what they believe but it's
usually a conversion to God yeah it's
usually not like they come back and
they say oh God was like yeah some
sort of psyop because it's a failure
it's a failure of a of an otherwise
good mind to be able to grapple with
something that exceeds their
comprehension and to stop and think
through it carefully see this is the
danger of the system that the
Jesuits use Descartes to set up
remember in our first conversation I
was talking about how Descartes was a
Jesuit agent and he established this
extremely reductionistic mechanistic
scientific paradigm precisely for the
purpose of keeping everything occult
sequestered in the domain of the
church and religious faith and
religious authority over
interpretation of the occult because
our society was bifurcated in that way
anytime something dramatically occult
happens to anybody especially anyone
with a high rational faculty they
suddenly are an off God
because they have been inculcated with
this false dichotomy and they've never
been trained to think carefully about
the paranormal and all kinds of
different types of phenomena and
possible sources of some phenomena
have you ever had anything paranormal
happen to you many many things yes I've
had many crazy things happen to me most
of which would I have to say
unfortunately even some of the people
closest to me in my life who I had
great respect for their intellect and
some of them studied my work very
deeply but I can tell you that if some
of the things that have happened to me
happened to those people I bet you they
would have embraced God also they would
have seen light for sure but it seems
like you think that's sort of like a dumb
simpleton takeaway from a paranormal
it's a failure it's a failure it's a
failure of the test the test is for us
to be able to think through these kinds
of often absurd manifestations in a way
that increases both our cognitive
capacity and our creative imagination it's
complicated though you know like Jacques
Vallée he talks about this sort of you
know idea a lot he says that like
absurdity is what drives the phenomena
it's what makes somebody sort of
rabidly obsessed with it and want to
learn more about it he talks about you
know the sound of one hand clapping from
the Zen Cohen so it's these things that
scramble your brain kind of break all of
your priors and then make you
contemplate constantly and then and then
kind of go forth and investigate yes you
know what's going on and I and I
believe that's the devil and so but in
through that maybe you grow but then at
the same time he's also like a fan of I
think these are the likes the movie the
ninth gate that Roman Polanski movie
with Johnny Depp where he's like trying
to gain sort of occult powers yeah
collecting these devil books yeah it's
about a long time ago yeah so then you
have this Gertes story of Faust and like
you have all these sort of you know you
ally with these sort of powers and you
know if you take the occult route and not
the faith route you take the left hand
path you end up you know kind of burning
yourself alive you end up incinerating
yourself Jack Parsons would be another
sort of you end up Prometheus on the rock
right so like that doesn't sound very
good to me you know what it is a growth
process like when a caterpillar becomes a
butterfly yeah it's an incredibly messy
process and the chrysalis yeah as a
caterpillar is like turn inside out not
you know to become a butterfly right yeah
look the reason I didn't use Faust yeah my
political I mean I have I do did write a
book at one point called Faustian
futurist mm-hmm but the reason I didn't
use Faust as I could have easily you know
coming from out of Oswald Spangler's
analysis of the Faustian soul of Western
civilization and so forth and I used
Prometheus instead as a central symbol of
my philosophical project is that the
Faustian myth is already deeply
conditioned by Christianity mm-hmm right
it's an understanding of the diabolical from
out of a Christian context Prometheus
precedes Christianity it's a pre-Christian
symbol mm-hmm so it has nothing you know
inherently has nothing to do with the
Abrahamic religion but I don't yeah and
it's a positive symbol however it's also a
symbol of sacrifice meaning for sure if you
defy Zeus and Olympus yeah and if we're
ensconced in a control system run by
sadistic overlords then if you rebel
against that you're definitely going to
face adverse consequences you might even be
martyred are you familiar with the parable
of the parties this sort of it was like a
kabbalistic parable and it was these four
rabbis and you know they're all trying to
engage in these sort of celestial ascent
practices similar to you know Enoch some
speculate Paul Jesus you know went up to
heavens walk with God or whatever and you
know one of them ends up crazy two of them
end up dead and one makes it up or something
right and so it's this idea that you know if
you do engage in these sorts of investigations
or whatever it's a it's a very narrow path
yes so kabbalists who who have that story
also say you should never study kabbalah
until after I think the age of 30 35 and you
have to be married married have a family well
that's retarded okay the complete opposite to
that are the surrealists look at these guys
yeah Andre Breton Paul Elward Roger Calois Max
Ernst they're like in their early 20s you
know doing crazy shit like pushing the
boundaries of human cognition and creativity
and yeah somebody might get killed in the
process too you know life is dangerous but
look what creativity came from out of it
I don't know it seems a little nihilistic or
something I don't think it's nihilistic at
all in fact I think it's the opposite when
Nietzsche takes nihilism as his principal
target in his philosophical writings right
Nietzsche's entire philosophical project is
set up against nihilism he says that look
we are confronted globally by the advent of
nihilism like as a world historical phenomenon
we're all previously existing frameworks of
meaning including the religions that helped to
hold them up are collapsing and we and he
meant particularly European men including
America are tasked with engaging in a level
of creativity and self-determination that can
confront nihilism without the illusions and
delusions of naive religious belief systems
of the past and Nietzsche's solution to that is
radically aesthetic it's it's a it's an art
project really I mean he at one point calls the
uber mention art the artist tyrants of the future and
so and by tyrant he didn't mean like political
ruler he meant like the way in which these
people are going to go to work on the material of
the world and even the material of what the human
being is is going to be tyrannical it's like
they're not gonna hesitate and they're going to be
extremely intrepid and that's what I see in
surrealism and to me it's like the ultimate
expression embodiment of the life force of what
Bergson called Elan Vital yes you know so I don't
see it as nihilistic at all yeah it's this vital
force what how do you how does this all relate
to Herman Hesse's magic theater well there you go
so in Steppenwolf has his novel Steppenwolf which
is one of my favorite novels there's this character
grappling with nihilism Harry Haller who wants to
kill himself and he meets this very enigmatic woman
Hermine who introduces him into into this occult
underworld of people who are now this was
written in the 1920s or so and they're the first
people using psychedelic drugs and they they're
also clearly involved in theater and in staging
theatrical performances and stuff and basically
these you know countercultural people involved
with this enigmatic woman ultimately invite Harry
Haller to enter this magic theater that they let's
say have access to and he goes through this place and
it's like basically he stepped into the twilight zone and
like space and time are not normal inside this magic
theater and he is confronted with a bunch of different
performances that are meant to symbolically convey
different things and get him to reflect on certain aspects of
his subconscious in other rooms he has to engage in long
conversations in some cases conversations with like past
historical figures anyway long story short he goes through
this labyrinthine magic theater and in the end he he finds
out that like all the great creative geniuses of history are
there like from like Mozart and Beethoven to Newton so and so
forth and they oh and the last person he has to have a
conversation with is like an older version of himself and so he
has to confront himself in the future too as part of this
process and point being in the end he's let in on the secret
that the magic theater isn't this isolated space like like a
venue in our world it's a metaphor for the world that we're
living in and that that's the nature of human existence
i take this idea of the magic theater in my writings and i put it
next to this idea of the theater of cruelty that was developed by
uh the surrealist uh Antonin Artaud um who became a total lunatic
uh dysfunctionally so but uh he made a lot of interesting art in
the process and he came up with this idea that we should develop a
new form of theater that breaks down the distinction between the
spectators and the audience i mean the between the uh performers
and the spectators between the the dramatists and the audience
that this classic distinction between the performance on a stage and the
people watching it that formed in classical
greece with aeschylus that this this should be
deconstructed all right real briefly a note on greek
theater in my first book prometheus and atlas i get into this in in
great depth and detail that the reason greek sculpture becomes
like photorealistic becomes perspectively accurate at the same
time as there are the first large-scale dramatic performances
with poets like aeschylus is that it was the first moment in history
of recorded history that people were able to take the position of
spectators at a theater sitting in different places on different nights
meaning that first of all they were perceiving geometric perspective for the
first time so like one night you're in some
shitty seat in the back up here in this corner of the amphitheater
another night you're in the middle close to the action
another night you're off to this side and one thing you notice as you watch the
same play or different plays from different perspectives
is you actually notice perspective for the first time geometrically and there's a
good case to be made if you look at like for example
julian james's study the break the origin of consciousness break in the breakdown
of the bicameral mind the origin of consciousness in the breakdown of
bicameral mind he looks at like homeric literature from
archaic greece and you know the ancient mesopotamian texts
and he's like look these people's minds just did not work the way ours did their
cognitive if their cognitive structure wasn't different than their cognitive
capacities were radically not at the level that ours are and one of the things
that i believe they lacked was perspective they actually could not see
perspective the way we do and it's why archaic greek art looks like a bad
hybrid of like egyptian art and mesopotamian art then you get these
theater performances and all of a sudden you get these magnificent greek sculptures
but the other form of perspective that i think the plays cultivated in them
was um psychological perspective where for the first time people got like an
outside view of dramas in human lives and they started to see themselves as
characters they start to realize that oh what's going on in this drama is like
like oh that's like me in this situation in my life and it starts to cultivate and
deepen a sense of psychological perspective in people
and isn't it interesting how the first figure in greek drama ever to take the stage
is prometheus the prometheus trilogy of aeschylus was the first series of
dramas ever performed so now to go back to arto
so the point was this the classical drama did transform human consciousness
in a way that was conducive for the rise of our rational faculties
and our self-reflexive ability however arto now wants to take it to the next
level where now that we've developed reason and
perspective and so on and so forth and objectivity he wants to deconstruct it
in a way that allows us to again as it was the main aim of the surrealists
develop a more conscious relationship with our subconscious or make the subconscious conscious
and so he designed a form of theatrical performance where the audience was repeatedly violated
by the performers by certain types of extreme harsh lighting by performers like intruding on the personal space of the audience by suddenly subjecting people to fear and anxiety in the in the course of a performance loud noises
he identifies taboo breaking scenes that force a person who's a spectator to confront his subconscious reaction and whatever beliefs are being violated by this like taboo breaking spectacle
and he calls this the theater of cruelty
well i take the magic theater from herman hesse's steppenwolf and and synthesize it with arto's theater of cruelty
and develop this idea of a magic theater of cruelty
and by the way the thing that made that click for me is this line in one of jim morrison's songs
where he talks about us in some insane and ancient theater i don't know if you remember
you remember that it's some line from one of his songs about how we're like in some insane and ancient theater
i don't know he's he was an avid reader but yeah and so i developed this idea of a magic theater of cruelty
and suggest that this is what we're inside of
uh we are inside uh from the perspective of the thing
of the super intelligent ai that's instantiating the trickster archetype
the whole thing is like a theater where there's no distinction between the performers and the spectators
which by the way that in in a certain heretical form of hinduism there is this idea too
in the um shakta uh cult in shakti tantra there's the idea that what the conservative hindus call samsara
and what they seek moksha or liberation from or what the buddhists seek nirvana to get out of namely samsara
is not really maya a veil of illusion it is lila which is a theatrical play
and that shakti divine power is expressed through this theatrical play
including in extremely violent and cruel ways right but it's all part of the growth of the life force
and so yeah i mean i i developed this idea you know a magic theater of cruelty that hybridizes
uh hessen and artaud in a way and i think that allows us to make a lot of sense out of some of
the absurd and terrifying elements of the close encounter phenomenon
this is fascinating man you're uh you're brilliant i don't necessarily agree with you on everything
but uh the amount of connections your brain makes is remarkable it really is and uh i uh i feel like
we should do you know more of these because i i just learned so much and i i enjoy speaking
absolute pleasure and there are many other places we can go likewise it'd be an honor and yeah thank
you so much jason thank you justin awesome we just launched what i think is maybe the coolest
merch line in the world when you're wearing it it's not like you're shilling me or the channel
they're just really epic and i think they look good we have a couple of amazing designs for you
we have our cowboy ufo tee pretty epic you see there's a rancher he's witnessing a ufo a little cow
is getting abducted by the ufo in the background and then you know that i love mid-century history
specifically spooky science atomic era stuff and so we have our atomic age tea here uh pretty cool
vibe uh you got a robot serving this guy a little martini and then a ufo off to the side go to
americanalchemymerch.com americanalchemymerch.com to check out all of this amazing new apparel the
cowboy tea that i'm wearing is a hundred percent cotton super relaxed fit we went for quality on
these uh so check them out