And that's when you see that footage, and he just unloaded.
He says, I know UFOs are real.
I was inside one.
I know they were made with materials that we can't duplicate, we can't replicate.
First time you ever hear him like, fuck the noise.
My name is Jeremy Corbell.
I seek to weaponize your curiosity.
And I see a white light pop up and stop about 100 feet in the air.
On Weaponized, you've broken some amazing stories.
Matthew Brown, Dylan Borland, Jim Lekatsky.
You told us, because you were allowed to tell us, that our government has a UFO in its possession and has been able to access the inside of it, right?
Yes.
It's a Rubik's Cube.
It's a constellation.
It is a variety of investigations with different hardware, software, and mines on them to exploit in different ways.
Working on a craft is different than working with a craft.
Do you think we get another Bob Lazar coming out near term?
We almost got it, and he's dead.
Matthew Sullivan was, fact, going to testify two weeks about before he died, I think.
And that's why people and the FBI are investigating if his death was suspicious.
Somebody you know worked on the reverse engineering of a laser weapon system from a downed Russian asset.
This is an N-H-I asset.
Last name, start with T.
We're not playing that game in front of the camera.
I'm going to crack a beer for this part.
I wanted to have a drink with Jesse.
He's got water because he's an alien.
So this is back and forth, rapid fire.
Okay.
Are you independent or are you controlled?
Bro, let's not get into it, right?
You said you don't want to.
Okay.
So let's not.
We can if you want.
Bro.
This is going to be so awkward for your audience.
Before we dive into this wild episode, I want to give a huge thank you
to one of today's sponsors, Dose.
Dose for your liver is an extremely high quality, drinkable supplement.
It tastes absolutely delicious.
It makes you healthier.
And all you have to do is take it once a day.
I love nerding out and finding the best new health and wellness hacks.
And it's super easy to overlook the biggest internal organ in your body, the liver.
It's your body's most metabolically active organ.
It runs over 500 functions every single day.
It processes everything you consume.
It detoxes you daily and it supports your energy levels and your digestion.
A lot of people with bad guts actually don't realize it's linked to their liver health.
What I appreciate about Dose is that they actually have serious research behind it.
Two double-blind placebo-controlled studies showing positive impact on liver enzyme levels
and liver function.
Having data like that is very rare in the supplement space.
And it's the reason I was comfortable working with them.
No pills, no powders, and no icky taste.
Just a two-ounce shot that tastes like tangy orange juice.
It's simple, effective, and super easy to build into your routine.
New customers can save 35% on your first month of subscription by going to dosedaily.co
slash jesse or entering jesse at checkout.
Again, that's D-O-S-E-D-A-I-L-Y dot C-O slash jesse for 35% off your first month subscription.
I love this product.
I want to thank Dose so much for sponsoring the show.
Now back to today's episode.
Jeremy Corbell, Jesse Michaels.
This is an honor, and it's been a long time coming, and I'm just so grateful for you coming on the show.
This is really cool.
You need no intro, but I'm going to give you one.
Okay.
You broke the OG original whistleblower of the UFO reverse engineering program.
The guy that did it in, you know, there are guys before him like Bill Ewhouse, but in the most credible, thorough way, and that's Bob Lazar.
You made an amazing documentary about him and covered it as thoroughly as anybody, obviously, working closely with George Knapp, who broke the story.
I was going to say, I did not break that story.
I know.
The story got broke because Bob was about to get broken by opposition, and George Knapp not only broke that story with Bob, but he carried it along the way, making sure his reporting was accurate to this motherfucking day.
That's right.
Can I say those words?
You can say those.
You can say whatever you want.
We broke the fuck barrier.
We did.
And you and George are close collaborators, longtime colleagues.
He's called them your mentor, and you guys both host the podcast Weaponized.
Everybody should check that out.
So, on Weaponized, you've broken some amazing stories.
Matthew Brown, I want to get into.
I want to get into Dylan Borland.
I want to get into another person who breached the hull and walked into a UFO, not in some sort of liminal state in a dream, but in presumably a hangar, an aerospace hangar in Jim Lekatsky.
So, you've broken some of the most incredible, interesting stories when it comes to UFOs, and I'm very excited to speak to you today.
Thank you so much, Jesse.
I'm excited to speak to you.
There are things that people don't know, background things, that I think will be really interesting to people.
You didn't mention David Grush.
I want to talk to you about how that all went down.
Yeah.
He came over to George Knapp, leaned to him at a bar with the unclassified ICIG complaint.
And we took so much time vetting him to make sure, and I fought to make sure he could talk in Congress.
And he'll tell you the exact same thing.
I fought.
They didn't want him to testify.
And he's one of many they didn't want to testify.
Additionally, what people might not know is George Knapp and I did break the Commander Fravor story, the Tic Tac story.
We did it quietly, on the radio, twice.
Before the 2017 New York Times.
Yes, sir.
Reverse time machine.
Wow.
People got to be audio die decks or whatever.
They got to go in there and listen.
I can pull them up.
Well, let's get, because you just said something very interesting.
Leaning over at a bar.
Yes.
David Grush.
So what happened there?
Okay.
So there's so many things.
Where's your audience?
There's so many things Jesse and I want to talk about, because this is like actually him and me just talking.
And this is long overdue.
So when you ask me a question, I'm going to answer it directly, and then we can go from there.
What happened there?
What happened is we were in Rocket City, Alabama.
And we were there for SCU, because there were some people that are not public, that we wanted an opportunity to meet with, where it was like we could go somewhere and have a actual private in-person meeting.
So we went to the SCU thing so that we could do a journalism thing.
I happened to be filming, because that's why we were there.
I was filming.
And I'm pointing the camera at George, and I thought it was just so cute.
He's like, you know, gets to this thing.
He's overwhelmed with all this stuff.
And like he and I like to just have a beer.
I'm going to crack this at a certain point.
So bartender gives him a beer, and as I'm filming, this guy's blocking my shot.
He like comes in, and he whispers to George Knapp, and I'm protected like a pit bull, right?
So immediately I capture, I watch him, and it turns out that was David Grush.
And he's essentially, we knew about David, but we have to vet every single source, no matter how good they sound.
That's our job.
You got to vet them, right?
And that, I'm on cosmic time.
Journalists that rush stories out, they want to be first.
I'm going to be first.
I want to be right.
I want to get it right.
So he leaned over, and I got it all.
Lip readers know what he said.
He was kind of trying to do like, he didn't know it was filming.
Now he does.
Well, I'll give you an out.
What did the lip readers say that he said?
You know, essentially all he said was, my name is David Grush.
I'm an intel officer, you know, a little bit of his history.
I am going to file, or I just did file, actually, my official ICIG, Intelligence Community Inspector General, which we should break down for your audience.
A lot of people don't know what that means.
Inspector General is like the police.
Look at it that way.
How I understand it from a Simpson version, right?
Police.
The IC is Intelligence Community.
Wraps up all the Intelligence Communities.
At the top of that is ODNI, Office of the Director of National Intelligence.
But CIA is under them, as well as maybe 16 intelligence agencies that are acknowledged within the United States.
So that's what the Inspector General of the Intelligence Community is, is the watchdog of the Intelligence Community.
And that's very relevant up until this minute we're talking.
Some stuff was in the news a few days ago, and I want to break that down for people.
So David Grush provides, in absolute legal capacity, enough information for me and George to begin.
So we have our little side talks, and we're like, well, I'm like, George, you know what I got to do?
He goes, yeah, you got to take him to a bar.
I go, but he doesn't drink, because I asked him, right?
All right, we'll get him anyway.
So I met up with him later that night, and he watched me drink beers, which is glorious.
And I always, like, sip him, you know, just to stay on the level.
I think Gary Nolan was there with us, and he did actually take a shot with me.
If he says he didn't, he's lying.
I think he'll admit to it.
Gary Nolan came out to the thing.
And I got to know David a little bit.
You know, how you and I, like, get to know each other a little bit over time the first time, right?
That's what happened that day.
But then what happened after is what people don't know, which is how do you communicate about something sensitive,
just like signal, smoke signals?
How do you do it?
So we got to a point where we knew David Grush was not only legit, but everything he said is accurate,
not just to the best of his knowledge, that it is accurate.
And there's a difference there.
So that began the conversation.
What is the end goal here?
You're worried, right?
Yeah, of course he's worried.
He's a lone standing wolf telling the world something they'd never heard before, always have suspected.
And our government has covered it up for all these decades.
I'm getting goosebumps because if I was in his position, think about the pool of people that know and then the pool of people that really know anything.
It was his job to investigate black budget programs surrounding UAP.
He did 40, like, depositions, whatever you call them, and more.
This guy has put everything on the line.
Everything.
He broke the fold.
It's not for personal gain.
First question I asked him at the bar, you know, I said, you got to tell me what I'm going to find out.
What's your dirt?
What's the lowest point in your life?
Because if you're telling the truth, that's what they're going to come after.
PTSD, bro.
I was in combat in Afghanistan in 2013.
You know, I got diagnosed with post-traumatic stress disorder, sought treatment.
I got help.
Good to go.
But there was an agency that tried to dig that back up and say, oh, Dave still has ongoing issues, unmitigated.
We need to pull his clearance.
And then I had to show my medical records and be like, no, dude, I sought treatment.
Still do?
Because that's what you do.
And they tried to use that against us.
It was crazy.
Almost every service person and non-service people I know can have that.
So they, of course, attacked that in a malicious way, leaked by intelligence community to a fake journalist.
Because fake journalists don't pay people, by the way.
So that's the story of the beer.
It was the beginning of the potential of having somebody raise their hand in front of the world,
America, the Congress, the entire world, and say, not only are UFOs real,
but we are reverse engineering the craft.
We've been exploiting their derivative technologies for decades.
We've made very little progress, but a little bit.
And there were biologics, just means pilots, beings, non-human.
And that was the assessment of, that's what he followed up with.
And that's what David Gresh did.
He popped the balloon.
And now we're all just trying to, like, catch up.
And you're talking about a guy who handled the presidential daily brief,
was well regarded by a lot of his colleagues.
I also, in the name of vetting, he was one of the guys who I got to know.
You got him on camera first and brought him out.
So you didn't know him very well.
Actually, Colt Hart did.
Oh, okay.
It doesn't matter.
But I also had known him for a couple of years before.
Yes, sir.
And I met some of his colleagues.
And they all just spoke about him in super high regard.
Even colleagues who weren't working with him in an official capacity investigating UFO programs.
They just worked with him in other capacities that are prosaically well regarded.
You know, like handling the presidential daily brief.
Here's a bullet.
Or being in, you know, the National Geospatial Agency.
I want you to give his biography and all that.
But, next level.
Find somebody that doesn't like him.
Find out if they tell you, I don't like him, but.
And then they tell you what he did.
And then you're like, uh-huh.
I have met people who don't like him.
And it feels like they have ulterior motives.
Right, right.
But you still, in the early stages, you know, co-worker situation, all this.
You got people like people, don't like him, that kind of thing.
When you're investigating something, you always try to find the people that want to hurt somebody
or don't like them and see if they can't deny certain truths that you're looking to validate.
That's one tactic in journalism.
The funny thing is, when I try to kind of corroborate his claims with, you know, people I meet in
the government, I say, hey, like, what about what he's saying isn't true?
And they're like, well, a lot of it checks, to be honest.
And, like, you know, he's pretty above board as far as his background goes.
But, like, I don't know.
It's just this.
And they use these, like, hand-wavy ways to sort of explain it away.
And I'm like, okay, well, why don't you go a little deeper?
Why don't you look into it?
You know, if you have the proper clearances, you know, he gave presumably hundreds of pages
to Thomas Monheim, the IC inspector general.
Not allegedly, whatever word you said.
I don't know about the amount of pages.
No, no, no.
I'm like, no, it doesn't matter.
Yeah.
You're right.
And 40 firsthand people that worked directly on the craft.
Not only that, but I have reason to believe that there are factions involved in UFO disclosure.
And there's a specific faction that's sort of come out, you know, and, you know, is gung-ho
about a certain disclosure to a certain extent.
And I think they weren't really anticipating David Grush.
Oh, no, they weren't.
That was a planned thing is how to move somebody from, he's lived in his whole life, you know,
kind of in, you're not going out there trying to be on social media.
He lived his whole life, I say, in the shadows, right?
This happens with a lot of these intel guys.
They're not used to the public attention and then good or bad, it hurts them or it makes
them feel better.
I tell them, praise and blame is all the same, man.
You got to be right with yourself and your family and your dogs and make sure, this guy
got dogs and make sure that you're solid because that public attention, when you bring your
head out of the parapet above, it can really harm people.
It has harmed people.
Absolutely.
Well, I also, I think it's really important, though, to make clear, you know, upon questioning,
you know, him and others, I feel like it's very clear that his sources aren't only the
ones of the people who want disclosure to a certain line.
His sources go deeper than that.
And so there's this constant question of circular reporting.
Are you just talking to the people who did NIDS and Bigelow and all this sort of, you know,
external OSAP stuff?
Even they don't believe, though.
Even Dr. LeCasse doesn't believe we should handle disclosure.
Don't kick a sleeping dog.
That's what I've been told.
Every time I got to the top of the food chain, the highest George and I could ever get to,
every single time.
It's like they practice that saying.
So even people that you're naming don't think disclosure is a good thing.
So imagine the people that have, their whole lives have been to guard it.
You can't get that out of them.
That's been their job, protective programs.
It's protective programming.
Why do you think that, you know, when you get to the inner layers of this program, it
always comes out that like, oh, if you knew what I knew, you wouldn't want this stuff out.
Yeah.
First of all, you say program.
I think it's really important to break that down.
People say the legacy program.
Dude, that's a holding name.
Like Bill is a holding name for a team of FBI, Frank.
It's a group of people, right?
So the legacy program, when people say that, yeah, program.
There are programs and they are isolated from one another.
So not every single person was a technician directly on a craft that David Grush brought
to the ICIG.
They had direct exposure to the program with an S, right?
So that's really important to know.
We call it the program, the legacy program.
Bro, many names.
Palm is Apple in French.
I was just told by GSP.
Apple is Apple.
You know, so different names, same thing.
But it's a Rubik's Cube.
It's a constellation.
It is a variety of investigations with different hardware, software, and minds on them to exploit
in different ways.
Working on a craft is different than working with a craft, right?
That's what's so weird.
I'm curious to hear if this is your experience because you've done this for decades longer
than me.
But for my experiences, I always think, okay, in a few months, I'm going to get to the bottom
of this.
I'm going to figure this, you know, and then a few months go by and you learn about this
whole new weird aspect to this.
Careful, though.
Yeah.
How so?
Because there are protection programs to dilute.
Sure.
To misdirect.
And they're seductive.
They're shiny.
You want to believe it.
You have to be careful of the next aspects.
But it is an onion.
There's layers to it.
I didn't mean to say there aren't.
It's just be careful with it.
For sure.
Well, no, I think you have to think with extreme epistemic humility.
What does epistemic mean?
Not a way of knowing.
So you can't jump to any sort of conclusion.
You can't snap anything to grid.
You have to sort of say, OK, I'm going to wait for corroboration for that in the future.
But this could be counterintel to like everything.
You have to process everything.
If you listen to Dr.
Lukatzky said on my program with George, you know, he gave a warning about two things.
One is the protective programs and the disinformation that he knows he never identified who somebody lied while their hand was up in Congress knowingly, I think he was saying.
And then he said that people believe things because they're shown in official capacity.
But I'm not talking about stupid nonsense where people are saying Yankee blue.
That was a that was a psyop.
They're trying to pretend that that existed in the capacity they say.
So he warned us against that.
Dr. Lukatzky.
He also warned us very strongly, if you watch, that we're going to lose the ability to really engage this topic without the brightest minds because we're not teaching inside scientifically the younger generations.
And he is scared about that, that because of the secrecy, which he doesn't want full secrecy on this, but because of it, we are going to fall behind with the American mechanics of how to interrogate the UAP problem.
And that's what's really interesting about his new book, New Insights.
At the end of it, he goes into a bunch of modalities and frameworks that he clearly wants spread among young STEM students all over the country.
He gets into high frequency gravitational waves and we rotate solid state rotating superconductors for gravitational manipulation and like really crazy shit.
They should hire you because let me just tell you, most people don't read his book and take from that what he means.
And you have to translate complex things into you don't dumb anything down.
You simplify it until the next question is asked and he needs to practice that because his voice, man, he's done more for, he has actually done more from a knowledge standpoint of transparency on this than I think most people throughout history.
If you go and you read his books, like you did, but we need bright minds to look at it.
We need everybody asking the next question.
Like when I started this man, people thought it was like UFOs, this guy, right?
So now we're at a consensus reality where it's like, okay, there's a there there, but what's the question not being asked?
Did you find it frustrating when he was on your podcast and you asked him about him stepping inside of a UFO and he said yes, but then he also was like very clear that he couldn't say much more than what he had said in the book.
Is you're officially allowed to tell us that the United States government has in its possession, a craft of unknown origin, and you were able to access the inside.
Is that correct?
The wording that you read is correct.
Ah, you're going beyond the wording.
No, I'm not.
I'm not.
I'm asking you, did that meeting happen?
And is it true?
And it's true.
Yes, yes.
Okay, you're telling us, you told us because you were allowed to tell us that our government has a UFO in its possession and has been able to access the inside of it, right?
Yes.
Why do you think he was able to get that cleared?
The fact that he stepped inside of a UFO?
Right, and that conspiracy, like why could he get that cleared?
Well, I think it's a reasonable question.
No, it's extremely reasonable.
Yeah.
But it creates a conspiratorial mindset, right?
Like, oh, we've distrusted government on this.
Why are they allowing it now?
It's like people ask questions like, how is Jeremy and George not in trouble for, and how do they obtain such a variety of different products from argument that I'll call sensitive most likely, right?
First of all, about me and George, it's called fucking journalism.
And if you are not seeing that, you are looking at the wrong thing.
So with Lekatsky, why?
You asked a bunch of questions there.
So why did they let him?
Well, you know, not everybody at a dobser desk, you know, is equal.
You know, and you can submit a book in one way and say it's fictitious, or you can submit it and say it's, this is fact.
And he did the fact way, right?
It's harder.
Took a long time.
George knows how long it took with each book.
Why did they let him?
I know for a fact there are people in the mechanisms of government that let things get through because they're on our side.
Truth.
I suspect that's why.
It's not some big plan.
Dude, if this was planned, I would kick back, relax, and stop and not worry because then we've got a planned situation.
This is Vietnam.
Everything has been provoked.
It's been fought for millimeter by millimeter for years and decades.
So what you get from him is the absolute factual information.
It's not theoretical.
It's factual.
And so he says when he doesn't know stuff.
He's a senior DIA rocket scientist with a long history.
And I think it's important for people to realize there's probably a war going on inside the government.
And there are probably elements of the quote unquote legacy program that want itself outed or partially outed.
Like there are members of, you know, inside these programs that think the way they're being run is ridiculous.
That's why you had the vice president of Lockheed Martin trying to get the craft and hardware that they have obtained a long time ago out the back door into the sunlight through the front door and studied that way.
They saw the writing on the wall and it was being facilitated by Dr. Colin Kelleher, Dr. James Lukatzky, a bunch of people they worked with.
That's the truth, what you just said.
There are a lot of people that realize there's no right, there's no purpose to hold back from human beings the ultimate truth, whatever that might be.
I got some guesses, you know, maybe there are UFOs and they're not from here, whatever that means.
I mean, why would you build a Ferrari not to go fast?
Why would you make something that appears that it could travel amongst the stars if it doesn't?
And that gives you a sense of at least one aspect of origin.
Yes.
Of course, there might be more.
So, yeah, dude, I look, man, it's my favorite topic.
And you and I got so many things we can talk about that I agree with what your analysis is.
Well, I want to touch on something that you just mentioned, which is the VP at Lockheed Martin, his name was Jim Ryder.
That's right.
And he gave a very interesting speech called The Garment of the Gods.
And it's very strange.
It's about the veil thinning.
And he talks about extrasensory perception and consciousness.
But he's a VP at Lockheed Martin Space Systems who's very well respected.
The idea that everything from spoons to stones are conscious is gaining academic credibility.
Who wrote that?
One of the most senior physicists in Canada.
It's the only conclusion we have.
Everything is conscious.
We're just discussing amount and levels.
I find him and Lekatsky's language around this topic very interesting.
Lekatsky talks about Plato's cave and consciousness.
And it affects you.
Yeah.
To know something this big and hidden, it's like if you've ever taken a psychedelic, right?
You've seen this world around you at all times, but you are not initiated to what that world is or means.
So you might see like a tie-dye or Dancing Bears of the Grateful Dead.
But as soon as you breach the hull of that craft, you see a world that has always been hidden to you, but has always been there.
And it has disturbed people to their core.
And then they start getting angry that other people don't get to know.
And this goes back to your question.
Was it frustrating?
Why did he not go outside the parameters of his book?
Why was he allowed to say that?
I told you why he was allowed to say it most likely.
Yeah, you can see on my face.
I hold my emotions like right here.
You could see I'm frustrated.
I'm not trying to hurt the guy.
I mean, you know, I'm sure they all got mad at me at different times.
I'm just pressing because I know people want to know.
And he can't say the words that aren't printed because he's the kind of guy you want protecting secrets for America.
He's the exact kind of guy.
It's so interesting and it's so messy because it's like, ideally, if this thing is like a portal or a gateway, the object is,
to a new sense of the actual true nature of reality, this should be for humanity.
It should be for everybody.
What is human beings' knowledge and information?
We own that, right?
It is.
So having that held back, you know, you know the reason, you know, okay, America first weaponization, strategic surprise, strategic advantage, technological advantage.
Like, I get that.
Now, that's some like Stone Age thinking when we're in the Jetsons, you know, that we're past that now.
So, but that is, I understand what, so they need to formally acknowledge the known facts, formally acknowledge the unknown facts.
They really need to define the terms and boundaries and parameters and topography of what we're looking at because if they don't do that, if they don't, if they give us like this partial disclosure of stuff,
then we get kind of lost with what it means to be human.
We get lost with understanding our position in what it means to exist.
And there might be questions that are unasked there, that are profound, that have profound answers that we just haven't, I'm like eating the mic.
No, you're kidding.
We just haven't been able to ask.
And how do we evolve if we don't have the right questions?
So we need, you don't need to tell somebody how to make a nuclear bomb, but you need to tell them nuclear physics exists and you can study it and try to protect that part.
So we've got to get to the point where we're all at a consensus reality that matches up a little bit better with actual reality.
And if we, if we do that, then we're going to have questions.
And those questions, the answers might be a little disturbing if you're a person that gets disturbed, but it will be the truth and the truth.
That's what's going to help us evolve.
And so that's why I'm so upset with the secret keeper.
Well, it makes sense that they wouldn't disclose it because on the one hand, you're kind of ceding your authority to this higher thing.
That's flying with impunity at your most, around your most sensitive sites, around your nuclear installations, tampering with the nukes themselves.
So you don't want to admit that if you're in some position of governmental authority.
And then you don't know as far as, you know, what could confer a tactical advantage to the adversary.
Maybe you haven't figured it out, but it's this weird cat and mouse game theory thing vis-a-vis China and Russia.
And so it's this weird thing where they have this asymmetric knowledge on the nature of reality, which they should not have any right to vis-a-vis normal people or scientists.
But their incentives make it so that, you know, they're just not going to go full open kimono anytime soon.
Well, don't go so fast or quick.
I mean, you know, what are we fighting for?
Unless we can wrest it out of them.
We can provoke.
You can't, just how you can't give anybody anything, because all you can do, you put it in their hand, but it's an object.
You can't give anybody anything.
You can lead by example.
You can't take anything.
It's not just one person's thing.
You need to provoke, and they need to give.
And when they give, you need to receive.
And that's, so I'm not trying to be oblique here.
It is an ontological issue.
This thing, and ontological, I believe, means relating to the existence of being and existence itself, relating to the existence of being, right?
Is that what it means?
Yeah.
So, this is, the UFO thing is a symbol.
There are things a lot deeper than UFOs, I suspect.
I agree.
I think it's the tip of the iceberg.
Yeah, but it's a symbol.
It's a symbol of freedom of thought.
Because if you, if we can talk about it with the right words and factual information, then we have freedom of speech.
Freedom of speech causes debate.
Debate causes thought.
Then we have freedom of thought.
It's fucking beautiful, man.
What are we fighting for?
It is beautiful.
And I hope we're on the verge of a paradigm shift.
Because, I mean, how do you feel now that the Department of War has a website with more hits than, you know, people in America?
And, you know, we have stuff coming out.
And you can say that the stuff often is repackaged, repurposed things that have already kind of existed in the open source world.
I find it hilarious that that is what's making, you know, the Citadel scientific gatekeepers like Neil deGrasse Tyson take it seriously, is the fact that it gets a stamp of approval from authority.
So it kind of shows that they were never doing science in the first place.
But how do you feel?
Do you feel vindicated?
Do you think it's going to keep going and we're going to get more?
Or how do you feel about where we're at?
Yeah.
I don't self-reflect when I'm fighting, when I'm going forward.
That's like the death gargle if you're doing martial athletics is thinking about what you just did wrong or, you know, what happened yesterday.
You need to be fully forward-facing and forward-looking.
So what I feel is optimistic, but I'm an optimist, you know.
But now there's tangible evidence that we should all have optimism.
But don't get complacent in that optimism.
Optimism is only powerful if there's action behind it.
So what we need to do in every single way, every person, we need to fight for what we want.
If we want truth, we have to fight for truth.
If we want inner peace, we have to fight for inner peace.
Counterintuitive, but it's true.
People ask me all the time, what can I do?
It's like they feel powerless.
I'm not this.
I don't have this.
A microphone.
I'm starting a podcast.
Bro, I figured it out.
Use your voice.
Now, how do you do that?
I talked to some grade school teachers.
I talked to some high school teachers.
And I talked to some professors at major universities all in one weekend, right?
They were all there at the McMinimins UFO Fest, which is the finest thing in the world.
You got to come to me next time you get a golf cart and a six-pack of beer.
It sounds epic.
And I was put in jail one morning.
And that's a true fact.
What?
It's hilarious.
So what you can do is you can show other people your curiosity.
If you have a class, none of us have the answers.
You got a class?
Teach it.
What do you know?
How do we separate critical thinking?
The average singular person with nothing, there are five followers on Twitter.
And they're like, what do I do?
There's a woman that came up to me.
She's a little bit older.
I'm like, oh, don't worry if you have five followers.
Say what you're thinking and tag every representative that is fighting for this.
Tag the Department of War.
Tag at Energy.
That's the Department of Energy.
Tag them.
And here's why I know that's what you should do.
Because I get calls from people that saw the tags and it affects them personally and it starts building.
So imagine if everybody did that.
Rep Luna, great job.
Keep fighting.
Don't stop.
Oh my gosh.
People read that stuff and they go.
I mean, I notoriously don't because it's toxic for me.
There's organized attempts at that.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
But that's what the average person can do.
If you're a scientist, look at it from a scientific perspective.
If you're a philosopher, look at it from a philosophic perspective.
Teach it.
Pass it on.
Show people your curiosity.
And they'll be weaponized just like you and me, Jesse.
Let's go.
Yeah.
I want to talk about how you got into UFOs, which is described very well in this new movie, Sleeping Dog.
The first person that I ever pointed a camera at and was like, oh, fuck, it's like a Rubik's Cube.
You know, I got to get this person talking.
It was really hard was John Lear.
It started where a lot of people have to start with UFOs, which is you have to start with the widest possible filter.
And for you, that was embodied in a man named John Lear.
He taught me how to keep my mind open, but not let my marbles fall out because he was spilling marbles sometimes.
And it was, I'm going to crack a beer for this part.
I wanted to have a drink with Jesse.
He's got water because he's an alien.
There's my beer.
Yeah.
So I, like you, I'm not going to repeat what people can watch in a movie, right?
I, like you, I think like everybody who gets interested in something other than themselves, you know, they look outward.
And the ancient Greeks used to say that the stars were pinpricks from the beaks of hummingbirds.
So that was a beautiful cosmology.
And then all of a sudden science stepped in and goes, actually, it's fucking cooler than that.
That sounds cooler than science to me.
No, I don't know.
I, I, the orbiting planets, galaxies.
I'm come on.
I'm going to take the beaks of hummingbird pinprints.
Okay.
So I love hummingbirds, man.
They're fucking fantastic.
They're amazing.
What they can do.
Anyway, um, so I got curious and I've said this before, you know, I heard George Knapp's voice interviewing a guy named Bob Lazar on the radio.
So they were replaying it on one station, probably K rock or something.
I was a dumb ass kid.
I don't know what station, you know, I wasn't really tuned into the whole coast to coast thing.
I was 13 and something really happened to me that day.
And I, I, people make jokes when I say my, my curiosity is weaponized.
So I started making jokes.
It's like when people call me, you know, fuck you, four name online.
My family all now calls me four name.
It's like, you have to embrace the thing.
You do.
So what I embraced in that moment is that Bob Lazar said, it's not a reactionary propulsion system.
It's a, I think he said, it's a field propulsion system.
You're falling where you need to get, which is the story of my life.
Actually, which is hilarious, but you're like falling to it.
And that just like flipped this switch in me.
And I was like, holy shit.
If what he's saying is true about travel, then distance no longer matters.
Cause everybody told me, um, I wasn't into UFOs and stuff, but when it came up, when you're
a young kid, it's like all the scientists, like the Neil deGrasse Tyson's, well, there's
no way life is probably way out in the universe, but don't be silly.
They can't be coming here.
The distances are so vast.
You'd have to travel the speed of light almost for 36 years to get to our closest plan, all
this bullshit.
And I thought, damn, they really got it figured out unless Lazar was right.
So I was like, because from rockets to roller skates, it's, um, push something out the back.
You go for it called reactionary propulsion system.
So all of a sudden, if you're falling into time space, distance is irrelevant.
And I was sitting there as a dumb ass kid thinking, oh my God, is this guy telling the truth?
That's what I was thinking.
Cause I thought then, obviously it's not hummingbirds.
Obviously there are tons of planets that are in the Goldilocks zones in these hundreds of
billions of galaxies, not just our galaxy.
And I'm like, is he telling the truth?
And then I went and, you know, just like met up with my girlfriend and started doing jujitsu
more and like just dropped it like it's hot.
But I never forgot that moment, that feeling.
It taught me that authority is something we bestow upon people, not something that they
truly are.
They can have more knowledge than you.
That's what the word sensei means is born before knowledge in you is born before knowledge
in me.
So you're my sensei at this, right?
So everybody's teaching each other.
A sensei is somebody that he has, or she has certain knowledge that's born before.
So you pass it on one generation otherwise, and it's gone because it's a physical art.
It's not written down.
It's transmitted physically.
You have to actually choke someone out, right?
So to just back up, because I get so excited about this moment, I feel it as if it was
yesterday.
That's how it really got started.
But I was a kid.
I was sure I was just going to do the martial athletics thing my whole life.
I didn't think I was smart enough to do other things.
And then I thought, well, maybe I am, but this is what I like doing.
So I'm going to do what I like, because if I do what I like, I'm going to get good at it
because I'm going to practice it 10,000 times.
Then all hell broke loose.
And this is what you were talking about.
As you know, we have a new starship.
Of course, we have a health care center on board.
Ask what my new favorite product in it is?
iRestore's Illumina Face Mask.
This mask is like a med bed for your face.
It's lightweight, super convenient, cordless, and runs red, blue, and infrared light therapy
all at once.
The same type of technology NASA studied for skin healing in space.
It's safe for your eyes, too.
So you don't have to sit there like a statue.
You can live your life.
I've definitely had a few late nights reading about magnetic pull shifts.
But with this mask, I look like I actually slept.
Did I?
That's debatable.
It's warm, wireless, convenient, and makes your skin feel super soft.
And iRestore is kicking off their summer savings with some very big discounts.
Right now, you can get the Elite Plus Illumina Face Mask bundle at an exclusive deal when you
use code JESSE at iRestore.com.
That's JESSE, J-E-S-S-E, at iRestore.com.
Please support our show and tell them we sent you.
Because of an illness, I couldn't physically train.
So I said, what am I interested in?
Fell into art, fell into then getting a camera.
That was cool to see that you did that Sharon Tate exhibit.
That was amazing.
I didn't realize how deep and rich of an art background that you had.
And that was kind of an expression of the pain of the illness that you fell into.
Dude, you learned that from the movie?
Yeah.
Shit, I did.
Okay.
And it really, the movie's really good.
And I recommend everybody watch it because it really, it helped me understand your psychology.
Okay.
And where you're coming from, what you're motivated by.
Yeah.
And I think UFO space, now, you know, I didn't need that from the movie because we've gotten
to know each other.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
But UFO space can be a hall of mirrors.
And if somebody doesn't know you personally, I think it's a really good way to kind of
get to know you.
That's what the kid sold me on, you know, that and the self-defense mechanism of showing
my personal life.
But yeah, but I think that moment you were talking about was, okay, I've got this camera.
First time I pointed it at somebody, they spilled the beans.
It was my grandmother, right?
And she told me a story about my family that she had kept hidden from everybody.
And she was like 90 or something.
And I recorded it.
I'm like, holy shit.
So I pointed it at John Lear because I was like, who can I get to that seems to have these
wild ideas?
And let's say crazy.
It wasn't crazy at all.
Very sane, man.
You know, CIA pilot did some incredible stuff.
One of the youngest people ever to climb the Matterhorn.
The dude has had so many life experiences people don't know.
Won a bunch of flight records as well.
Like really amazing, esteemed pilot.
Bro.
So he called me back, finally.
And it was so like, come over, Las Vegas, Nevada.
Yeah, I'll be here.
It was the weirdest call.
And I fucking packed my bags and I looked at my wife and there's a scene in the movie.
I know the kid, my voice is all hoarse.
That was after that first trip.
The first thing I, Michael just, I said, when you make it, when you tell this story, don't
put anything visually out of order to see it exactly like it happened.
First time I roll up to his gate, filming it.
Like that's all real.
Exactly in the order it happened.
So because of his openness to me, I mean, he didn't tell me shit about UFOs at first,
but he was testing me.
Right.
But that's how it started.
And then I would just see these floods of people over the years just come into his house.
He'd let everybody in.
They tell him sometimes the craziest and you could tell they weren't rap so tight stories.
And he just listened like, like he cared because he did care.
And then other people come in and they were CIA, FBI, NSA, amazing pilots.
I mean, just all these people, this world of people that I would never have had contact with
because I had a camera.
They would talk with me.
It looked, they mistook me as a authority figure with that camera.
But, but what John did was he had no filter and that's the trap.
The trap is you belief and actual functional reality start to blur when you have heard it all.
Yeah.
Which he did.
Start talking about soul catchers on the moon and all sorts.
I can't, I can't verify his craziest theory, his, his wildest theory.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I can't verify.
Well, uh, what did he tell you that did check?
Because I think it's important to caveat about him.
He broke the F-117 to George Knapp.
He actually knew a lot about advanced aviation well ahead of anybody in the kind of civilian world
and was kind of, you know, hanging out at Dreamland at Area 51 before anybody knew it was even real.
So he definitely knew some real stuff.
Bro, I have original photographs from 1977.
Groom Lake, lake level with a chain going across.
John Lear drove out there many times back in the day when security was different.
And he came, I'll show you the photographs.
It's amazing.
He wrote to me, let's, it's Groom Lake, you moron.
Let's go Wednesday.
Because Wednesday was the famous night, nights that they would fly the sport model.
So what he did was he sat there drinking beers on the back of his pickup truck with a buddy
of his who I know.
And he snapped a bunch of photos in a row of Groom Lake at lake level.
You've never seen a photo like this before unless I put it out or Lear.
I don't know if it's leaked online, but I'll give you a print.
Then what he did, because it's John fucking Lear and he's so,
and they knew his dad, William P. Lear, inventor of the Learjet,
Learjet 8-track stereo, became Motorola, his company, the whole crazy shit.
But worked on some amazing stuff with people that you talk about sometimes, by the way.
Hans and Brown.
Not saying shit.
You're going to talk about what you know will be, you'd be my sensei on that.
So what he does, because he's so John Lear, he takes his Panera, boom, boom, boom, boom, boom.
He sees the dust trails in the desert.
You see the dust trails of the, what the fuck is this guy doing out there?
Daylight, sitting on the back, tailgating with a beer, right?
He takes the 35-millimeter film thing out of the camera, hides it under his ashtray,
puts it in another, does an identical set of photos.
And when they came, they said, John Lear, okay, well, you can't be here.
And, you know, we're confiscating the camera.
He goes, no, it's not my camera.
We're taking the film.
They took the film and left.
John drives home.
That's how I have a photo of Groom Lake at lake level with a chain that I will give you a print of.
Whoa, crazy.
77.
What?
That was the year I was born.
Oh, my God.
He did that.
That's crazy.
So what did he tell me that was true?
He did break the story of the stealth fighter, but it was Ned Day.
It was George Knapp's mentor in journalism.
Shout out to Ned Day.
Big sip here.
Shout out to Ned.
I've learned about Ned from George.
So John had some credibility.
He also knew a lot about CIA operations when they were flying drugs because he'd never ask what was in his flight.
He'd fly anywhere at any time.
And he gave me all these, like, this footage of him going in, like, these tiny little runways made of dirt flying for the CIA.
Well, you're on Contra's situation.
He was moving drugs a lot of the time.
Yeah, Felice.
He says, I don't know.
I'm just a bus driver, you know?
There's a famous photo of him with G. Gordon Liddy.
And, like, you're like, this guy's in with, like, the spookiest of spooks.
Right.
And that's why people think people would try to influence him in the negative ways.
And maybe they did, but most people like me love, there's something about John Lear.
He had a laugh.
I've only heard one other human being on planet Earth, and one day I hope to achieve this laugh.
It is the most joyous, belly laughing, almost, like, wink at the same time, you're on to something, you're on to something.
It's just this really inspiring laugh.
So he rolled deep with some people.
So he verifiably gave good evidence about a whole bunch of terrestrial stuff to the news station in Las Vegas at KLAS.
He had credibility there.
He was running for senator or state senator at the time or something.
And then he walks in with this UFO madness, and nobody, Ned Day, George's mentor, he said, I think he said, if this was true, I would have already known about it, John.
George is, like, peeking over.
He's like a young reporter, you know.
And he's like, hey, John, I'll check out the files.
And that's how it started.
So that's why.
Did I answer your question?
You did.
Sometimes people say I don't answer questions.
I'm just pumped.
No, that was a thorough answer.
Describe your first time meeting Bob Lazar.
Oh, wow.
You know what that's like.
I now am.
It's so surreal.
I mean, I'm honored to have had that experience myself.
It teaches you a lot.
Use the word honored a lot.
Like, you know how we all have the same amount of time?
So people choose if they want to spend it together, right?
It should always be an honor with somebody you're hanging with because you're both choosing in space time with limited amount of life.
But anyway, so first time meeting Bob Lazar.
Well, first of all, reverse the tape.
You know that I wanted to know if he's a liar or not.
That was the only thing I wanted to know.
If he was not a liar, then, I mean, it's so, like, then distance doesn't matter.
That's in my brain, caveman brain.
That's what I thought.
I want to know he's a liar because the distance doesn't matter.
That's my line of thinking.
So John kept telling me that George Knapp won't talk to anybody because I've been trying for years to get to George.
Bob Lazar, there's no way.
But he does, you know, John always wanted him to come for, like, a birthday party.
So he always had these big birthday parties.
Really wanted to brag that Lazar was his friend, right?
So he kept kind of telling me, you know, maybe Lazar will show up this year.
And I'm always, like, fucking call him.
And then, you know, I'm like, I would love to just, no cameras.
So what happened was, answer your question.
One day, I'm just filming with John like I did every day for years or every week.
At least I'd go out there every two weeks.
So, oh, God, what happened?
Oh, and he goes, Lazar's coming over.
First thing he says to me, I go, oh, shit, because I got my cameras already all set up.
We're doing our daily thing.
How well known was Bob at the time?
Right.
See, it's very different now.
Yeah.
It's very different.
So niche.
Right.
So, like, nobody knew his name unless you're a UFO nerd on the Paranet, they call it, right?
So, like, a very popular city councilman or something.
Less than that.
But in UFO land.
Yeah, sure.
He was UFO Jesus.
You know, he was the Messiah.
Yeah.
You know, the unwanted.
Like, he didn't want the attention.
It's the weirdest conundrum of a guy.
I call them the big foot of UFOs.
Is he real?
Does he even really exist?
So my first experience meeting him was, like, first I go total respect mode.
I'm like, I can't.
I'm not even a filmmaker.
Never made a film.
Putting away all the cameras.
I don't want him to feel like he's walking into a bear trap.
And I'm like, John, just talk with your friend.
But I knew that all that was out there were these tiny little clips of him, these small
little hard-to-find interviews, and that the majority, 99% of what you read, by getting
to know Lear and all this, it wasn't true.
So here's my pitch.
He comes in.
I'm just looking at him.
You know, really good to meet you.
Yeah, I'm making a movie, I think.
Um, Bob, when I get a respectful moment of silence, Bob, um, I don't know if you're telling
the truth, but I do know from knowing John, the entire world within this UFO little silo
is saying things that aren't true about you.
And three minutes of you talking would completely change the dynamic of, um, the ratio of what
people know, because it's just not out there.
Do you mind if I push record and ask you a couple of questions about UFOs?
And that's when you see that footage and he just unloaded.
I know there are alien craft here from another planet.
I, now, I saw other ones, but I was inside one.
I know it was not made on Earth.
I know it was made with materials that we cannot fabricate, we cannot duplicate, and we've never
been able to.
I know it uses a power source that's so advanced that we could only dream of something along
those lines.
And the energy density on it is phenomenal.
And I, and I was just looking at him like, holy fuck.
First time you ever hear him like, fuck the noise.
So, so, so I thank him.
He sits down with Lear and never released his footage.
Michael put it in the movie because I gave him 20 years of my footage and he just used
it and it's, he's with Lear and he's arguing with Lear about Lear's crazy ideas.
Right.
And, and, and so you see Bob all the way back then being like the rational dude.
The greys were controlling the soul sucker on the moon and when you die, it sucks up
your soul and it gets reprocessed unless the greys steal it.
I mean, come on, John.
What the, what the fuck?
And it just, it just, it just, what it was like was like, okay, now I really got to find
out.
Well, he's, he's a walking mind fuck because he, that's a cool term.
He is.
Cause you, I, so I have the same motivation as you.
And as you know, and I, and, and I, you know, as of a few years ago, probably netted out more
skeptical than believer when it came to his story, not necessarily the like surface level
details, but I thought maybe there was sort of like a cover for something else or something.
How do you know the information is all that you, whatever information you have, you have
to base your assessment.
A hundred percent.
And I, at the, you know, at the time and even now have immense respect for Jacques Vallée,
sort of godfather of UFO research.
And he had said some negative things.
I pushed him on it once at my ranch alone.
He and me were sitting there and I love him with all my heart.
This is nothing negative, but I pushed him.
I don't want to get into it, but like, what, where did that come from specifically?
Why do you say that?
How do you know that?
Do you know that?
Are you just saying that?
And I'm just saying, yeah, we are friends, but I stick with, I stick where I stand on
that one.
It wasn't compelling, but, but dude, he's incredible and everything else is compelling.
But that, that idea of.
But you stress, you wanted to know where he was coming from.
You felt.
Is there something I don't know?
Right.
Tell me.
I knew where it all came from.
The, I know exactly specifically who it came from, why they said it, what their secondhand
knowledge is that all in the scientific world, they start spreading around that somehow.
So, you know, that he's a marionette, you know, right.
He's some sort of MK ultra.
Like he had bullshit.
Yeah.
But, but I do want to address one thing, which is that I did have and do have a secret and
that's for me.
And what that is, is why I knew that Bob Lazar was telling it as it is, meaning a facility
like that exists, exactly what's inside of it exists.
Because I wanted to find out if Lazar was actually there and saw it for his own eyes or if he
was lying and being used as a marionette.
So that day I knew for the first time, because I asked him certain questions, I knew that
it was worthy of deep, deep, deep investigation.
It took me.
So you already knew about the existence of S4?
I say that in, I say that in the movie that there was every, a lot of people knew about
the existence of S4 theoretically, what I'm trying to, but it sounds like you had a pretty
good source.
What I'm, what I'm trying to do is go as far as I can, but we have to respect one thing
as a journalist.
When someone says to you, um, this is my, this is for you to know, not to say if you break
that one fucking time you're done.
Yeah.
Nobody will ever trust you.
And it's so tempting sometimes.
Of course.
I'm just trying to say as cleanly, I'm not being oblique.
I'm like, you know, it's a bright room, sunglasses off.
I'm trying to tell you what I can while respecting my oath.
Yeah, of course.
And that is that I didn't go.
You had good reason to believe.
Yes.
I had, I had very solid, good reason to know that Lazar was correct.
Now, was he there, right?
Was he there and did he see it?
You know, cause that's another trick that's played when you're spilling information, like
use people as emissaries to propagate a truth or a lie.
So I hope I explained that to the satisfaction of your amazing and beautiful audience.
And, you know, that's, that I had cause to want to bullet test Lazar.
And then meeting him was the first step to me saying, okay, this guy is not a liar, but
I need to really find out.
Legend has it that in 1943, the Navy tried to teleport a ship in what's known as the Philadelphia
Experiment.
And it worked, sorta.
It disappeared, reappeared, and then half the crew got atomically fused into the ship's
walls.
Others just vanished.
No one was where they were supposed to be.
Talk about a breakdown in communication.
You know what that sounds like?
Your team.
Before you had Quo.
This year, upgrade your system to a workspace that keeps your team from shattering across
dimensions.
If you've ever tried to schedule a meeting across five time zones and six different platforms,
you know the horror of losing people to the ether.
That's why today's episode is brought to you by Quo, spelled Q-U-O, the business communication
system built so you never miss a call.
Your entire team can handle calls and texts from one shared number, so no more missed messages
or dropped conversations.
Everyone sees the full thread, replies are faster, and customers actually feel taken care
of.
It's the number one rated business phone system on G2, which is the premier place where
you review these sort of workspace applications.
It has over 3,000 reviews there, and more than 90,000 businesses rely on it to stay connected.
So it has an amazing track record.
No vanishing, no fusing into calendars, just your team, fully entangled and synced across
time zones, timelines, and even caffeine levels.
Money is on the line.
Always say hello with Quo.
Try Quo for free, plus get 20% off your first six months when you go to Quo.com slash Jesse.
That's Quo.com slash Jesse.
This guy is not a liar, but I need to really find out.
Yeah, and I think something I want to talk to you about is the fact that you really corroborated
his presence at S4 Area 51, because you spoke to some other people that one of the pilots
that flew the Blackbird, really cool fucking plane.
Yeah, I mean, look, in so many ways, not public, but also public.
I got one dude on Ancient Aliens to give his testimony that he saw Lazar there.
Wild.
Yeah, getting on a bus.
It doesn't prove flying saucers, but it proves Lazar was there.
He proves he was there, yeah.
Oh, dude, there's so many things like that.
That's what I always say when people are like, do you believe him?
I'm like, I 100% at this point think he was there, and I 100% think S4 exists, and then
I'm high probability on the story, you know?
It's a great-
But like, I can't say I'm 100%, you know?
But after spending time with him, why I say he's a walking mindfuck is I asked him all
my most skeptical questions, and the dude didn't bat an eye.
He was cool with me just hurling everything.
And to him, he's probably annoyed, right?
Because he hears all these things ad nauseum, and this is like, you know, one of his last
kind of media tour.
Maybe he does something else, but as you know, he hates media.
And he's just getting like all these skeptical questions thrown at him from this kid he just
met.
And he handled all of them gracefully.
And he's a great human being, and he's a fighter.
People don't know that.
Like, he's very strong.
He just doesn't want more drama in his life, and he doesn't want to cause more pain, which
I can relate to, to his family, to his beautiful wife, and all the animals.
He's had five heart attacks, too, since-
Are you allowed to say that?
Yeah, it was on our episode.
He talked about it publicly.
Okay.
So, yeah.
There's a lot of-
He said it's just from stress.
He said his arteries are clear.
I've had five heart attacks from stress.
And other things from stress.
And look, man, I really try to keep the personal stuff away, because I've had problems with that.
But there was something in what you said, just kind of meeting him.
It's not good enough to say, well, I met him, and I can tell he's not a liar.
No, I want a tangible, actual, actual proof, you know?
And, oh, yeah, I found that.
And so the question then becomes, do you protect this guy?
Do you blow up his life?
Dude, I started making the movie.
Here's what happened.
I never sign anything with anybody, and I don't make them do it, right?
So I show Lazar the movie, and I go, look, here's the deal, man.
I'm not a filmmaker, but this is-
I want people to see who you are.
It's not about proving anything.
I just want them to see how I've gotten to know you after all these years, right?
We've become friends.
You've let me in your life.
So look at it through that lens.
And I said it's a gamble.
Right now, you're so terrorized by any time you say something, people twist it, and they
get angry.
At that time, Jesse, people were really angry at Bob.
He was, you know, it was attack, attack, attack.
Now he's like, with you up on stage in Austin, and everybody's cheering.
Everybody loves him.
But imagine the risk.
So I say, look, I don't know if anybody's going to pick up this movie.
I don't know, but watch it.
Think about it.
And you can ask him.
I said this.
I said, if you want, I'll scrap the whole thing.
I didn't have you sign anything, you know?
This is, to me, I think important.
So I give him the movies with his wife, and they're, you know, popcorn, like, let's watch
it.
And there's, like, excitement, like, oh, this is pretty neat, you know?
And he'll call me right after, call me right after.
24 hours goes by.
Not a call.
48 hours.
I mean, I have, like, the receipts, like, my phone.
I thought it was so funny.
I was being shot at it.
So I just calmed myself.
I said, okay, okay, that's going to go on.
He calls me, and, you know, he gets that, like, you know, he's struggling because he knows
how many years I spent, and he knows that I'm, I want to.
To do this.
I want the world to see this.
And it was just, like, no.
And I go, okay, well, what?
So here I am, being calm.
I can actually do that, by the way.
I can instantaneously be calm.
But I don't like to.
So I calmed myself.
I say, okay, what, what, what did you not like?
But then, well, why did you show, he didn't yell, but he's like, why did you do this?
And I go, oh, let me walk you through why I did that scene.
Why I showed that personal part of your life.
Oh, well, that makes sense.
Okay.
I'm winning here.
I'm winning, you know.
I'm like, okay, well, what else?
We went through the thing.
And he, to his credit, he's like, okay, you know, you made a, you made a good movie.
I, okay.
And I'm like, so that was the moment where the world almost didn't see it.
And then how that would have changed things is that people would not have seen who he was
as a human.
And he would have been this totem pole that you could just put gasoline on and light it
on fire or worship.
And you should do neither.
It'd probably be relegated to like deep corners of the web, like, like Reddit forums and shit.
Like people wouldn't really.
I mean, cause then you guys went on Rogan and that is the most viewed Rogan episode of all
time.
I think it has like 66 or 67 million views or something hungry, people hungry for this
to Joe's credit.
It also took an act of God to get Bob there.
And like Joe, um, had asked me about my first film patient 17.
He actually, the first DM I ever did was Joe taught me via, it was a, it was a, a public
post.
You probably find it.
And I was like, I don't know how or something.
And he goes, dude, you have to follow me.
I'm like, oh, so I follow.
And then you learn, I never sent a DM and it was about patient 17.
It was like this weird thing.
It was a movie I did before.
I want to talk about patient 17, but.
And, um, so then Joe to his absolute credit kind of kept tabs, I think on the stuff going
along the way.
We weren't friends or anything at that time.
It was like, you know, you never know where you stand, but he just asked me out of the
blue one day, how I remember it.
He asked me, can you, um, ask Bob and you guys come on the show.
And I don't, I don't know if it was what the size of the show or anything.
I'm not following.
I'm not tracking that stuff.
I knew it was big though.
So the thing is, I said, Joe, it was a phone call.
I'm like, I, I'm like, like literally a month ago, you know, two months ago, this came out.
He said he would do one interview one.
And I took him on Larry King.
That was like the one thing he would do to promote them.
Just sit next to me.
The one thing.
And I said, I don't want to do that.
But Joe said these magic words to me.
He goes, can you just ask him?
And before I talked, I thought, can I, I can.
Okay.
I can.
So yes, I can.
Absolutely.
Cause I would love it.
I would love for him to be heard more.
Right.
Not just about the film, just Bob, you know, and, and how cool have somebody else who can
interrogate him.
You know what I mean?
And so, so then.
And in a long form, you know, Larry King was, I love, you know, great, great legend, but
he's got the suspenders and it's like this legacy sort of format, you know, Rogan's just
just, yeah.
Unnatural.
Yeah.
Rogan's got the long form, you know, and for people to build trust, that's really important.
But I wasn't thinking about nothing.
I was just like in this, um, world state where it's like UFO Vietnam.
And someone's asked me to pull this guy back out somewhere to go on.
It was months after the initial movie came, but right before Netflix got it.
So basically the funny thing is, is that, um, I mean, it's hilarious.
I was, I was, he goes, he goes, is he a disc jockey?
Bob said, I go, Bob, look, George and I are coming out because we have a premiere or a
screening, um, in Michigan.
So we're coming out.
Let's just talk about it then.
So I remember texting Joe like, um, okay, I'm going to need you to ask him because I've
really tried to do all this stuff with Bob, you know, and I don't want to.
And so then there's this really funny phone call and George is standing over here and
we, I said, Bob, just get on the phone with Joe, dude.
He's a good dude, dude.
Just get on the phone.
Like you can say no, but just hear the dude out.
You know how people, Bob, you know, fill in the voids on you.
Just don't fill in the voids.
Just, just talk to him.
And I was like, so I get him on the speaker phone and, and Joe talks to them.
Um, and I remember Bob saying, okay, I'll, I'll think about it.
That's a win, right?
I hope it works.
You know, you know, I hope it works.
I would love to see that George snapped a photo at that exact minute.
And behind us is this eighties poster of like John Lear's face with Lazar and nap.
And there's me and Bob leaning over.
And that's the moment that really like Bob Lazar was about maybe to tell the world one more
time what happened to him on a big ass platform and just do it.
I mean, different than a movie.
Right.
And my, by golly, did he ever.
And that episode, I think why people loved it so much is because we are all starved to
know the one thing.
Is this true?
Any of it, all of it, some of it, I don't know.
But it was cool as fuck.
It was cool as fuck.
And Joe got him.
It was amazing.
And he didn't put the bone down, right?
He didn't put the bone down.
So you could stop there, but he's had on, I get so joyous.
Even if I don't agree with somebody and what they're saying, people are on there and say,
Bob's a liar.
I'm like, okay, well, I can tell you what you don't know.
But he's brought it into a popular culture thing where I think a lot of us wouldn't exist
in the same way with this if he didn't, he allowed the discussion to occur.
Well, you were inextricably a big part of that.
So I hope you just take that as a compliment.
I was sitting in the room.
I want to get into some other amazing people that you've sort of broken out into the public
and are now part of the whole UFO conversation.
Who is Dylan Borland?
Okay.
Do you think your audience would prefer if I just give you really short, direct answers?
No.
I think they want the full, deep, I love what we're doing now, which is just getting into
it and, you know, talking naturally.
I can do yes or no, right?
No.
Okay.
Dylan Borland.
That's Larry King.
Okay.
All respect to Larry.
No, no, no.
He was awesome, dude.
You know what he did when I walk in with Larry King and Bob?
I'm like, you know, nervous, but for Bob, because I'm making him do this thing early
morning, I come in, Larry King looks at me and he just like winks at me like a 1950s,
like, you're going to be okay, kid.
But I wasn't the nervous one.
You know, it was funny.
He was a cool dude.
Yeah.
So Dylan Borland.
So friend, intelligent.
Balls like church bells.
A man of faith.
Husband.
Animal lover and protector.
Honest.
Nervous at times.
Endured extreme adversity.
He doesn't have a roadmap because other people got shit cleared.
By getting stuff cleared, he would expose himself.
So he has to dance a line until they let him talk.
And he's endured extreme adversity, like you said.
And people don't know all that.
I was just with him for five days.
We were just having a good time at McMinnville, you know.
And I know I try to keep the private stuff out, but he just say he's very loved and has a loving
relationship and is an absolute, in my assessment, honest, straightforward.
He has a little OCD like me.
He's like, did you lock your room?
I'm like, I think so.
He ran back up to check the door, you know.
So he's fastidious is what I like to call it when someone's like it, fastidious, you know.
That's who Dylan Borland is as a human being.
He also is somebody that you should trust.
What did he experience?
Okay.
That I can talk about.
He told you in Congress is there was a large triangular-shaped craft that was near the NASA
hangar.
It moved over towards him.
It had zero sound.
It had electrostatic, like the smell of rain.
His phone had interference, went hot, went out.
All the classics.
It was between one to two stories thick, equilateral triangle.
I could never see the top of it.
And the edges were 90 degrees.
There were four lights in total, one light on each corner and a larger light in the center,
two to three times the size of the corner lights.
The craft itself was this black metallic flake paint.
But on top of the craft was this gold, lava, plasma, some type of fluid going over and around
the craft.
A little lava, plasma.
That was something that if I had a nickel for every time someone described the seemingly
intelligent, gold, undulating hue that engineers have described to me, they can't describe the
exact, they're engineers, it really bothers them when they can't, they don't have the words
or something, you know?
What it made them feel and intelligence.
Now, Dylan didn't say that part, but if I had a nickel for every time I've heard that.
So yeah, that's undulating, lava, lava lamp style, gold, and then shoot straight up.
You, you'd mistake it as a star and then took off on a military base.
That's what you know.
And the world really knows up till the very minute, basically, of what he experienced.
But a lot more.
Sounds like there's a lot more.
I have direct firsthand knowledge and exposure to crash recovery, reverse engineering, integration
of technology into redacted, as well as the most important piece of technology on the
planet, and it's not the craft themselves.
It would be the power source.
You can make that assessment yourself.
Is your sense that that craft was being housed at the military base or was doing sort of recon
from above at the military base?
Or is it like anybody's guess and he's open to either interpretation?
Yeah.
If he doesn't know, I can't know.
I don't know.
Um, it is a conundrum.
What was it?
What was it doing?
Were we operating?
It was at ours.
Is it a program where we utilize things?
I mean, look, if we have that technology, everybody's been lying to me.
So if we have it, I really want us to have that technology.
And there, there are some arguments.
You believe we have crafts.
You believe we have crafts and saucers and hangers.
Oh, no, we do.
Yeah.
But, but I'm saying, I guess what I'm saying is some people claim that we have a modicum
of control over them.
Like even Lazar, you know, they gave him the impression that we were flying it.
Obviously it seems that way.
Yeah.
Low performance tests.
So these triangles, there is evidence that would make me think that we've done something
like a retrofit, but it's not something that there's a thumbprint for that is easily findable.
I don't think there is one.
So I think at best what we're doing, and this leads into other things that were told to
me by an intelligence agency that I said for the first time publicly, because my lawyer
said, well, if they said that to you, you can.
Dylan never said it to me.
They did.
And that's well documented.
So I was able to say three things last weekend that were never said before.
And Dylan couldn't answer any of them.
And to, to, to, to get to your, I'm sorry, get to get to your, I think.
Can you say what the intelligence agency said?
Yeah, yeah, I can, but then we go off on a whole different tangent.
It's just broke news.
It's breaking today while we're doing this.
It's just high level.
The, the, yeah, I can, but let's just finish this one little triangle thing, which is,
I think, um, there is evidence that we, meaning that the United States have been able to put
a non-human power source into a constructed body of other craft.
The problem is, is it can't handle it.
It's like putting a Ferrari engine in a Pinto, you know, and then you try to drive that fast
on those wheels, you're dead.
Right?
So that's where I'm at.
At this point, the evidence has directed me to that, that we've made some exploitive derivative
technologies based on it, but the skin of the craft.
But non-human power source, the ability to make it work at all.
Well, even if you can't retrofit it onto some, but that's what it's, it sounds like.
Well, it does.
So I'm thinking that it just does work.
And then you're trying to harness that and not have the wheels break off.
You know what I'm saying?
Sure.
So it's like, you know, you can.
Slap it on there and.
Slap it on there.
Yeah, exactly.
So that's to the best of my knowledge.
Yeah.
Without getting too specific and in the weeds for your audience, that's to the, to the
best of my knowledge.
Sure.
And then the three things I said, is that what you wanted to know next?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Okay.
So I said that I was directly told by a lead of the ODNI's dig, the director's initiative
that Dylan Borland drew four drawings.
I think it was, which was a lie.
He did draw three for the ICIG because it was filmed.
So why the lie?
We'll talk about that.
But I think it was, I think it was four drawings is what they said.
So one was the craft and everybody knows that.
That's just, he saw it at a base, doesn't know anything.
But the ODNI told me that he had told them about Project Rubik's Cube.
Now, if that is a classified UAP program, then nobody should be telling me that, especially
if it was set in a SCIF.
Now, the problem is, I already knew about it.
Multi-source.
I don't know the full nature of Project Rubik's Cube, but I think they were trying to entrap
him to see what he had said to me in George in private.
He had never said that to me, but I knew about it already.
Multiple sourcing, right?
So George and I were like, when ODNI told us that, we said, you said it, not us.
Yeah.
So.
So he shouldn't get in trouble, to be clear.
Well, he can't.
He can't.
He never said it.
So I asked him on stage.
But his face did look down in a possible recognition.
I don't know what he looked like.
I tried not to look at him.
I said, I'm not even going to look at you.
Yeah.
And I wasn't trapping him either.
No, sure.
You know, I called Chuck McCullough prior.
Yeah.
Like earlier that morning.
And I said, here's the deal.
You know, ODNI was targeting me and George.
And they were targeting us and all these whistleblowers.
And then we got proof, by the way.
The CIA, the whole thing that happened in Congress.
We'll get to that if you want.
So they're targeting us.
But I said, Chuck, they told me about Project Rubik's Cube.
And kind of long silence with Chuck.
And there's two more things.
And he goes, well, he goes, you're a journalist.
You have no, they have no authority.
If they said that to you.
It's on them.
That's on them.
I said, so I can say it.
Yeah.
Can I try to get Dylan to confirm that?
And he goes, essentially, as a lawyer, right, if he knows or doesn't know that he is not in
a legal position to admit or anything about that.
And I said, well, I'm going to ask him if you say I can say that on stage, because I think it's important people now know.
And I know Dylan can handle himself.
Nothing preplanned.
He stood up in front of Congress and handled himself, right?
So I asked him, I was told by an ODNI agent that Dylan testified to ICIG, the police of the intelligence
agencies, that there is a UFO program and it's called Rubik's Cube.
That's what he said.
That's what I heard from the ODNI, which they shouldn't be calling me and telling me what
was described in the SCIF, should they?
Right.
So I'm a journalist.
So I listened and I am testifying to you, believe me, or not, I'm a bearded tattoo journalist
who would break me down for it.
You don't need to believe me.
Project Rubik's Cube.
Dylan.
I'm not going to be looking, dude.
Have you ever testified to ICIG about a UAP program, containing UAP, called Project Rubik's
Cube?
Let me collect my thoughts.
I am not in a stiff.
I am not going to jail.
I can neither confirm nor deny, but if you want me to answer your back question, ask
for amnesty for the whistleblowers, ask Congress and the executive branch and give it to us
and I'll answer that question.
In my read that says, if he is protected as a whistleblower and they want him to be able
to talk freely, then he will absolutely talk about that.
So he didn't confirm nor deny it.
Smart move.
Now it gets weird.
Through the intelligence agency, George was on the call.
Through the intelligence agency, they said he drew, obviously the triangle that he saw
or whatever, but in the ICIG that he drew a pyramid-shaped power source.
Pyramid.
Triangle by angle of observation.
Pyramid-shaped power source.
Non-human, we're talking about.
NHI.
I don't know if we publicly said where that was being housed, but I have already reported
this to multiple agencies that were trying to find where the legacy shit was being held.
So this is like, I already reported all of this.
What I knew, right?
Factually.
When they're holding facilities, when they're trying to hide it from DOJ, who's trying to
find out where this stuff is.
As a journalist, right?
When the American government says they're hiding from us, I openly will try to help an agency
go hold them accountable, like another agency.
Oh, I'll fucking help them.
No problem.
I'll tell them something.
We're not talking about sources or witnesses.
You know, nothing to do with that.
Third thing that was told to me by ODNI is that Dylan did a drawing of like a hieroglyph.
And by the way, these were told to me they were classified.
Why would you classify a symbol?
What the fuck?
So I imagine the symbol is somehow associated physically on the pyramid.
That's trippy.
Yeah, bro.
Well, because when you said pyramid, I started tripping out because I'm thinking about the
pyramids all over, you know, disparate civilizations from thousands of years ago.
You can go to the Yucatan in Mexico.
You can go to Peru and you can go to Egypt and you can go to, you know, Cambodia.
And, you know, one of the sort of, you know, most common things is a pyramid.
That is that is sort of very common structure.
And then what I also find fascinating is there now there's a guy named Filippo Biondi who I've
had on my show is an Italian radar scientist who with synthetic aperture radar Doppler
tomography has found these this energy grid is what he believes it is.
At least we know it's tubular, 20 meter long, eight of these things with coils wrapping around
them that go a kilometer deep, tens of meters down below the pyramid.
I've hosted a debate on my show.
I don't know for sure if it's real, but it does seem like he found some anomaly under there and
there is something under there.
Yeah.
I looked at the Italian stuff too.
I mean, there's something under there.
Seems like there's something under there.
Didn't Joe talk about some tic-tac shaped metallic object they also found?
Is that real?
That's in the labyrinth that Herodotus and Pliny the Elder and Ben Van Kirkwijk is now sort
of reporting on.
Good beer, Pliny the Elder.
Pliny the Elder.
We had to get him in somehow.
Pliny.
But yeah.
And so I know less about that.
But Egypt's so weird because it seems like there's like an underground city, like even
the most conventional archaeologists, I think, would say that there's so much going on underneath
all of these kind of topological structures.
Even, you know, the Sphinx, there definitely are shafts below that.
Even Zahi Hawass, who's like the embodiment of like, you know, gatekeeping in the region,
former, you know, minister of culture, will admit that there's a shaft below the Sphinx.
And for whatever reason, it's all like locked down.
And I don't know.
If you're Egypt, you've got to be thinking, what's the number one GDP boosting thing we
can do?
Dig.
Figure out what's under there.
And you find some new exciting, you know, discovery that's like for all mankind, everyone's
going to visit and be excited and celebrate.
It's like being the disclosure president.
Wouldn't it be great?
I mean, President Trump has forced this mandate and is following through so far.
Look, whoever does this first is going to be hero for the rest of their life, hero for
eternity.
But you're talking about something outside of my scope of knowledge and ability.
Like I've heard of all these things, but let's to bring it to.
So, but maybe it's the UFO power source.
Is this this pyramid?
There's some maybe there's something about the pyramid shape.
Yeah.
So that's now I'm going to tell you what I pretty much I'm.
I'm pretty confident.
And there's pyramid tubulin in the microtubules of the brain that Roger Penrose and Hamerov
think are responsible for collapse of the wave function and consciousness.
And even Hal Puthoff, who's out here in Austin, talks about this as his best model of consciousness.
And there are rumors of UFO legacy programs recruiting psionic assets to call in craft mentally.
And so the tubulin pyramid structures in the brain might have some sort of part in that.
Okay.
So now when you talk about tubulin brain structures collapsing, the waveform of consciousness,
I am lost on what those words represent in functional reality.
However, sounds fucking cool.
I don't know about the whole psionics thing.
Yeah.
What do you think?
Do you think that's real?
Just top level thing.
Yeah.
Like the sky watcher stuff.
Do you think any of that?
So I'm not.
Like the green Greer pushes this stuff.
Yeah.
So two things.
One, when I'm talking about a pyramid power source in a class, in a classified ICIG.
Yeah.
Alleged drawing from Dylan, again, he didn't tell me.
And he still says, I can't confirm or deny, but I'd love to have the authority.
The symbol, I think the word was used to me, and George, hieroglyphic, I think on the thing.
We're talking about something that you could put in other stuff, you know?
So if we're talking about a power source, I'm imagining that's how we would retrofit things.
But I'm not sure on that.
Like, let me report back to you.
Just the multitude of sources that we've got, it's all aiming towards this idea that there's different parts of technology that are held by different groups.
And that's why DOJ is like saying, remember, I mean, it was a public thing that we're like trying to find out.
It's a public thing that Burleson, Rep Burleson, was going to places for different hardware.
So I'm not speaking out of school.
What I'm trying to say is there are certain different types of hardware that I understand to be held in different places.
So I'm not talking about big pyramids.
I'm talking about something that appears to maybe movable as a power source.
Now, you just went somewhere else.
I want to catch you back on where you left off, but I wanted to qualify that.
No, yeah.
What was the last?
The last thing I was saying is, do you think this idea of psionic assets, is that real?
So what people don't know is that a homeless guy came up to me in 2013 and said, look up.
Wow.
Yeah.
And I looked up.
And I saw like a globe.
Like just a, I don't know, balloon?
You know, so then I started, I think it was 2013.
No, no, I'm sorry.
That's, no, that was in 2004 because, or 2005, it was right after I was sick.
So this homeless guy says, look up, right?
I'm looking up.
It's a little bit more than that.
What happened was I got a message on a YouTube video that I posted because I saw this thing
in the sky and I didn't know what it was.
I filmed it.
It's called this.
I called it the silver surfer.
And I just, it looked like these zigzaggy things.
Do you know this part of, oh, this is cool.
You got to hear this.
Okay.
So zigzaggy things.
And I pulled out my phone.
I'm filming.
I'm walking in Santa Monica with my now wife, right?
And we had a different pup, Lucky, three legs.
So I filmed this shit in the sky, post it onto YouTube.
Next thing I know, Bill Nye, the science guy, is saying, oh, I don't know.
He probably superimposed brine shrimp onto the film.
It could be sea monkeys, which are brine shrimp, shot in the right light and superimposed on
the blue sky with the shaky thing.
I immediately go on Google.
I look up what brine shrimp is.
It's sea monkeys.
And I was like, I was fucking pissed.
So I like, I thought people on TV that were science, people had like scientific method.
I don't even know how to superimpose nothing on iPhone footage.
At the time, I was like, just barely.
That's whack of Bill Nye, man.
Yeah.
What was the first year of the iPhone?
2008, I think.
2008, 2009.
So it must have been 2008.
So we'll look, you know what?
But I think of Bill Nye, I'm like, that's such a bummer.
Because he's, you know, he's like this Mr. Rogers character of science.
But I'm obsessed with.
He's accusing you of shrimp brine.
Yeah, it gets better.
I'm super obsessed with getting the right date.
So you can look up the video yourself.
That's how you know the date.
Oh, so maybe it was a little later.
I used to get kicked in the head for a living.
I literally, when it comes to dates, I have to keep all in a phone.
And I use photos.
So if you guys look up Silver Surfer, it's probably one of the first videos on my YouTube.
It's probably there.
What happens is he goes on the news.
I get pissed off because I didn't know about news.
What are you doing, right?
So I call the news station.
I say, wait a second.
I didn't superimpose anything.
And they just dismissed me, right?
And I'm like, the fuck?
But they did this, like, story about it.
So I went to deep dive investigation on my UFO sighting.
I mean, I went into, like, forums and, like, Facebook and, like, what was it?
It was called, like, you know, all this stuff.
Myspace.
And I found all these people that had also filmed it.
I got six angles of this shit, right?
So I went, like, crazy, bro.
I was like, no one's going to tell me, you know, that I superimpose brine shrimp.
And I literally.
That's such a weird accusation.
Bro, I literally.
Yeah, yeah.
Bill Nye.
Oh, you might be a nice guy.
I literally.
He's probably a science guy as well.
I don't know.
Worst joke ever.
Yeah.
I don't know.
No, there's, oh, Bill Nye's a science guy.
So then I just, like, so then, here's the deal, man.
I get six angles of this thing.
Yeah.
So I can then figure out where it was.
I figured it out.
There's a bunch of people online.
It's a funny story I'll tell you later about online who was there, but figured it out.
And I got the footage from the helmet cam of the Red Bull skydiving team with iridium
flares that look like the silver server.
So I debunked my first UFO case in life.
So that's how I, like, finally realized, like, you know, you got to fucking make sure and talk
about something.
I didn't never say it was UFO.
I just asked the question.
Well, even then, it was a UFO.
It was an unidentified flying object.
But I solved it.
And I realized you can solve it.
I remember writing into, like, some UFO thing.
It goes, hey, guys, guys, I have a solved UFO case.
They were so not interested in a solved UFO case.
It's a problem with, you know, a lot of the reporting.
Yeah.
They don't want the debunks.
But that was kind of like a funny thing.
So where I realized that people were disingenuous and that they were just saying shit and that
they're not authority, you know, on stuff.
And they're not even scientists sometimes.
You also, I mean, there's so many layers to that story because it does eventually get
debunked by you more accurately.
But there's, like, a fake debunk as well.
And so you want the right debunk.
You don't want it.
But then you also want the community to say that the debunks are important.
They are.
And they didn't care about, like, the ultimate debunk.
I would say debunk.
I would say, like, you don't.
So debunking means you already have an idea and you have to fit it into that idea.
In my.
Yeah.
Or it means you were presenting it for sure as not human.
You weren't just saying, well, what is this?
Analysis is important.
Right.
Analysis.
You analyze it.
Some of the UFO videos are going to come out from the government had deep, deep, deep
analysis, like instantaneous acceleration.
That is what you're seeing in that video.
They did not want that video out.
Yeah.
But even then, do you think that there are possible ways to poke holes in it and that
there might be.
Oh, yeah, dude.
And look, one day, you know.
Like if it were massless.
If I get more.
Was massless?
Like if it didn't.
If it was some sort of, you know, looked real like it had mass, but it was a hologram.
Or something.
Bro, it got a weapons grade lock on it.
Uh-huh.
And by the way, fuck, how do I say this?
So like.
Because you can technically look like you're breaking Newton's third law.
If you have conservation.
So you've got, so you've got, so the debunk, not the debunk, but the plausible.
And I'm not saying I believe.
No, no, no.
Look, new information, I'm going to absorb it.
But we learned this the hard way life did, you know, people did in a cool way.
So yes, sure, Jesse, maybe that's not a UFO, you know, spacecraft that it's instantaneous.
If you give me information, you should give it to the government, first of all, because
they disagree.
But, you know, because they have eyes on all the assets.
Well, I'm sure they know that.
So here's my point.
That was a deep dive analysis that came out, right?
Because George and I obtained and released it.
Our government hasn't released it.
I'm sure there's a pilot, a mission report on that.
I want that.
The world should have that.
So yeah, and at some point, you do your best, you put something out, and then maybe it's
not what you were told or what the government thought.
And the reason I'm saying this is because in these, they call them tranches of releases,
there's going to be good information and bad information.
And that's why we want it out.
So people, really bright minds, the internet can solve shit real quick, right?
That's why I struggle with video myself.
Because I'm like, I'm not a VFX guy.
I don't know.
So I see some of these videos.
I'm like, they look compelling to me.
But like, you could probably give me some bullshit.
And I would probably think, you know, maybe that looks compelling to you.
So I just try to like, not even weigh in.
Let me argue why it's tip of the spear.
Okay.
Right now.
Now, this should change.
This should change.
But right now, it's tip of the spear.
Because man, if you were with me 15 years ago, one video from the military.
Are you kidding me?
You'd go crazy, man.
And you're going to get bad stuff inside these UFO drops from the government.
Not because they're trying to trick you.
But because certain products have been highly evaluated.
And there's multi-sensor platforms.
Some they can't show you.
Like with the 2019 100 UAP swarms.
Some were pyramid in shape.
Some were, look, there are other platforms.
So when you have multi-platform, multi-sensor.
Some of that's going to be really good and well thought out.
And the government should be giving that up to you.
But some of it's going to be like, this looked cool.
That pilot says, that was all crazy.
And that's the pilot report.
But here's how we learn the hard way in a good way.
In those 46 videos, that's the tip of the spear.
Just to begin the process.
The last, the first tranche of stuff that they put out.
George Knapp and I had reported on something called the Baghdad Phantom.
We released seven images, which were still shots.
Because obviously people are leaking shit.
So I don't even, we make it in a way so we could never even know sometimes.
But we validate everything.
But we put it out.
We told people, here you go.
It's cold.
It's running through here.
And you're like, cool video, dude.
Right?
And all of a sudden, it wasn't a video.
We stitched together the images.
But the process worked.
They knew that people knew about that case.
So guess what was in that first tranche?
Was the actual video of the Baghdad Phantom.
That felt good to me and George.
Because we're like, look, we're pushing transparency.
But what people missed, if you look and read through all the documents like a psychopath,
there is a mission report of that collection.
So that's before it gets into the disinformation arms of the old arrow.
Because now everything's going to be thumbs up, from what I understand.
Maybe.
No, I'm just, I'm going like this.
But we're going to hold them accountable.
And they know that we can.
They know exactly how we can.
Yeah.
So one of those ways is, look at the mission report from the Baghdad Phantom.
That was supposed to be declassified in 2047.
Whoa.
Just the mission report.
Well, that's cool that that came out.
It did.
Because what it does.
What does the mission report say?
Look at what the pilot said.
What did the pilot say?
It's very simple.
It just shows the process is working before it gets twisted by intel agencies, like Arrow
has been acting like one in the past, given maybe future props.
So that is what I'm saying, is you learn that when you put something out, if the pilot report
was like, oh, no, we knew what this was, then I would know that wasn't a UAP.
When they label it UAP, when they talk about how it went by them super fast and they tried
to keep the camera on it, right, and they got as much footage as they could, it reinforces
what I said.
Central command has a bottleneck to UAP information before it gets to the people who legally it's
supposed to get to, who want the information, even Arrow.
So we informed them about that and about the bottleneck at CENTCOM because we found out
about it.
Anything else of note that the pilot said in the background?
No, it's really simple.
It's just an example of a mission report that goes with footage that you were told about
three years prior to it through proper reporting, and it should give you confidence, confidence
that reporting is working and that pushing this way works.
You mentioned Arrow.
Under Kirkpatrick, it does feel like it was not only like a, you know, an intel agency
or something or a modern Project Blue Book kind of trying to dismiss, you know, many UFO
cases.
It seemed even more nefarious than that.
It seemed like maybe it was acting as like kind of a fly trap.
Like it was explicitly getting leads on the cases that I'm most familiar with are some
of these nuclear cases.
Arrow, the people that took the testimony from these veterans, did not record them.
They were told, a couple of the veterans were told, well, we're taking notes.
Well, if you're conducting a serious investigation, you want to tape record every word, every grunt,
every syllable.
And they did not record any of the interviews, according to the veterans.
And they wouldn't take notes, but they would maybe take high-level notes about where, you know,
certain evidence would lie and then they might even go and try to find that evidence and
destroy it in certain cases.
It just seemed like a total limited hangout with ties to UFO legacy program.
Like, like the definition of bad actor agency is my sort of rough assessment.
But what's, what's your assessment?
For, you know, for, for people to say I don't answer questions directly, here's a direct answer.
You are 100% correct.
It is exactly my assessment and I can back it up.
And there are a number of ways in a court of law.
Arrow was acting as a counterintelligence against the American public to siphon out what people
knew and then to be able to clamp down on them.
It was a honey trap.
It, uh, was a disinformation campaign.
Um, Dr. James Lekatsky even said that on our podcast, mine and George's, uh, you know, he, he says,
well, they're sure acting like it, aren't there?
Something like that.
Uh, this is a known thing.
Now I have direct specific knowledge and evidence of exactly how that mechanism worked recorded, documented.
Whoa.
Oh yeah, bro.
Oh.
So for example, if somebody, but there's a lot of good people that work at Arrow, by the
way, shout out to the good people.
I do know some good people that work at Arrow, but it under Dr. Sean Kirkpatrick, all the way
up from the NASA people that are sources of mine who have told me what, what it's like in
the room with him, what he tried to do.
Yeah.
To the direct harassment of witnesses.
Not, I'm not talking about dismissal.
I'm talking about harassment threats and I'm not, I'm not sure how to go far to go right
now, but imagine it's recorded.
So recorded.
So in the court of law, I could prove that Arrow was intimidating and harassing whistleblowers
and it's wild.
Yeah, man.
So fuck them.
Sorry.
In that, in that old version.
Now I hear that, um, Dr. Kozlovsky, everybody I know that knows him professionally before he
was in that role.
Yeah.
My job is to have sources everywhere, right?
What do they say about that?
That he's a great guy.
Okay.
That I've heard similar.
That he's an honest guy.
Yeah.
Now he is in project blue box.
It's the modern version, much more sophisticated.
The battlefield is, is cyber.
The battlefield is social media.
It's PR.
Notice what he asked for when he went up.
The last thing with Gillibrand, all he asked for wasn't more money.
He asked for public trust because he realized coming into that job, poor guy, after it was
just kind of shit on by Kirkpatrick and shit on by Tim Phillips, right?
Coming after whistleblowers publicly on like LinkedIn.
When are you kidding me?
Is that in your job description?
Project blue box, dude.
It is worse than project blue book, a book.
You can open a box.
How do you get in?
And it's, it's so bad.
It's so bad because it's, you can literally tie its inception to legacy programs.
So Kirkpatrick was at SAIC.
If you study UFO legacy programs, SAIC is all over that stuff.
Ronald Moultrie, who is office of, you know, undersecretary of defense had Battelle on his
resume and scrubbed it.
If you, again, study anything about UFOs.
In fact, you can even go back to the pentacle memo at the inception of blue book and Battelle
was behind the scenes doing sort of, you know, the more real stuff while blue book was kind
of doing the front facing things.
So, you know, definitely legacy stuff going on there.
It's obviously, you know, very close to right pat, you know, Ohio state, a lot of interesting
stuff happening in that sort of nexus.
So it's, it's people where you don't, Glenn Gaffney is on the board of Arrow.
And Glenn, Glenn Gaffney is director of science and technology, the CIA, who's blocking UFO
transfer between Lockheed and Bigelow, which we just discussed with Lekatsky.
So you have three people who like.
The guy that George Knapp said his name with his hand raised.
That's right.
At Congress, Glenn Gaffney.
In the transfer of a non-human intelligence craft.
I have a name for you.
Go ahead.
Glenn Gaffney, CIA.
So those are the three people who are supposed to be helping we, the American public, make
sense of UFOs.
Congressionally mandated.
It's crazy.
Dude, bro.
I'm so glad you're tracking all this because the average person is not, and not everybody
can track all that.
So like, um, putting that out in a digestible way, explaining that to people, that there
is a generational pattern of relationship, just like you would have in any organization
or agency or group of people, cabal, you know, I don't know the word, like Edgar Mitchell
said, like a group, a secret group of people.
Is that what he told you?
Because he said a secret group of people?
Cause I know you, you interacted with Edgar Mitchell, the sixth man to walk on the moon.
Sixth man to walk on the moon.
Uh, allegedly some people would say, um, he, uh, I don't want to get into that.
He, um, he, um, he absolutely in the film, you see, there was the last filmed interview
before he died from what I understand at this time.
Um, spent many days with him and he was very clear with me.
He really let me in.
He knew that time was ticking.
We became friends.
He, he lived for a little while after, but that was like the only filmed, like, you
know, cameras in his home kind of interview before he died.
I lived, lived longer, but then, um, we, we got down to brass tacks and yes, that's, that's
exactly what he said.
He told me who he talked with.
I knew about the Wilson Davis thing long before.
Wild.
Of course.
Yeah.
You know, the things that George and I can't say, you know, um, look, man, I'm
there is a, I wish it was organized.
There are groups of people holding information back for me for no good fucking reason.
And, um, the idea is how do we get it out?
We can't take it.
But Mitchell talked about some sort of cabal, some sort of closely knit.
Yes, he did.
Interesting.
But, but not that he knew everything.
Sure.
And I didn't dodge your, your cynics question.
We should get back to that for your audience.
Right.
But, um, yeah, Dr. Mitchell talked about how, cause look, six man to walk on the moon.
People want to talk with you.
They're born in Roswell, New Mexico, bro.
Right.
Yeah.
He behind the scenes, um, and in front of the scenes, tried to be an advocate for truth
and transparency on this.
Cause he knew it was true.
The whole enchilada.
It's so interesting to me, the dynamic around this whole topic is you have people like Edgar
Mitchell, you have Wernher von Braun at the end of his life, talking to Carolyn Rosin,
his, his.
She texts me sometimes.
Oh, amazing.
Yeah.
She's cool.
And she's talking about some planned alien invasion.
And then you, I feel like you have modern equivalents of them where it's like guys who
are really well respected in their agencies or, you know, with their past credentials, people
like Lekatsky or Hal Puthoff.
But those guys, everybody I just mentioned considers themselves an outsider.
And that's interesting about this whole topic because you have guys who are, have very high
security clearances who can, you know, walk into all these places, like no questions asked.
Bigotless.
Yeah.
No, there's bigotless.
Okay.
You have to, so.
What do you, what do you, yeah.
It doesn't matter your clearance is need to know.
It's very simple.
They're bigotless.
That's what happened.
But there's a cabal that's deeper than Wernher von Braun.
Like I think of Wernher von Braun is like, he's got to be part of the cabal.
No, but he's not, he's on the inside of what he needed to know.
Like how Bob was on power and propulsion, you know, with Project Galileo.
Um, but worse you, you, you have, I hope there is a cabal that is planning how to do this
right.
I don't think so.
Cause everything's been provoked and forced, but, uh, yes, all these people, you know, that
you would imagine like how put off, maybe he also could just can't tell you certain things
or I know for a fact, like, you know, I know there's a lot.
For example, somebody, you know, and you might know this, but somebody, you know, worked on
a laser weapon system from a downed Russian NHI spaceship.
Someone, you know, have they told you that?
Nope.
You're just saying that cause you're on camera?
No, I really don't know who you're talking about.
Okay.
So somebody, I'm extremely curious.
Somebody, you know, worked on the reverse engineering of a laser weapon system from a
downed Russian asset, NHI asset.
Last name start with D.
We're not playing that game in front of the camera.
I'm trying to get you.
Well, there's one person who said something along those lines in a documentary.
You're an investigator, bro.
Okay.
Here's the deal.
What I'm saying to you is that even if they wanted to, they can't tell you how much they
know.
Now, are they in this cabal planning shit?
Oh, fuck no.
Who those people are highest, highest up on the food chain.
All I found is the cabal of people who want you not to know, not the people that do know.
Did you really hear what I just said?
Because that's important.
I found the people that want you not to know, but not the people that do know the full thing.
Yes.
I don't know that anybody does.
Yeah.
I don't know.
Blind men touching different parts of an elephant.
There we go.
I can relate to that.
The parable.
Yes.
Something like that.
So the question is.
That's apparently what General Neil McCaslin told Tom DeLonge.
It's in Secret.
That was an op because no general like that, by the way.
He's a boomer.
Okay.
I've learned what that word means.
Now I had to look it up, which I'm not ashamed of.
It's a cool word.
Boomer.
Um, basically anybody from that era of national defense will never, do you think he sits
back and listens to Blink-182?
Do you think that guy, honestly, on his free time, do you think he had been to a concert?
I don't know.
Why is he talking to Tom?
Right?
Um, love.
Tom did some amazing stuff.
You know, he pushed this forward.
Yeah.
Good for Tom.
So I, I really.
I'm a huge fan of his.
I think he's awesome.
His music too.
Yes.
I don't.
And, and as a person and as a person, I think he's.
No, dude.
I think he gets a lot.
He gets a bad rap sometimes.
Absolutely.
Vigilante, like really helped get a lot, you know, shake the tree down and get a lot of.
Let's make this clear.
Yeah.
Tom DeLonge is, yes, he's a rock star, but that's a tiny little piece of who he is.
He is like you.
He is curious.
He is fascinated.
He called me back in the day before he's ever.
He's genuinely fascinated.
Genuinely.
He used to read all the books with the blink thing.
And he, he, George is always making me get on calls with people and I don't know who
they are.
He's just really important to talk to him.
The, I remember this call driving home from Vegas from, uh, right after I kind of got to
know, um, some, somebody else, but I'm driving back and Tom calls me.
He's not like in the UFO world in any way at this time.
And he's just talking to me.
He knew so much about the UFO thing.
So people put him in as like, Oh, this rock star and blah, blah, blah.
That's not what I'm saying.
I'm not saying they wouldn't talk to me because he's a rock star, dude.
He trained with George Knapp on like how to make his approach, what the pitches, how to
use his face and his fame to get in there.
You know, he got into like a Lockheed little soiree.
Tom fucking did it, dude.
He pushed in.
He got through.
He went for it.
He became proactive instead of being a consumer.
He was a consumer for years.
Like all of us reading books.
He did that man.
And he gets a bad rap because people jealous.
They weren't in that room with Tom or they weren't in this with Tom, dude.
He's a good dude.
And he's super knowledgeable on the UAP thing.
Um, but when I said it was an op, this is important to me, the distinction of that.
Um, so George is helping to sharpen the pitch of Tom and hooking him up with some people
people don't know about was look, you got a bad rap.
You've had to keep this secret and that's going to change.
So you need to look like the good guys because you are good guys.
You were just protecting America, but now it's gone too far.
It was something like that.
I was in a WikiLeaks email.
Yeah.
Oh, okay.
So, so, okay.
So, wow.
So what happens then is you got this boomer.
Now, do you think when I says part of an op, I'm going to say it's bad.
I'll explain the op, but do you think someone like that charged with protecting our national
security, which by the way, he's fucking missing right now.
I know.
Why?
That's interesting.
That's really why.
Because if that was like Russia or China and they got him alive somewhere, what does he
know that they want, not UFO related?
What if it's some rogue element of the program?
Well, so that would be really sad and that would be really fucked.
So I have trouble believing it's an adversary.
I'm just saying all options on the table because we don't know.
Sure.
But what's the op?
So a guy like that.
Yeah.
He ain't going to talk to Tom DeLonge.
He didn't listen to his music.
He's a boomer.
And he has this oath like Lekatsky.
You think Lekatsky be calling up rock stars talking?
No, no, no.
So when I say op, it's not a bad thing.
That was an operation, meaning there were people trying to get shit out.
Now, not all of it is true.
And don't be one of those people that believes everything just because someone gives you one
good piece of information.
So if you look at that and if I look at history, here's what I would think.
Here's my putting on a little theoretical hat.
So I'm thinking that Hillary Clinton thought that she was going to be president.
And I think that certain people knew that the information was dying and that we needed
bright minds just a little bit.
We just need a little bit of knowledge out there.
Or maybe she thought she'd be disclosure president because her husband really tried until they
crushed down Webster Hubble after asking, look back at your history.
So Clinton tried.
Maybe she could be the disclosure president.
Okay.
How do we pave the way?
You do an op, right?
Not negative, like actual information authorized from the White House, people in the White House.
Now, you can start seeding because when come time, because I'm going to win, she thought,
everybody thought, everybody thought.
There was no way this guy, Donald J. Trump, could become president.
Remember that?
Oh, yeah.
People thought that, right?
Or I'm not a political person, but I remember people saying that.
No, he was a complete sleeper.
There was no way.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Okay, that's what they're telling me.
Yeah.
So basically, this guy, McCaslin, one of many that Tom was talking to, obviously, WikiLeaks
you mentioned.
Yeah.
Okay.
So then what happens?
Wow.
Shocker.
She's not president.
So what happens to everybody that was part of that?
What happens to everybody that was prepping the battlefield for disclosure, which we all
want, as long as it's true what they tell us and not a fear campaign, right?
So if it's truth, what do they do?
What do all these people do now that that didn't work?
You got to pivot.
You got to change.
And we're starting to see, we've seen that if you've been paying attention.
Who are those people?
Good people?
Bad people?
What do they want?
I think good people.
Well, there was definitely a threat narrative that came out of, you know, elements of that
group.
But that was very, it was very like, you know, they're prepping the battle space, you know,
they're doing recon, they're looking at us.
And I've always had an issue with that narrative in particular.
I think it's sort of, I think anyone that says they're only good or they're only bad
is so ridiculous.
Yes, absolutely.
You know?
Yeah.
And can you trust them?
So if like a ET comes to you and says, I come in peace, you're going to destroy the
world with your technology, you know, spread the word.
No.
You can't take anything at face value in either direction.
Like with any human, the words don't matter.
That's right.
It's the action.
And if somebody speaks in absolutes about intent on either side, I don't trust them.
I'm like.
Because you're an individual and every individual has different intent.
Why would it be different?
But we can organize.
So let's look at the fact.
The fact is they've turned on nukes, they've turned off nukes.
They didn't stop Hiroshima and Nagasaki.
They've constantly been watching, call them the watchers, right?
They've been watching for what seems like the beginning of recorded human history, whoever
they are.
Is it one group?
Is it two groups?
Actions or zoo?
Who freaking knows?
Are they angry at each other?
Are we a commodity?
Are they protecting us?
Fact is they haven't like neutralized everybody's brain where you're walking around like a robot,
right?
So that we know of.
That we know of.
Yeah.
We know of.
I know a few robots, but.
So the threat narrative, let me hit that on the head with you.
Yeah.
Oh, me too.
I think it's fucking ridiculous because if you talk to people that actually had interactions,
it's like a mixed bag.
Some people, it's like the greatest thing in their life.
Other people, it's terrifying.
Totally.
Like patients I'm team, terrifying.
He didn't tell me that.
So after I saw it, it got cut out of his leg.
This is a guy with an implant.
They called it an implant.
I had it isotopically analyzed for zinc 64 one time and they wouldn't give me it back.
I talked to Jacques Vallée, showed him the results.
It was way beyond the scope of terrestrial zinc 64 isotopically.
Isotopically, I'm not a fucking scientist.
But it had isotope ratios that you'd never find on earth.
And Roger Lear took this out of this patient.
Yes.
This was this last patient.
We can get to patient 17.
Threat narrative.
This is for you.
I'm talking to you.
I don't give a shit about this.
Yeah.
I agree with you.
Here's the thing.
Why?
Why do they have that narrative?
Don't look at them like bad folks.
Like why?
I think it's probably some sort of armaments build up in space and, you know, things of
that nature.
You're a deeper thinker than me.
All I'm thinking is it's their fucking job.
Sure.
Yeah.
When you're a hammer, everything looks like a nail.
That too.
Yeah.
So all these people are coming from a military, intelligence, national defense standpoint.
They have to think about it.
It's in their blood to think about it.
But I would just say one, I would add one thing to what you just said, which is I agree
with that.
And then it's like, why now as well?
So like there's some sort of ramp up in the threat narrative.
It seemed like around that time.
And so maybe it's because we're in a nuclear multipolar world, but like the nuclear thing
had been happening since the 50s, 60s, 70s, the tampering with the nukes and stuff.
So like the going public about this could be a threat seemed to start at that time.
I don't know why.
I'm curious.
That is fact.
Yeah.
But let's play that out.
Is that because there is a threat in their minds that.
Yeah, it could be.
It could be genuine.
On there.
They could really believe it.
I suspect it.
I don't feel like they're trying to make humanity scared of it.
Like on the big scale, that's not the big message I'm getting from all of this movement.
For me, it's more of curiosity.
Let's say they did that.
Let's say that it's an operation to control people.
That's ultimately what you're saying is that I think you correct me if I'm wrong.
No, I'm not even going that far.
I think it's possible.
Anything's possible.
Anything is possible.
What's that?
With this, yeah.
With this.
And I think it's a smokescreen.
I think it's a Rorschach test.
And I think it could get used for blue beam style stuff.
Okay.
You know, religious awakening.
It could get used to clamp down and then it could be extremely libertarian and subversive
of any kind of institutional authority structures.
And so it has this infinite superposition of possibilities attached to it.
And I do think people are trying to manage the narrative.
I think they're trying to manage the narrative and shape the narrative less than some of the
people I meet on like, you know, Reddit forums or whatever think they are.
Like you meet these people and they're like just earnestly into it.
And maybe they've been socialized in certain spheres to believe certain things and that
shapes their belief in implicit ways.
And I think there are less sort of, you know, bad actors, I think, than some of the people
on the internet think, you know, that's for fuck sure.
But yeah, you know, look, I mean, we just listed a bunch of bad actors, but it's, it's
like, there are bad actors, but it's, it's not, it's not everyone.
And it's, I find it interesting that there's, there's, there's a certain type of person who's,
it's like, they're so, they're real, they're angry and they're railing against the control
system around UFOs.
Like, it's like this parapsychological control system around this whole topic.
And I, my second order thought is always, if, if you're spending all your time so angry
at this, you're probably part of the control system.
You're probably falling prey to it.
Well, I, not only falling prey, but you are allowed to run psychological campaigns of
disinformation on the American public as Americans.
That is legal.
That is law.
You're allowed to do that.
Is that true?
That's what, that's from my understanding, like Google that shit, look it up.
But from the Obama era, the idea of protective programs and being able to seed American news.
Look, we've been doing it.
That's interesting.
Did it start?
It became legalized somehow under Obama.
That's what smarter people, legal scholars.
That's fascinating.
I don't know if that is accurate.
So I'm not a legal scholar.
But that makes me, that makes me wonder about some of the UFO related narratives that popped
up around that time as maybe, because maybe it was on the back somewhat of, you know,
fact check the Obama law change or whatever.
So fact check me on that.
That is my understanding, right?
It's propaganda, the idea, right?
That we're allowed to deceive the American public for protective programs, right?
That is 100% legal.
And now the new terrain is all digital because that is the way that we consume information.
So the real battlefield is the battlefield of freedom of thought.
And that occurs on social media, in news, in all media that is consumed.
And they've gotten very, very savvy to the point where you, I mean, it's so easy.
Like if you get an AI to look at the repeated words and the timing in which people post and
when they created their accounts, dude, I've got a whole list of people everybody says I
should block because it's an organized attempt to take a single post I had to say and then,
you know, diminish it and make me less credible.
So that, that, that world exists and it's called shaping the emerging UAP narrative.
And why I've said that now for the 400th time on camera is because I was exposed to
a CIA document that gave the mandate.
The mandate was to shape the emerging UAP narrative, which I thought was so interesting.
Not control, not stop, shape it.
That's wild.
As if they know this narrative is emerging.
So how do we shape it?
And I'll tell you, there is a news source.
Was there anything specific about how they were shaping in what direction or?
So the documents that I was, um, I am familiar with.
Yeah.
Our CIA documents.
I reported those to FBI with George because it is illegal.
What, what, what they started saying in it is commander Fravor misidentified his instrumentation.
And I was thinking, yes, picked up on radar motherfucker.
How the hell did he saw it with his eye?
What are you talking about?
There were five other sets of eyes up there.
So I started thinking about as I'm exposed to this, like, is this document real?
First of all, I was just exposed to it.
I don't know how better to say it here.
Legally.
I was exposed to it.
Never had possession of it.
Don't have it.
Was exposed to it.
How I validated that document was through DOJ.
So this document was talking about shaping the emerging UAP narrative.
I will tell you this.
There is a news publication that popped up right around the Lazar movie coming out era.
And I saw them grasp the ground and the terrain.
That is a CIA stood up media source.
And they were trying to say, oh, this is a real, this is like an outlet that exists.
This is an online publication.
And you know the name and it's like a thing.
Yeah, bro.
Whoa.
Can you say or what the name is?
I'll talk to you in person about it, but I think, I think we'll want the world to think
and question and then review.
I gave you enough information now to know.
Yeah.
That is a CIA that stood up media outlet.
Okay.
So what are the clues?
It was popped up around the Lazar time.
Yeah.
One of the best.
Around the Lazar time.
I'll get, maybe I'll, I'll text you more specific.
We'll put some images in and just fucking blast them out.
But there's a bunch of people that work for it that are good people.
They have no fucking idea.
They're literally just getting a job, but you'd have to kind of operate this from overseas
is another hint, right?
On this publication.
And are they UFO specific or not?
So that's, what's funny is yes and no, like there's other really good articles and writers
and there's like great valid stories, but when you need something seated into the media
as CIA, it's great to have a bunch of people working for this.
And then any story that comes down from the King, you put in and you know exactly which
writers to talk about, you know, to talk to, to see them some very special information
that is breaking news.
It's so classic textbook CIA.
We go back to, you know, even, um, I heard that a lot of the journalists, you know, were
on payroll.
We've got their names now and what they were paid and all this stuff all the way down to
people you really trusted back in the sixties.
Whoa.
Right.
No, I think this is public knowledge, right?
So if this, I think I might know what publication you're talking about.
So if they can't buy you, if they can't seduce, I'll use that word like seduction, whatever
that means, like, you know, something alluring, if they don't have a blackmail on you and then
they try and can't get you to bite on that blackmail, then they're kind of running out
of options.
So what can they do?
They can start to diminish your public profile and they can threaten you.
And that's the way you control somebody.
Now they're not trying to stop people who have loud voices because you're useful.
These are intelligence operations, right?
You're there.
You're useful to them if they can get one of those five things I just mentioned to shape
what you're saying.
And that's, what's so dangerous.
I mean, you got to be squeaky clean, watch your back.
You got to document everything.
When Chuck McCullough says in my movie, not my movie, Michael Luzofsky's movie, I gave him
20 years of footage.
He made it.
And to my chagrin, if that's the right word, like I had to ask my whole family, like, is
it okay?
Hey, can I show the dog?
You know, he wants to do this.
It should be protection.
He's saying it's protection.
So what, what my point is, what are they, what are they doing by shaping the narrative
that's already emerging?
Is it sinister?
Is it what Jesse Michaels said right now?
Is it to create a level of control and threat?
So everybody goes, oh God, big daddy government, you know, protect me because there's something
coming, you know, like a big craft really slowly to earth.
Oh my God.
So scary.
Or is it to acclimate you for something that they know is going to occur?
Or that, that's the other possibility.
And I hear mutterings of that all the time, all the time of like, you know, certain dates
and, you know, and I, I, I almost like the, the, um, book of Matthew of like, you know,
only God knows the, the, the day or whatever on the apocalypse that applies to, and that
has its own stigma.
And I shouldn't even say, you know, reference those things in the context of kind of a more
scientific conversation, but I think that applies to this, you know, 20, 26 or seven
or, or 35, no one knows only God knows, or only some omniscient force knows.
Or it's just complete and utter bullshit.
Or it's a BS.
And the funny thing is I can call BS like I did on that.
I tried to get out ahead of, you know, you're behind the eight ball and be ahead of the
eight ball.
Yeah.
And then when I came out and said, look, all these Intel people, I have taken all of this
information, these conversations, all this data, I basically run it through.
Um, a way to look for key repeated words.
And I found that I, and very directly to was trying to be utilized to propagate.
Oh, you want something really special is happening.
Like something really special, but I'm just going to tell you what the fuck tell everybody
if it's really special, it's important.
Right.
So the manipulation of me, that's why I came out and said, look, my fear is that you're
going to be told that there is a craft slowly moving to earth and it's bullshit.
And then, you know, just the world.
I was, I was told that too.
And you were, yeah.
And I knew it, but I always just, whenever I get something like that, I just, I just don't
like, I, I'm like, I know what you're doing.
This is passage material.
This is a test.
It's, it's probably some sort of bizarre passage material slash.
Can I trust you hybrid or something?
And I'm like either fucking way.
I just don't want to like ever mention it again.
My fear is that.
And then if somebody totally independent says something that I'm like, okay, maybe.
But you're the reason, one of the reasons why I would say that publicly, because, you know,
I knew I'd get shit for it and everybody would like, you know, cut that up and make me
seem like a crazy person.
I said it out loud, it's because people like you have said to me that you were getting
that same shit.
Oh yeah.
So now all these people speaking loudly are getting the same messaging and it's like,
so we have to defend against that or we become a part of that machine and mechanism.
Now, ultimately, end of the day, I don't fucking know, but I highly fucking doubt that that
is an accurate assessment of what's happening in 20, 20, 30, 36, whatever.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
But hey, I'd be wrong.
Do you think, I think there's something so unique going back to Lazar, there's something
so unique about him because he's this, uh, kind of hapless, like normal person, engineer.
He's not, he doesn't have any sort of counter Intel background or anything like that.
Uh, do you think we get another Bob Lazar coming out near term?
Cause I think that's what a lot of people want.
I don't think they want the person who saw the thing on the document or the, you know,
that the, who knew the other guy and that person worked directly or, you know, I think
they want another Lazar.
We almost got it and he's dead.
Tell me more.
You know about this, right?
Sullivan.
Right.
Yeah.
Okay.
So a little example.
Yeah.
Fact.
He was to testify behind closed doors.
Matthew Sullivan.
Watch it.
Right.
Um, Matthew Sullivan was one of the 40 people that, you know, that, that number's loose.
Um, there's probably more that, that David Grush brought to the attention of the ICIG.
Matthew Sullivan was fact two weeks about before he died.
I think going to testify, we call it behind closed doors because you know how many people
I've taken in to, to speak in DC that you will never see publicly.
This is to inform them, taking them in to testify.
You're under oath.
You're in a skiff.
I have facilitated over 10.
Oh yeah.
Well, yes.
Wow.
So, so, so the question is this Matthew Sullivan.
Now I didn't know him personally, but I knew he was going to testify and that is testifying.
And that's why people and the FBI are investigating if his death was suspicious because it ain't
adding up all the math.
Now he could have just been PTSD and broken down and scared and, but that's not the word
on the wash.
So I don't have any direct knowledge that I can talk about of that case, but I do know
the FBI is looking into it and there's a congressional letter that I do mention, if you read between
the lines, I didn't know that this could be public.
I didn't know this was going to be public.
He's one of the two people that I'm talking about when I say, you know, mortal crimes.
Um, we don't know, it's a suspicious death and, um, he was going to testify behind closed
doors.
He had direct, direct hands-on with the craft.
That would be like Lazar, wouldn't it?
So man, they wanted to stop Lazar.
They don't want people that would convince everybody out because now.
Were you in touch with Matthew?
Uh, it's a really sad story.
And, um, I just know, I was kind of trying to figure that out recently.
I get a lot of signal messages and they delete a lot.
And, um, I did get a message from him and it deleted.
And usually I try to be good about keeping those, but it was on a thing, but I never talked
with him.
I was trying to figure that out because of my memory, but, um, you know, I can show you
on my phone what happened.
That's a bummer, man.
It's a bummer because I was hoping maybe he was reaching out because I could take people
from embryo scared Dylan Borland.
You see him in the movie that audio, he knows I speak always on speakerphone and by my nest
cameras.
He knows that.
So Dylan Borland, um, he knew that I was doing that for our own protection.
So in the movie, you hear him really scared and that's way before we knew that we were
going to get him standing hand to God and to country and be able to testify.
That road is so hard.
It takes me two and a half months sometimes for, for, for national security people to
vet some of the witnesses that I want to testify to you.
A lot you'll never hear about.
You never got to hear Daniel Gauquerel, small story, but I had him on weaponized after he
saw a triangle, but these, these bad-ass motherfuckers that worked on the programs, you have to understand
they're so locked down.
They're not in there because they're trusted.
They're in there because they have legacy generational trust.
Most of the people in the legacy atmosphere are, it's not because just you are trusted.
It's because your grandfather was trusted.
Your father was trusted.
You got kids who are going to be trusted in that same intelligence circles.
So they're so tightly packed in there, um, to get somebody to break out of that cage is
dangerous for a lot of reasons.
Cause why would you do that?
You have to think this is so critically important.
Otherwise keep your head down, do your work.
You're on one of the coolest projects on planet earth.
Literally.
Do you understand what I'm saying?
I do.
Yeah.
That's crazy that maybe he was taken out.
I don't know, bro.
The timing's weird.
There's a lot I can say about that.
But I, yeah, let the DOJ do their job.
Okay.
Damn.
But like, you feel pretty confident that he was working directly on the craft.
To the best of my knowledge, do I feel very confident?
Absolutely.
Do I have all the information?
No.
But I think people that have more information than me and knew him should speak to you.
Not me.
Interesting.
About him.
Is there going to be somebody?
Man, it shouldn't be on a Bob Lazar.
Our government should come forward.
And this is the problem.
The first release is a bunch of videos, bunch of documents.
Wait a second.
Didn't David Grush raise his hand and say that we have been generationally exploiting non-human technology,
hand to God and to country, and say that we have these programs?
And didn't he say that we have alien bodies by law?
Didn't he say that?
Oh, shit.
Where was that in the releases?
Yes, and the IC inspector general said, this is urgent and credible.
Sure.
But now we got a real issue.
The ICIG is the police of the intelligence community.
That might come out later.
The question being this.
Who's the real watchdog here?
Can we trust them?
Well, it doesn't seem like they've acted on Grush's, you know, report that he handed in in 2022, four years ago.
So, I don't know.
You know, I hear there's a guy, and I hear he's a really good guy, and I hear that he is the current ICIG, and I hear that his name is Christopher Fox.
And I hear that if someone like him, being active ICIG, wanted to, and didn't have to recuse himself for some reason, that there's actually four people, because I've talked with Chuck, who was the first ICIG in American history.
So, you know, pretty much, I'm pretty sure he knows the job.
I think if they wanted to, that they could rapidly come to conclusion on that ICIG report.
I think the ICIG, I think that they also have the video footage of Dylan Borland's testimony.
So, I think that this could be very rapidly sorted out if people wanted to.
You feel what I'm saying?
And I also think, the one thing I didn't tell you, because we got into a different space, is the fourth thing that I heard directly from ODNI,
is that Dylan Borland drew a fourth drawing of a sensor system.
Oh, but that's really classified, because it's not UFO-related at all.
Now, wait a second.
They were asking me, did he draw that for me?
Motherfucker, he drew me a triangle on camera.
Didn't draw nothing else.
Here's what I know as fact.
Dylan Borland wouldn't even know what the fuck they're talking about, or how do you draw a sensor system, Jesse?
You're a smart guy.
You're basically a fucking scientist.
How do you draw a sensor system?
So, they lied to me.
Why did they lie to me?
They lied to me to get Dylan Borland on treason, which carries a life sentence or death penalty.
They lied to me about Matthew Brown, saying he's a Jew-hating racist.
That's so crazy.
Oh, when I told him he was at a Jewish wedding, he was like, what?
By the way, he's part Jewish.
Let's back up and tell people who is Matthew Brown.
Okay.
I just want you to know that ODNI ran an operation for nine months.
Not all of them are bad people.
Actually, all of them are good people, but some of them are doing a job.
What their mission was, their mission, if I had to assess, it's just my opinion, was to co-opt me and George to go against whistleblowers and to fabricate evidence, fabricate evidence against an American hero, a whistleblower named Dylan Borland, to fabricate evidence against Matthew Brown, to pressure everybody into a corner.
But why?
Ultimately, to control Congress's ability and ambition to continue what they're doing, having hearings.
I could probably prove that.
Actually, I could prove that in the court of law.
So, wow, motherfucker, we got that going on.
Then, put on top of that, did you see a few days ago that the head of the DIG, the director's initiative group, which was the part of ODNI that came to me and to George first, and we provided them a ton of whistleblowers and people just saying, hey, telling the whistleblowers, we don't know if we can trust them, but do your best, right?
And they did it.
Most of them talked with them.
I think very smartly, David Grush didn't.
I don't think, I am confident, Tulsi Gabbard was completely unaware that the CIA was running an operation through ODNI on journalists, on whistleblowers who were bringing in saying they have ultimate authority to protect you.
You can tell them anything, right?
But wink, wink to the whistleblowers, like, really careful, throw them some underhanded pitches first to make sure they're not running something.
Here's what we find out.
A few days ago, a CIA agent goes in front of Congress, and he says, I ran the DIG.
He got emotional in it.
He's like, the CIA, he said, I ran the DIG, the director's initiative under Tulsi, and I don't think she was aware that she had these rogue elements, you know, like we're talking about, little cabal.
From the CIA, by the way, running this op on us, and he says, like, he's a whistleblower, he says, he found out that when he was running, the anomalous health affects the COVID cover-up and the UAP initiative of the DIG.
That the CIA, they found out, and he's CIA, they found out the CIA was spying on the whistleblowers.
That means everybody that we brought in, their computers, their cell phones, everything.
He's self-admitting.
CIA's response was, he wasn't authorized to speak to you on Twitter.
You're like, what the fuck?
You're not denying those claims?
That is illegal.
He said that's illegal.
He got emotional, and I don't know this guy, John, John something the third.
I don't know him.
Oh boy, we should have a talk, because if you ran the DIG, did you know that they were trying to entrap
me, George, Dylan, Matthew, Lou Elizondo, Lekatsky, Jay Stratton?
Like, did you know that as the head of the DIG?
Did you know that?
But I suspect, I want to see the unclassified version of that report.
Who's Matthew Brown?
That's what you asked.
Yeah.
Okay.
Wow, that's interesting.
And that's just breakfast.
Let's get to lunch.
You have the agency that's supposed to oversee all other intelligence agencies being red-teamed
by what's supposed to be a subordinate agency in the CIA.
That's a pretty wild phenomena.
I think that's why people like you, because you just took a very complex thing that I'm
very emotional about, because they tried to hurt people I care about and use me to do
it, and you just made it simpsified.
I tried.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Okay, who's Matt Brown?
While they are observing the Russian vessels, a large black triangle materializes or decloaks
or something.
The point is, is it did not move.
It appeared above the, directly above these ships, probably no more than 200 meters.
Matt Brown, courageous as fuck.
I mean, just goosebump, courageous as fuck, Matt Brown.
Absolutely 100% worthy of your trust.
Has a loving family relationship.
I met his dad, his mom.
I think two of his brothers.
Talked with his wife.
He's got cats.
You know, he said to...
Seems like a kind of a gentle soul.
He's not as fragile as people think, because, you know, he'll tremble when he gets angry,
like, or scared, or nervous, and I'd be nervous as fuck, too.
I snuck him in, you know, to have a secret congressional briefing with three members who all said yes
to me.
Like, snuck him in with my camera crew.
He has balls of steel.
He's so smart.
What an asset to America.
Patriot.
He's a patriot.
Worthy of your trust.
I said that.
I want to say it again.
He revealed Immaculate Constellation to the world.
That was a thing.
He has endured more than I'm comfortable saying here, from a personal standpoint.
He was at the office of the Secretary of Defense, right?
State Department.
He was at the State Department.
Yeah, that was his main job, but he was at Pentagon before that.
And he had TSSEI, and he was doing some, like, audit or something.
How did he run into all of this UFO-related info?
Fuck.
I mean, I think Matt should talk for himself.
So you notice sometimes people say, I don't.
I am so protective of people.
And, you know, there's so much that goes into my brain that, like, I have to be gentle with.
Because one wrong little word, and I expose something they didn't want exposed about them
personally, and then they get harassed.
But high level, he was doing some routine thing, and he bumped into documentation.
Okay, I can tell you this part.
Yeah.
So on a shared Intel Link server, there was something misappropriately uploaded.
So anybody can go in.
But at the time, he was kind of in a purgatory.
It's like, fuck.
He has to, like, basically clean up a bunch of files.
Now, he's fastidious also, a good word, right?
So he goes in and looks through everything and puts them in the right place.
Boom, sees Immaculate Constellation.
The heck is this, right?
It actually had a picture of Lou Elizondo on it.
Not that Lou made that.
It was saying that Lou came forward in the UAP space.
But it caught his attention, right?
Okay.
And then he starts going through it.
And he's like, dude, this is not supposed to be on this server.
So what did a real patriot like Matthew Brown do?
First thing, because everybody can see, he goes to his boss, or his boss's boss, and
he's like, you know, hey, this was not supposed to be there.
I was not supposed to see this.
It looks like a working report.
And they're like, okay, cool.
Goes back to his desk or whatever.
And I hope I'm saying this right.
And Matt, you can speak for yourself.
And you will very soon.
People are going to find out.
So...
How I understand it is, he was so nervous by how they reacted to the spillage, they call
it, where you see something that you're not supposed to be read into, that he's like,
dude, they're going to throw me under the bus if I need to tell somebody else.
So he goes and tells somebody else.
And the reaction kept being this like, okay, but like no assurances to him.
Are you doing the right thing?
So that gets under your skin.
You get a little worried, right?
I mean, your whole career is your clearances.
If they even put your clearances in purgatory like they did to Dylan for years, they're not
saying you don't got it.
And these are people trusted by our government.
In Dylan's case, really, really trusted, bro.
I can't say the agency specifically he worked for, but you could subcontract for the big
ones, okay?
So there's Matthew alone.
Who are you going to call?
Batman.
Like, you know, who are you going to call, dude?
So he proactively, being a very thoughtful person, documented everything.
Every move, everything documented for self-protection also because he's like, you know, why did I get
exposed to that?
You know, and also I think as a curious guy, he had some time on his hands and probably
kept his eye out for UAP information, right?
And here's a guy that like an all source analyst, I don't think he was, but like one, you kind
of start putting together what they call the mosaic and you look for what you know to be
true, then as a dutiful, patriotic person, when he realized what was going on and how dangerous
it was, and that's as far as I'm going to say about that, he can talk because not everything's
cleared for him yet.
He can't like go ask the State Department again.
He came to me very early on and was able to,
get that information into the hands of the people that I trusted and I do trust still
and we're in position of power and could assess it.
That's how it began with Matthew Brown.
That's how it began.
He didn't know who to trust at first.
He made some mistakes or we won't get into all of that, but some people are not worthy of
your trust at all.
Journalists don't try to pay people ever.
Jesse.
Interesting.
That's not a journalist.
There was something.
Bro, let's not get into it, right?
You said you don't want to.
Okay.
So let's not.
We can if you want, but.
Dude, let's talk about things that excite us.
Okay.
One day people will understand.
Yeah.
One day people will understand what makes me angry.
I didn't know anything about.
I know you didn't.
Possible pain.
That's why you.
No, no.
Look, we're not saying specifics yet.
Don't make an assumption.
No, I know.
You might've just made an assumption.
Well, I think I made a correct assumption.
But we can just move on.
Also, this is going to be so awkward for your audience, but Jesse and I, we made one agreement
going on is that there's, you know, we're, we're just going to talk freely and that we're
going to enjoy ourselves and talk about what makes us happy and inspires us and sparks
our curiosity.
It's basically what we said last night, right?
Yeah, exactly.
So I want to, I want to do that.
You know, this is.
And to your credit, I did say, I like to focus way more on the truth than people drama.
Right, right, right.
Because I think it's so much more interesting, but, but, but it's an important heuristic
if a person is also, you know, a conduit for information.
So people, people drama, I stay out of, but dangerous people, I inform everybody about
it because the thing is, is that you got to know who to trust.
So you, you're not working in government.
I'm not working in government.
So we signed out none of these NDA shit.
We don't got to do fuck, fuck all when it comes to UAP stuff, right?
With listening to what people tell us to do like daddy, right?
But other people do.
So the stakes for them are so much higher.
So imagine if there were a bunch of whistleblowers and they go to the wrong person to say, I need
to see if you can get me from embryo to hand to God and the American public, right?
And you go to the wrong person, that could be one of those five traps I told you.
And, and then you're controlled.
They own you and you're fucked.
So if you're outside of this world, that might feel dramatic to you.
The problem is, is that it's true and that is a real issue.
So let's say you've got, I get photos from people at Wright Patterson and they've got
up on their cork boards, you know, weaponized stickers, uh, Jesse Michaels podcast, their
favorite people come up to me on the street and tell me that they love your podcast.
I sent you videos.
Yeah.
Your fans.
So like you get people in these offices and they got, they're, they're just fans.
Okay.
They don't know much about UFOs, but they, they saw some shit on radar.
This happened or that happened.
And then you narrow in from those, let's say that's 5,000 people, right?
That have hit me up in the last year that are inside government.
Then you narrow down.
So now you've got, let's say 500 people.
So those 500 people, they know something a little bit more very specifically about UAP
and whatnot and the reality.
And then you narrow down to, let's say 50 people.
Now they feel like they want to tell Congress or Senate or a formally report.
I'll get those calls.
How do I formally do this?
What's the mechanism?
Who can I trust?
Not trust.
And I'm like, okay, well, here's how you do it.
I'll link you with them.
We'll make a call.
I'll bring you in.
If it's really important, I'll meet you there.
We'll do this signals.
Okay.
For that.
Then you get from those, what was that 50 people you get in and you narrow down to,
let's say 10 people.
Now those 10 people, they know something more.
And those 10 people, they really need to tell people, but okay, so you got to deal with those
10 people.
Then you narrow down to, let's say five people.
But the amount of information they have compared to those 500, 5,000, it's like critical.
It's provable.
It can be national security issue.
It could be dangerous.
How hard is it, do you think, for someone like that to break from the fold and say,
I have fucking tried everything.
I am now going to leak something to a journalist I trust, which is an illegal act.
And I've never solicited.
I actually tell people, like a young kid called me from a base and blah, blah, blah.
And I go, stop.
Don't even talk to me.
You got a long career ahead of you.
So whatever you saw or think you saw, keep it in your head.
And one day you'll be able to speak freely about it.
Do not tell me, you know, that joke I have going right now, don't call me.
And I've got that number going on.
That's what that's born from.
I say to people, don't call me ever again.
Find me in 10 years when we're living in a different world.
You got a long life ahead of you.
It's not that important for your life and your family.
But I'm just trying to show you that the amount of people that know, dude,
but then the amount of people that know, that would think it's so important to leak something
is so minuscule.
It's so tiny that it baffles me to this day that people all day, every day, contact me
and George and they put that trust in us and they should, and we're trustworthy.
And, and, you know, we do get leaks.
We assess them for years and we, our primary things do not hurt American security.
I think that's why we've been effective, but I'm just trying to show you, man, like you
talk about a cabal and all this.
I don't know who knows all this, but I know who doesn't want you to know about it.
Yeah.
Matthew Brown's super interesting to me, especially your, your interviews with George Knapp and
him, uh, because he obviously ran into some pretty hardcore, you know, immaculate constellation
documents around quarantining sensors.
And to be real clear, Matthew Brown is not a leaker.
He did everything by the books.
We just went from that conversation.
Yeah.
Not, not, not the segue in my head.
Matthew Brown tried to do everything under God that he could do the right way.
And he did, he got, he got pre-pub from state department, you know, so it's like just, boom,
here we are.
Matthew Brown, you want to say something, go.
Yeah.
Well, so he ran into all this kind of documentation of this stuff and he saw video and, you know,
photos and that sort of thing.
Um, and then he has kind of a whole worldview that he's kind of associated with his findings
that feels almost like Gnostic in nature.
And he talks at the end of your interview, he says, you know, um, people are a resource
maybe for the NHI.
And he says things that to me are extremely intriguing because I prefer actually in some
ways, like the sense-making layer, like what's the worldview, what's the ontology that, you
know, you were talking about earlier that comes from all of the data, not just what's
the data.
Uh, sometimes I think we, we over-index on the data itself.
So, I mean, extremely like my curiosity's peaked and then my other side of my brain
is like, but how did he come to that conclusion?
It's a personal thing.
Sure.
Yeah.
So everybody, um, again, I don't want to speak about people.
They speak about themselves, but you know, he has a very fascinating mind.
I can say that like from his own personal stuff, the way he, um, sees the world is a fact.
I mean, I learned so much, you know, from like a sensei, something's born before in him.
Uh, even if we disagree on the fundamental nature of that reality, I think what you're
highlighting is that online, he said some very Gnostic kind of quoting things.
And yeah, that's the way his mind.
Talk about almost like a white house timeline manipulator too.
Like they have sort of timeline.
Yeah.
Like they have some sort of AI timeline thing.
Oh, really?
Yeah.
It was like a super, super AI at the white house.
Like we should always be ourselves.
Right.
That's the thing I keep in this interview.
I keep thinking, Jesse asked a question.
He's got something to say.
And then I say so much, we got to just be ourselves.
Matthew has a very unique way of thinking.
He's so like pointed and fastidious and he'll, he'll be silent a lot of time on calls and just
listening and then he'll say something and it's very thought out, very thoughtful.
So I think what you're seeing is what we call, um, personality.
Yeah, sure.
Yeah.
I just, okay, well, at some point, maybe when this is all said and done 10 years into the
future of disclosure and it's all acceptable, I want to go deep with him or if I can at any
point go deep with him on how did he get from the data to that worldview?
Cause the worldview is interesting to me.
I'm like, what, you know, what happened there?
But, um, I realized he's gotta, he's gotta speak for.
I don't think that was from like, if you read the documents or saw the videos that he,
he, um, has testified to seeing, right?
Not, he hasn't been allowed yet with his hand up in front of Congress.
We fought hard for that.
He didn't want to have his face out there, you know, at all.
Um, but I think if you read the same stuff, cause I know a lot of people that read and
saw the same stuff and more than he did, they don't have the same worldview.
Interesting.
Yeah.
So it's not like in the documents.
That's just his interpretation.
That's what I'm saying.
Okay.
Yeah.
Well, that's helpful.
I mean, that even the, what you just said is really helpful that other people have consumed
the same thing and not come to the same worldview.
Matthew Brown has, has this much of the mosaic.
Yeah.
A tiny, tiny, all he did was be a whistleblower.
Because there's a lot of other things that, that he can't talk about that weren't, there's
a lot of things, corruption, things to do with, um, WMDs.
That was his specialty that, that he also whistle blew on the people don't know about, you know,
it's just not public.
That's freaky.
But, um, on, uh, on another note, cause I'm sure you can't say more about that.
Um, and maybe, maybe a good note to, to, to end on and, and, and, and close this amazing
conversation.
Uh, what do you hope for the world?
Uh, you know, 10 years from today, you know, snapshot of where we are with respect to this
issue specifically, what do you, what do you hope, uh, to see?
It's like, um, you know, I can't look back, but I'm trying to look forward now.
It's kind of, um, if the truth.
Is that there are technologically advanced craft that they've been here since the beginning
of recorded human history, if not before that major, all the major technological nations
on earth have started to try to understand and replicate and grow and evolve from that
technology.
And if the truth is that we've harmed people and lied, our representatives have lied to us.
And if that is true, and if we have biological entities that are not from planet earth.
Have you talked to anybody who's said they've seen biologics?
Yes.
In my work, a hundred percent.
Whoa.
A ton.
But Jesse.
Yeah.
I need more proof and I can't solicit.
Sure.
As a journalist, it's a specific word.
So, of course, do I believe them?
About half of them.
The top dogs.
Other people, they just want to seem cool or they want to get into my head for later.
Yeah.
I've heard that.
Mostly autopsy reports.
Okay.
Yeah.
Anybody like in person with the...
People have told me that, Jesse.
Yeah.
But, like, actually a public interview I did once, the anonymous interview, when I brought
Richard Dolan in to interview this man as he was dying on, like, I think it was like
a dialysis machine and we got him out of the thing and he came.
His wife didn't want him to...
Is this Oscar Wolf?
Yeah.
That's his real name, but I wasn't allowed to release that for like a long time.
I have his DD-214s.
That's a crazy story.
Yeah.
It's fascinating.
I had to be real quiet about his real name for a long time, but it was, I have his DD-214s,
all this stuff.
I was setting up that interview with Reuben Langdon, who set up the entire citizen hearing
on disclosure.
He saw one.
He saw an alien getting interviewed, according to him.
At S4, Area 51, I believe.
At S4, we viewed the autopsy film.
And then the colonel said, what we've got in here is we're interviewing a gray alien.
Bro, that is so in my ancient past.
I'd say just watch the video.
My impression is that, if I recall, he was one of the people that I'm saying that has
like said that, because you asked me a live alien.
No, not a ton of people have said to me they've been or seen a live alien in government capacity.
Yeah.
Versus experiencers.
There are a lot of autopsy readouts, and I know which autopsy.
So you start narrowing it down after the years, and people that don't know each other have
kind of run across it.
Enough where you're pretty high confidence.
Oh, we got bodies.
That's a component of it.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
But like, I don't, are they cybernetic?
Like, are they printed flesh with AI high fucking minds?
I don't fucking know.
But yeah, I think that's the ultimate thing.
So you were asking me to go, what do I hope?
Yeah, what do you hope?
I'm just trying to, sorry for the detail.
No, no, I'm trying to stay on your track.
Yeah.
So it's like, ultimately, if, I keep saying if, if this is true, if this is true, this
is my best assessment, right, then I would hope that those tasks with withholding the
fundamental nature of what it means to be human, which is to interact with a larger idea
of, of being, would then stand the fuck down, tell the fucking truth, and let human beings
decide for them fucking selves if they can handle it.
That's what I would hope.
Now, people have hoped for disclosure for a long time, you know, way before me, before
I was born, I was born in 77, before I was born, none of them got it.
Now we are getting something right now, but we're not having the conversation.
No, but I hope it, uh, it snowballs.
You know, I think you kind of saw it with the Epstein stuff where like a little bit came
out and then people are like, whoa, there's something there.
And then they wanted more and they wanted more and they wanted more.
And then you have all of a sudden representatives in the civilian, you know, Congress who are
fighting to get more out and you get more and more documentation and slowly it just kind
of snowballs.
And I think that might be similar with this topic or JFK or a lot of these things where
the consensus just shifts over, over a long time horizon.
Um, so it, while you can sort of, you know, I know a lot of people kind of belittled this
drop or think it's a distraction or whatever, uh, I think it's, uh, the beginning of infinity.
It's not, it's not the end, you know, it's, it's the beginning of a possible paradigm shift.
And that's, that's so exciting.
The beginning of infinity.
I always saying it's the floor, not the ceiling.
It is the beginning of infinity.
I am hopeful that we're going to get somewhere, but the only way we get there is if we push
and we do it asymmetrically and everybody that has a voice and everybody that has a
desire, just use it, just move, keep talking.
Don't take nothing personal sticks and stones will break my bones, but words will never hurt
me.
Right.
Just push, push.
I bet you that tomorrow we will know more, um, than we do today.
I bet you when people see this, we'll know more than, than we knew the day before.
And, um, yeah, man, I'm optimistic.
I'm glad to have you in the fight and everybody that has a microphone or thumbs can just make
some noise.
On that beautiful, inspirational note, go watch sleeping dog, check out weaponized, subscribe
and anything else you want to plug.
Yeah.
Um, I want to say that it took a long time for me and Jesse to, to trust each other because
trust is never given.
It's always, it's always earned and then it's, it's built.
And then every day you keep reinforcing, you know, to the, the trick of being trustworthy
is to, to, to actually be trustworthy.
And so I'm, I'm grateful that we get this, um, construct the room and we get to do this
for the first time and that, you know, we will continue this dialogue until we're old,
old, old man.
Um, that's what I kept thinking this whole car was so fun and you know, I would love
to run it back.
So.
Yeah.
But just keep fighting, keep pushing, keep doing what you're doing.
And I would like to do a, um, two minute rapid fire cause I have questions for you.
You can put it in your episode or not.
Sure.
Yeah.
So this is back and forth rapid fire.
Okay.
Yeah.
Um, did you start this, what you're doing with the intention to try to get information to
the public that you thought was important?
Yes.
Are you independent or are you controlled?
Independent.
I know.
Um, do you have people that support you in your life so that you'll keep going?
Like loved ones and.
Yes.
Yeah, I do.
Yeah.
Okay.
Have you found friends that you really trust at this point in this part of your journey?
I have.
Yeah.
On this topic.
I had before this.
Yeah.
Yes, for sure.
Will you protect that?
Always.
Yeah.
Before anything, before, you know, relationships over, over anything.
Will you tell the truth if you find out something is incorrect and will you tell it loudly?
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
I believe you.
Thank you, Jeremy.
I'm glad I passed the test.
It's not a test.
Yeah.
It's like, I learned those things about you through time.
But now maybe people learn it about you because you just told it how it is.
Yeah, I love it.
There we go.
You got a, you know, a lot of people that, you know, are suspicious of you.
I know.
And, um, I was.
Yeah, fair enough.
Yeah.
But here we are.
Here we are.
It's frustrating to me and it, it's, it makes me want to quit sometimes.
Cause it's like, uh, it's like, fuck.
Like, what, what do you do?
You know, like it's a, the offense on a conspiracy about yourself is always going to beat the defense.
Like you can always say shit about me and whatever.
And so I can, I can always say you're wrong.
You know, you're, you're just wrong.
And I can point to the facts, but then you can always construct a new thing.
And so, uh, you know, it's like, uh, yeah, it's tough.
I don't know.
That is a reality is that people do want to quit.
And that is the work of a very organized attempt sometimes, sometimes, and we need to identify
that and we need to bring it into the light and you're not going to quit because you told
me just now that you do have people that love you and support you about keep going.
And it feels, it feels like a mission that's higher than me.
So that's why I, the part that wants to quit is like the ego that wants to remain intact.
Right.
And like wants to stay out of the limelight.
Fight or flight.
You want to, you don't want to be in pain.
In pain.
Yeah.
And like, and you mentioned stuff around, um, you know, your, your personal life being
encroached on.
I've had similar things that freak me out.
And I'm like, uh, and then, so it's, it's funny to see that simultaneously.
And I know you face this as well.
You have that, you have like creepy shit happening in your personal life.
And then simultaneously you have people calling you a spook.
Right.
And it's like, you're, you're, uh, be on both.
You're being flanked and I'm like, I'm not a fucking spook and go the fuck away and just
let me, you know?
And, and, uh, and, and, and, and, and, and I'm sure you feel sympathetic to this as well.
There's so much that you put out that they, they wouldn't even be into this shit if you
hadn't put the thing out.
That's what they're fucking using your lexicon and all the stuff you bring out.
They're taking that, but then they're throwing you in the garbage or whatever.
And it's like, fuck off.
Like, you know?
So the thing is, it's not about you.
I know.
It's not about me.
It's not.
And I've got tunnel vision.
So I'm seeing you right now.
I don't see nothing else.
You got to do that, but I'm going to crack you on one thing.
I hope you find it useful later.
Okay.
Which is that you said something about defense and you said something about like when you're
getting all these attacks from every side and people make you want to quit.
Okay.
Then they win if you quit.
Now quit.
If you find a beautiful girl and you want an Island and just like go live over there,
you don't need to be doing this.
I know that about you.
You don't need to be doing this.
I don't need to be doing this.
Right.
But I can.
So I will.
So the one thing I want to correct you on is the best defense is to outpace, outmaneuver
and outperform.
Never look back unless you're reflecting, but your mom and dad and brothers and sisters
and your friends will tell you if you're being a bitch and an idiot and help you self-reflect.
So they're better at it than you anyway.
Right.
So you look forward.
You keep going.
If you want out at any time, make it your own choice.
The best thing you do when you get an attack is don't look back.
Keep moving forward.
Don't think about those attacks.
Don't let them in.
Don't penetrate them.
They don't know you and they don't own you.
You're independent.
Fucking fight.
We need you.
I appreciate that.
Well, thank you, Jeremy.
Love you, buddy.
You too, man.
I am.
Oh, that was great.
That was so cool.
If you've made it this far in the show, then I know you care enough to hear about this.
Our show, American Alchemy, is growing super fast.
It's bursting at the seams.
We are looking for an amazing editor to join the team.
If you're an experienced YouTube editor, podcast editor, trailer editor, or documentary-style editor,
maybe you're even a traditional Hollywood editor and you're just really into our content
and you want to work on some of the most mind-bending stories in the world, we really want to hear from you.
We're especially looking for people who are deep into the content and who have a real editorial eye.
Someone who can dig through long and sometimes dense conversations, find the most powerful moments,
build tension, create great hooks.
Basically, people who can turn these raw conversations into very high-quality, almost cinematic episodes.
Strong technical skills are a prerequisite, but especially for the documentaries we make,
we really need somebody with taste, who has strong instincts around pacing, music, sound design, story structure,
you know, all the things.
And big bonus points if you're genuinely into UFOs, consciousness, frontier science,
and big questions about the nature of reality.
So if you're a strong, experienced editor and you know how to keep audiences engaged,
and you want to work with us on some of the coolest stories in the world,
please email all your relevant work and your application to apply at jessymichaelsmedia.com.
And if you have a friend who would be great for this role, please let them know.
Thank you so much, and we look forward to hearing from you and maybe working with you.
If you want to access our episodes 24 hours early and want to watch them completely ad-free,
please consider supporting the show by joining our YouTube membership.
Just click the link in the description to join today.
Your support helps us so much, and it allows us to keep making the show
and go deeper into the kinds of stories we care most about.
And a little early access and not getting bogged down by ads is kind of a cool perk.
So join today.
We'll see you next time.