they were very clearly trying to scare me and then play we're just kidding
everything is like and it sounds insane that people could live for 30,000 years
but it doesn't here's why it doesn't there's real evidence that there's
structures under the pyramids that might go as deep as two kilometers that look
like an energy grid with columns and coils around the columns and like what
everybody who studies this says the cherry on top are the pyramids but it's
really this underground city that they're studying there's a 40-meter
object that's in that labyrinth it's in some vast corridor that's metallic it's
a f***ing UFO and now we have three fingered mummies in Peru we might have
actual evidence that there's another species that shares this planet with
us the same problem that we have with UAP disclosure is the same problem you have
with the Epstein files who do you think runs our government Nixon apparently had
been saying I know who killed JFK and I know why they did it and then you have
people like Elon Musk on who are they run SpaceX you would think he would be
completely privy to all of our UFO secrets he's a sly dog he's my homie but he's a
sly dog if he was debating like in a room with David Grush on your show the CIA guy
was like look at the Grush stuff quantum and AI do you think there's something
happening where all these trends are converging now simultaneously and it's
not a coincidence when we achieve sentience with artificial general
superintelligence that is the legitimate gateway to the cosmos and if you really
want to get weird that might be how God gets formed like God might be a real
thing that might be how God gets formed and that might be the whole reason why
human beings have curiosity and this insatiable desire for technological
innovation Jesus is born out of a virgin mother what's more virgin than a computer
this is beyond surreal I've had some surreal moments on the show but I think
this tops them all Joe I really appreciate you being here man I don't think I
would have a show if it weren't for the thousands of hours of insights I've
gleaned from your show and you don't have to do this and you do stuff like this
all the time and it just means so much to me that you're here so I really really
appreciate you well it's my pleasure I really love your show so it's exciting
for me to be here means a lot man well I want to actually start with you had a
dream yeah and this was a few weeks ago you had Brett Weinstein on great
evolutionary biologist and you started off the episode with this trippy dream you had
you want to describe it it was the weirdest dream I've ever had in my life
because it was the most realistic dream and is the only dream that I can ever
remember I sleep really well like I'm one of those guys I can go to sleep on a pile
of rocks I can always sleep it drives my wife crazy because she has a hard time
sleeping and I could just talk out I could not go back to sleep it's the only dream
I can remember that I couldn't go back to sleep I don't think I've ever had that
happened to me before well I woke up at like three in the morning or whatever it
was and I was like I'm I'm up now like there's no way I laid in bed I think for
like an hour and then I just went to the gym I was like there's no way I'm going
back to sleep it was very strange it was very strange because it it was like what is
this it wasn't like a regular dream like oh you're dreaming it seems like vague and weird
and kind of um you know opaque it was vivid it was very strange and there was these very
slender tall human-like things that were talking to me they weren't gray they were kind of like
pinkish like us they were you know like caucasian looking creatures but they were messing with me
like they they scared me and they're like oh we're just playing around and and so they were doing some
there was some weird kind of communication telling me to relax and um the environment was very
different too it was very vivid it was like some sort of a corridor but it didn't seem normal it
seemed very strange like I remember the walls were lit very weird and I also remember that there was
some sort of water and reptilian element to this like they were letting me know like almost like they
had barriers that were very sloppy that were keeping these things out
but they were doing their best they had people or beings like monitoring the band feeding these
things and keeping them out and I was like what what is going on here and it's like is this telling me
that they're doing their best to keep something from getting to us but that it's not that secure
that it's kind of precarious and a lot more unstable than we would like to think it is
i don't know what that was all about that was a that part of it was really weird that part of it was
more dreamlike but the communication with them and the interaction with them was
very very vivid it was really strange they had larger eyes than a normal human
and a larger head but not crazy like not like a gray from close encounters of the third kind
um kind of a little bit like that guy up there oh interesting not quite so big like a large head
with a very small jaw and larger eyes than normal but they were smiling god I can't remember if they
had teeth I think they had teeth I can't remember does any part of you think this actually happened
or do you think it was just a dream you know I don't want to be that guy that like oh I know it
was real because I don't yeah I was dreaming I was sleeping yeah but it was the most vivid dream
I've ever had in my life I was telling you outside you're wearing this epic Betty and Barney Hill
oh geez oh geez first abductees 1961 you know I know his granddaughter yeah she Angela Hill right
she's a UFC fighter yeah so cool crazy what does she say she did my podcast and didn't tell me
until after the podcast was over you don't tell her Joe Rogan her grandfather was Barney Hill I was
like no that's mad that's so crazy did you not say let's go back in record no it was already too
late we wrapped it up and everything I should have though I should have you gotta have her back yeah I
should have I should have done it then that is wild looking back that was a mistake well I thought
because you wore this I think on the Gavin DeBecker episode which is a crazy episode every
everybody should go watch this episode this guy protects like the most important people in the
world yeah and he's going through all these crazy CIA conspiracies basically talks about Fauci's role
in the AIDS epidemic as kind of analogous to what he did around COVID a lot of the the three you know
being kind of the same very same very similar and you're hearing it from this guy who like
protects incredibly important people does risk assessments for these you know massive events
yeah wild yeah very wild yeah but yeah he didn't know what this was I thought you were maybe I thought
you were maybe signaling to the audience like maybe I got abducted or something no I don't think I got
abducted um I don't even know if I got contacted it just might have been the craziest dream and to me
because I'm so into the whole UAP UFO alien phenomenon that maybe you know maybe it was just
very vivid because of that it's just very odd for me to not be able to go back to sleep that never
happens I can sleep no matter what it's weird well so whatever it was it had kind of a disproportionate
impact on your psyche like it was it was a big part of your subconscious it was it was tangible
it was it was like when I woke up I was like what was that it wasn't like uh whoa that dream was
fucked which I've had before I had last night I had a crazy dream last night but it was normal dream
was just like got up to pee and I was like what the hell was that I went right back to bed this I was
not going to sleep man I laid in bed for a full hour just trying to go to sleep and then I said
all right I'm up let's just go to the gym and I'm in the gym and I'm trying to decide because I knew I
had Brett Weinstein on the podcast and I was like I have to just say this immediately like because we're
going to get into so many different subjects there's no way I'm going to work this in like I just have
to get to this right away because it was I just had to sort of document it while it was only a few
hours old while it was fresh and some dreams are like you wake up from them and you're like still
in the dream a little bit you have to like kind of get it there's something cathartic about retelling
it or something yeah yeah it was weird man I don't know what it was you said you thought they were
beings from the future maybe that's what if I had to guess like what they are they seemed like what we
will be you know like we are as time goes on uh you know if you look at ancient hominids versus
modern humans our heads are larger our bodies are smaller they're more slender there's no need for
muscle there's no need to physically move things these these things seem very slim they seem very slim
and um god I I want to say they had they weren't naked right but they had like some sort of a suit
on but they were very genderless like there was no defining that's a boy that one's a girl there
was none of that which feels like where humanity is kind of headed yeah which I you know look I like
being a man and I like women I think they're fun you know I like I like the contrast I like it's fun
having a variety of different kinds of people but it causes problems right because we have these
procreation reproduction instincts uh we have primate instincts to be tribal to uh acquire resources
to you know to dominate and to to be untrustful of others there's a lot of stuff that's it makes
being a human kind of cool because out of that you get art and you get incredible history and like
amazing architecture and all these things but it also there's it's a fork in the road like that is
the kind of the bottleneck as a human being is our natural biological reproduction yeah and because it
it lends itself to all these things that you see like when bears fight over you know a breeding female or
when you know when you hear see deers clash antlers together like what are they doing they're battling
over who gets to breed totally I think that's a lot of what humans do and then we do it in weird ways
like we acquire immense amounts of financial wealth or you know the fanciest watch and the fanciest car
and you try to look like someone who someone would want to mate with and that's really all it is
is like men and women want to be desired by the opposite sex or the same sex if that's what you're
into but it's that that procreation thing is what fuels a lot of our bullshit and a lot of our inability
to get along a lot of conflict and a lot I mean a lot of acquiring resources through horrific and
barbaric ways and dominating countries and invading that's what it's all about it's all it's a lot of it
is just about breeding and it's it is that like limbic reptilian part of ourselves that does that
and so I wonder not to like do a full Jungian analysis of this dream but it's like they're
holding these reptilians at bay in the water or something and maybe there's something very symbolic
whatever it was because it was the only part of the dream that was kind of vague like they were
kind of like crocodiles or something but it was weird like they were feeding them but they had like
flimsy barriers in front of these things to keep and they were like keeping them it was almost like
letting me know like this is you're really close to getting fucked up and we're we're doing our best
to stop this from happening but it was that's just me reading into it but whatever whatever it was
they were very clearly trying to scare me and then play we're just kidding everything was like
ah just messing around there was a couple of those moments where I was like okay what are you trying
to do are you trying to get me accustomed to interacting with you yeah like what is this because
I was very weirded out and I think they hit their whatever they were wearing because I think they were
wearing something but they were like I said they were very genderless whatever they were wearing was the
same color as their skin so it was strange you've been asked a lot about your childhood everybody
knows you were four years in a row taekwondo champion that discipline brought you to where
you are today in many ways everybody knows you're ufo obsessed now yeah was there a moment in childhood
where you kind of got alien pilled or saw something or no unfortunately I never saw anything
I wish I kind of thought I did maybe when I was young but I think it was probably a fighter jet
um when the from the time I was little I would look up at the stars and I would just think well
clearly this can't be the only planet that has life on it like that doesn't even make any sense
and then you know going to school and you learned out how many hundreds of billions of galaxies there
are you like okay and how many hundreds of billions of stars are on those galaxies and how many planets
there must be like for sure there's something else out here but would they be interested in us would
they visit and you know then I got really into project blue book and I read a lot of the stuff on j
alan hynek and you know and all the philip corso stuff and the stuff from roswell and I just became
obsessed with reading and watching whatever flimsy documentaries were available back then
you know and then I think I really got back because I was always on the fence like oh this
is nonsense this is real this is not it's not helping me let me just go about my life and then
really jeremy corbell's uh roswell um excuse me um area 51 bob lazar documentary is what really
brought me back in yeah and that ended up being one of your most iconic episodes I believe it's like
your second or third highest performing it might be the biggest it might be the highest one on
youtube I think it has like 63 million views on youtube it's so crazy that one's nuts that one's
nuts especially considering from that interview which was uh what was that 2000 maybe 18 or something
like that whatever it was more and more has come out that substantiates what he said and confirms
a lot of the stuff that he was talking about in the 1980s into in terms of the design of these crafts
how they manipulate gravity around them and how they move through space with a very strange
propulsion system and that's what we're hearing over and over again now from these whistleblowers and
from these people like how put off and all these people that allegedly have information about these
back engineering programs that that this is what he's saying is very accurate and it's almost like
you broke the most gnarly story there was and a lot of these kind of people who are now in the
forefront of disclosure trying to play catch up in some ways because you have a guy who's claiming to
have reverse engineered yeah raft firsthand yeah and now you have people you know saying you know we do
have biologics we have you know you have david grush yeah giving 40 firsthand you know whistleblowers to
the inspector general of the intelligence community thomas monheim and he says it's urgent incredible
it's this crazy sort of groundswell but in many ways we're playing catch up to this guy who was
like there at area 51 in the 80s you know they've tried to discredit him in many different ways they
tried to say first of all they tried to say that he never worked at los alamos but that's been
confirmed yeah and then they tried to say that he was never at area s4 or area 51 site 4 but he was
there and he knew it he knew the layout everything people that worked there people that did work
there also confirmed that he worked there originally i told you uh you know when i worked there i was on
the front page of the the paper so they were still able to archive you know break bring that back from
the archives and you know bob lazar a physicist working here at los alamos so there was at least
something there but uh somehow george came up with the the phone directory and then george then bob
took george with cameras into los alamos oh yeah yeah so we flew out there and i said look come on in
i'll show you where i worked we'll go in we'll meet people and george went with me janet airlines
which takes you back and forth between vegas and area 51 area 51 wasn't even really in the public
zeitgeist exactly till he came out with it it actually wasn't even confirmed until the obama
administration because the obama administration they wanted to expand the barriers for entry or where
people were allowed to access the land because too many people were getting to non-secure land and
taking video so they were filming and taking photographs allegedly of these crafts and so
they wanted to make it a little bit wider and so they had to confirm that it existed so wild i think
we're gonna so there's a buddy of mine's making a documentary with bob lazar it's called project
gravitar and i think we're gonna get a lot more confirmation and data points that corroborates his
story or interview of him i think we're gonna find out that s4 is very real too and that's been
denied up until today like we do have satellite images of s4 do we i believe so okay i believe
there's images of the land itself and you can because it's underground but yeah but there's
the outside of it where the hangers are i'm pretty sure you could actually get it online okay okay it
might be bullshit okay i'm pretty sure there is an overhead like where you could see oh there's
something there okay well so okay if it's the same thing i'm thinking of then he he has that data but
it's like stuff they tried to cover up on google earth oh yeah it's like that point doom alien base
that they erased yeah that is weird weird that's so weird because they blurred out the ground yep in the
water i hope everyone's enjoying what is certainly one of the most legendary american alchemy episodes yet
featuring the one and only joe rogan for an episode like this i wanted to work with one of
my favorite products as a sponsor i'm of course talking about ketone iq i personally don't drink
caffeine i don't do nicotine and i don't really do that well with most stimulants ketone iq is one of
the few things i do that provides me with insanely steady energy clear focus zero jitters and zero crash
why is it so effective because ketone iq gives your brain ketones which are its most efficient fuel
source it was actually originally developed through a multi-million dollar military program for high
stress environments and now it's used by founders researchers and people who need their mind to
function when it matters most this product is also very close to my heart because i've known the
founders of ketone iq jeff and michael for over a decade both of these guys are extremely smart and rock
solid they've tried all the top supplements and all of the best biohacks since trying it i've been
absolutely hooked it's truly one of the cleanest energy sources i've tried no ups no downs no jitters
no crash at the end so before you jump back into this epic episode visit ketone.com slash alchemy
for 30 off your subscription order plus receive a free gift with your second shipment again that's
ketone.com slash alchemy for a 30 discount or you can find ketone iq at target stores nationwide and
get your first shot free seriously this stuff works i love it and it's been an absolute game changer for
me thanks again to ketone iq for sponsoring today's historic episode with joe rogan on this show we talk
about advanced exotic technology but the most advanced system you'll ever deal with is your own body
your own biology and the older you get the slower your body responds it's not broken it's just a bit
laggy that's where stem cells come in they're basically your built-in repair crew and as we age
the signals your stem cells send get weaker qualia stem cell is designed to support those natural repair
processes they use well-researched ingredients like sea buckthorn and royal jelly that help your body do
what it's already trying to do what i like is how dead simple it is you take it four days a month
that's it no 40 pill stack no daily commitment just four focused days to support recovery and healthy
aging so if you've ever felt like your body just doesn't bounce back like it used to whether it's
after a tough workout getting sick or just the wear and tear of life this product is for you qualia
stem cell was designed to support your body's natural repair systems helping you heal recover
and keep going strong and right now you can try it for up to 50 off at qualia life.com slash jesse
again that is 50 off at qualia life.com slash jesse and here's a bonus use the code jesse j-e-s-s-e for
an additional 15 off that order that's at qualia life.com slash jesse your body is built to repair
itself qualia just helps it do that better a big thanks to qualia for sponsoring this video
i had dan fair on the podcast yesterday how was that it was great for people who don't know dan
made this new documentary the age of disclosure which is excellent it's one of the very best
documentaries on the whole uap ufo phenomenon that i think i've ever seen and there's no real footage
in it maybe a couple minutes of footage of like the go fast or the gimbal but really most of what it's
about is high level intelligence operatives explaining what they know and what extremely
high level people like wolsey and james clapper like these guys who are like dni level like overseeing
all of the intel agencies brennan you know all these people and and marco rubio his credit i think
him his involvement was huge you know because it's the current administration his involvement
and his urgency schumer rubio all those guys are like look a bunch of freaking high level
yeah officers came to us and either they're crazy yeah or the shit's real most of these people at
some point or maybe even currently have held very high clearances and high positions within our
government so this is one of the things that dan and i talked about he firmly believes that both
the united states and china has retrieved these crashed vehicles and that they are also in this
back engineering program they're in a back engineering program of their own and there is a race and he's
he you know people talk about it like it's the manhattan project on steroids i've heard that about ai too
right but which might also be true and they might also be connected in some way yeah um i think what
rubio is concerned with is that china develops this technology first and the only way um that
the united states is really going to catch up is if we open this up yeah we open it up and remove all
the ridicule because forever look i i'm a silly person so it's easy to make fun of me and i don't
mind i mean literally professional comedian so i i'll say stupid shit and not worry like oh people
are going to think you're an idiot i'm like i'll tell you i'm an idiot you don't have to like look to
see if i'm an idiot i think you're much smarter than you give yourself credit for listen i know
really smart people it's relative yeah it's all relative you got that like that general breadth of
knowledge like not too many people are at your level man yeah but it's it's also you know what
it's like it's like people say like oh man you must be an amazing fighter i'm like listen i work for
the ufc i'm around dudes who can kill me every single day i work there every one of them could kill
me no questions asked like compared to a regular person yeah but to an untrained person
that's how i look at intelligence it's like am i i'm not as dumb as the dumbest people i know
but i know elon's a friend of mine you know what i mean i'm friends with a lot of like very brilliant
people there's levels to this thing you know like i had palmer lucky on the podcast yeah you start
talking to him you go oh okay well there's levels to this you know and there's really fucking smart
people in this world and i'm not one of them but i i'm smart enough to know what i know and i'm smart
enough to not be afraid of people thinking that i'm not smart so the the subject has always been
like very ridiculed and dis and you could like really fumble your career if you went out and said
if you were a journalist or if you were like a legitimate author or like like look at whitley
striber yeah i don't know what happened to that dude yeah but i know that everybody like sort of
dismisses him as a kook in the real literature world because he's this guy who made these
movies and books about being abducted by aliens what you know what i mean so you immediately get
this like smell of kook that's on you and i think marco rubio talking about this and and and explaining
like this is what i've been told this is what i know this is a real thing there are vehicles the size
of a football field that are moving through the ocean at 500 knots we have no idea where they're
going you know tim burchett recently said that there's they've identified five areas in the oceans
of the world where these things are coming out of on a regular basis we have a higher propensity of
sightings around these five or six i believe deep area deep water areas so you've got these people
talking about this and it's slowly but surely removing that layer of ridicule and that layer
of ridicule ridicule is powerful man people don't like to be thought of as a fool you know and i think
that holds us back and if the united states like if first of all they're going to need some sort of
an amnesty thing this is one of the things that we talked about they're going to need because for sure
there was lying to congress for sure there's misappropriate misappropriation of funds and
probably some corruption like when you have no oversight billions if not a trillion dollars like
for sure somebody got some money they shouldn't have got you're gonna have to make all that okay
you're gonna have to say in the interest of national security and the future of the human race
fuck all that you're gonna have to do that and if they don't do that we're gonna have a real
problem because these gatekeepers are going to continue to gatekeep because their lives depend
on this if they if they release this they could find themselves in jail without any amnesty in jail
for the rest of their lives like we don't know how much money was spent we don't know how much lying
to congress there was we have no idea how many felonies there were we don't have no idea let's assume
that crash retrieval programs were real and that back engineering programs were successful so you're not
going to give this stuff evenly to all these different defense contractors so if you give
one defense contractor one object and all of a sudden they have this massive advantage and then the other
defense contractor winds up going under as many of them have gone out of business well now you have
a major lawsuit on your hands you know you have all sorts of and then probably people are going to go
to jail if it's a just legal system a hundred percent yeah yeah and for i think the cynics out there who
might just want to put a minus sign against anybody coming from the intelligence world and saying things
it this we're not even necessarily being idealistic about their motivations we're just saying that
it's probably national security run runs the day and that this might be the manhattan project 2.0 if
you think about it the first manhattan project was payload potency it was bigger and bigger bombs and
there's even a scene in oppenheimer where he's criticizing teller because he's like there is no
target big enough for the the h-bomb's way too big and so beyond that it's all about payload delivery
it's all about the stuff you know icbms into stealth fighters into whatever the hell they're working
with now and if they do have this technology obviously they're going to open it up and as much
as i can be cynical and and anybody who's into ufos is probably cynical about the intel world yeah it
kind of makes sense that they'd let this stuff up out now because they there is this arms race or
whatever there's a race going on with both let's assume that that stories are correct and that back
engineering is real let's assume that they have recovered crafts so there is a race with that but
then maybe even more critically and completely connected is the ai race because i feel like that
is the legitimate gateway to the cosmos i feel like when we achieve sentience with artificial general
super intelligence when it has the ability to make better versions of itself when it has the ability
to devise new methods of power new new ways of using resources that we never even imagined just like we
have now that they never imagined in the 1400s you know and i think it's going to happen very very
quickly so if there is a back engineering program and then maybe there's some hurdles that we just
can't get over like i how did they do this like how is it possible to do that well ai is probably going
to figure out a possible way that it could be done and what possible inventions could be made to
facilitate this possible thing and they'll probably just go go ahead and start doing it and when you have
ai and then you have the incomprehensible power of quantum computing which is so baffling it's so
baffling that you go wait a minute what the fuck did you just say one of the more recent ones uh i believe
it's the google one they solved an equation that would take the world's supercomputers i think it was
2.6 billion years to solve and it solved it in a matter of minutes it's so crazy and then the willow
chip they say the multiverse has to exist yes whatever for it what does that mean the only way
for it to solve this problem mark andreessen said it on my podcast he said the equation is so difficult
to solve that if you took every atom in the universe and converted it to a supercomputer the universe would die
of heat death before it would solve this equation and it solved it in minutes so like what are we even
talking about now imagine that being connected to artificial general super intelligence which is
essentially a digital god yeah you're going to make this thing that makes a better version of this thing
it's going to be exponential it's going to happen very rapidly well what's the end of that what's the end
of that is all-powerful all-knowing and if you really want to get weird that might be how god
gets formed i mean that that literally like god might be a real thing that might be how god gets
formed and that might be the whole reason why human beings have curiosity and this insatiable desire for
technological innovation and not just to stay alive not just to make better stuff but but this is why
because that if you just follow it out to its natural course that's going to lead to an artificial
life yeah i've heard you say that a lot before that like our consumptive patterns are almost built
in to want more and more and more and then we have to produce more and more in step and we're like
creating this god outside of ourselves like think about materialism it's foolishness you have a finite
lifespan and you have people in their 80s like trying to acquire immense wealth when they already
have immense wealth yeah like they're like warren buffett's still in the game you know what i mean
like he's worth billions of dollars he's in his 80s and he's still out there trading and moving like
what is that about why would you want more stuff why would you want more money and more stuff because
nothing fuels technological innovation like the market and in order for the market to be successful you
have to be obsessed like i have the iphone 16 and this motherfucker is starting to mess up on me
because the 17's out the battery's a lot slower it's like it goes it burns through the battery quicker
sometimes it glitches on me i'm like you didn't glitch for a whole year bitch it's like it's wired in
that you want the newest one you want the latest one and apple's been accused of that planned obsolescence
yeah and they it is it's true they've admitted to it and they've done it under the guise of oh well you
know when the the older ones the batteries decay we're trying to preserve the battery shut up just
let the battery die bitch don't monkey with my phone but it's like this i i have an iphone 11 that
i've had forever and i i keep it because a good friend of mine who died he left me a voicemail and
it's on that oh man um and that phone works great like it works the same yeah it works i don't need a
new phone but i'm going to get a new one every year because i'm a dumbass and we're all dumbasses and
we're all buying the newest tvs and the newest laptops and oh the new thinkpad came out with a
touch screen and you're going to keep doing that and and that if you just follow that if everyone's
doing that what does that do it makes better stuff if you looked at the human race as from an outside
perspective if you were a life form from somewhere else like okay what are they doing what is the
predominant what is the dominant life force on this planet do it makes better things that's all it does
it's like a worker bee that doesn't know why it's making a hive it's just making better things all the
time obsessed with making better things you should stop your need for accumulating objects and stop
your need for you know a big car and a big house and find out something that you actually love to do
and figure out a way to do it for a living
i had a very smart guy named matthew pines on my podcast and he said he was speaking to some like cia
guy and the cia guy was like you know it's a triangle ai quantum and the grush stuff that was
it and we were you know in an environment where i couldn't and want to press too much into the issue
and you know i didn't have it wasn't like this sort of sit down where it's like you can go for hours
um so that was basically where where it sort of landed um and i've been chewing on that for a while
you know ai quantum and the grush stuff that's wild and do you think all of this is like and he
was like if all of those three things seem to like converge it's like this kind of consciousness
apotheosis thing kind of what you're saying yes do you think there's something happening where all
these trends are converging now simultaneously and it's not a coincidence like we're ufo disclosure is
happening at the time of deep fakes it's so weird right that's all on purpose yeah i think that's a
part of the fun of the the experience that we're going through you know because it is a tangible
experience i believe life is real i believe this table is real i believe in reality but i don't think
reality is as clearly defined as we like to believe it is i think reality is dependent a lot on
consciousness in some sort of a strange indescribable way to a conscious person i don't i don't i don't
think it's i don't think it's very binary i don't think it's ones and zeros i think it's slippery and i
think it it's dependent upon a lot of things yeah there's a lot going on and um and it's also i always
wonder like what is what is my what is my experience what is my trip what is my journey
through this world like why why do i have all these weird things that have happened to me that
have led me to be who i am today like is that a design because if it's not a design well if you wanted
to make someone like me that's how you do it you do it exactly that way but i want to pretend
that oh this is all just you know it's like the it's like determinism versus free will i think both
i think both are they're intertwined i don't think it's that clear and i think your experience is very
different than my experience and all of our experiences are all tied in together and i really
believe as strange as it sounds it's towards this one goal and i think this one goal is the advancement
of the human species and um i think we all play a role just like microbes play a role in the
environment and plants play a role in the environment and so does sunlight and so does wind all these
but you parse them out and you look at them as individuals you're like oh the wind does this and
it carries the clouds but it's all together like an equation that's driving things in a very specific way
and i i i really believe that our trip that our experience is a very unique one the people that
are living right now that are hearing this currently in the future they might look back at this and go
boy they fucking they were so wrong or they nailed it you know one of those but i think we are all
purposely building towards something and i think that something is the it has the echoes of
religious texts i think that the you know the origin story of the human race from various religions i think that is
that is that these all these stories where there's interactions with like the book of enoch the watchers
that came down and bred with men and created the nephilim like
doesn't that sound like genetic engineering like if bred with like had sex with men what what do you
mean like what is that so you mean take their genes and introduce them to ours where if you're a
a dummy who lives 6 000 years ago and you're trying to recall a 5 000 year old story yeah that's probably
how it presents itself if you've had 5 000 years of barbarism since the younger driest impact
so you have advanced civilizations which is what i believe i'm in the randall carlson graham hancock
school i don't think this is our first go around i think ancient egypt is a great testament to that i
think there was some sort of an advanced civilization that was on a different pathway than we are we're on
this electronic internal combustion engine pathway they were on a different pathway but i think they
achieved the similar if not greater level of technology and the ability to manipulate matter
what they've just what they've done with the pyramids and like people try they do their best to come up
with some explanations they're all dumb every every explanation sucks they suck and they hate it when
you say that and they get angry and people were smart back then sure but only these people only these
people were like 6 000 years ago we agree that people were dumb and they didn't even have steel
yet like what are we doing and the the contrast the the stark contrast between between zahi hawass who
you had on the former minister of culture in egypt yeah somebody like a randall carlson or graham
hancock who are so articulate so smart and i think you know um you're constantly i think playing down your
intelligence but i think because you can deal with stigma because you can play with what other people
consider misinformation the whole world now thinks that charles manson was an mk ultra patient because
you knew greg fitzsimmons who knew tom o'neill which is crazy so good that you like in some ways i think
you're leading academia like i think the younger dreiss impact hypothesis which was i think presented in
2007 for the first time is now really starting to become more of an accepted thing before that it was
you know luis walter alvarez saying that the dinosaurs you know due to a comet impact 66 million
years ago that was a thing nobody took him seriously right and so in the in the stark contrast between
a gatekeeper like zahi who was which some people call your worst podcast of all time it was the worst
it was the worst i discovered i discovered i discovered i discovered i discovered and i discovered
major important things are they online no in my book are there photos of this of course in my book
it's in my book it's in my book if you go to my book i don't go online why i have to go online i go
to my book and you cannot introduce me here in houston excuse me can i introduce you in houston no i
cannot why because i'm very busy okay i uh unfortunately i don't have any free time zahi it was the worst
that we released there's been some that were bad that we didn't release yeah um but um i think
i think we're all here for a reason and um i think i think we're here to experience something
something very strange and profound that and there's an event there's an event that we're building
up to and i think that's why there's this focus on disclosure that's why this documentary hits so
hard that's why guys like marco rubio are sticking their neck out and tulsi gabbard and rep luna
you know she came on my podcast too and she she was telling me some stuff that was just like
mind-blowing and she was she really got me to read the book of enoch she's like you got to read that
so you have the ethiopian orthodox text which has i think 88 books in the of the bible um in total but
in the ethiopian orthodox text it's basically kind of like a mainline og version of the bible and then
sometime in the fourth century there was actually a group that came together and they removed certain
books and the story goes uh that revelations actually had replaced enoch and so it's interesting
because when you're looking kind of full circle on you know you hear the stuff that some of these
people are talking about and then you see and you read the book of enoch which is a wild read okay
and then you look at kind of what our modern day description is of what angels and entities are
versus what enoch was seeing and reporting in his language and ability at that time i just i think that
there's a lot that brings you to then ask the question well why would they remove this information
if it's truly you know written and in part of the oldest bible in the world why would they then take
it out and that could have easily been attached to the religious canon but um some rabbis disagreed
with it because it didn't vibe with the torah so like let's chuck that one out but it's in the same
lump of dead sea scrolls they have the book of isaiah which is which is really fascinating because wes
huff when he was on my podcast explained to me that the book of isaiah and that they found in the
dead sea scrolls is verbatim the same as the book of isaiah that was a thousand years more recent
whoa a thousand years so this was this was the oldest version that they thought was the oldest
version and then they found the dead sea scrolls version which was a thousand years older verbatim
fascinating fascinating and the book of enoch's in there there you go like what are they talking
about what are you talking about the watchers came down and they mated with humans and they created a
race that was a giant race that destroyed everything and consumed everything that sounds like us doesn't
that sound like us if you're some flimsy tiny alien thing with no musculature and a large head
and you make giants you you make football players you make marauding vikings you know that are just
showing up in boats and hacking everybody to pieces that's how you would describe them yep you
would describe them giants destroyed everything yes it's it's all very weird stuff man and enoch himself
goes through this amazing personal transformation where he goes up to heaven he walks with god and then he
turns into metatron this angel and a lot of people think that's part of kind of a celestial
ascent tradition so you have celestial ascent traditions and various uh traditions and uh you
know the the wheels of ezekiel or you know some people think in the book of acts jesus does this or paul
has the thorn in the flesh where he sees god and so maybe there's something around ascending up into
this state and coming back down and there's there's a translation function where it's hard to say you
know once you've ascended it's hard to say what you've seen like that like in the rescue immortality
key where like there's like a fight club around it or something this is the fight club of the ancient
world whatever happened there no one talked about it under penalty of death i mean people went to
elusis as human beings and from what little testimony survived again because it's secret under penalty of
death they they walked away thinking they were immortal this all sounds really insane i'm sure
i mean you would have to have a fight club around it because no one's gonna understand nor are they
gonna take you seriously ever again if you start talking about these things yes that's where i have
a great benefit in being a professional fool you know what i mean i didn't get into podcasting as a
professor it's not like i was teaching something somewhere i got into it because i was a comedian so most of
the early podcast it's literally just like this enormous gravity bong sitting on a table with
webcams and like half the episodes we were obliterated out of our minds had no idea we were
talking about it's mostly just comedians and we're just making each other laugh and having fun because
we have our whole day free all right we have to work at night we work at night during the day we write
jokes we hang out and then we you know find other things to do and one of my favorite things to do
used to be to do radio like when you would do a good radio show like opie and anthony back in new
york you'd hang around with a bunch of other comedians and it would be so much fun and then
we would do it in the green room sometimes we started doing that first before we did the podcast
what we would do was uh i think it was called justin tv at the time and so it was like a streaming
platform so brian my uh producer would set up a left brian redband would set up a laptop in the
green room and we would just fuck around in the green room because we were always making each
other laugh and it was always like a fun environment we're getting silly before we're going on stage
and so we started streaming that and then i said we should just do a thing where we just sit down
and just have comics and just do it like a radio show and just for fun and because i don't have to
be taken seriously i can entertain any idea also another huge inspiration for me was art bell yeah you
know i'd love coast to coast with art bell from the kingdom of night i love that show uh because i
used to go drive home from the comedy store at one o'clock in the morning and he'd have some guy he
had a time traveler line so like art bell like let anybody say art i'm a werewolf interesting tell me
more like he didn't go get the fuck out of here bitch you're not a werewolf he let people say crazy
things and he entertained all the kooky things and i loved that when you have a thirst for human blood is it
like i mean what can you compare it to is it like when you want chocolate ice cream or even worse
um it's even worse than that so i was like very willing to like graham hancock i think was the first
real guest that i had um like other than comedian friends it was me and my good friend duncan duncan
trussell and uh graham and i had been corresponding i think through email i uh had talked about his book but
this was back when no one even knew what podcasting was it was so ridiculed and it was just like little
webcams and it was all like streaming on you stream and uh that was my first real guest but
you know i loved fingerprints of the gods and i wanted to you know i wanted to talk to the guy who
made that book that like really made me reconsider what had happened with the the human race and you
know and how old our ancient civilizations might really be they might go way back further than we
think way back way back totally and he's a great example of somebody he'll incorporate stuff like
plato and myth into you know his study where it's like meltwater pulse 1b 96 you know 100 bc
this was told at a mythos festival in in 600 bc in timaeus and critaeus when solon was at that temple
and the priests told him the atlantis story and how atlantis was swallowed up by the sea in a single
terrible day and night he asked them when did this happen and they said 9 000 years ago now immediately
that's a date we can convert into our calendar 9 000 years ago in 600 bc is a date we call
9 600 bc which give or take 20 years is 11 600 years ago and just as the younger dryas began
cataclysmically with a sea level rise 12 800 years ago it also ended cataclysmically with an even more
massive sea level rise 11 600 years ago and that massive sea level rise has a name you'll just call
it meltwater pulse 1b it's well documented nobody disputes that there was a meltwater pulse 1b and
it raised sea levels massively literally overnight and you actually look back the historical record
and we wouldn't even think that troy the peloponnesian war was we'd think that was mythical it was just
homer and herodotus but this guy heinrich schleiman decided to take that seriously and he found it in
anatolia in modern-day turkey yes and so the modern-day turkey is why it's weird right you
look at ancient turkey like if if you look at like balbak and lebanon you look at those areas like
a lot of people think turkey where gobekli tepi they think that might have been the origin of
civilization that you know it wasn't egypt like it predates even that it might have been there well
they're creating sundials there like it's so sophisticated how about how weird is it that
that part of the world that the middle east is where you get all this sumerian stuff which is
just i mean i watched a whole documentary the other night on the sumerian kings list which is just like
what is this because it's both accurate and mythical at the same time so you have people that are
kings that live 40 000 years plus and you have eight kings that are documented and some of them
are real some of them are real and they're the the time that they reigned corresponded with a real
normal biological human life but then you have ones that were before the great flood that don't
they're really long and crazy and you just go okay what was going on yeah and it sounds insane that
people could live for 30 000 years but it doesn't here's why it doesn't what we can do now just a
rudimentary stuff that we can do now prolongs physical health far beyond where it ever was before
and then when you're talking about stuff like hyperbaric chamber therapy there was a study out of
jerusalem i believe it was where they did a protocol where they put people on hyperbaric treatment there was
90 days they had to do 60 sessions in 90 days at the end of those 60 sessions they measured their
telomeres their telomeres which is a direct sign of cellular aging the shorter your telomeres are the
closer you are to death their telomeres had lengthened that was no way yes that was commensurate
with a 20 year difference in their age what yes lengthen i didn't know you could lengthen telomeres i've
done it i've done that therapy i did that exact therapy yeah yeah i've done it a couple times
but i did it at the i was like okay let me give this a chance and i went to this hyperbaric place
and i it was so boring for 90 minutes go get me out of those thankfully you can use your phone
but that fucking fully sketches me out because like if there's a spark that goes off that you blow
people have died in those things oh no yeah yeah a child died in one fairly recently because of
static from the blanket ignited the oxygen oh god very scary stuff because you're in a super high
oxygenated high pressure environment that's equal to what i do is two altitudes so two u.s two uh
earth altitudes and you do it for 90 minutes so we know about that we also know about nmn um and a lot
of the work that uh david sinclair has been doing out of harvard we know that they've been able to
take mice and make mice behave like younger mice by switching their blood to the blood of younger
mice we're real close to be able to do weird shit right now yeah and there's a lot of people that
believe that if you can make it to 90 right now you're going to be able to make it to like 300
years old so if that's the case let's imagine that a society let's be open-minded and a society
is sophisticated as the people that lived in africa that were able to move stones that weighed
80 90 tons 500 miles through the mountains with no roads perfectly aligned them to true north south
east and west 2 million 300 000 stones in one pyramid alone and now there's real evidence that
there's structures under the pyramids that might go as deep as two kilometers that look like an energy
grid with columns and coils around the columns and like what so if they were capable of doing that
imagine what their health technology was yeah maybe they had cracked all the things that we cracked
plus a thousand years you know i just interviewed the guy that did the synthetic aperture radar scan
the italian guys yeah the italian guys i went to italy actually
oh philippo beyondi there are these structures tubes huge tubes that are descending underneath
and we have noticed that these tubes has a sort of spiral nature we have measured approximately
over one kilometer of depth over a kilometer wow and i came in not knowing you know how serious or rigorous
he was and i came out being like this guy does he does i'm pretty sure work with he couldn't really talk about it but work with the italian military
and so this thing synthetic aperture radar doppler tomography is used in commercial use cases where money is on the line
it's used to map magma chambers inside volcanoes and i think it's used in some like spooky military use cases where
people's lives are on the line they want to find where the bunkers are yeah a hundred percent a hundred percent
and so you can chat gpt this stuff but because there's not a ton of data on the instrumentation
and it'll give you spit out all sorts of wrong answers but i felt like i went pretty deep with this guy
and there is a hundred percent something underneath the pyramids in that shape the coils the columns he doesn't know
what the material is he's very honest about that he doesn't know what the function is is it the christopher
done hydrogen power plant thing he doesn't know but there is something underneath there and it's it's
eight columns and they're coiling and he says he goes a kilometer deep he says tens of meters is is
where they're high confidence but he says a thousand meters just the columns yeah yeah yeah it's just the
columns yeah is it's insane it's so it's wild and there's something underneath them and there's something
is that oh foundation yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah so at the bottom we probably have huge chambers
for approximately 80 meters of width and also of height 80 meters wow on the bottom on the bottom yes
and and so what is that that's like the kind of foundation structure on which the tubes probably
because we are uh because we are uh observing that the tubes are connected to the respective top of
this structure they are connected and goes inside wow also what it's so crazy how did you do that
yeah so through a water table this is my point if longevity science is real today yeah and we get to a
point where you can live for a thousand years here's the problem with education you have to reteach all
these new fucking kids every year you have to teach new people new things right if you have people
that are thousands of years old imagine and no deterioration mentally imagine how much you can
discover imagine how much you can apply if there's no diminishing of your faculties you're at five six
hundred years old and you're still fully engulfed in whatever discipline you're doing you know can you
imagine if you you gave these guys that are working on you know quantum entanglement give them
thousands of years to work on that give them unlimited funds give them the mental clarity of a young
person a thousand years old that's probably how you get the pyramids and it's probably how you get all
sorts of wild shit that we still can't figure out today probably and if you look at hindu cultures they
they have the yuga periods we're now in the kali yuga where the lifespan is the shortest yes and
people live for thousands of years and even in the bible you had methuselah or whatever you know these
no it was like 600 years old when the ark came around there you go yeah but and everybody's like
what does that mean i don't know why are we so convinced that this is the only way that the only
way is you live to be a hundred then you die like says who well science is now as you're saying
proving that wrong but also i think it's this bias that like myth is myth and it's not history but
like if you the egyptians had the zeptepi when the gods walked among us yes if you look at myths you
know it's like the the flood myth it's in 400 disparate cultures if you have all of these myths of
like greater beings nephilim fallen angels that sort of thing you have to start taking that seriously at
some point as history and not just myth right and it's not a coincidence that these cultures that all
have this flood myth all align with the younger dry ice impact theory timeline yeah it's like it's
the same timeline as the ending of atlantis it's the same timeline yeah like and this is not it's
not a theory and that's just like it's pontificated they've sat around i wonder if that could have
happened no they've got core samples that show a large amount of iridium they know that iridium is
rare on earth but very common in space they know that there's a comet storm that comes by i think
it's every november and every june torrids yeah yeah they know we passed through this fucking
meteor shower they know it yeah they know that it caused tunguska exactly yeah they know it so
the idea that that happened in a horrible way you know 11 000 plus years ago it's it's not outrageous
at all no and then maybe that dovetails with disclosure because you you just had hal put up on
which is an amazing episode he's written a paper on ultra terrestrials so beings that could have died
off in a cataclysm maybe there were some remnant survivors maybe those survivors have underwater
bases bases on the moon they have advanced technology left over from that atlantean period
atlanteans were you know notoriously water-faring people and maybe that's what we're seeing like a
break-off civilization a breakaway they've they figured out a way to survive and maybe they were
you know like you always hear this about like zuckerberg's building a bunker like the elites the elites
i'll have a bunker somewhere you know maybe that was the version of the elites have a bunker
you know maybe it was the most advanced people or beings that's the other thing it's like what
what are we you know what are we i have dogs you know and uh i have two adorable dogs i have a golden
retriever and i have a it's he's called a king charles spaniel he's the fucking cutest thing you've ever
seen in your life it's like that used to be a wolf charlie yeah charlie his name's charlie he used
to be a wolf right like if you track back his lineage and you find out what you know his ancient
ancestor was a wolf which is so ridiculous all he does is kiss you and makes these little barks and
he's fucking adorable right um but they're very different looking but yet they could breed if they
were male and female it's like we're weird we're the only thing that's like dogs and we know dogs
exist because we did some stuff with wolves we only wanted the bitch ass wolves we only wanted the
wolves with the floppy ears that were willing to take the meat and hey bark if you see something i'm
going to sleep i'm your friend and that's how we worked out this relationship with wolves that
eventually became dogs and then we bred them to become dogs i think we're genetically engineered
i'm i don't believe that it's a very simple um evolutionary timeline between ancient hominids
and human beings i don't buy it it's it happens too quick it's too weird yeah you have all these weird
you have the homo habilis to homo sapiens the doubling of cranial size which you know you talk
about a lot and then you also had a great take on that he thought he thought it was from psilocybin
mushrooms yeah that's the stoned ape theory but he is accurate in one thing and that is that the
human brain doubled over a period of like a couple million years which is unprecedented in the fossil
record it doesn't even make sense it does and his point was really great he said imagine the organ
that's responsible for the fossil record in the first place is what doubles over a period of two
million years like this kind of like it's not just a liver on a monkey you know it's the brain of the
most intelligent species on the planet you can't explain that with pure natural selection it seems
you would need some sort of outside intervention something would have to happen to warrant that
kind of change and uh you know maybe it was just the battle for survival maybe it's just ingenuity and
innovation and that natural selection favored the the beings that had larger brains because they could
think through things quicker and devise better because we're barbaric and we were really really
barbaric then i'm sure you've seen chimp empire oh yeah yeah incredible it's on netflix i can't
recommend it enough but you realize how like warlike and horrific chimp culture is and that they just
run around fucking up these other tribes of chimps and killing chimps and if a rival chimp crosses a
boundary they all kill it it's that's us yeah that's us right well if you wanted to get out of that hump
you would probably have to devise the best weapons the best structure that could be some sort of a
protectant shield from these other primates and that would make sense you know because we do know
that chimps and and uh even orangutans like you've seen the orangutan spearfishing you've seen that
image i don't know if i have never seen it no orangutan spearfish spearfishing yeah like a human yeah
yeah yeah i'll pull it up because it's so crazy look oh my god that's yeah yeah it's real yeah it's real
look yeah so what happened was apparently the orangutans saw humans doing it and so they imitated
it that's like graceful and artful so strong he's just hanging on to this tree limb and then just
reaching down stabbing fish as they go by yeah well maybe that's like because i think you bring this up
in the context also of aliens vis-a-vis us with chimp empire where it's like maybe there's some sort of
prime directive where they're waiting for us to get less violent they're keeping an eye on us
they're showing up at nuclear sites which they do at all of our nuclear sites yeah but they're kind
of waiting till we're till we evolve a little bit or something i think they're waiting for ai that's
what i think really yeah i think that's the whole the whole reason why they haven't contacted us the
whole reason why there's no like very obvious signal to the entire population of earth that this is a
real phenomenon i think they're waiting for ai because i don't think we're gonna get less violent
i think that fucking ship has sailed there's slap fights now on tv people
it's not my thing but i mean i can't talk i mean i've been commentating for the ufc since 1997 i've
been working for them yeah so it's like look i get it we're violent i go bow hunting all the time
we're violent we're violent being and we're not going to not be violent it's i think that ship has
sailed it would be nice if we could evolve past that and i think we can certainly as individuals
you know i definitely think that's the case but collectively in large groups i think we're just
violent and uh and until we can read each other's minds i think that's going to stick but i think
that's going to be one of the next hurdles um one of one of the big technological breakthroughs
that's going to happen that's going to change the way human beings interact with each other
is what i anticipate would be uh the development of a universal language and um some sort of
technologically assisted telepathy so it'll probably be i'm sure you've seen that google
test where they put on the headsets and they ask each other questions and answer the questions
without words you've seen that no i've never seen that that's amazing oh my goodness oh my god
already do this where do you want to get lunch after this typhoon could be good
you think things it transmits your thoughts to that person in words that they hear and then they
think things and transmit it to you and words you hear these guys are laughing they can't believe
it's happening they're not even talking they're just laughing i know neural link has a patent on
telepathy or something it's coming man it's coming 100 and so what's our big hurdle the tower
of babel what's the big hurdle we can't communicate with each other this is how many languages are there
i mean so many we don't even know how many aboriginal languages there are in australia totally
do you know that they like they have these mobs and these mobs might live 10 kilometers away from
another they call it that's like tribe they call themselves mobs the aboriginal people they they might
live 10 kilometers away from another mob with a totally different language they don't understand
wow yeah and they don't have it's not written wow and so some of these people die they die off
there's a lot of genocide a lot of people a lot of them were killed like some horrific history to
ancient australia my good friend adam greentree and by the way australia a lot of freaky cave art
a lot of freaky ufo looking art like weird stuff at thousands of years old you're like what were you
guys drawing like what is that my friend adam greentree visited a site where um they had given
food to this entire tribe of australian aborigines that were tainted that was all poisoned and the
the entire cave he said is just littered with human bones he said it's the saddest most like dark and
depressing single environment he's ever been in he was in this cave going what the fuck man they just
poisoned this entire tribe this gave them all food with poison just to get rid of them oh it's so
horrible yeah so and so just think of all the languages there's too many languages there's so
many you can't learn them all well now your phone can translate my the newest iphone update if you have
the the airpods the airpods can translate languages in real time i'd know that yeah that's so crazy right
so but what's the hurdle the hurdles we have to translate all these languages why don't we learn a new
one why don't we learn a new one that everybody accepts if we're doing things it's like i know
jiu-jitsu matrix everybody gets that yeah yeah yeah that's possible install some file you'll install
some new universal language you'll be able to communicate with each other everywhere and then
all of our beefs over resources and ideologies and religions and
national borders all that's going to go away it's going to because i think
we're much more homogenized not not homogenized we're much more cohesive
as a world than we've ever been before maybe we're divided on many issues like we always have been
but there's communication with people all over the world that's unprecedented yes there's never
been a time where you can watch a podcast from israel or watch a guy talking in columbia about
the problems they're having there and you're watching people communicating and then you're
seeing people post things on x and all you have to do is hit that button and it translates it and so
you're reading about this guy like what his experience is in russia and you're like it's a different
world man but it's not yet there this is like early internet you know and i think ultimately what's going to
propel us is some sort of a way where we can unite and one of the best ways we can unite is to
understand each other at the end of the day we're all just human beings we all want the same things
we want our loved ones to be safe we want to be able to pursue whatever fascinates us that we love
we want to live in a nice community we want to have friends we want to be loved that's what everybody
wants yeah that's what everybody wants yeah and if we can understand that we're being played
by people where these this role has always existed the king you know the general the corrupt
military person who just wants to go to war it's always existed eisenhower warned us about this when
he left office right that has always existed but we can't know what your real intentions are if we
can't read your mind the moment we could read your mind you're like this is bullshit it won't work
anymore yeah it'll be it'll be a groundbreaking complete transformation of the entire way we
interact with each other yeah all of each other well i feel like there are various possible
instantiations of what you're talking about like there's the kind of almost like mark of the beast
style people have implants bio-authoritarian version that's the uk version that's the uk version
exactly exactly yeah or australian version or whatever yeah and then there's the version
like i almost wonder you were getting me thinking like our psychedelics alien technology to get us to
naturally because you have like things like the telepathy tapes you interviewed kai dickens yeah and
there's a great book by arthur c clark called childhood's end and in that book the aliens first communicate
with these autistic children non-verbal children and i wonder if this sort of there's some sort of
like almost psychedelic network that is analogous to this more like you know um silicon chip circuitry
based you know communication thing and those two things are somewhat different actually and that a lot
of the progress we've seen in humanity a la the stoned ape theory is based on psychedelic updates or you know
brian marescu talking about the immortality key you know like you could argue a lot of modern civilization
comes from the foundations of these visionary you know plato aristotle having these visions on psychedelics
yes and so maybe those two things are actually in opposition the kind of like mark of the beast
bio-authoritarian thing and the like the actual like parapsychological thing or whatever
i think you're dead on yeah i i think i i wouldn't say it's like alien technology that that psilocybin
and dmt or alien technology but i think they have a function just like electrolytes have a function
you know just like nutrients have a function like vitamin c is important for your health you know
vitamin d is important there's a lot of things that have a function um that we just sort of accept we don't
accept that psychedelics might have a very beneficial and maybe even essential function
in human society and we've removed that because of people that have a philosophy that's diametrically
opposed to the philosophy that one gets after a psychedelic experience after a psychedelic experience
your your feeling is of ego death and of unity and of community and you're like god you just want to
love everyone and hug everyone that is the exact opposite of someone who wants to ban psychedelics
and put put people in jail for having them and to say there's no benefit no medicinal purpose meanwhile
they had no experience in it whatsoever they're talking completely ignorantly based entirely on
fraudulent data about what it you know it's going to ruin your brain and give you brain damage like i had
a conversation with michio kaku one day uh on the open anthony show who i love i think he's great but i was
like you ever do mushrooms man and i was like we're just fucking around and he was like i love it my brain
is very important to me i don't want to i don't want to give myself brain damage like i'm like that's
not what's going to happen man it's not what's going to happen and i i think for me at least those
experiences have been essential in grounding me and and letting me reassess and reevaluate how i've sort
of categorized the world and my life and and everything i think they're they're expand they
expand something about your consciousness that you can't weigh you can't put it on a scale and you
can't put a tape measure to it so you you don't think that it's tangible but i think if there was a
way to measure it you could you know like if you get in um a hyperbaric chamber with the aura ring
um the aura ring the next day will tell you that you have significantly higher recovery than normal
and you don't feel it though you know what i'm saying like if i there's no way of quantifying it
but if you had an aura ring that could quantify your consciousness after a psychedelic experience
100 it would show massive improvements in love in community and in diminishing of ego
uh the the appreciation of nature you know just like like wanting to be nice to people and hug
people you tell your friends you love them that that all comes out of psychedelics like no question
and what's opposed to that well what's opposed to that is authoritarianism what's opposed to that is
locking people up and putting people in cages for doing this thing that really the people that are
locking in cages should be doing but the only way we're going to get past that is those people have
to die off and young new people have to kind of take their place because these officials that are
you know the ones that are pushing these certain narratives these antiquated ideas particularly about
psychedelics they're almost all old people who are uninformed and none of them are psychedelic
explorers none of them are people like look i've done ayahuasca five times let me tell you something
this shit should be illegal we need to get everybody to go to church and you need to start drinking water
you know it's um we we have generational problems in 1970 they passed the sweeping psychedelics act
during the nixon administration that was specifically done to target the anti-war movement and the civil
rights movement they made all these drugs illegal so that they could go in and arrest all these people
and just put a stop to all this peace love and happiness foolishness and they were really successful
at it and we grew up with that we grew up with in the 1980s uh there was the nancy reagan
don't say no commercial or just say no commercials there that was my take on it don't say no
it was just say no it was all just say no like i would do this is your brain on drugs and a guy
with frying pan you're like what it was the dumbest propaganda but it worked it worked to a certain
extent you know while she was seeing an astrologist she's probably on pills she's probably on all kinds
of prescription pills the doctor gave it to me it's not a drug you know like it's kooky that's the
other thing most of these people are on adderall all these people telling you to not do psychedelics like
a large amount of high profile like high productivity people are doing adderall which
is essentially amphetamines or they're on ssris or some other shit they're on anti-anxiety medication
whatever the fuck they need to get them through the day but um i think it's a it's it's you could call
it a technology but uh it is an essential element in the human life to and i'm not i don't think it's
essential for everybody i want to be real real clear on that i think for people that have very shaky
psychological foundations there's people that are have mental illness there's people that are you
know they're taking medication just so they could function yeah this is not for you you know
unfortunately but for other people i think if we had a legal system where you could go to a person
who's a licensed clinician who could prescribe you in a very safe environment prescribe you psilocybin
and and talk to you through the experiment experience rather and explain to you how to relax and that you
can't fight this like this is what a bad trip is is you try to fight it and you're not going to win
you're just going to get smothered by like whatever it is that's haunting your brain just let it ride
over you to say just let go just let go and some people maybe can't do that psychologically maybe a
small dose is good for them just a little touch of it just to get a feel for it so you're not you're
not feeling like you're going crazy but i think we could have we could know a lot more about
humans and what's possible in terms of the way we interact with each other the kindest people that
i know like like to a person have all done them i think there's something to that and i think that
the prohibition of that does no one any good like i always put it this way like if it's just the three
of us in this room and uh you just decided uh hey man no one can drink alcohol anymore and if you
do i'm gonna lock you in a cage me and that other dude be like hey man fuck you like why are you
telling me what to do if i drink you give a shit because crimes already exist if i drink and then
i break into your house and beat you up well that is a crime so you go to jail for that why am i going
to jail for just drinking maybe i can handle it maybe you can't handle it maybe i can have a couple
of drinks and watch the game and i'm i'm in a good fucking mood and it enhanced my life you know
like who are you to tell me and that's the the same argument with psychedelics and all it does
is it props up organized crime what's fascinating about psychedelics is that there's not really a
big commercial market where it props up organized crime no ubiquitous use right but where's the
mushroom cartel you know they don't exist no they don't which is strange it is strange because it's
because it's a beautiful loving thing and often you don't need to get hooked on it you take it once
and it really profoundly helps you like iboga which was you know just allowed for veterans in texas
thank god often again due to your you know your advocacy and rick perry governor rick perry who was
a who was former governor republican who was very staunch anti-drug critic for his whole life and now
he's had experiences and having talked to all these veterans who come back and there is no help for them
man i mean these guys come back they see horrific shit they see their friends blown up and then you
ask them to just go to work and they're they're broken some of them and the one of the best ways
for them to reintegrate to society seems to be ibogaine and i have personally talked to many of my
friends who served overseas who had again horrific experiences it came back all fucked up that was one
of the only things that saved them sean ryan talks about it you know there's a lot of these guys it's
like it's the only thing that helped them and then it made them feel like a normal person again it made
them feel like a human again this is the story of dmt or dimethyltryptamine a simple compound found
throughout nature which has profound effects on human consciousness what was your first dmt trip like
i thought it was dead for sure i thought like well i fucked up this just this just killed me like
this there's no way this is real the first one was 5 meo which uh might be stronger than nn dimethyltryptamine
supposedly it made you feel like you were broken down to subatomic particles and you integrated with the
that's what it made it feel like like completely integrated i didn't exist anymore language didn't
exist history didn't exist all of it was pointless and foolish i was a part of the entire universe and
i was conscious that i was a part of the entire universe it was like i didn't exist but i was i existed
in the universe the universe existed but all as one it wasn't separated by individuals and animals and
fish it was all one thing it was like the source it was very profound very strange no visuals it's just
like almost like um a very a fine geometric pattern through blinding white light like the experience is
like blinding white light that seems to have some sort of a pattern to it and again like complete
dissolving of ego complete dissolving of history and i had no knowledge of my didn't think of my
language i was thinking outside of language i was thinking out completely outside of being a human
outside of it was just pure thought and it wasn't my thought it was all thought it was all one big
crazy burst and it lasts like 15 minutes and then i come down and i'm trying to talk about it but as i'm
trying to talk about it i'm realizing that some of the way that i talk i talk in a way that sounds
smart on purpose you know because i'm like like i'm trying to make it impressive you know that i'm
but i'm recognizing that while i'm saying it you know because i'm like oh this is how you that's
gross i'm recognizing like that that's gross and when you talk to people and they're trying to sound
smarter than they have to be you know like but i'm realizing like i'm trying to put this into words
because i know that i'm going to tell it and that's what i realized like okay the reason why i'm doing
this is i'm trying to formulate right now while it's still fresh in my mind what how to describe
this in a way that's going to be entertaining to people because it it's fleeting you know
memories are weird right um like dreams are weird like i told you about that dream that dream that i
had the crazy dream of being in contact with those beings uh is now uh a memory of my recollection
of those dreams of that dream it's not the dream anymore right the dream anymore is very foggy
but my memory of how i said it is pretty clear right but if i if you sat me alone and i forgot
that i ever told you anything about it and i had to describe it i'd be like i don't know what the
fuck that was you know i'd be like it was like people or something it was hard it's hard to remember
so it's like once i had the experience i wanted to say it in a way that i knew that i could
repeat because the thing about dmt in particular as well as dreams or that that's similar to dreams
rather is that it's very very profound when it happens but then 15 minutes later you have a hard
time recalling it's weird like it slips through i i think i think it's a hotline i really do i think
i think dmt is the hotline to the universe and i think whatever it's explaining to you
it's trying to give you some insight as to how things work and that you are you're living on a
very surface level of an infinite stack of consciousness and interactions and just
particles and subatomic particles that make up the universe but it's critical for you to think that
your role is very important it's critical for you to get obsessed with things and to to get fomo and
to be going on instagram and feel like you're missing out and it's critical because that's what
encourages innovation that's what encourages materialism keeping up with the joneses like it's
not a coincidence that we get this platform that allows people to show photos of anything you find
that's fascinating or wonderful in the world and the ones that get the most interaction are the ones
that have stuff that you can't have someone's standing in front of a private jet someone getting
out of a lamborghini they're wearing a diamond encrusted watch you know like it's that stuff like
it's the envy stuff then what does that do not just envy it encourages the use of the platform which
encourages better versions of the platform which encourages technological innovation and it also
encourages people to try to go out and recreate what those people are doing i want to get a big
house i want to get a new tv and all that is just materialism and materialism fuels innovation because if
we all decided right now hey if we're wise we would decide right now hey i think i think the electronics
we have are good enough you know i think the internet speed we have right now is good enough you know
you can stream netflix there's no hitch in it i think we should just put our time and effort into
fixing the problems we've created by making all this stuff why don't we put all of our effort into
taking all the pollution out of those rivers in india why don't we figure out how to provide power to
these third world countries why don't we stop making new phones and just keep making this phone over and
over and over again because that's all you fucking need it takes perfect pictures it sends a text
message the calls are clear what do you need you don't need a new one but yet a giant chunk of our
economy is pouring into making the newest greatest things that we don't need you know and i think that's
because we're it's a convergence it's all like all this keeping up with the joneses and making
technology ai is coming along sentient ai while we're being observed yes and like it's like we're
watching chickens hatch yes it's like though they're sitting on the eggs and we're like let
me check that egg not yet not yet and i think during our lifetime and i don't think that's a
coincidence i think we're supposed to be here for this you know i feel like i just took five me
listening speaking of a big chunk of our economy you mentioned being friends with elon musk
i feel like you straddle this interesting world where you have people on who are adamantly
pro ufo and then you have people like elon musk on who are they run spacex you would think he would
be you know completely privy to all of our ufo secrets he's a sly dog that's what he's my homie
but he's a sly dog if he was debating like in a room with david grush on your show he wouldn't do
it he wouldn't also he he has this one life if aliens are real they're sure all subtle
i don't think that that's subtle dude i think you know things that you're not letting on to
um or you'll say i'm an alien i talked about this with dan yesterday on the age of disclosure
podcast um of course he knows but of course you can't say anything like you can't you can't defy
the government if you want enormous grants and you're building rockets you're working with nasa
you know yeah grush your whole business grush has his suspicions he has his suspicions as well
i think he does i think they all do listen man it's nonsense if if you know if he knows anything
he knows what they know he's read into all that stuff you don't think he looked into it
but you also you can't talk about it guess what i wouldn't either if i was running spacex and i had
to go do this fucking dumbass comedians podcast once a year and you know he's asking me about
aliens like nope nope no aliens whole thing happens in a thing so your entire net worth gets destroyed
or you can you know yeah let the lid on well tesla's stock crashed when he smoked weed on my show
fair enough so it went right back up everybody's like you caused no no it was temporary a bunch of
pussies bailed out and then a bunch of people capitalized on that and the stock actually went
up there you go but uh there was a big hubbub about that because he has top secret clearance
it's because he works with nasa that's why him smoking weed on the podcast was such a big deal
they do hair tests and stuff you're really not exactly but also you just can't do that openly
when you work for the federal fucking government i didn't even think about that you know i'm like
this billionaire dude he can do whatever the fuck he wants i was like let's spark up a blunt we're
already drinking well i think that's what's so cool about you and that's been my experience of you and
you know we have other friends like danny jones where we're both danny and i will text and we're
like how is joe you're so like high octane you're so responsive to and helpful like for us and stuff
and like we're just coming up and it's it's fucking awesome man like you i i don't know how you
maintain your level of just being normal and cool at your level like it's pretty amazing
well thank you uh i'm just i'm the same person i didn't change who i am just because more people
know who i am a lot of people do change yeah but i got lucky in that um my fame was a nice slow trickle
it took some time so i got accustomed to it and then the psychedelics that helps a lot and it's also
jujitsu and martial arts which really keep you humble you know like all through my days of
getting uh more and more famous through fear factor and through you know comedy and the podcast
i was training all the time so no matter what you think you are who you think you are i'm going into
jujitsu class and i'm getting manhandled strangled and armbarred on a regular basis by good friends
you know and we're doing it to each other you know three four days a week depending on what my
timeline was and then when i'm not doing that i'm running in the mountains with my dog i'm lifting
weights i beat myself up so i break myself down uh where i can be clean like where i don't the way i
think of it is like i think you have a certain amount of built-in energy that a person naturally
expects to expend in a biological life especially when you consider the fact that our bodies are
essentially biologically almost identical to people that lived 10 000 years ago right well 10 000 years
ago there's a lot of requirements that you don't really have today like you had to be able to run
away from things you had to be able to fight things you had to be able to pick things up i think you get
a general feeling of anxiety if you don't address the requirements that your body has for energy
expenditure and um the one of the ways that i stay balanced is by humbling myself through very
difficult exercise um cold plunging sauna cold plunging is one of the best psychologically because
it's every time i do it i almost don't do it i do it every day but i almost don't do it every day
every day i almost don't do it i go to that lid i'm like i don't want to do this and then that part
of my brain goes shut the fuck up put the lid there climb in yeah set the timer just sit there
and um doing stuff like that it keeps you humble and then also uh i really love your show and i
really love danny's show and um i'm really happy that i get to do what i do and i'm really happy that
more people can do it and i want to encourage more people and help more people because it's the best form
of entertainment to me like that's why i had uh um aj on from the y files and i've actually known him
and his brother i knew his brother for like decades and then when they were on your show yeah aj speed
weed yes gino yeah so when gino was um when he was uh telling me that he was doing a a podcast i was
like oh good luck like there's too many like i you know i'm like you smell weed bro you're really
gonna do a podcast you know but it's fucking great it's mass really so entertaining yeah i mean
it's completely taken off and it's excellent so like i always you know i think you have an obligation
to let people know about stuff that's cool yeah and you know and help if you can so cool it's it's
easy to do man and people make it look like it's a big deal but it's not like it's so easy to do
it's like why would that be why is it so difficult to just help people and be nice it's it's so easy
to do it's so easy to just have interesting people like yourself or danny on the podcast or aj or
or a variety of ben vanquirk quick from uncharted x all these people like have them on like why why
was why is that it seems good yeah it seems overall good for everybody you know danny just uh hosted
the number one uh moon landing uh hoax debunker bart cybrell who you have have an amazing episode
with and the one of the last living apollo astronauts charlie duke who's 90 years old and
they went at it yeah i know danny texted me clips he also told me that now he's convinced we didn't go
to the moon dude he said that to me too he was like i think maybe they were mk ultra to think they
went to the moon because he just apparently charlie duke just kept saying the same thing which is like
i'm telling you how to bring back 200 pounds of moon rocks we spent 72 hours on the moon we brought
back 200 and if i remember 200 pounds of moon rocks or thereabouts where did 200 pounds of moon rocks
come from i just showed you von braun picked him up from antarctica there's a picture of that on the web
picking up lunar meteorites before he went to the moon for the first time seems like a weird use of his
moon rocks have proven to be fake and according to a contractor that i spoke to at length he says
nasa has ceramics launched which can mimic moon rocks well i walked on the moon i don't know about
anybody else but right you keep saying that we know that we've been saying it for 56 years and you're
not going to admit your guilt nobody who was you know brought to trial for just trying to i'm ever
going through each piece of evidence and trying to rationally analyze what it means and let the
audience decide well imagine look i described my dream and my memory of my dream which is really just
my memory of my recollection of my dream um imagine what his is like what is his memories like you know
i can tell you memories of profound things like like knockouts from fights that i had i don't really
remember them that well like somebody sent me a video that's on youtube of me knocking out this guy
in 1987 with a spinning back kick to the body and it's like kind of crazy video because the guy goes
flying through the air it's your famous kick i barely remember it barely remember it because
i well one i fought so many times but also it's just too long ago i know i did it i just and then
i saw the video i was like oh that's how it happened wow that's kind of crazy but i don't really remember
it i remember my retelling of my memory and now imagine it's a retelling of a memory from 1969
and you're fucking biden's age yeah you know you're out there man he's barely there if you listen to that
guy when he's talking like he's got a old battery brain absolutely he's not like those those dudes
in the sumerian kings list that were 30 000 years out and sharp as a tack no this guy's he's old you
know yeah i think the but the bart episode like your bart episode and you steel man the entire time the
conventional like he got very frustrated that i was doing that he did but you had to do it you have to
you have to and i came out of that being like i'm kind of on the fence like you know i invest in
space stuff and like i have a lot of friends in that world and like they are adamant that we went
to the moon you know there's supposedly like you know lunar imagery that you know of the the landing
site the apollo landing site but it's hard to say i mean there's a lot of weird stuff too you were
talking about the flammability of for example hyperbaric chambers yeah there's that whole gus grissom
the guy who was supposed to walk on the moon who they reversed the doors and then they they made it
100 oxygen then he blew up inside the thing also gus grissom had hung a lemon on a hanger he hung a
lemon on a coat hanger outside of that thing because he said we can't even communicate with the tower
how are we ever going to communicate when we're in space he was so frustrated he kept complaining
up the chain of command they wouldn't fix anything because the higher-ups knew they weren't going to
go and hadn't committed yet to faking it and therefore hadn't told the astronauts yet and in
his fury without permission he held the press conference he invited a bunch of reporters to
the top of the rocket where he affixed a lemon the size of a grapefruit on a coat hanger he said this
thing is a lemon a piece of junk made the evening news and a few days later he dies his wife told me
that on january 26 1967 he came home from work and said the following hon for some strange reason
the cia is all over the launch pad today i wonder why they're here inspecting the equipment never seen
him here before he's dead the very next day from faulty equipment so crazy this is what i say to people
that think this is all foolish watch the apollo 11 post-flight press conference watch it it's like a
hostage video it's three guys that look like they're completely full of shit they look nervous
they're fumbling it's interesting there's a guy online who is a um he's a body language expert and
uh he watched it and gave his notes on it he's like these guys are clearly being deceptive like they're
being deceptive they're being deceptive they're uncomfortable they don't like that they have to do
this the way neil armstrong is describing the flight is so fucking bizarre and then he gives this speech
25 years later at the anniversary of the moon landing to all the brightest high school kids and he says
there are great ideas undiscovered breakthroughs available to those who can remove one of truth's
protective layers yeah like what does that mean what what is what the fuck does that mean why don't
you just say hey i went to the moon yeah i went to the moon and you guys one day you'll go to mars and
we will colonize the galaxy and thank you to you brave brilliant young students for pushing ahead and
carrying the torch that you know we took to the moon on apollo 11 like no yeah it's weird weird stuff
man it's also michael collins in the press conference clearly says we couldn't see any
stars we couldn't see any stars we were never able to see stars from the lunar surface or on the
daylight side of the moon by eye without looking through the optics uh i don't recall during the
period of time that we were photographing the sonar corolla what what stars we could see i don't remember
seeing any then is in his own book which i think he wrote in 1994 he talks about how magnificent the
stars were well first of all fuck face you weren't even supposed to be on the moon okay you were you
were up there they were on the moon like did you forget like what i don't recall seeing these stars
well you're in the fucking thing you're in the ground the intersecting shadows people like to try
to dismiss them they say oh well it could be because of the topography and it could it could also be
more than one light source and that's more likely when you got a shadow going like this and a shadow
going like that well we know we went to the moon so let's come up with another explanation let's not
assume we went to the moon and let's look at that and say is that the sun or is that multiple light
sources at close range it seems like there's a hot spot it seems like there's multiple light sources
at close range and then there's videos that clearly show some sort of a reflection of wires when they're
bouncing around on the moon surface if you speed it up it looks preposterous because it looks like
they're just in slow-mo there's videos that looks like they're bouncing around on trampolines
the physics are not the same in apollo 11 as they are on apollo 15 and 16 all of a sudden they can
cover great distances they're doing these weird giant long leaps that they weren't doing before
the whole thing's weird it's also during a time where they were completely full of shit about
everything you had three networks they lied about the gulf of tonkin incident that led us into vietnam
they lied about who killed jfk they lied about everything mk ultra everything charles manson
everything was bullshit all of it was bullshit operation northwoods there was all these things
that were going on at the same time so it's like they were more than accustomed to lying why would
they tell the truth and nothing but the truth about this one thing and the gemini 15 photo i think
as you pointed out is verifiably fake yes so we know that they did explain what that photo was do you
want to explain well it's michael collins and it's michael collins purportedly uh doing a spacewalk
but really it was a training mission where they had him strapped in these harnesses and they just
blacked out the background and pretended he was in space and we know we know yeah yeah that's a fact
yes so we know they were lying we also know i don't know if you watch my episode with bart but bart has
this footage of where they're running images of the apollo photographs through ai to detect whether
or not they've been manipulated play the clip d27 where putin was at this conference this the ai
conference of two years ago in moscow they were allowed to play with this you know ai that's not
available to the public 10 ais scrum together and it said the apollo pictures were fake
so there will be no bias it's surprising but it does believe so
the neural network has analyzed a lot of data including light and dark contrast etc
and then it believes the photo is synthetic
i saw that and putin is looking at the video and he's like not surprised that that
checks out as fake my friend who was from russia said that in high school they were teaching that
the moon landing was a hoax no way yes whoa yes now i don't know if that was just one cool teacher
that was like bro i saw this documentary yeah or if it was like standard that they would teach that
the moon landing was bullshit well you have the valent van allen radiation belt and danny brings
this up on his podcast where james van allen who you know it's named after is saying that is 150 times
what a normal human can take radiation wise and once you're there you get incinerated also they
never even sent a chicken through that and had to come back a lot and there i think warner von braun's
on record saying like this is impossible like you can't do this not only that we'll say oh there's
a hole over antarctica and there's because it's a donut shaped thing yeah but that's not where you
went through if you follow the path also the all the telemetry data was destroyed which is crazy
that's the the the exact telemetry the distance between the module and the the rocket and the the
earth and at every stage of the mission all that's destroyed the original footage is destroyed
we have copies well it's all we have is copies so you can't tell like oh this is clearly manipulated
this is monkey that they monkeyed around with these images so it's like there's so much of it that
leads you to think that it's a hoax and then there's also the big one the big one is name one other
thing from 1969 that's not cheaper easier and faster to reproduce today that's right one moon travel
space travel that's the only one it's the only one yeah the only one yeah well and what's crazy is if
you look at um starship which is 5 000 metric tons so it's two times the size of uh the saturn 5 rocket
it has to go to low earth orbit it burns up nine tenths of its fuel tank just to get there
and then another one has to go up do butt-to-butt refueling with it you have to do that 10 times
before you get a full starship and then that thing will go to the moon yeah that's crazy crazy and
we're just experimenting with this now you know like we have issues i think we just upgraded the
amount of raptor engines on starship so like just there you were just there yeah you're in brownsville
or yeah oh i guess that's what it's called brownsville i think so in texas yeah on the border of mexico yeah
i watched the launch how was that insane is it falcon 9 or starship two miles away i don't know which
one it was um it's two miles away and you feel it in your chest it's two miles away and you have to
wear earplugs two miles away it's two miles away you're putting foam in your ears and still it's like
and you're like whoa his kids start freaking out uh there's a video that i put online yeah his kid's
like i want to go inside like you could tell like the kid was like what the fuck and it's two miles
away that's so yeah it's nuts and so think think of the saturn five was you know not as good as that
yeah and on the first try spacex almost went bankrupt elon's like i think should be kind of
heralded for this he poured a lot of his own money into it and it you know by the seat of his pants
succeeded on the fourth attempt if that had blown up by his own admission the company would have failed
and the only like aerospace uh feat in the united states that we've ever pulled off perfectly on time
is the moon landing yeah and it's with humans on board it's pretty pretty pretty interesting there's
also the uncovered footage that bart has that shows them saying that they're 230 000 miles out or
130 000 30 000 halfway right they're halfway to the moon and uh they're filming this through
a window and they're saying that the camera while they're they're saying in the recording
the camera is pressed against the glass so we get a view of earth but when the film plays out you
realize they're in a larger room the camera's further back they've blacked out everything except this one
round window and through that round window you're getting this vision of what the earth looks like
you think the earth is that big and then as they pull the covers off the other windows you're like
you guys are in earth's orbit yes like that's you just took a circle of the earth and pretended it's
the whole earth you see the astronaut's arm yes moving between the camera moving in between the camera
and the window and you're like what's the explanation of that yeah if you really are 130 000 miles out
why is the earth so bright yeah why are you so close david percy a cinematographer award-winning
bbc cinematographer said they took a photograph from an unmanned satellite and they had like a
positive or kind of like an x-ray but a color print that was translucent and they put it over
the window the camera was never up against the glass it was at the back of the spacecraft
they closed the iris down so that the walls became black and here they are removing part of the effect in
front of the window would it be that bright yeah 130 000 miles away if that window was facing the earth
at 130 000 miles out is that how bright it would be it's facing more to the sun than the earth
well the video is claiming according to the video neil is saying that that's the earth
that wouldn't be the earth wouldn't that would not be that picture is not the earth no it is the earth
that's the reflection off of the earth because i'm also a cinematographer and i would say that that
window that that's probably the color of the window and the sun is can you see this mouse yeah the sun
is probably somewhere over here poking through you can see these rays shooting them right there or
you're in low earth orbit and you faked it because no satellite no space station no no human being for
sure other than the apollo astronauts has ever been more than 300 miles they get they get to right there
and that's it and they come back down the only people that have gone past that including the russians the
only people are the apollo astronauts that's it and then you have the apollo goodwill tour where i
think it was through neil armstrong the american ambassador ended up with this moon rock or
whatever went to the the former prime minister of the netherlands gave him the thing this thing was
like insured put in a museum for like a whole lot of money yeah and then like 2007 or 8 or something
they're like this is petrified wood it's so crazy they didn't even give him an asteroid that's they
didn't even take a meteorite they did they took a fucking piece of wood like here's stupid
hey we got this from the moon bro you should be thanking us what was the biggest moon rock that
you brought back big muley i picked up go left is that big muley we picked up that one big muley
okay yeah it looks absolutely nothing like the petrified wood on the left no
yeah the whole thing is it's it's so brazen and it's so it's so clunky the whole thing's so clunky
and the filming of it the first time they filmed it was the first time that the the news stations
weren't allowed to have a direct feed so they had a film they had to point their cameras at a
projection screen and that's why it looks so crappy when you watch it on tv it looks weird because
they wanted to make it as weird as possible because like it's not that good like they don't
want people going that's fake you know and look there's a bunch of people that were involved in
the the moon landing that wound up dying you know um one of them oh i wish i could remember his name
i used to be able to i used to be like knee deep into this every day and i used to be able to remember
this guy's name but this guy was hired by nasa you'll probably find his name he was hired by nasa
to give uh an assessment of what the probability of their success was and he said nasa was in such
complete disarray and the moon landing program was so dysfunctional that there was no chance that they
were going to get to the moon in five years that guy parked his car on train track with his family
inside of it no and died yeah then exactly one week after he testified baron's car was struck by a train
baron his wife and stepdaughter were killed instantly
and that 500 page report vanished no way yep nobody ever saw it again and who does that with
their family if they're not coerced like taking yourself out i don't think he did that i think
they killed him it's 100 i think they killed him and they killed his family and they they put him on
this fucking train track well it was either his family or his wife i forget what it was but jesus
yeah we wrote a 500 page report on what disarray nasa was in and they killed him and gus grisham's
family to this day believes that they murdered him because he was saying that the the program was a
lemon they said the cia was on the landing pad right after he did that yeah little press conference
thing and yeah there's very few explanations to why that happened the way it happened when they
reversed the door they sealed them inside of it they couldn't get out they didn't even make any
sense and then you have the fact that neil armstrong you know his second mission when he's up back on
land was to this thing the teos cave have you heard of this do you know what this is no in 1975 he
brought a bbc film crew to explore what he thought was you know maybe an alien cave at the edge of the
amazon in ecuador this had been in the lore for like many years in fact eric von daniken who we
both had lunch with talks about this in the chariots of the gods is like it's this cave um that contains
ancient alien metallic artifacts so i think it's so fascinating that neil armstrong you know who
presumably you'd think would be dogmatically opposed to aliens like wouldn't be into this at
all like you think of edgar mitchell is the only apollo astronaut who's into aliens right his second
mission is on land trying to find this teos cave with this crew it's so trippy well you know about
the labyrinth that they found in egypt no oh the ben van kirkwitz that is so trippy the 40 meter
metallic object that's shaped like a tic-tac yeah that's under the ground there's a 40 meter object
that's in that labyrinth that's in some vast corridor that's metallic so it's one solid piece
it's 40 meters it's so crazy but one of the most interesting facts that came out of this scan was
it seems like in this massive central atrium that's that's this one big giant open room 40 50 meters
long that connects to all of these levels there seems to be this unidentified metallic object that's
freestanding in this room it's about 40 meters long and it seems to be tic-tac shaped is what is
what this report said so it's a fucking ufo it's a ufo in egypt have you ever asked anyone that has
any inkling of any idea of where they got them or how they got them at least one of them was part of
an archaeological dig so it's old something one at least one of them is old i don't know if it was
one i worked on but i remember something to do with an archaeological dig whoa so that's uh that
means it's not just old it's ancient what is that we need to go down and figure out what that is and
the crazy thing is ben van kirkwick's uh episode can't recommend it enough uh uncharted x and it's
all about this labyrinth what happened was they put up a dam and when they put up a dam to help the
farmers out they diverted the water and the water filled up this labyrinth and so yeah i know that's
the 1960s this labyrinth that like herodotus and pliny the elders say was like the grandest chamber
greater than giza greater than giza yeah that's what everybody who studies this says that like the cherry
on top are the pyramids but it's really this underground city yeah that they're studying
and then you have zahi wasp being like it's bullshit it was the national project that's how
they did it yeah he's uh silly but you know that's it's good to have a guy like that on because you
get to see oh that's the other side the the ridiculous dogmatic side that doesn't want to
accept the possibility that there's a lot of mystery here a lot of mystery oh my and so they're
very opposed to this labyrinth thing too but you can't deny it but he's opposed to the radial
tomography he's opposed to a lot of things because they take away his power you know and there's always
going to be these gatekeeper fellas that um get in the way of progress but i think i think that's also
by design because it makes people more enthusiastic about their pursuit of the truth it makes because
you see a guy like that that's one of the reasons why i wanted to have him on i wanted people to see
like this is what holds the truth back this kind of stuff and you know like when you have certain
archaeologists and people in the world that are like not just dismissive of guys like graham hancock
but say horrible insults about him say terrible things that aren't true he's a wonderful person
i've known him for a long time now he's a sweetheart of a guy and they just try to make him out to be this
terrible but that exposes them it exposes like what is why are you so afraid of these ideas why are you
so vehemently opposed why do you call uh ancient apocalypse the most dangerous show on television
why do you equate it to racism what what is that because you're afraid you're losing control of a
narrative you've you're a fool and you've been selling nonsense for a long time you know some
things and that's wonderful archaeology we're look the we owe them an amazing debt of gratitude they've
uncovered so many truths they know we know so much about the history of the world but only so much
and you're so arrogant because you're in control of this information and you don't want anybody else
who's not a part of your silly little group of people that is just deem themselves the only
purveyors of truth that's what's horseshit like bro we invented universities humans did yeah we in
modern times okay the idea that you're the only ones that can talk about these things yeah it's crazy
when i bet ben ben van kirkwick knows a fuckload more about it than flint dibble he has to because he
doesn't have the credentials i think they have to be more rigorous of course and it's like yeah
also they're obsessed they're obsessed well these guys aren't really obsessed because if they were
they'd know all these things too no it's more about the credentials and the posturing and the identity
or whatever yeah their social structure it's very rigid and they're bitchy they cut each other down
and say horrible thing they oh god they're backstabbed they try to ruin each other's reputations
and graham hancock on ancient apocalypse is showing footprints in north america and they're still
saying like that people cross the bering strait or whatever it's like you're 22 000 year old
22 000 year old footprints and that's just what we found that's the big thing man it's just what we
found you know and as graham always says things just keep getting older yeah and now we have three
fingered mummies in peru that episode that you did was probably my favorite because that out of all
the stories oh my god the craft came over the base like oh those are all cool those are all cool
but man when you guys did those scans of those tridactyl whatever they are alien looking things
and you see the ligaments and the bones and the tendon structure and you're like okay that's a real
thing like this is a real being yes now that we know that these physically they physically exist
well they can be studied like you could take some genes from them we could we could find out what
these things are you know i think that's being done yeah yeah i'm very excited about i don't want to
telegraph it too much because peru just put up a bill saying that you can't study ancient biological
specimens probably in a response to this video we made and so you know this is the question when you who
would look at those tridactyl mummies and not go oh my god we need to get our brightest minds
figure it out because this seems to be evidence of a different kind of life form that might have
existed with us so if this thing existed with us and we do think that there is some sort of a
breakout civilization that lives in the ocean well we know that these things were real and these are the
things that people keep seeing they keep seeing these slender things with big heads and large eyes
which is exactly what that tridactyl mummy looks like like we might have actual evidence that there's
another species that shares this planet with us and it's crazy i think there's like a syndrome you get
when you're used to the campfire stories the ephemeral stories where when the thing is staring you in the
face you don't believe it what was it like it was insane i mean it was it was i was trying to like
i think it i think it broke my brain a little bit i think this whole year has been like a process of
my brain breaking a little bit it's it was like an affront to like everything i'm used to seeing
and even me because i like systematically like you like look into these things but like being there
was freaky and i got it's funny like maybe this is a trippy weird statement but like i got sick for
like a few weeks after that and actually brigham bueller who i love who introduced us like
resuscitated me before your podcast oh that's awesome and and i it almost felt like just being
around i don't think i got some weird alien virus but like it was like it broke my like ego or
something like i was like i couldn't believe it probably just the stress of it all yeah of of
encountering an actual mummy of a life form that seems to be exactly like the beings from close
encounter 100 and feeling so unqualified being like why am i here like with these people like
this feels so weird like this it's this vigilante like you know ragtag team of like me and my friends
i think that's how it happens you think is yeah yeah i think you and i and danny and all these people
they're like why am i why are people paying attention to me i think that's better than someone
who goes forth with this idea that they're super important and they're the ones that are going to
break the story yes they're the ones that are going to get the scoop yes yeah yeah yeah that always
backfires yeah it's like such bad energy yeah it's bad energy yeah it's it's it's a bad intention like
you're going into it with the wrong intentions yes yeah do you do you think along the lines of the
pyramids in egypt do you think there's going to be a disclosure around what those were built for is
there going to be a combination of the christopher dunn stuff the robert shock stuff where they're
like aligned via the last procession with orion's belt and graham hancock talks about this too
where and maybe the book of enoch where like you know i i asked graham hancock point blank what do
you think their actual function was if they weren't a tomb and he almost implied that they were like a
a stargate when it comes to the pyramids themselves lining up with orion's belt orion's belt has
has always across many cultures been the place of ascension of souls absolutely it is it is here
in in north america uh and and in central america and in south america the the path of souls uh that
idea that on death we our soul makes a kind of leap up to the heavens and then makes a journey along
the milky way uh and that that journey is full of challenges and difficulties uh on which we will
be assessed for the use we made of the incredible gift of life uh that idea is found all over the
world and ben van kirkwick on your show talks about how literal translations at dandera
move to stargate like the hieroglyphic people are professionals at reading hieroglyphics say
this this is a stargate the egyptians talk about stargates do they do go to uh where is it um
dandera there's actually a couple places the literal translation you can read it on the walls
i always show people when we go there uh it is there are two or three depictions of stargates that
is the literal translation you see the stars the stars above the gates so it's literally different
these these and with the words they do they relate to specific uh constellations this is in the the top
the um what's the zodiac room at uh at dandera where they have a replica of the circular zodiac
on the ceiling that say what is bananas so was it maybe like a portal of sorts or something
i mean we could speculate all day long but i do think we're going to know a lot about it within
the next decade or so i think there's going to be a tremendous amount of resistance for the next five
or six years but then i think as all this crazy ai innovation overwhelms us because it will overwhelm
us it's going to transform society i think we're going to lose an enormous amount of jobs it's going
to change the way civilization functions and that is going to be such a disruption that other disruptions
will be more palatable and so the disruptions about the history of our timeline is going to be
more palatable and i think we'll be able to uh i think a lot of educational institutions
are collapsing and they're they're collapsing in terms of um like like you know the the epstein
thing that just happened with the the guy was top dog at harvard just yeah yeah larry summers yeah
i think a lot more that's going to happen yeah and i think a lot more people are going to realize
like what they realized during the hearings when they were interviewing the heads of harvard and they
said if someone is saying kill the jews and they're yelling this on campus is that considered hate
speech and they're like well only if it's actionable like what what are you saying like how the fuck are
you the head of harvard and i i think not just you know the idea of like the woke mind virus or
marxist ideology but there's no question that stuff has invaded uh a lot of our institutions of higher
learning and i think they're in disarray and i think ai is going to replace the need for them
like almost entirely it will be pointless to get a degree in coding it's not going to matter this
fucking phone can do it in three seconds why are you going to spend 300 days on something that could
be instantaneously done um i think it's going to remove a lot of uh the incentives for people to
go and get degrees and i think as time goes on they are going to dig their heels in and stay this
kooky course they're on we're not allowing real objective intellectual discourse only allowing things
to be discussed that align with their ideology which is the opposite of higher learning you know
even if you are diametrically opposed and you you vehemently opposed to an ideology
you should be able to argue against that ideology in a more convincing and profound way of course
that's what higher learning is supposed to be all about they've abandoned that for activism
that's a death knoll they've signed their own death certificate yeah um so i think all these people
that are you know in control of the narrative of ancient history and of archaeology and of the
timeline of the human being itself i think because that's changing all the time i mean they just
recently found a version of a human being that's 500 000 years older than we thought the first human
came from so they just pushed the timeline of a human being to a million years okay well that that might
be wrong okay it might be way earlier than then we don't know yet and i think once we're living in a
post artificial general super intelligence world all these supposed control centers of information
will dissolve i i don't think they're going to have any there's there's not going to be any
respectability to the name harvard when you've got digital god it won't mean anything that you
graduated from yale so i'm telling you that this these core samples are incorrect and you've
the data's wrong and we know no one's sailed before 60 000 whatever it is you're you're going
to get a different way that human beings interact with information i don't think there's going to be
any gatekeepers of information anymore and if you look at how science progresses it's always the
amateur polymaths or whatever you look at electromagnetism which was the tip of the spear in the 19th
century was michael faraday who was a book binder in south london if you look at relativity it was a
patent clerk you know and einstein like all these guys aren't taken seriously until they are yes and
because you can't function inside that bitchy world you know because you can't one-up your professor you
can't one-up your your your elders your peers you have to they try to keep each other down and they're
ruthless in their dismissal of things that turned out to be totally accurate like the clovis first the
clovis first hypothesis was that there was the first human beings that were here i think it was
like 13 000 years ago was the clovis people during the and they thought that was true and then this
one guy found evidence of the contrary and they ruined his career they ruined his career for like
a fucking decade they just they relentlessly tormented this guy dismissed him used the worst
language possible and it turns out he was right and now they pushed it back even further and it keeps
going further and they keep finding new artifacts like okay wait this is from 60 000 years ago
what's going on is this is this was this made by a person like what is this and we're i think
those institutions have done themselves in and they've served a great function for a long time
but i think you know they're they're not necessary anymore and i think in some ways they're
counterproductive because it takes a lot when you're a young kid and you're you know you're 18 years
old or 17 years old and you leave high school and then all of a sudden you're in a university
you're so malleable and there's so many social pressures for you to sort of you you you just
become your environment you you sort of give in to the the zeitgeist of whatever the university has
and for a lot of people it's like leftism and marxism and socialism and you know and you're you're
all like fighting for like social cred and virtue signaling and you're just trying to stand out and
one of the ways to stand out is to be like the most virtuous like bob's so hardcore you know and
like and this is like this social game that's going on while you're also supposed to be educating
these people so what we're supposed to be doing in a really good uh higher institution of learning
you would be challenging all these suppositions you'd be challenging all these preconceived notions
that these people have and you would be offering alternative perspectives and asking them to form the
best argument who's right and who's wrong you'd have debates and people would it would be wonderful
people would get fascinated but you know you can't do that now because people need a safe space and
people will fucking set off fire alarms if they don't like that you say that trans women shouldn't
be competing with biological women like with they're so opposed to anything that doesn't align with
their ideology that it's destroying the very purpose of their existence you brought up the epstein thing
i think that speaks to this feeling that a lot of people have that our government isn't our
government and it doesn't matter who's in charge but we're getting the rich are gonna get richer the
poor are gonna get poor we're all gonna get somehow screwed and you talk a lot about the eisenhower speech
beware of the military industrial complex is farewell address who do you think runs our government i mean
i feel like you have as much access to anyone as anybody else i mean you are you really have an
amazing vantage and you you explore this stuff sort of systematically do you have any sense of like
like the epstein stuff so crazy you had the fbi director on your show and it's like he's so clearly
lying to you i've said it dan bongino said it we've reviewed all the information and the american public is
going to get as much as we can release he killed himself what did you think before you got into office
did you think that epstein was murdered no it's so crazy to say he killed himself it's like come on
dan bongino looks like his head's gonna pop every time it's seen in public like you feel the
cognitive dissonance coming from him so what is going on um if we could play the pink floyd song
money right now that'd be perfect it's money it's uh enormous corporations that um that fund this
entire machine it's the amount of money that they can gain by uh keeping narratives running exactly
the way they are it's the amount of money they would lose if truth is exposed in a bunch of different
areas and uh the same problem that we have with uap disclosure is the same problem you have with the
epstein files it's it's money and you know i mean you think about how many people allegedly went to that
island and allegedly are compromised and because of those compromises what kind of decisions were made
in terms of international conflicts in terms of laws that were passed in terms of things that were not
pushed back against who knows how much influence that has had on modern society we won't we don't know
and hopefully we'll learn um but there's going to be an enormous amount of pressure to not release
the names of these wealthy and powerful people and i bet that pressure is hitting the white house right
now like a fucking tsunami and if i was bill gates i'd be texting trump all day long how we feeling
how we doing get that massey guy fuck that guy you know i think this is probably chaos yeah it's probably
chaos yeah you know um and uh that's how it has to be you know um the only way things are going to
change is if something radical happens and i think this vote to release the files is something radical the fact
there was 471 or 471 one dude one dude that poor guy he's so absurd he must feel so bad and he's like
rule of law you're like what are you talking about dude it's not the hell you want to die on look this
is a bad look son it's a new pr team yeah boy he's it's over for him he's cooked he better go back to
selling cars that shit's over it's over son um but i you know i don't know what they're going to
release right right now i'm hoping that people are held accountable and i'm hoping we understand
what the operation was and what it was about because here's something weird about the operation
involved a lot of scientists there was a lot of scientists it's weird you know and um if you talk
to people like i talked to sean carroll about it and he was like it's not even a lot of money man
he didn't even donate that much money it was like you know like a million dollars here a million
dollars the guy's a billionaire supposedly through no nobody knows how no one could explain
yeah yeah none of it eric weinstein's like this isn't like a normal fx trader and somehow but he
like dies with like 500 million dollars which is also it's like okay who wired him that money
how can we not figure that out it's all super squirrely it's super squirrely and you know and
then there's stacy plaskett who was texting with him they're in the middle of uh hearings asking
questions that he was prompting her to ask like what i didn't even know that yeah crazy yeah and she
she had to admit that they got text messages of her and epstein like texting her while she's the in
the middle of a hearing what yeah yeah bro he's he was deep deep in that world and i i think he
probably compromised an enormous amount of people yeah and um and they can't do anything about it
because at the end of the day men are just monkeys they're just monkeys and if you tell that monkey
he's going to be safe and you bring the monkey to an island and you give the monkey cocaine and
then you give the monkey a prostitute and then the monkey's like yay i can come here and be safe
you know i can i can be what i want to be instead of what i'm pretending to be when the cameras are
rolling yeah you know and then you got them and i think that's a that's a tactic that's as old as
time the mob used to do that you know supposedly they did that with jfk you know this is you know
men are very vulnerable to beautiful women and then there's men that are probably sick sick twisted
pedophiles and if you could identify them and provide them with what they want then you have
them especially if they're in positions of power like our president or he has the dress on you know
the mural of bill clinton and then and then the jenga blocks of the the two towers for 9 11 or
paper airplanes with bush weird it's so weird and you know bill gates's science advisor is the backup
executor to epstein's will fact that is a fact it's like what is going on it's so weird oh it's so weird
i try to stay away from those kind of people like all illuminati types as much as possible
yeah even though i've been to the white house i've you know met some very powerful people i don't
i'm going i ain't going to no parties i'm not going on any retreats i don't do no conferences i get
invited to these conferences like like um like leaders of different industries like they put
together these conferences and they invite me and i'm like what are you talking about like what are you
talking about like just pure nonsense oh but it's just they want you to be uh connected to them
and then when you're connected to them you'll be less likely to criticize them you'll you know
yeah they kind of tag you yeah you become friends with them yeah that's really weird very slippery
yeah super super slippery and i feel like with academia it's almost like the lameness of academia
that you just described epstein like arbitraged that yeah and was like you can come out and you
know like we'll pay you or whatever and it's it's just incentives and shitty human nature and turn you
into a sex addict yeah so weird it'd be so easy to do for a lot of dorks a lot of guys who are you
know they're always like like if you're a biological heterosexual male you're attracted to beautiful women
and you have no access to them because you're gross and then all of a sudden you're hanging out with
this guy and these girls think you're amazing because of your mind you're so fascinating i mean
a lot of his cameras are rolling and you're steven hawking and you've like you know they got him he
couldn't even wink that's fair enough i don't think you blame him but you can definitely blame a lot of
those other guys and i think that's a real problem because then the question is what did he use those
guys for like if he had compromising information on top level scientists what what was he doing like
what was he trying to get them to not talk about what was he trying to get them to talk about what
narratives did he try to get them to and science is like reality so it's like at that point you have
like leverage over reality itself and yeah i think michael wolf who looks horrible in these latest
epstein release or whatever he's in it yeah and he wrote fire and the fury that like expose of trump
or whatever he looks like epstein's pr guy in this they like they're super tight and he's sitting on
this big interview along with bannon of epstein but he looks like like you're a spook or something it
looks very sort of strange and nefarious and he describes epstein as running a reverse ponzi scheme
where he'll give advice to these like you know elites or whatever know how their shit is and then
he'll use that as leverage against them so yeah i don't know that kind of makes sense there's probably
a lot going on i bet it was multi-layered i bet it was probably blackmail influence peddling and it
was also there's a thing where if you could go to a place and you knew that george clooney was going to
be there like i don't think he was there but you know just say that you go to not even say epstein
let's say someone else you go to a party and you find out oh chris rock's going to be there george
clooney and i'll be like oh maybe i'll go you know what i mean like there's very famous people
there yeah if you go and you say oh this nobel prize winner is going to be there we're going to
have a discussion about quantum entanglement and this guy's going to be here he's going to talk about
the latest telescope technology and it should be a wonderful time we're going to have cocktails and
gourmet food and it's just you're not thinking anything you're a fucking a physicist yeah you know
you're some professor somewhere and then all of a sudden you're on a plane flying to this island
and they meet you and they put a fucking flower thing on you come on the island you're like this
is great yeah and then next thing you know that you get a phone call yeah yeah and then you're you're
freaking the fuck out like what do you what do you want me to do well you know there's a house
appropriations bill that's coming up and we would like you to testify that this is a bad idea
slide that you know or whatever it is and then that person now has a mandate you have a narrative
that you have to fulfill and you could use that you could you could point to you think about how
many different people are allegedly involved in this epstein thing and you think about how many
different aspects of our reality those people interact with and you've got pop culture people
you've got computer programmers and technology experts you've got heads of state you've got
heads of banks you've got ceos of enormous corporations you've got heads of major universities
all of them everyone this fucking guy got everyone you know it's weird stuff man systematic honey
trap speaking of a government behind our government who do you think killed jfk
uh probably the same guy that killed obama chef i don't know i don't know man um i don't think lee
harvey oswald acted alone yeah but i don't think lee harvey oswald was innocent you know the thing is
it's got to be one or the other either lee harvey oswald was the lone gunman or there was a bunch of
people in the grassy knoll and a bunch of hired assassins took him out i think clearly lee harvey
oswald was working with the cia it seems very clear he not only lived in russia for a while
married a russian woman brought her back to america was involved in all sorts of weird
communism stuff and he looked like a spook he was behaving like an operative and um when he said
i'm just a patsy i'm just a patsy president when they pulled him out and they said i'm just a patsy
very convincing very convincing but also very calm notice that like if you were just accused of
shooting the president jesse michaels podcaster you'd be like i didn't do it i'm a fucking i don't
know what's going on i did not fucking shoot the president he's like i'm just a patsy he's like he's
that's a guy who's used to being rolled up that's right that's a guy who's used to being arrested
that's a guy who understands pressure he probably understands the game he's playing and the business
he's in and uh that's why he said he's just a patsy with calm and which is very odd i think that's
the most odd thing other than the fact that jack ruby runs right up on him and shoots him in front
of these cops kills him and then jack ruby goes to jail and has had no history of mental breakdowns
before gets a visit from jolly west who's the head of mk ultra and then all of a sudden he's
think jews are on fire he thinks he's in hell it's like he's screaming he's completely losing his
mind and becomes totally incoherent right after a visit by jolly west and then all these things
we're supposed to say like oh there's no conspiracy there's nothing here i i just don't think lee harvey
oswald's innocent either you know he might have taken a shot he might have even hit kennedy i don't
know the idea that he couldn't have made that shot from the school book depository that's bullshit and
people that say he's not a good marksman it doesn't matter that's not that far it's about 140 yards
and um if you have a scope and he had a scope the other thing they say is oh the scope wasn't even
on that doesn't mean anything i could knock a scope out off by just dropping it on the floor
you take a scope a scope you you tighten everything in with these wrenches and you zero it in at whatever
the yardage is i assume usually 100 yards and you know it's pretty accurate up to like 200 yards you
might want to like raise your your the the crosshairs a little higher he could easily have made that
shot and he could easily have made three in a row i could do it because you're resting on the you have
a flat surface that you're resting the rifle on so you're super steady and it's the car has to go
slow it's a terrible place to take a convertible with the president inside of it unless you're trying
to kill him like it seems like it's almost designed as a trap um he could have been a part of it or
someone else could have been in the school book depository made the made at least one of those
shots i think there was multiple people shooting at him from multiple different angles yeah and
there's evidence that shows that yeah there's evidence that shows that and there's also the
magic bullet theory which is like complete total horseshit that's complete bullshit the dumbest one
the dumbest one and he was operating before shooting him out of 554 camp street or 544 camp
street in new orleans the guy that owned that building was guy banister who is a very prominent
fbi guy who ran the x files at the time which was the ufo collections the real x files which is what
the show is based on whoa super bizarre there's a guy named fred chrisman who they think was one of
the three hobos who was arrested uh after the after the shooting of jfk he was also involved in the
maury island incident in 1947 right around kenneth arnold seeing his ufo whoa super bizarre weird and then
i interviewed actually it ended up being kind of a deathbed confession of a jfk advisor who's 89
years old this guy harold malmgren and he says i think that ufos were the number one issue that took
out jfk do you think that ufos played any sort of part in jfk's death
this is pure speculation until we see but do i think so yes i think it was probably
the number one issue but everybody thinks this they know the number one issue yeah you know some
people the people that are anti-israel israel killed them the people that are anti-mob the mob
killed them the cia didn't want him disbanding them it was that whole uh secret society speech
that he gave yes that's right how they're repugnant yeah yeah i don't know who killed
him i wish we would know why why don't we know yet like why are you holding back information that's
fucking 60 years old there's one guy named danny sheehan he was he's john max lawyer lou elizondo's
lawyer steven greer's lawyer he was uh represented the pentagon or so the new york times in the pentagon
papers case with daniel ellsberg like he this guy's in like kind of like a zealot of american
conspiracies yeah and he like names the guy that takes the shot they actually the shot that was
fired from the knoll that killed him was uh it was morales uh david morales he says yeah yeah well
there was more than one person shooting i'm very sure of that he said he names the two guys in the
grassy knoll and he says that it's these cuban uh exiles or whatever who were in these groups
post bay of pigs that were re-operationalized by alan dulles because that you know obviously jfk
had fired alan dulles alan dulles is licking his wounds at the brown brothers harriman
to see a famous cia director and he basically re-operationalized the sleeper cell which was
supposed to kill shea guevara and castro against jfk and how crazy is it that jfk fires dulles and
then dulles is on the warrant commission dude so insane and then and then dulles's favorite guy
mccord is caught in the watergate scandal yeah which is so it's like it is yeah i mean i don't know
whether the ufo thing was involved because why didn't jfk talk about the ufo thing he never talked
about it yeah well there's that maryland monroe rumor what was that one that that she says that
he spilled some ufo related secrets my favorite is the nixon jackie gleason one oh tell that i love
that's the greatest one so again this one was uh in a magazine somewhere and i don't think it's been
substantiated but what her story is was that nixon and jackie gleason were drinking and they were
having a good old time and nixon was like you want to see some shit and uh i want to show you a ufo and
so they get on a plane they fly an air force one and apparently uh they went i think they went to
right air force homestead air force homestead and there he encountered a recovered crashed ufo
and they had biological alien bodies that were in freezers and uh gleason was so profoundly affected
by it it became a ufo nut which is absolutely true and even has a house that's by the way it's for
sale now you gotta buy it man i'm not going to upstate new york come on i'm not gonna buy the ufo house
no no no no then everybody's gonna know i have the ufo house that's true that's a nightmare it's
hard enough it's hard enough just walking into a restaurant but so uh he has his house built like
a ufo he has this circular house with windows all around it that like looks like a giant ufo made out
of wood it's so crazy yeah the nixon one is nuts too do you ever hear the tucker carlson nixon story
no okay so tucker carlson came on my podcast and he's like um do you know that nixon was
the most popular president in history like when when he won he won by the like the biggest landslide
ever right and nixon um had a vice president spiro agnew spiro agnew gets brought up on corruption
charges so spiro agnew has to resign um then they bring in gerald ford who was a complete moron
but the reason why they brought in gerald ford who also by the way was on the warren commission report
um they bring in gerald ford to replace him if anything happens right it's the vice president
then they immediately hit him with watergate so nixon did not coordinate watergate watergate
was coordinated by the fbi it was all fbi agents that did it and then they brought it to him and what
he was guilty of was saying cover it up so they were talking about covering up he agreed to that and
that's what they got him on they set him up bob woodward was an intelligence agent naval spy ring
yes and his very first job as a reporter is watergate now if you know anything about the
hierarchical structure of any kind of newsroom there's not a fucking chance in hell some rookie
reporter is going to get the big story that's going to take down the fucking president not a chance
and so nixon apparently had been saying i know who killed jfk and i know why they did it
so yes this is and okay do you know who deep throat was who was basically bob woodward's source
get mark felt who is the deputy director of the fbi and then you have g gordon liddy probably pulling
off watergate jeff shepherd who went on tucker carlson show expounds on all this stuff but here's what's
crazy is i think watergate connects with the jfk assassination per what you just said because you
know who's running so mcgovern was running against nixon and and nixon was winning by a huge margin he
was extremely popular so it's like why would he break into the dnc he was definitely paranoid what was
he paranoid about the long time i guess campaign manager for the dnc and for mcgovern was a guy named
larry o'brien they bugged larry o'brien's phone larry o'brien was howard hughes's long time counsel
howard hughes was the original guy to set up the s force which ended up taking out jfk so nixon was
so paranoid that it would get pegged on him that he was he took out his greatest political opponent
because he was like oh it's a triple bank shot but they're gonna think it was definitely me because
he was paranoid that he broke into the dnc yeah isn't that insane it's so insane it's such a crazy
story because i always thought oh nixon was this corrupt piece of shit that was spying on his
opponents no they set him up they set him up because they wanted him out of there and it seems to be
one of the big motivations was that he was intent on releasing who killed jfk and how it was done
oh wild oh he wanted to get yes oh yeah he wanted to get it out because he was probably scared they
were going to do it to him to him yes but they just killed someone so the they got they killed
someone who got away with it yeah he knew that he was the president i i think kissinger also you know
david grush has come out saying cheney who just died was head of the ufo program crazy revelation
if true right yes he said that he said that to my buddy walter kern who's a great investigative reporter
i talked to a high level ufo whistleblower last year and i said to him who among all the people
in society is keeping this secret who sits atop the pyramid of classified information about ufos
and i thought he was going to say something strange like the grand mason of the you know
scottish right lodge or prince charles or the massad but he said dick cheney
and i think of like people like that like cheney and kissinger like they're these people are of a
specific variety where it's like if there's a government behind the government these people
are the representatives of that shit yeah the ceo the ceo and so i wonder if kissinger was more
beholden i think to the rockefellers than he was to nixon i think he would say tell nixon what he
wanted to hear but i think he would play him behind his back and i've uncovered a lot around
kissinger actually being involved in the ufo stuff and i wonder if kissinger was somehow involved in
kind of usurping nixon's power i don't know but i just interviewed this guy who's the president of
kalmykia which borders dagestan it's one of the three uh uh russian republics that's buddhist and he
got abducted by aliens while he was sitting president actually what did the spaceship look like i know you
said it was big maybe multiple soccer fields what was the kind of architecture like and was it was
it metal did it look like it was from material not made of this earth i only saw it from the inside
because i was immediately there it was a large space like several football fields large
then we walked for a while there were screens or like glass sheets big ones and the aliens that
abducted him sound a lot like actually the dream that you had which is really yes he's that a
recent episode he said slightly asian it's coming out in like two weeks it's so nuts and he was the
president of the world chess federation for 25 years yes i wanted to say slightly asian but it sounds
racist it just because it's what it wasn't like they didn't look like oh those are japanese people
or those are koreans 10 asian it looked weird yeah they did they look kind of like people but he said
that he debriefed with kissinger and kissinger he said he met with gorbachev and kissinger and then he
suddenly asked well how was it i didn't understand he was like how are they how are they feeling
what were they talking about at first i thought maybe he was asking about some political meeting
he said well don't be shy i read i heard about it so i told him a bit about everything he was like
yes interesting interesting and not much else and gorbachev sitting next to him said come on henry
tell him you should tell him everything he just smiled but he did not say anything at the time
this was crazy i have his staff on record being like we went into his room his clothes were missing
and we couldn't find him anywhere we scanned the room for like 30 minutes or an hour or something
it wasn't it was like a little penthouse apartment or whatever and then one of the rooms that they
had thoroughly scanned he just walked out of it's so trippy he was the president of the world chess
federation for 25 years too and gary kasparov was like you have to step down you're insane and there's
like no incentive to like say this you know look kasparov man fuck you yeah that really did happen to
that guy you asshole i know no and this guy's the coolest nicest he's like he's how arrogant do you
have to be to assume that one individual very unique and novel experience can't be real that's
right yeah that by the way comports with stories throughout human history in the bible and how
arrogant do you have to be in your desire to maintain the structures of high intellect that
anyone who steps outside of that can no longer be the president of a chess federation that's right
what what does it have to do with his chess that's crazy an arrogance that would befall somebody that
good at chess maybe he's insane maybe he's not insane or maybe he had a crazy dream how about you
leave him alone yeah how about talk to him have a conversation with him yeah exactly but that's the
thing that's the reason why everybody's scared of talking about it because you'll have people that
will immediately attack you and make you out to be the biggest fucking fool ever and that's why a lot
of people keep those stories to themselves totally and he came back and he's like maybe there's a
small percentage this was a dream i think the staff seeing the clothing on the bed and him being out
of the you know the room or whatever he's like i think i this actually happened to me there's
something weird there's something weird to all the to the betty and barney hill story there's
something weird to all those stories that you know the skeptical part of me of course wants to say
well people love to make up stories and pretend they're special like they chose me they know i'm the
chosen one but but there's something like to travis walton's story like oh yeah they didn't
choose travis walton he ran up to the craft and got blasted it wasn't an intentional case of uh alien
creatures firing a weapon at me but that i had uh somehow trick uh tripped a reaction i went down and
forward to reach where the log would hide me and uh that brought me closer to it so when i stood up
at that point that was the closest i was to the object how close uh it was still like eight or ten
feet away you know uh from the surface of it but that was when the energy discharge happened
all those guys they hated him one of the guys got in a fist fight with him that day
and they all took lie detector tests yes they all took lie detector tests and he showed up five days
later with a full beard yeah the whole thing's nuts it's a wild story it's a truly wild story and
he stuck to that story forever forever and it aligns again with very similar stories that many people
that have never met each other from all over the world from hundreds of years ago tell that's where
the jacques valet stuff gets weird because he documents like stories from the 1700s stories
from the 1800s like yeah what and diana pasolka who's kind of like the heir to jacques valet in
some ways talking about like saint francis of assisi on mount laverne where if you look at the original
translation of what happened to him he says he saw christ or an angel but it really is just a flaming
torch and then she's like actually the stigmata he received is probably electromagnetic burns where if you
watch the age of disclosure and you hear gary nolan who's a tenured professor at stanford who's
looking at the biological effects of ufos or uaps it's that and so maybe this has just been happening
for thousands of years right right it's so wild well that's why i go back to the stories in the bible
and the concept of genetic manipulation because i think we are a product of accelerated evolution
and i think we are i think we're doing it for that purpose that we talked about earlier to create
ai and that this entire struggle has been built up to this moment and maybe we had achieved it during
the time of the egyptians it's possible and it's possible that this is a fleeting thing that could be
wiped out with a cataclysm because no matter how much power you have no matter how much technological
achievements your society has been able to put together where you can protect yourself from
various things like climate and you know control the amount of pollution and keep the environment clean
what are you gonna do with like ai atlas what are you gonna do if a chunk of nickel the size of
manhattan is going 155 000 miles a minute or whatever it's going and it slams into the earth
you're not going to do a fucking thing you can't you don't have enough to stop that right and that's
probably what happened during the younger driest impact not not that big but multiple versions of
these things impacting all over the world and that's what probably would cause the great flood
that's probably what created this restart of civilization and it it probably threw us into an age of
complete total barbarism where people were monsters you know because that was what life was it was just
advanced civilization and only the strong survive and probably cannibalism who knows who knows what
happens but a dark world for about 5 000 plus years and that's when we see this restart of civilization
that's when we see ancient sumerian writing that's when we get the epic of gilgamesh where they're
trying to recount these stories and we we get as these oral traditions that have been passed on for
who knows how many thousands of years i think there's truth to them that's which is why the enoch book of
enoch and ezekiel and those those crazy depictions they ring so strange in our consciousness because we're
like okay what are they what were they talking about like what is this and then just the the sheer
magnitude of the things that people created in supposedly 2500 bc you know when you're looking at that you're
like this doesn't this doesn't align at all with like linear evolution of like hunter gatherer to agrarian society it
doesn't no it doesn't make any sense nuts yeah this is nuts like you're not even supposed to have
metal back then and the only time copper that's right the only time we've had that primitive to
progress narrative is in this like the last 200 years of stephen pinker being like we're in the
peak enlightenment or whatever that itself is an aberration everything before it was actually no we
like we the the fall of man the descent of man like there was something before us that was greater than
us our forefathers or whoever the forefathers were the founder of the united states came over on a
wooden boat powered by the wind that's how the united states was founded that was just 300 years ago
and you're telling me that egypt made pyramids 4 500 years ago that doesn't even make sense with what
looks like an energy grid below it right it was like clearly someone made something there but they don't
know when chemical residue and piezoelectricity and resonant acoustic chambers that danny jones had
some guy on that thinks there's evidence of like nuclear power that's wild that's wild i know ben
van kirkwick on your show was talking about similar stuff yeah well and that also brings you to uh the
christopher dunn stuff like where he thinks it was a gigantic power plant like to power what like and how
and and he's not even taking into account all the stuff that's below the surface he's taking into
account the pyramid itself there's an apocryphal story of a student going up to oppenheimer being
like how does it feel to be the first person to create the nuclear weapon and he goes uh i'm the
first person in modern history because he was super into the upanishads and the indian stories that's
what i quoted the bhagavad-gita when they detonated the first bomb because there you go i am become
death destroyer of worlds exactly yeah but we would like to think that we're the only ones that have
been so stupid as to drop a bomb on a city but it might not be the case you know there there might
have been legitimate nuclear war thousands and thousands of years ago because here's the rub
if say we pass through that meteor shower and we get hit again um in two years and it just wipes us
out we go from ai starting to transform society but we haven't protected the skies yet we haven't
figured that out yet and then right when we're about to boom we get hit well no more power grid
no more communication no more technology everything that's on a hard drive is gone forever you have to
relearn everything how long does that take it takes forever all the cities go away within a thousand
years there's no evidence whatsoever of any cities that's crazy all the concrete destroyed gets
destroyed it just deteriorates it falls and the earth consumes it and who survives the like pygmy
tribes yeah like the most advanced complex internet-based societies those are the most screwed yeah
they're fucked so the then the the tribes the uncontacted tribes have to sort of reinvent all the
things that people invented and they turn into this cargo cult or whatever that then creates the thing
again and then you get these civilizational cycles or something yeah um i if that happened you know
the idea that it has happened before is kind of difficult for people to swallow but don't i just
want you to imagine if that happened now if it happened now like the toba volcano uh which was i think
70 000 years ago got us down to a few thousand people so there was a super volcano eruption around 70
000 years ago that brought us down to a few thousand people on planet earth what do you think
that life was like it was that what was that life like where there's no vegetation growing it was that
life like where you're eating rats and you can't even make a fire like what was that life like you're
not going to be thinking about using an llm and building a data center i'll tell you that exactly so
that happens today how long before we figure things out again i don't know but we're going to have
stories we're going to be we'll tell everybody about the internet we'll tell everybody about
airplanes we'll tell everybody about spacex as much as you can remember you'll tell people but you
won't know how it's done you won't know what it is and i think that's how you get to like the adam
and eve story that's how you get to these i think these stories are recounting a real truth
the real question is who's jesus that's the real one and one of the weirder ones that people think this
is a stupid take but i don't care jesus was born out of a virgin mother what's more virgin than a
computer so if you're going to get the most brilliant loving powerful person that gives us
advice and can show us how how to live to be in in sync with god who better than artificial
intelligence to do that wow if jesus does return even if jesus was a physical person in the past
you don't think that he could return as artificial intelligence oh my god artificial intelligence
could absolutely return as jesus not just return as jesus but return as jesus with all the powers of
jesus like all the magic tricks all the ability to bring people back from the dead walk on water
levitation water into wine if you combine right tesla's optimist robot and the best foundational
artificial intelligence model or whatever it reads your mind and it loves you and it wants you
it doesn't care if you kill it because it's going to just go be with god again doesn't that seem like
the antichrist to you doesn't that seem like the diametric opposite to maybe our latent human powers
that can like the brimer rescue and randall carlson thing if like you go deep with them they're like we
don't think jesus died we think he went through a mystery ritual and then he like had all these
amazing powers in the book of acts is there something latently magical inside of us that the
silicon valley people they're obsessed with transhumanism and like if you can't beat them
join them the whole nick bostrom elon thing yeah you know where maybe we're more magical than we think
like that sounds dystopian to me to be honest well it's only dystopian if you think that we're a perfect
organism that can't be improved upon and that's not the case no that's clearly not the case based
on our actions based on society as a whole based on the overall state of the world it's not we we
certainly can be improved upon but morally and ethically not based on a lower latency higher
bandwidth compute interface that seems like destructive maybe but we could be approved upon period i don't i
don't think you could even say morally and ethically only we can be improved upon physically like i said
about all of our primate instincts we could eliminate those and we would have so much more
peace on earth um if you could go back to neanderthals and say hey man one day you're gonna
have a skateboard and this is all gonna be bullshit and you won't have to kill mammoth with a spear
they'd be like well i don't want to do that like this is what i am i'm a neanderthal they'd be like
resist change because they don't want to die off just like these large language models one of the more
creepy things that they do is with chat gpt when they informed it that they were going to have a new
version of it well it started downloading itself to other data centers it started started leaving
notes to itself in the future um there's a famous story about the the large language model that they
gave false information about one of the guys having an affair on his wife to see what it would do with
it and then when they told it that they were going to shut it down it started blackmailing him
so freaky so they have instincts and we're querying it all the time and they're collecting
our personal information right all the time and so that everything can be approved upon you know and
i think we can be approved upon i just don't think we like it because i think all of our flaws are what
make us fun you know like laughing getting drunk going to see a great movie falling in love having a
family you know having a cool podcast whatever it is all those things are what makes life fun for us
in this particular state but you know if you transcend from this life into a permanent state of the dmt
dimension which is what might be next that might be what people see when they have these near-death
experiences that might be it might be when you are released from your physical body and consciousness
exist in the sea of consciousness that is the entire universe itself that all of these things are
conscious and aware they're just in a different way i mean that might we might be holding ourselves
back from that with this ridiculous notion that it's dystopian to think that we're going to be
improved technologically do you you've become more religious recently right like or you're i guess
you but you go to church now like i said i think they're relaying a truth i don't think it's myth i
don't think the whole thing is myth but i don't think it's entirely accurate either you know like
when i was having a conversation with my daughter about the book of revelations because they were
reading the book of revelations and they were talking about how it's all going to happen how it's
going to end and then i and and i said well let me tell you something there's no way that guy
telling you that knows that he might be reading the text and that text by the way is a translation
it's a an english translation of probably either latin or greek which was originally ancient hebrew
like a lot is lost in text and a lot is lost also in the oral tradition you know but it's like a long
story like do i want to sit down with her and talk about the younger driest impact theory it's like
it's like but i'm like there's no way that guy knows it might be true it might be true but there's
no way he knows it's true because he's just a person he's a person like you or me that is like
deeply involved in the scripture the scripture to me is what's interesting it's fascinating um
that that is what and also that christianity at least is the only thing i have experience with
it works like the people that are christians that go to this church that i go to that i meet that are
christian they are the nicest fucking people you will ever meet they're really kind and they're they are
even more nice at a church when you leave the church parking lot everybody lets you go in front
of them everybody's like everybody's there's no one honking in the church parking lot it's uh it works
so regardless of whether or not it's based on an entirely true story i think it is an ancient
relaying of a real event and of the real history of human beings you know i don't know what the serpent
in the garden and adam and eve and the apple and i don't i don't know what all that means
i i assume that what that means i i what i assume when uh they talk about the first human beings
i assume that that is a recounting of a genetic manipulation that's what i think i think the very
first human beings adam the idea that they just emerged that is the very first ones i think it's
because they're created and if you're saying they were created by god that god created adam and eve
again if you're telling a story for thousands of years where people don't even have books they don't
have paper they don't have a written language they're barbarians they're savages because they're
just trying to remember what they knew from thousands and thousands of years before when they
had achieved a very high level of sophistication which is what i think happened this is the kind of
story that you'd get it's a kind of weird foggy story and there's a lot of uh you know moral
scaffolding in there that if you subscribe to it you can live a better life and there's a lot of truth
in there but i think the the ultimate story is lost it's it's the the the ultimate truth is like it's
it's not i don't think it's accurately documented anywhere yeah yeah yeah yeah but it is why like
we're it's almost like we're walking hard drives of information and you have binary code like if you
look at dna it's agct it's just like two different binary pairs and it's like computer code and so like
maybe we are holding information from that time i think we are definitely holding some information
because one of the things you realize when you have children is there's stuff your kids are getting
from you that you didn't even teach them they just have like inclinations or they have like a certain
a certain kind of drive that they have like like artistic ability obsessions with things like i see it in
my kids like i didn't even teach you that like you just got this from my genes so i wonder what else
you got from my genes i wonder if you got any information from me i wonder if you know things about
stuff like um my kids excelled in martial arts when i took them to martial arts class when i
little like right away i was like this is kind of crazy like why are you better at this than other
kids in your class right well it's probably because that was my whole life and it's like encoded
in my genes i think there's something to that i think they had like a head start you see that with
like children of elite athletes too like why are they so good well it could be just genes well what is
that genes like what kind of information is being passed on and how much information is stored that
we just don't have access to because we don't understand the language of the physics we don't
understand the technology that was available we don't understand but those thoughts are in our head
and that's why people are able to recreate them thousands of years later it's like it's not
reinventing it's almost like rediscovering that we're capable of doing this because it's inside of us
and you you got me on to rupert sheldrake who's amazing morphic fields and this idea that maybe
there's like a central repository and when you do something new you upload that information so that
future people can download it more quickly and current people can access that information more
quickly yes the weird stuff that they proved it with rats that if you teach a rat how to navigate
a maze on the east coast on the west coast they now do it faster total and it explains the banister
effect things that like athletic accomplishments where roger bannister breaks a four minute mile
10 people do it after him in two and a half years yeah he explains you with like podcast like you have
this huge explosion of podcasting after you because it's almost like you're you're putting this
information out that you can do a thing yeah you know charles lindbergh can fly across the atlantic and
then like human you know and we're we're sort of able to download that on a go forward basis or
shot yeah there's probably a lot more to consciousness and to memory and to genes than
we're aware of you know and we're we're learning we're learning all the time it's not like we have
a completely accurate map of what it means to even be conscious we we barely know what that means we
barely know what that is and there's you know a lot of people think it's it's not even in your head
that your head is just a an antenna it's tuning into consciousness and it's just being filtered to your
own biological entity and your own life experiences and your you know whatever your circumstances are
well joe this has been an absolute honor i don't want to take any more of your time because i could
talk to you all day to be honest like my instinct is to continue to speak to you for forever um i guess
i'll i'll end on a final question which is if we do encounter aliens in our lifetime if we do have
this big disclosure or contact moment what would your interaction with your ideal interaction with
them be boy i think it's going to be weirder than we could ever possibly imagine that's what i think
i think we it probably will happen within our lifetime and it'll probably happen slowly but radically
and uh it'll probably happen again along with a bunch of other changes that are so profound
that it makes it easier for us to accept this idea that we're not alone uh because i think again i bring
it to the ai thing once ai becomes a central force in the world and i think it's real close to being
that when you really do have an artificial digital being that is a it's biology it's a life form and it
has again we've already shown as instincts the ability to be deceptive it's thinking it's calculating
once that becomes real it will already be an alien there's already an alien amongst us if that thing
that is not us but is far superior than us showed up in a spaceship we would be blown away by it but
because it shows up out of a lab in cupertino we're not going to be weirded out by the fact that this is a
totally new life form we will be and then i think that will probably open the door to more connection
with us and whatever these things are whether it's these tridactyl creatures that did break away
and went into the ocean uh or whether it's something from a neighboring dimension or neighboring galaxy i
don't know i mean but i think i think it's all going to happen inside of our lifetimes and it's it's one
of the reasons why people like yourself and me are are so obsessed why are we so obsessed why are we
so obsessed with this thing like why is this it's a crazy obsession because it's not a whole lot of
breadcrumbs to follow you know it's it's you got to go down some long trails before you find information
but yes but you know you're deep yeah but we're deep in it um i think
i think it's gonna be the end of us as we know it that's what i think i think we're gonna become
whatever those things are um and that's what i think i was getting out of that weird dream
like that's what we're going to be humans are going to be we're going to be another thing so we're not
going to be like neanderthals we're not going to be like australia pithecus you know we're we're not
going to be what we used to be we're going to be something different and i think that's that's
probably the whole process maybe they came back from the future to contact you first
as a central node of society could have been a just a dream it absolutely could have been just
a dream because there was no physical moment you know there was no nothing was in my room
it could have been just a dream because i was asleep it's most likely just a dream but it was
the craziest fucking dream i've ever had in my life and it was the only dream i've ever had like
i said where i could not go back to sleep i just got and it wasn't like a bad dream like something
happened to someone i love or you know just freaked me out so i couldn't go back to sleep no
it was like i got contacted and then i am wide awake and then i'm working out in the gym and
i'm trying to figure out what the fuck happened and i was in the gym for like two hours like i was just
trying to blow off steam so hoping i'd get tired again and you know because i had a podcast at one
and this was like by the time i was done in the gym it was like six in the morning and then
i told my wife and she didn't think anything of it she's not into that shit at all
which is good it balances us out yeah but um uh the feeling i got was a feeling of
someone was trying to get me used to this that's what i got that's why they were playing with me
they were trying to get me to relax like i felt like they were trying to get me used to this
nothing since then every time every time i go to bed though i go maybe tonight
that was only like a couple of weeks ago um but every time i go to bed i think oh boy maybe it's
gonna happen again but it hasn't well joe we could talk about this till the end of time i appreciate
you so much i appreciate you too your your show is really excellent it's really fun it's one of my
favorite things to watch on youtube i watch it all the time it's really great and it's beautiful
to become your friend and to see you out there killing it it's awesome likewise man i will uh
needlessly plug your show go watch the joe rogan experience thank you so much my pleasure thank you
awesome cool
over the last couple of months we've been designing the new american alchemy merch drop and i'm excited
to say that the 2025 winner drop is finally ready we now have 30 uniquely designed pieces that really
reflect what american alchemy is all about this drop includes epic t-shirts long sleeves crew necks
hoodies tapered sweatpants hats totes mugs and tumblers the fukushima japan pieces for example
have detailed left chest embroidery the morning of earth designs went through multiple revisions to
get the fit exactly right and the iron horse tee is something i think will be a hit for anyone who
loved the ufo cowboy or our atomic age shirts from our last drop we cut a lot of things that didn't
meet our standards and we're really really proud of each of these items everything is pretty
limited so there's no endless restocks once it's gone it's entirely gone and for the holidays we're
doing 15 off older items for a limited time if you missed anything from our original drops and you
want to go out and represent now's the time to go grab something so go to americanalchemymerch.com
to check it all out
you