Well, I was assigned to a Minuteman missile, and I was on the night shift.
And my job is to just basically sit there and do nothing, really.
And it was foggy.
Next thing I know, I see this shadow in the fog.
I'm looking ahead and I see this shadow, and I see a man, which appeared to be a man, emerge from the fog.
But as it got closer, I realized this was not what it was.
And I could feel it in my mind.
I mean, it was like it started grabbing hold of me.
For decades, there's been a strange and deeply unsettling pattern lurking beneath nuclear weapons and missile facilities worldwide.
A pattern that almost no one wanted to talk about in an era of Cold War secrecy.
Air Force officers whispered about it, and most of the people who lived it stayed silent.
Until now, it's all coming out.
Today's guest is Richard Barth.
In 1964, he was an Air Force security guard, an air policeman, stationed at Vandenberg Air Force Base.
Vandenberg wasn't some remote radar outpost or ghost station.
This was the epicenter of American nuclear missile testing.
Atlas missiles, Thor, Minuteman, Titan.
This was the place the United States government went to actually learn whether its nuclear missiles worked.
So naturally, something else was watching from above.
And it happened to interact with our next guest.
A figure emerging from the mist.
A moment of absolute terror in seeing this figure's very foreign face.
Loss of control.
And then lost time.
All of a sudden, Richard is taken.
He wakes up hovering on a flying saucer with a few more beings overlooking the entire Vandenberg base.
Richard is given a message.
One that directly connects with other alien encounters by nuclear base employees.
And perhaps most remarkably, this story happens on the exact same month of another Vandenberg UFO incident that you may already know.
You see, Richard had his encounter in September of 1964.
That same month, Bob Jacobs, a photo instrumentation lead, caught video of a UFO that seemed to encircle an Atlas missile, target it with lasers.
We've spoken to Jacobs, and this is a case we discuss all of the time on this show.
We could see clearly on film, the nose cones separate.
And then we saw the dummy warhead.
And suddenly, into that frame, an object flew in, chasing the warhead and so on at the same speed.
Didn't they delete your records from the government as well?
People denied that you worked at Vandenberg?
Is that right?
They denied there was ever a Robert Jacobs in the Air Force.
And between Bob Jacobs and Richard Barth, it looks like while we were testing nuclear missiles in September of 1964 on Vandenberg Air Force Base,
something else was testing missile defense and deterrence.
This interview raises some very uncomfortable questions about access, surveillance, and intent on our most advanced weapons capabilities.
And it leaves us with possibilities that are far more strange and destabilizing than are we alone.
This episode isn't about believing.
It's about listening carefully.
Because whatever is going on at our nuclear bases doesn't seem random.
And it doesn't seem finished with us.
Between 2003 and 2005, five UAP incidents occurred at Vandenberg Air Force Base.
So without further ado, please enjoy this courageous testimony from this week's American alchemist, Richard Barth.
I'm here with Richard Barth, and this is an honor.
I really appreciate you driving to L.A. to speak with me.
Robert Hastings is one of my favorite journalists in the UFO space.
He's written an amazing book called UFOs and Nukes, and he is the premier chronicler of all of these amazing veterans
who were stationed at nuclear bases across the United States, often with, you know, pretty high clearances,
experiencing tic-tacs, saucers, orbs, UFOs all over these bases.
And sometimes nuclear missiles get shut down.
All sorts of anomalies occur on the bases.
And in a few cases, like yours, you actually experience a close encounter of the third kind,
where you see beings and you experience communication with those beings.
And so it's an honor to speak with you, and I really appreciate you sharing your story.
What made you decide to come out now?
I was listening to Coast to Coast one night, and it happened to be Robert Hastings,
although at the time I didn't know, but something just compelled me to call in.
And he was talking about UFOs and nukes, and I had this experience that I had pretty much kept to myself for quite a while.
And it just seemed that, you know, the guy seemed so credible that maybe he might be interested in my particular story.
So I called up, and I was very fortunate.
I got right on.
I explained to the person that monitors the call, and he put me right in.
And we got through about half my story, and then we got cut off somehow.
Last question he asked me, is I aware of any lost time?
Lost time.
Yeah, he wanted to know if I had any lost time during the event, and I was going to answer him, and everything just went blank.
There was no response, and I didn't know how to get back on.
And so I kind of dropped it, but it brought it to the forefront of this discredibility of Bob Hansen that really triggered it.
So you called into Coast to Coast, and you got through a lot of your story.
Then the call dropped.
But that brought that to the fore and to the mind of Robert Hastings, who wanted to follow up on it.
Actually, before that, I had read Whitney Streber's book, and it seemed credible to me, but it also made my experience seem more credible to myself.
You got to kind of understand that when something like this happens to you, you question yourself, was this real?
Or was this something that, you know, I imagined, or it's so much part of you that you accept it as real, but you still question it?
How did you end up at Vandenberg Air Force Base in 1964?
Okay, I wasn't doing well in college at the time, and so I decided I was going to join the Air Force, and I went to the recruiter.
And I had actually, I'd been a pre-med major, and so I asked about going into medical corps.
And he said, well, you got two years of college.
He said, would you consider being a navigator?
And I said, I love flying, but I, you know, I need four years of college to get commissioned or do anything like that.
And so he had asked me, would I be interested that they had a navigation course that had opened up that the requirements were that you can get in with two years of college.
And I said, yeah, I love flying.
I'd love to fly if I could fly.
So I said, well, why don't you go down and take the test and see how you do?
They sent me down to L.A., and I passed that.
So I said, well, you're in.
All we got to do is find you a class.
So I waited about three or four months for a class to open up for me to get into.
And I was doing quite well until I got to Celestial Navigation.
And I didn't know it at the time, but I had, like, dyslexia.
And what was making things bad for me was not on the academics, which I was high on, but I would transpose my numbers, especially when I got under pressure.
And a 1-2-3, 1-23 would become a 1-32, which is a significant navigation error.
Well, you do three practice missions, then a test mission, and I failed the first test mission.
And then they will send you again, and I'd allow you to do another test mission.
And I failed that one, and so I was basically washed out of the class.
When I had joined, one of the conditions of joining was that you went in under a selective service requirement,
which was basically two years with some reserve time to follow.
And if you didn't pass a class, you would go on that reserve status and just finish out your two years and go on reserve status.
Otherwise, if you passed, you would be commissioned.
You would sign up for an additional four years, and you would actively be in the Air Force as a navigator.
Well, I just opted I was going to get out.
So that left, well, I've got 13 months left of my selective service requirement.
And so they didn't want to put me in a position that required a lot of training, and so guards don't require a lot of training.
And I can pick something that was relatively close to home.
I lived in Los Angeles.
Vandenberg Air Force Base was up the coast above Santa Barbara for about a four-hour drive,
and that seemed, well, I might have time and go home and be with my friends and family.
So that seemed okay with me.
I thought I can deal with it.
So you were a missile security guard, or what's the exact title?
Yeah, I'm listed as an air policeman, but I was assigned to the 4392nd Combat Defense Squadron,
and we were essentially guards.
We didn't wear the blue uniforms.
We wore fatigues, and we carried a .38 pistol.
And we just basically stood on post all day, and there wasn't much training involved other than weapons training.
What are the types of things that you guarded on the base?
We had the missile maintenance stuff where they assembled the missiles themselves.
That was a large hangar.
The missiles would be on their sides.
They would be—the stages would be mated with each other.
They would—electronics guidance would be in,
and then they would take them out to the actual silo or launch sites where they, you know, fueled them and fired them.
And there were—you'd guard like a crypto room where cryptographic information came in,
particularly at night when nobody was there.
They were locked rooms, but they wanted to guard on there.
And frankly, we guarded things that didn't need guarding.
A lot of these missiles at Vandenberg, a lot of these missiles were set up by the manufacturer,
like Boeing would do the Minuteman, Douglas would do the Thor,
and Lockheed would do the Agena stage, Convair would do the Atlas missiles,
and those were the four missiles we had.
Most of the three missiles, the Thor, the Atlas, and the—were obsolete, basically,
but they were great for launching satellites.
And you can get—the Thor was a lightweight missile, intermediate range, actually, not ICBM.
And it was good for setting spy satellites because it can get them into the low altitude that they wanted,
and 100 by 100, 150 miles.
That's where you took your pictures from.
If you had something heavier, you'd put it on an atlas.
The Thor was very similar to the Redstone that they launched Al Chepard on.
It was, you know, just for to loop them up into space and come down.
But then they moved—for the remainder of the flights, they moved to the Atlas missile,
which was a two-stage missile, which was much more powerful and can get the orbits much higher than that.
And then later, they did the Titan missile, which was an ICBM, liquid-fueled.
And a good thing about the Titan is the Atlas missile required pumping in oxygen and hydrogen just prior to launch,
which took time, so that you had to do an immediate launch.
You could—you'd have 15, 20 minutes just fueling the missile before you launched it.
The Titan fuels were not refrigerated fuels, and that missile could sit in the silo, fueled and ready to go,
and could be launched immediately.
So the Titan was an advance over the Atlas, plus it was a much more powerful missile
and could carry much larger warheads.
We called them re-entry vehicles, but they were basically warheads, the atomic warhead.
And one thing about Vandenberg Air Force Base is that it was not a primary nuclear base.
And the reason was it was too easy to take out.
It was right on the ocean.
You can drop a bomb, an atomic bomb, right in the ocean, right next to it.
You just add up a tidal wave or a tsunami, wipe out the base, and the base becomes useless.
So it was too easy a target for nuclear.
But we were right on the ocean, and we had the Pacific Test Range,
and it was a great place to fire missiles down over the ocean, downrange.
Because they were—see, like the Minutemen.
The Minutemen were all stationed inland, far inland, in Montana, Moffitt Air Force Base
or Malstrom Air Force Base, and spread out quite a part because they were difficult targets that way.
They were spread out, and they were well inland.
The trouble is you couldn't launch a missile from there because there was always a possibility
that missile would land on somebody's cow or even a city, even worse.
But we could launch over from Vandenberg Air Force Base,
and then we could bring the crew out for the launch, and they can actually launch a missile.
But there's other things that could be tested, like the amount of—you know, these were solid fuel.
Minutemen was solid fuel.
And that fuel would sit there for a couple of years.
Well, what was the integrity of the fuel after a couple of years?
You could test that because all missiles are launched on inertial guidance.
In other words, once you send them off, they're on their own.
The course is set.
And the main reason for that is, like, you can send a missile to the moon,
and you can make mid-course changes.
But you don't want to do that because the enemy can make mid-course changes
and get your missile off target.
So once the missile was programmed to do a certain trajectory,
and once it was fired, it was on its own.
So if the fuel was not—the integrity of the fuel was degraded,
it might not get to the target or as close to the target as you wanted to.
So that was one of the things we wanted to test
and also give the crew a chance to fire the missile.
So do you—I mean, clearly you are, right now,
displaying extensive knowledge of all of these missile systems
in a way that, to me, unless you, you know,
went back and read a bunch of textbooks before this interview,
I think it shows that you were at Vandenberg Air Force Base.
But for the hardcore skeptics in the audience,
you can provide your DD-2414 service records.
You can give them to me if possible.
You have photos of them and stuff.
Yeah, I gave it to Robert Hastings.
Robert Hastings, and that was one thing.
You know, he's very, very thorough.
When you read his book, each case is well-documented,
is thorough when he vets each person that he interviews.
He's extremely thorough.
Extremely, and so he's extremely.
And he called three separate friends of yours, right,
to corroborate that you told them the same details that you told him.
His interest was that this is not something I had made up recently,
he went, you know, with a new, all this stuff coming out,
and just wanted to get on the bandwagon.
And you've made no money off of this story?
No, I've had no intention.
In fact, when I wrote, originally, when I did an email to Robert Salas,
which was the first one I tried to contact,
the reason being is that my experience was two years prior to Robert Salas's.
When I heard him interviewed, I thought he might be interested.
Well, the really interesting thing, Robert Salas, that's interesting.
Did he get back to you, or?
Not right away.
He did, and then he didn't follow up.
But when I wrote him, I said, I'm not interested in money.
I'm not interested in writing a book.
But I think there's a relationship between my experience and your experience,
in other words.
Well, I want to get into that relationship
after we get into the core details of your experience.
But I think even more relevant than Bob Salas,
who had an extremely interesting experience
with 10 missiles shutting down at Malmstrand Air Force Base.
He's at Oscar Flight Launch Center underground.
And this red glowing object is hovering above ground.
And that seems to correlate with these 10 missiles going offline.
Strategic Air Command wrote up a whole write-up
saying we're baffled and confused
as to this happening around, I think,
the Echo Flight incident, which was eight days before.
And then a targeting officer, Bob Jamison,
who is a colleague of Salas's,
went in to check as to, you know,
why did these 10 missiles go down?
Is it possible they just malfunctioned?
That doesn't happen.
Very rarely does a missile malfunction.
And I don't think any much more rare
would be two at the same time,
but never 10.
And so you had all this interesting kind of activity going on
at Malmstrand Air Force Base,
but that was in 1967.
Yeah.
What I find interesting about your experience
is that was, what was it, September?
September 64.
1964 at Vandenberg Air Force Base.
Did you know that Bob Jacobs,
who was a photo instrumentation specialist,
also stationed there at the same time as you,
has an honor?
I do now, but I did not then.
Yeah, he did not then.
So that's amazing.
Because this guy was,
basically they were testing an Atlas missile
with a dummy warhead.
Right.
And he was basically stationed at Big Sur.
And he was supposed to kind of, you know,
telescope the object and photograph it,
get video.
They wanted him to film the missile from the side
rather than straight on.
Because you go to Vandermeer,
you're just watching it go straight on.
And he can watch the projectile from the side.
Major management called,
and he said,
tomorrow morning at 0600,
get ready because we're launching an Atlas missile,
and we want you to photograph that
with the big BU telescope.
I went, okay.
So at 0600, we were up and ready to go,
and an Atlas missile popped up through the ground fog
that was covering the whole coastline
all the way down there.
It was beautiful.
We took the film back to Vandenberg,
where it was processed.
And a day later,
I got a call from Major Mansman,
who said,
come up to my office.
So I went to his office,
and he said there was a movie screen set up
and a 16-millimeter projector.
And there was Major Mansman,
and, as I recall,
two guys in gray suits.
On the screen was the film we had shot.
We could see clearly on film
the nose cones separate,
and then we saw the dummy warhead.
And suddenly, into that frame,
an object flew in,
chasing the warhead and so on
at the same speed.
It's going between 6,000 and 8,000 miles an hour
at that point.
And it fired a beam of light
at the dummy warhead.
The object flew up like this,
shot another beam of light
at the dummy warhead,
went around like this,
shot another beam of light at it,
went down like this,
shot a beam of light like this,
and then flew out the same way
to come in.
At which time,
the dummy warhead did this
and fell out of the frame.
The lights came on,
and Major Mansman said to me,
were you guys screwing around up there?
And I said, no, sir.
And he said, what was that?
And I said,
it looks like we got a UFO.
And he said,
Lieutenant Jacobs,
you are never to speak of this again.
It never happened.
And then these two guys
in tweed jackets in the back room
while he's watching,
they basically go up to him.
They say,
you know,
you are now sworn to secrecy,
and if you say anything about this,
you're going to be in real trouble.
And then they proceed to,
because he tells this story later,
they delete his records
from the government.
Didn't they delete your records
from the government as well?
People denied that you worked at Vandenberg?
Is that right?
They denied there was ever
a Robert Jacobs in the Air Force.
In another inquiry,
they denied there was ever
a Robert Jacobs
at Vandenberg Air Force Base.
Then they denied there was ever
anybody named Robert Jacobs
in charge of the 1369th
Photographic Union
division that I ran.
And you managed over 100 people,
so it's pretty easy
to corroborate.
Yeah, I had 134 guys
working for me,
and I had two friends
from college
who were my commanding people.
And I also have something
called a DD-14.
I have records here.
My officer efficiency reports
are in there.
I can't get rid of stuff.
My wife keeps saying,
clear that shit out of your
file camera over there, Bob.
I go, no, I might use it.
And sure enough,
it's turned out to be valuable
in defending myself
against the infamy of the CIA.
But we didn't have a launch
on that date.
There was no Atlas launch
that day.
Well, it got damn well
there was because Robert
found the files
from Vandenberg.
We've seen that particular
launch in detail.
So they also scrubbed
the launch itself
from the records.
Correct.
Never happened.
Wow.
And your mailbox
was blown up as well, right?
My wife and I had been
out to a movie.
We came back from the movie
about 10 o'clock at night.
And there was a message
on my answering machine.
And it said,
fireworks in your mailbox
at night.
Oh, what a beautiful sight.
You're going down,
motherfucker.
And my mailbox blew up.
I live on a farm.
I had a rural mailbox.
And so there was an explosion.
My mailbox blew up.
I took that quite seriously.
I bought an ammunition
from my gun.
And then Florence Mansman,
his major,
his superior,
eventually is tracked down
by, I think,
Bob Hastings
and some other researchers.
And in the 90s,
admits that he did manage
Bob Jacobs.
So it's this crazy story.
And that happened
at the same time
you had an experience.
Right.
Bob Hastings
put me in touch
with Bob Jacobs.
As you know,
on American Alchemy,
we cover a lot of technology
that goes beyond human limits.
This is about technology
that helps the body
catch up and feel good.
I'm talking about
the iRestore LED face mask,
a red light therapy system
that uses clinical grade wavelengths
to boost skin cell energy production.
The same exact principle
used in the top recovery clinics
and bio-optimization labs
in the world.
I've been using it
most nights,
10 minutes while I'm reading,
prepping for a show,
or decompressing.
It's completely hands-free,
comfortable,
and engineered
to deliver consistent
light intensity
across the face.
Not that uneven scatter
most cheaper masks use.
It feels like your face
is taking a warm bath.
What it's doing
is called photobiomodulation,
stimulating mitochondria
to repair tissue,
reduce inflammation,
and improve circulation.
You actually feel the calm
and rejuvenation
after a session.
I've tested a few of these.
This one really stands out
for the build quality.
It feels like it was built
in a high-precision lab,
and it's not just
a cheap beauty gadget.
So if you're into
real evidence-based
recovery tech,
this belongs in your setup.
Head to irisstore.com
and use code JESSE25
for an exclusive discount.
Again, irisstore.com,
code JESSE25.
Red light therapy
has really been
a game changer for me,
so I hope you love it.
because it did occur
at the same time.
So he gave me
Bob Jacobs' phone number.
I called Bob Jacobs.
We discussed this.
I had additional experience
when I was at Vandenberg,
and I was able
to watch him in at,
not in at minute,
I was able to watch
the Atlas launched,
and it had gone up.
Now, I'm underneath
the missile at this time
at Vandenberg
rather than from the side,
and I'm watching
this missile guard
and it's staged,
but before it's staged,
that means
this first stage
dropped off,
second stage took off,
this yellow orb
came over
and tracked the missile.
It didn't go around it
or anything.
It tracked it.
Then it's staged,
and then it's
continued tracking,
which meant
it wasn't a fuel leak.
Besides,
if it was a fuel leak,
it might have,
wow, blown up,
and I had relayed that,
and then Bob Jacobs
thought maybe
I had witnessed
what he had witnessed,
but the timing
was not right.
First of all,
he had taken,
when he saw
the missile launch,
he saw it come up
through the clouds.
Well, this was a cloudless day
when I saw what I saw.
He saw his bad experience
in September.
It was closer to May
when I saw this happen.
Now, you know,
I don't know.
I had asked
one of the sergeants
down on the launch site
the next day
what happened
with that missile,
and he just told me
if I was wise,
I would keep my mouth shut.
And I did just that.
I kept my mouth shut.
So you had already seen
essentially a UFO,
which I think at the time
they used to call tagalongs
because they would often
track missile trajectories.
That's what he did.
It stayed right
with the missile.
That's amazing.
And in 1963,
we have another example
of an F-8 Atlas missile
being tracked
by this sort of tagalong,
and it's even in the report.
And this was,
I believe,
a month or two
before the Bluegill
triple prime test
in, I think,
September of 1963.
The sergeant told me
if I was wise,
I'd keep my mouth shut,
and I figured I'm wise
that I'm going to keep
my mouth shut
because I didn't want
to get into any
of the problems
that, you know,
I was getting out soon.
In May,
I was going to get out
in June.
I just wanted to get out
and leave it alone.
So, but that's fascinating
because in May of 1964,
you see this sort
of tagalong UFO.
Yeah.
In September of 1964,
Bob Jacobs,
unbeknownst to you
during this test
on video,
sees a UFO
shoot a dummy
nuclear warhead
out of the sky.
And then,
I want to get to,
this is the,
you know,
kind of the core
experience that you had
was also in September
of 1964.
My core experience
was in September,
right.
And what happened then?
Well,
I was assigned
to a Minuteman missile.
I'm not,
yeah,
I was assigned
to a Minuteman missile site.
And the guard shack
is right next
to the gate.
There's a,
a fence
around the missile site.
And it's,
it's got
ATT alarms on it.
Do nothing,
really.
The site itself
is well lit.
It has,
has like a stadium
lighting up there.
And it's well lit.
And I was on
the night shift.
So that,
and it was foggy.
And so that,
that kind of,
it appeared like a dome
over me,
or you could probably
see 30,
40 feet
from where
the guard shack
was.
And I could see
the missile site
behind me,
but if I looked
straight ahead,
I just saw
a wall of fog.
Basically,
a sergeant had come
and delivered a lunch,
which would have been
two o'clock in the morning
on average
of your night shift.
And so the timing
would have been
right around two o'clock
because the sergeant
had just left.
And so I'm sitting there
and next thing I know
I see this shadow
in the fog.
I'm looking ahead
and I see the shadow
and I see a man,
which would appear
to be a man
or a humanoid figure
emerge from the fog.
And I thought,
well, what the heck?
Did the sergeant walk back?
And that's my first thing.
Well, the sergeant walked back
and I couldn't figure why.
But then the next thing,
this figure kept coming
towards me.
Now, it had like
a trench coat on.
Really?
Very similar to
the raincoats
that were issued
to the officers.
And he had a cap on,
which could have been.
So my next thing,
well, I wonder
if there's some officer
checking up on me.
But as it got closer,
I realized this was not
what it was.
And I could feel it
in my mind.
I mean, it was like
it was, it started
grabbing hold of me.
And I became
really frightened.
And as it approached me,
I tried to pull my pistol.
We had 38 police
as part of our gear.
And I tried to pull my pistol
and my right arm
was paralyzed.
I couldn't move it.
I could move my body,
but I couldn't move my arm.
And I became more terrified.
And it became closer to me.
Something, I can't see the face
in my brain.
If I try to see this face,
I can't see it.
It's a blank.
But whatever it was
was terrifying me.
And whatever it was
had control of
at least my right arm.
And I was standing
just outside the shack.
And I backed into the shack
just instinctively, I guess.
And I got myself back
to the back of the shack
and there was nowhere
else to go.
And the figure was coming,
continued coming towards me.
And there was a shelf
at the back.
There was a telephone
on there and it was
just a shelf.
And I can remember
distinctly pushing my back
into that shelf
and trying to push
the back of the shack out.
I was like a rat
caught in a trap.
And the terror was just,
I couldn't describe how,
I was just terrified.
The next thing I know,
I'm out, you know.
And I don't know
if I passed out
or it's just blank
at that point.
So then I come to
and I'm inside this,
it's a circular room.
I'm not going to call it a craft
because I didn't see it
from the outside,
but I'm in this circular room.
And I'm on my knees
and there's about a
two and a half,
three foot circle
that's open.
clear.
You could see through it.
And there's this figure
on my right-hand side
and it's communicating to me,
don't look at me,
don't look over here,
just look through the circle.
And, you know,
it's weird
because it's not words.
You know what it wants.
It's like he's,
it's very definitely a command,
but it's not in words,
but you know what,
you know,
I don't know
other people have
this psychic
thought process
or anything like that.
But one thing,
it was not words.
It was just,
I knew I was not
to look at them,
you know,
just look at this circle.
So I'm looking at the circle
and what you see initially
is just this gray fog,
basically.
One of the things I noticed
at the time
is that I would expect
a breeze
or something cold
to be coming through
and it wasn't.
It's like there was
a barrier,
but it wasn't like glass.
It was just clear.
And all of a sudden,
this kind of clears away
like clouds splitting
and there's a post
about 100 yards
down the street
on the opposite side
of the room.
Now, I'm on site D5
and this is site D11,
which is across the street
down there.
I'm familiar with the site.
I don't know which one it was.
It's easily identifiable
by the side of the street
and the orientation.
And it's just getting light
and I can see this truck
pull up to the gate
and it had,
it was a flatbed truck,
a long flatbed truck.
It had a lot of long pipes on it
and the guard was to the,
came over to the right side
of the truck
and obviously was getting ID
or checking whether
it was driving,
went over,
opened the gate,
let the truck in
and then the clouds
closed up.
And so,
I'm still looking
through this hole
and I'm still just,
you know,
just keep looking
through the hole
and I kind of raised
my eyes to look around
without looking over
and there were the opposite me
about six,
ten feet away
were these four figures
sitting on a bench
and I could see
that the wall
of the craft,
I'll call it a craft now,
I could see that the bench
was just a continuation
of the material
of whatever the wall was
and whatever lighting
was in there,
the figures were silhouetted
like the light source
that's behind
or from the wall
but very,
very consistent.
I mean,
there wasn't like
bright lights or anything.
Effectively,
the room was pretty dark
so the figures
seemed silhouetted.
It appeared to me
like a baby
had a large head
and smaller body
disproportionate.
The eyes were discernible
because they were darker
than the skin features
or whatever.
A lot of people say
they were,
you know,
these creatures
or creatures,
beings,
whatever,
were some sort of suit
or something like that.
I couldn't really tell that.
Basically,
a silhouette
with just slight features
available
and there were two
on one side
and two on the other side
with a space in between
that I took
to be some sort of door
out of this room
or something like that
and that's about it.
I mean,
that's next thing I know.
I'm sitting on the,
I'm laying on the floor
of the guard shack.
There's like a little porch
right in front of the door
to the guard shack
and I'm laying with my feet
off the porch
on the ground
and this being
is sitting on the porch
and has my head
at its lap
and it's saying to me,
it's communicating again,
it's communicating,
I'm sorry,
you know,
we didn't mean to scare you.
He says,
we didn't mean to scare you,
but we had to have access
to the site.
So we needed the intelligence
is what I was gathering
out of this form
of communication
that they were just,
needed access to the site
and I was in the way.
And so,
it really felt comfortable.
Like,
you know,
I felt like,
well,
this is okay,
he's not going to hurt me,
you know.
So I was fine,
But I kept,
the other thing
was keep my eyes
tightly shut.
It did not want me
to look at it
or see it.
Keep your eyes shut,
you know.
And I apologize,
I'm sorry
that we scared you so much,
but we needed to have access
and you were in the way.
And he says,
no,
I'm going to leave
and I want you to
just keep your eyes shut.
Just,
you know,
don't get up,
don't do anything,
just stay there
with your eyes shut.
And he left.
And I did just what he said.
I laid there
for maybe 15 minutes
with my eyes shut.
And I was glad
to see him go,
frankly.
And then I finally
got up
and looked around.
And the sun was just,
it had come over the,
there's a ridge of mountains
behind the,
what we call D sector,
probably a quarter of a mile back.
And the sun was coming up
over that ridge.
And if you look towards the ocean,
you could see the light
coming,
you know,
lighting up the ocean.
It was kind of a beautiful sight.
And I looked over
to my right
and there was a little chipmunk
on the ground.
And I have never,
I just felt so much love
for that little chipmunk,
you know.
I felt like
I was joined
with that chipmunk,
you know,
one living creature
to another.
And the little chipmunk
kind of just looked back
at me
and kind of scurried away.
About 20,
30 minutes later,
the time would be
probably around
6,
37 o'clock,
my relief came.
Now,
the missiles,
50,
60 yards
off the main road,
there's a little road
that goes to the,
to the missile site.
And,
you know,
my relief came down,
relieved me,
and then I,
they were all delivered
by these Air Force
blue pickup trucks,
four-door
pickup trucks,
basically.
And
I could have gotten
their four-door,
or four-door seat
in the back.
I could have gotten inside,
but I didn't want to.
I got in back
and I,
I put my back
to the cab of the truck
and I pulled my feet up.
And then they went
and picked up
the other guards.
And,
I was just real quiet
and they were asking me
what's wrong.
And,
you know,
and I knew something
had happened,
but I couldn't quite
put my finger on it.
Something profound happened,
but,
and I was confused.
And it was cold
because it had been
a foggy morning
until the sun came up
and kind of burned it off.
But it was still cold
and I was just
trying to watch
what happened,
you know,
what,
figured,
you know,
I couldn't figure it out.
And by the time
I got back to base,
well,
it was,
I couldn't remember anything.
Now,
I didn't remember
this particular thing
until two weeks later,
roughly two weeks later.
And I,
I was aware
that something
had happened,
but I couldn't
put my finger on it
and I'd try
to put it aside
and it was just
something that
nagged at me.
But then I got up
in the morning
or it was,
and we apparently
on the day shift
because it was
early morning
and all of a sudden,
and,
you know,
I've heard of
paralysis sleep
where people have
these experiences
when they're,
I wasn't paralyzed.
I woke up
and all of a sudden
I got flooded
with this whole experience
that I just told you.
And it wasn't a dream,
I could tell you.
It was so real.
I've never had
a dream like that before
and I've never had
that happen since.
It was real
and I knew it was real.
And I linked
next to some
Venetian blinds
and I picked them up
and kind of looked out.
The sun was shining.
And I looked over
and my roommate
was asleep
and I kept thinking,
God,
what's this?
I need to tell somebody.
This is critical.
You know,
there's some entities
got on my site
and I got up
and I got dressed
and was going
to breakfast
and I thought,
no,
this is crazy.
I'm not going to tell anybody.
They're going to put me
in the site board.
And then it was like
I got something
in my mind that says,
no,
don't you tell anybody.
You keep this to yourself.
It was like
there was a preset command
or something like that.
I think it was so vivid
that it was
kind of released.
they wanted a time lapse
between the event
and the time
that it came
that I was aware
of the experience.
It's almost like
that was so vivid
that it was
okay,
like there was
a release
of the command
not to forget.
And so,
but now I do.
This episode
is sponsored
by Z Biotics.
I rarely drink alcohol
these days,
but on special occasions,
I still enjoy
having a couple
of drinks with friends.
However,
I also care a lot
about how I feel
the next day.
And now that I'm
in my 30s,
I usually feel like
I definitely don't want
any good nights
to cost me
productive mornings anymore.
Z Biotics'
pre-alcohol probiotic drink
is the world's
first genetically
engineered probiotic.
It was invented
by PhD scientists
specifically
to tackle
rough mornings
after drinking.
Here's how it works.
When you drink,
alcohol gets converted
into a toxic
byproduct
in the gut.
It's a buildup
of this byproduct,
not dehydration
that's to blame
for rough days
after drinking.
Z Biotics'
pre-alcohol
produces an enzyme
to break this
byproduct down.
And it actually works.
It's an absolute
game changer
based on science.
Just remember
to make pre-alcohol
your first drink
of the night,
drink responsibly,
and you'll feel
your best tomorrow.
For me,
it's simple.
If I have plans
the next morning
and if I'm having
a drink with friends,
I take pre-alcohol
first and I feel
normal the next day.
Ready to try it?
Go to
zbiotics.com
slash jesse
now.
Again,
that's
zbiotics.com
slash jesse
and you'll get
15% off
your first order
when you use
jesse,
J-E-S-S-E,
at checkout.
Plus,
it's backed
by a 100%
money-back guarantee,
so there's literally
no risk
to trying it.
Subscriptions
are also available
for maximum
consistency.
Remember to head
to zbiotics.com
slash jesse
and use the code
jesse at checkout
for 15% off.
Thank you so much
to Zbiotics
for sponsoring
this episode.
Did these beings
say who they were?
No.
When I had my head
in his lap
and he was apologizing,
he said
that they were,
you know,
they needed to get
the information
on the site,
the data
out of the missiles.
See,
in the missile,
there's,
at the top
of a man-at-man missile,
there's like a donut
on a toilet paper roll.
There's a room
that has the electronics
equipment in it
and it has
a separate access
door to it.
And inside there
are all the,
they were big old
computers back
in those days.
See,
when the missile
gets the launch command,
then it's,
that's it.
in order
to keep somebody
from sabotaging
it or stopping
the launch,
everything takes place
in that little room.
And that's where
the crew does,
does the maintenance
on the missile
and everything like that.
There's a door
that actually opens
into the silo.
And so,
they needed to get
in that room
and probably
to those computers
and launched
things.
That's where
I'm thinking
that they got
the data.
That's basically
what I'm speculating.
They used
the shack
essentially
as a point
of access
for this.
No, no.
Okay.
They just,
I was at the shack
and they just
needed to,
he'd be,
he'd be out
of the way
basically.
And as he came
towards me
and I passed out,
I was out of the way.
So, you were just
between him
and this electronics
room essentially.
Well, there's a fence
with the ADT
that I'm in front
of the fence.
Got it.
So, somehow
they got through
the ADT
and got into
the crew access
area
and down into,
I have to assume
because I'm passed
out at this point.
But he did say
or communicate
that they needed
the data
from the missile.
So, my assumption
is they got down
in that crew area
and got
whatever data
they needed.
The first being
you see
has a trench coat
on and looks
like this shadowy
silhouette.
Yeah.
No, he's,
I just can't
remember its face.
Okay.
So, kind of hard
to just recall.
The face terrified me.
I know the face
terrified me.
I can't tell you
what it was
because I don't
think my brain
wants to remember
but it terrified me.
I don't know
that was the guys
or I have no idea
what it was
but it terrified me.
Yeah.
I know how terrified
it was.
You can't dream.
I don't think
you can dream
that kind of terror.
It's like a rat
that's trapped
in a corner
by the cat.
But it was wearing
human clothing.
It was very humanoid.
I mean,
humanoid,
probably 5'10",
probably,
very human.
And the trench coat
didn't seem
otherworldly.
No, it wasn't
That's what made me
think it might have
been an officer.
Yeah.
And so maybe
he was kind of
in disguise or something.
Yeah, you know,
I didn't know
what was going on.
That was my first impression
but then I,
when my arm
was paralyzed
and I felt him
in control,
he had control of me.
I say he,
but he had control of me.
You know,
I'm assuming it was,
I mean,
I'd read it
as a male figure
because the trench coat,
women don't wear
trench coats
and originally
I thought it was
an officer
and then it realized
it was something else
and then
as it moved towards me
it had control of me
and then I passed,
you know,
I couldn't pull my weapon.
Oh,
and I tried to scream
because I wanted to scream
and all I could get
is a little,
ah,
I couldn't even scream,
you know.
Wow.
and then I,
I remember my back
pressing into that shelf
and then the blank.
Do they look like
the typical classic
gray alien that,
No,
it was more like a baby's head.
It was,
it didn't have,
I don't recall ears.
I know there was no hair.
You could,
you could tell that
even in silhouette.
I mean,
there were,
it was a round head
with big eyes.
That's what.
But gray aliens have
large heads
proportionate to their body.
Yeah.
These were different
in some way
than the,
typical gray.
As I visualize this,
the chin was not pointed.
You see so many
pictures of pointed chins.
It,
it was,
looked like a baby's head.
Interesting.
You know,
and one of the things,
the necks
were like a baby's neck.
You know,
you see pictures
of the aliens
with these thin necks
and the big head.
Yeah.
Well,
those necks
couldn't hold
that heavy,
you know.
The necks
were proportionate
that were,
like our necks,
you know,
they're,
they're round enough
and strong enough
to hold up
this big head.
What color
was their skin?
Well,
to me,
it was just
all dark.
I mean,
it was,
it was just dark.
It was,
like I say,
it's solo,
maybe dark gray
or,
but hard to tell
because the lighting
was low.
The lighting
was obviously
backlighting
of some sort.
And they're,
they're communicating
to you,
don't look.
No,
they're not doing anything.
They're not,
they're not communicating.
They're watching me.
Okay.
They're just watching me.
So the,
the other figure,
that other figure,
the humanoid figure,
that's the one
that did all the communication.
Okay.
And that one
is communicating,
don't look as soon as,
one's saying don't look.
That's as soon as
you're in the craft.
He's saying don't look,
don't look.
Just keep looking
through the hole.
That's all it was.
And you,
you're looking through the hole,
but then at some point
you see these four.
Well,
when,
when we,
when they closed up
oversight D11,
then I raised my eye.
I didn't lift my head.
I raised my eyes.
So my view is,
you know,
through the top
and end up,
but I could see
towards the wall
and I could see
the four figures.
You mentioned being
extremely afraid,
around the original
humanoid figure.
What did you feel
when you're in the presence
of these four beings?
I feel very comfortable.
It was,
I felt everything was okay.
You know,
I wasn't afraid.
I wasn't,
just everything was okay.
It was almost to the point
I'm just curious
what's happening.
But no fear
at that point.
The fear had,
that terror had
gone away.
Did you ever have
the thought,
why am I not afraid?
Because this is an extremely
anomalous experience
I'm having.
I also wondered
why it was,
I felt so comfortable.
I was just comfortable.
You know,
it was like
I was experiencing
something like that,
but almost
like I'm not,
like I'm viewing myself
almost.
I mean,
I wasn't viewing myself.
It was from my own.
Were they making you
feel comfortable,
do you think?
Or obviously,
this is your interpretation.
they may have,
you know,
there's a,
there's a blank period
between
passing out in the shed
and waking,
you know,
or coming to
in the vessel now.
They could have
given me a sedative
or used telepathy
to make me feel
comfortable
because it went
from one extreme
to comfortable
and then on the
guard shack floor
to ecstasy.
You know,
I felt so good
sitting,
you know,
with my head
on this lap,
you know,
like I just felt
wonderful.
You know,
if I were to
relate it to something,
I'd say,
because of my background,
it would be a baby
suckling at its
mother's breast,
you know,
that just nice
and warm
and comfortable
and Bobby's there
and I feel okay
and the world's okay
and the world is good
and then it did say,
and it goes back
to your original question,
did he say anything else?
Yes,
or community thing else,
is that
they're not going
to let it,
you know,
go to nuclear war.
They needed to stop
these missiles
from launching.
They were trying
to get the data
on how to,
which was their task then
and that there wasn't,
they weren't going
to allow these missiles
to be launched.
They weren't allowed
us to go to nuclear war
in essence that
Earth,
you know,
was important to them
and then there was
another thing
that not every species,
there were more
than one species
and they weren't
all as benevolent
as they were,
this creature.
It's like,
you know,
and if a push
came to shove,
there could be
some real issues
over who's going
to control,
you know,
once they take,
at that point,
once they stop
all the missiles,
they're going
to take over
the sense I got.
So there are
multiple non-human
species.
This species
happens to be
sort of doing
recon on the
nuclear codes
and how things
work and they're
presenting themselves
as benevolent
and do you trust,
you know,
coming away from
the experience
that they were
benevolent?
Yeah.
I think I just
lucked out.
Did they say
which species
they came from?
Didn't tell me
any of that.
It's just
basically that
the Earth was,
the sense was,
look,
this is a
plan to support
to us
and we're not
going to let
you destroy it
and if
push comes to
shove,
we're going
to intervene.
The love
that you felt
for the chipmunk,
was that
representative
of some
larger flooding
of love
that you felt
for all beings?
Yeah,
it was like
I had this
feeling of ecstasy
while I was
laying on
the lap
of the being
and then
it just
carried over.
Once he left,
I kept my eyes
shut for a while
and then
I got up
and there's
this chipmunk
sitting there
and I just
felt this
connection.
I just
love that
little chipmunk
and I felt
connected to it
like
here's another
living being
and we're
part of the
there was
no separation.
We were
in the same
we were just
living beings
and there
was something
good about
that,
you know.
I know it
was dark
but what
did the
room look
like if
you had
to describe
it?
Do you
remember the
walls?
I could say
is that
okay,
the walls
were grazed
okay,
which
silhouetted
so there
was the
lighting in
the room,
I don't
know how
much came
through the
hole in
the floor
or how
much was
backlighting
on the
wall.
However,
the figures
were backlit
because they
were silhouetted.
So I
must,
you know,
the walls
must have
had some
sort of
condescence
that made
them put
the figures
in the
silhouette
that I
was looking
at.
I could
distinguish
the eyes
as large
but not
all of
shape like
you see
in a lot
of the
typical
pictures.
They were
just big
eyes and
dark,
darker
than say
the skin
or...
Did the
room look
indistinguishable
from something
man-made or
did it look...
Oh no,
it was man-made.
The room
itself looked
like it
could have
been...
Molded.
Yeah,
it looked...
If I were
to say
just one
giant piece
of plastic,
you know,
one giant
piece of
gray plastic...
Well,
that doesn't
sound man-made
to me.
I don't
think...
No,
it is.
Well,
it might
not be.
I mean,
well,
there's a
difference
between
artificially
constructed
by deliberately
and man-made,
human-made.
Are you
saying it was...
Oh, you're
talking human-made.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It had to be
an awfully big
mold.
I mean,
you know,
you're talking
a room
that's maybe
15 feet
across,
and...
Why did
it look
molded?
Because of
the bench.
Okay.
The bench
that the
four entities
were sitting
on,
you could
see...
They were
silhouetted,
they were
very dark,
but the wall
and the
material was
grayish.
So I could
see the
material.
And also,
the floor
was concave.
In other words,
they were
elevated
somewhat above
where I was
on my
knees down
there.
Any seams
or rivets
or...
So it was
sort of
smooth and...
Smooth,
even to
the point...
It looked
like I could
fall through
that hole
if I got
too close.
I mean,
it looked
like a
hole.
But there
was no...
It was just
the rim,
but there
was no...
You know,
there's not
like a
seam or
anything.
It was part
of the
same material
except it
was transparent.
So look,
it sounds
like a
classic saucer
that you
hear in
other alien
abduction
stories.
I guess
so.
At the
time,
I didn't
know what
other...
Especially
from the
inside,
you know.
Yeah.
Have you
looked into
any other
stories that
sort of
align with
yours?
It's hard
to find
anything
that describes
the inside.
I mean,
you know,
I hear
these bright
lights,
and these
creatures
obviously
didn't want
bright lights.
You know,
they have
big eyes.
The room
was dark,
and you
hear people
while they
wake up
in this
room,
and it's
all lit
up,
and it's
bright.
It doesn't
seem consistent
to me,
because if
you're going
to have
big eyes,
you must
be dark
adapted from
wherever you
come from.
What time
of day was
this?
You were
taken in
the morning?
Is that
right?
It started
right after
the launch
was delivered,
which would
put it
about 2 o'clock.
When I'm
in the
morning,
when I'm
looking through
the hole,
well,
it's light
enough to
see what's
going on
on the
ground,
like just
sunrise,
basically,
like just
kind of like
dawn,
you know,
not well
lit,
but enough
that you
can discern.
I could
see the
truck,
I could
see it
was loaded
with pipes,
I could
see the
guard walk
over to
the window,
I could
see him
open the
gate and
the truck
drive in.
That was
all,
but it
was like
not,
you know,
it wasn't
a sunshine
lit scene.
The sunshine
came when
I looked
and saw
the chick
monk,
and the
sun was
actually
coming over
that bridge
of mountains,
and it
was kind
of pretty,
because if
you look
towards the
ocean,
then you
could see
the ocean
kind of
with a
yellow color
to it,
and it
felt so
good,
you know,
I mean,
I'm sitting
here and
everything just
felt good.
And so
this whole
event was
morning to
like afternoon-ish?
No,
the whole
event was
like 2 a.m.
to,
Oh,
2 a.m.
Okay,
till probably
6 a.m.
I'm not sure
when sunrise is,
but.
Got it.
So there's
two to,
and that's
when Bob
Hastings asked
me over the
original,
when he was
on George
Norrie,
when I got
cut off,
he had asked
me about
a gap in
time,
and I had
not thought
about that
gap in
time,
but between
2 a.m.
and the
time the
entity came
to me,
and say
5.36 in
the morning,
well,
there's a
gap,
and I
had never
even considered
that.
And that's
when I got
caught off,
because I was
just going to
say,
hey,
I had
considered
that.
So there's
a gap.
Now,
what went
on in
that gap?
We're
talking,
say,
2.30 to
6,
that's
three-some-odd
hours,
you know.
It's more
than what I'm
describing to
you.
So I have
no idea
what went
on.
So maybe
some lost
time.
It's lost
time,
definitely.
You know,
I have
my friend
Lonnie,
that is
a doctorate
in psychology,
and I had
told her
about this
20-some-odd
years ago.
And one
of her
specialties is
regressive
hypnosis,
but she
didn't want
to put me
through regressive
hypnosis,
because when I
was relating,
she thought I
was so upset,
she felt this
wasn't her
pay grade,
you know,
to deal
with somebody
that,
you know,
with past
lives,
she didn't
deal with
the experience
like I had.
When you
are guarding
this shack
from like...
I'm not
guarding the
shack,
I'm guarding
the missile
site,
the shack's
for shelter.
When you're
guarding,
when you're
at the shack
and you're
guarding the
missile site
and it's
early morning
around the
time of,
you know,
2 a.m.
to 6 a.m.,
are you
generally
interacting with
anyone else?
No,
there's no
one there.
Guards are,
we were just
put out there
all by ourselves
and we spent
the whole shift
by ourselves.
We were
supposed to,
this is probably,
I'm not,
we were supposed
to make a call
when the missile
was in the
silo,
we were supposed
to make a call
every half hour
to command
post,
but we didn't
because it was
just a given.
call me in
the morning
and they were
supposed to
log it.
Well,
they logged
it all night
long.
They slept.
We didn't
sleep,
I think we
were,
but we didn't
want to get
caught sleeping,
but if you
were in
command post,
nobody can
get into
command post
without going
through knocking
on doors and
everything like
that,
so they would
take turns
sleeping,
they would
log all the
calls,
and we would
just fool
around,
you know,
and it
was boring.
You know,
you got there
in the middle
of the night
and it was
dark and
foggy,
you had
nothing to
do,
you can't
even read
because we
sneak books
on some
of the
sites,
but you
couldn't even,
at Minuteman,
it was too
dark,
even with the
bright light,
you couldn't,
because the
light was
focused on
the silo
itself,
on the
launch complex,
and you
have a little
light lake
one of
these up
here,
barely lit,
so,
basically,
we all
hated Minuteman,
every one
of us
hated Minuteman,
and sometimes
we'd get,
we had
phones,
because they
would call
in,
we'd had to
make the
call into
a command
post,
so we'd
call each
other.
When you're
in this
room,
or UFO,
saucer,
whatever it
is,
and you're
hovering above
the base,
do you
see what
they're
trying to
do,
or monitor?
I don't
know why
they showed
me that,
it's just
like,
they could,
they were
trying to
show me
I was
in a
craft,
I guess,
and that,
you know,
showed me
something that
I'd be
familiar with.
Do you
know what
day in
September
this might
have been?
No,
no,
because it
was two
weeks later
when the
full memory
came back.
And then,
so I
couldn't tell
you what
particular,
I probably
could have
at the
time.
Did you
tell anybody
at the
base?
Oh,
God,
no.
Did you
know of
any UFO
activity at
Vandenberg
Air Force Base
at the
time?
Not at
the time.
You know,
all the
scuttlebutt
was,
if you
went out
to D
Sector,
which is
20 miles
away from
the base,
and your
scuttlebutt,
you know,
to scare the
new guys,
there's Bigfoot's
out there,
and he's
going to
get you.
But there
was nothing
about UFOs
or even
talk about
it that I
know.
Do you
ever speculate
that the
UFO you
were in
was the
same UFO
that maybe
shot the
dummy nuclear
warhead out
of the sky
in Bob
Jacobs'
case?
They're
too close
together,
September,
September.
So,
this was
at night,
Bob Jacobs
was in the
daytime,
but I'm
sure the
activity was
coordinated,
you know.
It could
have been the
same craft.
Could have
been,
I don't
know what
their structure
is out there,
how many of
them there
are.
Have you
seen any
UFOs since
then or
had any
direct contact
experiences?
Not direct
contact,
but we
were on
4th of July
where I
live.
the park
is along
a wash
and it's
a great
place to
watch the
4th of
July fireworks.
And we
were sitting
there,
and this
would have
been probably
around 2000
in that
vicinity.
We were
out there
watching
fireworks and
somebody said,
what's that
bright light up
there?
And I
looked up and
I said,
I think
that's
Jupiter.
And I
said,
no,
Jupiter's
over there.
And I
said,
oh,
no,
it's
pretty
bright.
So I
had
binoculars
and I
looked at
it with
binoculars
and it
was going
side to
side.
This
episode is
sponsored by
Cove
Pure.
If you're
anything like
me,
the holidays
were kind
of brutal
and it's
time to
reset.
Everyone
wants to
start the
new year
the same
way.
New
supplements,
a new
diet,
workout
plan,
but they
ignore the
most basic
variable of
all,
the water
they drink.
Even mild
dehydration
hits energy,
focus,
and metabolism.
And when you
remember how
much garbage
is in tap
water now,
you're starting
behind the
curve before
you even
begin.
That's why
I've been
using Cove
Pure.
It's a
countertop
water purifier,
not a
giant clunky
tower you
hide under
the sink.
This thing
is sleek,
compact,
and honestly
looks like it
belongs in a
well-funded UFO
research lab.
Cove Pure's
clear wave
technology is
certified to
remove up
to 99.9%
of contaminants
in water.
That's
PFAs,
microplastics,
pharmaceutical
residue,
fluoride,
heavy metals,
pretty much
anything that
isn't water,
but that's
circulating in
a lot of
the water
supply today,
is gone with
this product.
It's the purest
water you can
get at home,
and it's the
best tasting
water I've
tried.
Two things
I love.
First,
it lets me
select whatever
temperature I want
on demand.
Ice cold,
room temperature,
or boiling
instantly.
Second,
it has size
presets right
on screen.
I hit the
16 ounce
button a few
times a day,
and I'm
actually hydrated
without thinking
about it.
So this year,
make a New
Year's resolution
that actually
sticks.
Start with
clean water.
Cove Pure
is giving our
audience $200
off for a
limited time.
That's a
crazy deal,
$200 off.
Go to
covepure.com
slash
American
Alchemy.
Again,
that's
covepure.com
slash
American
Alchemy
for $200
off for a
limited time
only.
You couldn't
perceive it
without the
binoculars,
but I could
see it was
side to
side.
And I
handed the
binoculars
to another
guy, and
he said,
look at this,
is that
moving?
And he
said,
yeah,
it's
moving.
So then
he came
back to
me,
and it
starts into
a zigzag.
And then
it goes
into a
zigzag,
and then
it kind
of shot
off towards
the north,
and so
there was
no real
interaction.
And I
said to
this friend,
I said,
that's a
UFO.
And so
he was
kind of
skeptical,
but I
said,
Roger,
it's
something
identified,
we don't
know what
it is,
and it's
up there
in the
sky,
so it's
a UFO.
I don't
think it's
a flying
saucer,
but it's
very unique.
That was
the only
other
time,
something,
and there
were like
five of
us that
witnessed
that.
Is there
anything
else worthy
of relaying
that you
haven't told
me about
the core
experience
in 1964
in September?
No,
because to
me,
it's three
segments.
It was
initially
the entity
coming out
of the
fog,
the terror
I felt
inside the
craft,
we'll call
it craft,
and then
on the
floor of
the guard
shack
and waking
up and
looking at
the chipmunk,
when it
came flashing
back,
that's when I
went back
and tried to
put the time
together,
like getting
on the truck
and knowing
why I felt
so odd
when I got
on the truck.
well,
it was
because I
had this
experience,
but it
was fading,
you know,
and by the
time I got
back to base,
it was gone,
you know,
it was,
although there
was this
nagging
feeling that
I knew
something had
happened,
but I
couldn't tell
you what,
but it
really
nagged
at me.
It was,
you know,
uncomfortable
feeling,
something
happened,
but I
don't know
what.
Did you
have any
physical
marks
or
chips
implanted
or anything
like that?
I know,
I could
tell you,
just,
and I don't
know if it
relates or
not,
I recall
at one
time,
I had
like a
sinus deal
and I
blew my
nose and
a BB
came out,
a little
round
ball with
a flat
side on
it.
Really?
Yeah,
but I
didn't
correlate
that to
that experience
at all,
I didn't
connect it.
Well,
when was
that?
Oh,
probably
a few
years later,
you know.
But that's
really interesting.
Yeah,
it is now
that I look
back.
A metal BB
came out
of your
nose.
Out of
my nose,
yeah.
And I
believe
the nose
is one
of the
most
common
places
that people
have
sort of
implants.
I didn't
connect at
all.
I just
was,
I thought
maybe
when I
was a
kid.
Bob
Hastings
himself,
who wrote
UFOs and
nukes,
is actually
a UFO
experiencer,
and he
wrote a
book about
this called
Confessions,
and he
talks about
an implant
in his
nose and
then waking
up with
blood on
his pillow.
You did
mention after
the camping
trip in
1988,
you waking
up with
blood on
your pillow.
Right.
Did that
have to do
with anything
that possibly
was inserted
in you?
You know,
there are
implants that
have been
reported in
certain
abduction
cases.
I was
aware of
the concept
of implants
and people
finding blood
on, you
know,
their bed
clothing and
so on and
so forth.
I never
felt the
need for
whatever
reason to
investigate
that further,
like try
to get an
x-ray.
I mean,
if you
went to
a doctor
and said,
you know,
I think I
have an
alien implant
in my
head,
would you
x-ray
me?
I just
wasn't
prepared
to go
there.
So,
you know,
I thought
I might
have something
in my
body,
but I
didn't
really
think
about
it.
Well,
in
2001,
I believe
it was,
I was
having
breathing
problems.
I had
a deviated
septum.
And so
I finally
had some
nasal
surgery.
And so
I have
that done
to correct
this
problem.
And I
go in
for the
post-operation
meeting with
the doctor.
And he
said,
he was like
I would
say in
his late
60s,
early 70s.
He was
shaking his
head literally
and figuratively.
And he
said,
I found
something in
your right
nostril that
was so hard
I almost
couldn't break
through it.
He said it
was the
damnedest
thing.
And he
was saying,
you know,
I've done
this for many
years.
I've never
seen anything
like it or
encountered
anything like
it,
whatever words
he used.
And,
you know,
I'm kind
of rolling
my eyes
and going,
holy crap,
I bet I
know what
it was.
But what
they do is
they have a
vacuum wand
with a tube
attached to
a tank.
And so
they're
roto-rooting
your nose
and getting
cartilage out
and cleaning
up your
nasal passages.
So whatever
was in there,
they just
sucked out
and discarded.
You know,
to him it
was just some
sort of
biological anomaly.
never saved
it.
So,
you know,
it was gone
by the time
he told me
about that.
I just
did,
it was
quite a few
years later,
I didn't
connect it.
I just
thought it
was,
I must have
put that
in there
when I was
a kid.
It was,
the only
thing,
it wasn't
a copper
BB,
it was,
it was
like
chrome-plated.
Did you
save it
and test it
or anything
else?
No,
because I
spit it
into my
hand and
I thought,
oh,
this must have
been there
for years
and I
throw it
away.
Did you
ever think,
what is
this doing
up here?
I thought
I maybe
stuck it
in when
I was a
kid.
You know,
I didn't,
kids stick
things in
their ears,
I stuck
stings in
my ears
and my
nose.
So,
that's what
I related
it to.
But now,
later,
when they
talk about
implants,
I think,
well,
it still
could have
been something
I put
in my
nose
when I
was a
kid,
or it
could have
been an
implant.
I
don't
know.
Did
you ever
do any
sort of
hypnotic
regression
or see
any
sort of
psychiatrist
about this?
I kind
of was
hoping
Lonnie
would want
to do
it,
but she
didn't
want to
do it.
Did you
ever think
that there
was some
sort of
trickery
involved
and somebody
was messing
with your
mind?
No,
it was
too vivid,
too real.
Nobody
could do
what's
done to
me.
Nobody
could create
that kind
of terror.
Nobody
could evoke
that kind
of love.
I mean,
nobody
could do
that.
That was
supernatural.
I mean,
the terror,
yeah,
I was
a rat
trapped
in a
box,
but the
love,
nobody
could do
that.
You
mentioned
Lonnie,
your friend,
who has
hypnotic
regression
experience.
So you
told her
about this
experience,
right?
How many
people have
you told?
How many
friends have
you told?
I told,
well,
Lonnie was
the wife
of my
best friend,
and I
told Mike,
my best
friend,
and consequently
he had
mentioned
something to
Lonnie that
I gave her
the whole
story.
And then
I had
told a
couple of
people that
I kind of
trusted that
they weren't
real close
friends,
but I had
coffee with
quite often.
And I knew
pretty well.
I mean,
we had a
pretty good
large group
of guys that
used to hang
out at Starbucks
and drink
coffee and
BS at
night.
Did you
ever tell
anybody who
was stationed
at the
base with
you at
Vandenberg?
No,
no.
Okay.
I kept my
you know,
it was,
first of all,
it was like,
if I wanted
to, I don't
think I could
because it
was like,
I was told
not to.
And not,
you know,
the beings
that conditioned
me or
hypnotized me
or something.
I would
try to,
and then
it was,
it was told,
you know,
it was as
if they
still had
some lingering
control over
you.
They had some
control and
you don't
say anything,
just keep
your mouth
shut.
Because I
tried several
times I
wanted to,
and I
couldn't.
Did you
know anything
about UFOs
at the time
prior to the
experience?
Well,
you know,
everybody
heard of
Barney Hill
and,
you know,
I had no
real extensive
knowledge of
it.
It wasn't,
I mean,
probably some,
I've read
stories,
but I didn't
focus on it
or dwell on
it or it
wasn't a big
deal to me,
you know.
Do you think
about what
happened to
you now a
lot,
and do you
think about
the implications
and meaning
of what
happened?
All the
time.
And what
conclusions
have you
drawn?
Just what,
that they're
out there,
they're not
going to let
us go to
nuclear war,
you know,
and come
hell or
high water,
and if
they do,
then it's
their game,
not ours
anymore,
you know.
They'll leave
us alone.
I mean,
this is the
sense I got,
that they
would leave
us alone
unless we
screwed up.
What do
you hope to
achieve now
by relaying
your story
to me?
Hopefully,
you know,
hundreds of
thousands of
people at
least get
to hear
your testimony.
What do
you hope
they take
away from
it?
Well,
it's just
one more.
Like when
I wrote
Bob Salazar,
I'm not in
this for
anything.
It's just
a piece
of data
that might
be interesting
to him
or anybody
else.
It's just
another piece
to me
is,
you know,
Robert Hastings'
books got
like 169
accounts in it.
You know,
if he updates
it at number
170,
this,
mine's a little
more unique
because he only
has with me
eight cases
of the third
kind.
Close encounters
of the third
kind.
And so
actually
experiencing
beings
themselves,
that's right.
Only eight
of his,
you know,
167 some
odd experiencers
have had
those experiences
where they
see beings.
I do think
though,
it's funny,
I've had this
conversation with
Bob Hastings
in the past
where I say,
did you
systematically
ask all
of the
whistleblowers
who just
seen crafts
whether they've
seen beings
themselves?
And he said
no.
And so
if eight
people have
volunteered
that they've
seen
beings,
you have to
think that
number is
actually just
much higher.
Yeah,
I assume it
is.
I think,
I mean,
there's lots
of people
out there
who said
they've
seen,
there's always
the issue,
you know,
how,
I could tell
this story
and there's
always going
to be,
somebody's going
to want to
debuck it.
The first
thing they're
going to say
and has been
said to me,
well,
you have no
witnesses.
You know,
you were out
there by
yourself,
so did you
make this
story up?
Or,
or,
before George
Norton,
you had
Art Bell.
Art Bell,
okay.
There was
somebody that
had,
I had called
in on
Art Bell
and I
did get
through
and basically
he said,
well,
he would
email me,
he bought
my email
and I said
that he
would email
me,
he says,
but if I
find out
you're
screwing
around or
lying,
he says,
I'm going
to make
it very
tough on
you.
Art Bell
said this.
Not Art Bell,
the guy that
he was
interviewing.
Ah.
And so we
had quite an
exchange for a
while.
I told him
pretty much
his story.
Who was
this?
I don't
know.
I tried
to look
back over
my emails
and I
could only
go back
so far.
Describe
him,
maybe I
could figure
out.
It wasn't
Bob Hastings
because I
told Bob
Hastings
about this
and I
didn't know
Bob Hastings
was one
I had
talked to
when I
called
George
Norrie,
except he
remembered
that he
didn't
remember my
particular
talk,
but you
know what
I had
said to
him,
but he
was on
George
Norrie
being
interviewed.
When was
this interview
with George
Norrie that
you called
into?
Probably
about
seven,
eight years
ago.
Okay.
And so
that's live
for everyone
to hear?
Yeah,
that was live
and the other
one was live
too.
And both
are probably
out there,
so we could
probably dig up
the first
one.
But all
I could
do is
go back
over
my AOL
and see,
but they're
all erased.
I can only
go back.
Well,
describe the
person who
Art Bell
was interviewing
and maybe I
can help you.
He was very
much like
Bob Hastings.
He had
written a
book.
It was
more extensive
than just
UFOs and
dukes,
but it
sounded very
credible.
And the
only thing he
said is,
you know,
we had this
exchange through
seven or
eight emails.
And he said,
well,
he couldn't
include me in any
further books
because he
couldn't
collaborate it.
corroborate it
because you
didn't have
someone else
coming out
who was
witnessing the
thing.
But he
said,
it's not
something I
could put
in my book
because I
want to
corroborate.
Well,
sounds like a
decent researcher.
Was the name
Lindemann by any
chance?
I can't
remember.
Or Oxler?
Okay.
I can't
remember your
name half the
time.
No,
you're good.
Well,
I think,
you know,
stories at
Vandenberg are
so compelling
because
not only
like do
you have
a story
happening
the same
month
that was
corroborated
by
Florence
Mansman,
who is
the major
in charge
and supervising
Bob Jacobs,
who's a
photo instrumentation
specialist.
So you do
have a witness
there,
but that
happened the
same month.
And then you
also have other
stories at
Vandenberg.
Do you know
who Jeff
Nucitelli is
by any chance?
He's an
interesting
witness and
he and some
colleagues,
I believe in
the early
2000s,
experienced
this UFO.
Between 2003
and 2005,
five UAP
incidents occurred
at Vandenberg
Air Force Base.
The incursions
began on
October 14,
2003,
when Boeing
contractors
reported a
massive glowing
red square
silently hovering
over two
missile defense
sites.
After several
minutes,
it drifted
further east
onto the base
and vanished
over the hills.
This event,
now known as
the Vandenberg
Red Square,
was referenced
by Representative
Luna at the
first hearing
on this
topic.
Official
Air Force
records of
this event
are in
possession by
Arrow and
the FBI.
Later that
night,
while I was
on duty,
security guards
at a critical
launch site
reported a
bright,
fast-moving
object over
the ocean.
I responded
to the
incident.
Chaos ensued
over the radio
as the object
approached rapidly.
I heard my
friend screaming,
it's coming
right at us,
right for us,
and now it's
right here.
Moments later,
I heard them
say that it
had shot off
and was gone.
When I arrived
on scene,
I talked to
five shaken
witnesses who
described a
massive triangular
craft larger
than a football
field that
hovered silently
for about 45
seconds over
their entry
control point
before shooting
away at
impossible speed.
So Vandenberg
is definitely
a hot spot.
It's one of
these places
like Malmstrom
base in
Montana,
where throughout
the years
you have
recurring
patterns of
UFO sightings.
So I do
think there
is some
sort of
intimate
connection
there.
Oh yeah,
I think this
is an ongoing
thing.
I think it's
going on
right now.
I think
what my
impression
was that
they're
not going
to,
you know,
they're going
to be ready
to intervene
should we
go,
you know,
let those
missiles loose.
But until
then,
they're going
to stay
in the
background.
Although I'm
not sure
they're always
in the
background
because there's
a lot
going on
now that
makes me
wonder if
they're
orchestrating
a lot of
this steps
towards
this
disclosure.
You think
the beings
themselves
might be
orchestrating
disclosure?
Yeah,
that's
speculation.
I don't
know.
Well,
Richard,
thank you
so much
for doing
this.
I really
appreciate
it.
You're
welcome.
And yeah,
appreciate your
courage and
all the
incredible
detail and
I hope that
this,
again,
allows other
people to
come forward
as well.
I hope so
too because
nothing else
does get
some people
prepared to
this
ultimate
disclosure so
that they're
thinking about
it and they're
ready for it
when it
comes.
And I
think there's
enough evidence
out there,
overwhelming
evidence,
and I think,
again,
we go back
to nukes
and UFO
nukes,
well-researched
evidence in
one source,
and there's
thousands of
sources out
there.
I'm trying to
think of
Project
Blue Book.
Who was
the doctor?
Jalen
Hynek?
Yeah,
yeah.
He came
and took
the evidence
and he,
you know,
very brilliant
man.
Yeah,
nobody who
spends more
than three
days on the
UFO topic
comes to
the conclusion
that it's
fake other
than people
associated with
our nuclear
programs or
the DOE or
the Atomic
Energy Commission
or the
NDRC or
precursors to
our atomic
programs.
So you have
Don Menzel
who's this
kind of deep
state spook,
friends with
Vannevar Bush,
held all the
clearances in
the book.
He,
you know,
ran Bureau
of Statistics
for the U.S.
He was
dogmatically
opposed to
UFOs.
You have
Jalen Hynek
who was
opposed but
then,
you know,
later retracted
all that stuff
and kind of
repented for the
fact that he
was opposed.
You have a
couple other
people in
official positions.
You know,
Edward Condon
who wrote the
first,
you know,
textbook on
quantum mechanics
in the English
language.
You know,
people don't
realize he was
pointed,
supposedly appointed
by the,
you know,
Project Blue
Book on this
independent
commission,
you know,
in Colorado.
And it was
supposed to,
yeah,
the Condon
report and it
was supposed to
go through all
these UFO cases
and basically be
an independent
check against
Blue Book's
findings.
And then you
find out that
he was,
you know,
very close
friends with
Oppenheimer
going back to,
you know,
their studies at
Göttingen in
Germany in
the 20s and
he wrote the
Los Alamos
Primer,
helped pick
Los Alamos
as the site
for the
Manhattan
Project.
The Los Alamos
Primer was
something that
all employees
had to read
upon joining
the Manhattan
Project and
wrote the
McMahon Secrecy
Act,
which is in
1946,
basically the
precursor to
the Atomic
Energy Act
in 1954,
which is kind
of this
cloak and
dagger way to
overlay,
you know,
atomic secrecy
with UFO
secrecy.
So basically
you spend a
few days on
this,
you become
open-minded
or you're
dogmatically
opposed because
you're like
some sort of
operationalized
asset against
the thing.
You're protecting
your own.
Exactly.
And maybe,
you know,
maybe there are
a few contemporary
examples where
I don't want to
say they're full
bad faith actors,
but,
you know,
it's probably
easy to impugn
a lot of their
motives as well.
But anyways,
you know,
even the latest
Ted of Arrow,
you know,
our official,
again,
modern investigation
program,
which is similar
to Blue Book,
it's probably
just this fake
hit job on
UFOs.
It's a guy
named Sean
Kirkpatrick who,
you know,
has long ties
with the DOE,
worked at Oak Ridge,
you know,
got this award
from Brookhaven
when he was,
you know,
a teenager
and,
you know,
has all sorts
of,
you know,
monetary incentives
to say this
stuff is fake.
So,
anyways,
Richard,
I really
appreciate you
and this
was a lot
of fun
and hopefully
it shakes
the world up.
Yeah.
Gone
...