I'm here with Filippo Biondi, who shocked the world.
I think it's one of the most interesting findings in the last century.
I am struggling to express in words just how significant of a discovery this is.
Eight hollow cylindrical structures that are underneath the middle pyramid on the Giza Plateau.
With columns and coils around the columns, I'm like, what?
We have measured approximately over one kilometer of depth.
Over a kilometer of depth?
Yes, over.
Do you think that the pyramid was a nuclear fusion machine?
Please give me another request.
Maybe the water goes through these spirals,
and the spirals are made by piezoelectric material.
Do you think we can turn the power grid back on?
We do like that.
I'm here with Filippo Biondi, who shocked the world with a discovery earlier this year.
He really did.
I think it's one of the most interesting findings in the last century.
And I don't know exactly what it points towards.
I hope you can help, you know, elucidate, make clear what it does today and what your methodology was.
But you detected through this synthetic aperture radar, Doppler tomography, this really exciting new technique.
What seems to be like, it looks like an energy grid below the Kapra pyramid on the Giza Plateau.
And there's a lot of controversy.
You have Zahi Hawass, who's this cultural, you know, minister of culture there, former minister of culture.
And he says, you know, it's fake news and there's nothing there.
And then you have a lot of people supporting you saying that, you know, there actually probably is something underground.
Obviously, that whole area is full of subterranean chambers.
So it's an honor to speak with you today.
I'm very excited to get to the bottom of this here in beautiful Perugia, Italy.
Thank you very much.
Yes.
Thank you for saying me that we made a very great discovery in Giza.
Just to begin the work was done together with Corrado Malanga, who is the head of the research group, Armando May, and me.
I am the technician that developed this synthetic aperture technique.
And I shared it to the group.
So to, and to everyone, to everyone.
And so to perform the scanning at the Giza Plateau.
I want to start with the most, like, to the point question.
And then we can back up and figure out how we got there.
What, in your opinion, say a gun was to your head, you had to just guess.
What, what do you think is underneath the coffer pyramid?
Okay.
Yes.
Thank you for this question.
The answer is very, it's a bit difficult for me to give, to give you an answer, a precise answer.
Because the truth, we will know the truth only if we go inside the physical leader to check what there is exactly.
Exactly.
Now, what we can say that we have measurements.
Measurements, physical measurements, that are acoustic measurements.
And this, we performed these measurements, as you announced before, using a synthetic aperture radar.
Then we will speak about the synthetic aperture radar and how we arrived to perform these measurements.
We are considering tomographic analysis on, first of all, we began this analysis on the Great Pyramid of Cheops.
And then we moved on the Kafr Pyramid.
And extending all the measurements, the measurements on all the Gisa Plateau.
So, what we are watching?
We are watching huge structures that are connected to the base of the Kafr Pyramid.
And these structures goes, are extending underneath for, let's say, tenths and tenths of meters.
Approximately, we have measured approximately over one kilometer of depth.
Over a kilometer of depth?
Yes, over a kilometer, yes.
Wow.
So, over a thousand meters.
And what do the structures look like?
Yes, the structures are like, the tomographies are public.
So, we have done a scientific interpretation of those tomographies.
And they are like tubes that are connected to the base of the pyramid.
We are counting, at the moment, four plus four cubes that are descending underneath.
And they are connecting the top, so the base of the pyramid, to something that is located at the bottom.
So, at the bottom, we probably have huge chambers for approximately 80 meters wide of width and also of height, 80 meters.
Wow.
On the bottom.
Yes.
So, what is that?
That's like the kind of foundation structure on which the tubes are coming out?
Probably, because we are observing that the tubes are connected to the respective top of this structure.
They are connected and goes inside also.
Wow.
Because, then I explain you why, and all the physics that is behind all these measurements.
And, obviously, we don't know the exact objective of these things.
What we know now is this.
There are these structures, tubes, huge tubes that are descending underneath.
And, we have noticed that these tubes have a sort of spiral nature.
So, they spirals around their self, going down.
Then, we have noticed that each tube has a core in the center, which connects the spirals.
And, this core descends down.
So, just to be clear, the physics behind all this work that we have done.
We have used an equipment or a device, let's say a device, a payload, that is called a radar.
Radar is an acronym that it means radio detection and ranging.
So, we detect things remotely.
And, while we detect things, we can also measure the distance.
This is a radar.
In the past, the radar was installed on board ships, maybe to know for safety navigation or on board aeroplanes.
But, today, they are also on board satellites.
And, of course, the technology advanced and radar became synthetic aperture radar.
Why synthetic aperture radar?
Because, we need to perform pictures, electromagnetic pictures of the Earth.
It recasts in the so-called remote sensing of the Earth, Earth observation.
And, the more the aperture and the detailed are the image of the radar.
So, synthetic aperture radar, it means that we synthesize a very long aperture in order to have very high resolution on the Earth.
We are talking about a submetric resolution.
Maybe a pixel can be of this dimension or of this square that is on the floor.
So, it is very important.
Yeah, it's like a quarter of a meter, right?
Yeah.
It's a pretty strong resolution.
And, there are companies like IceEye and others that do all sorts of work when it comes to synthetic aperture radar.
They have, you know, Umbra, Capella Space, which I think are responsible for some of these scans.
Yeah.
Are very credible companies that do work in defense and commercial applications as well.
Yes.
Okay.
There are the companies that you said.
Yes, they are American Capella Space and also ICI is an European company.
We have Cosmos SkyMed and Cosmos SkyMed Second Generation, which is an Italian company affiliated to the Italian Space Agency.
So, we have a lot of equipments, a lot of radars, and we use the data produced by these satellites to perform the scanning on GIZA.
And so, radar backing up is just bouncing radio waves off of physical objects.
Yes.
Synthetic aperture radar is a way to do that with finer resolutions, essentially.
And so, how does that work exactly?
Yes.
I have to tell you this.
That is very important because initially, when we announced this discovery, there was a lot of mess in terms of scientific information.
Hmm.
So, misunderstanding, a lot of misunderstanding.
Radar, synthetic aperture radar cannot penetrate the Earth.
Hmm.
So, electromagnetic, electromagnetic waves has also, has only superficial interaction.
According to the Maxwell theory, according to the past physics, classical physics, the interaction of electromagnetic wave is superficial.
Maybe you can have a bit of penetration, but very, very few centimeters of penetration.
In this case, we have used, we have developed a new technique, which we are able to detect the superficial vibrations of the Earth.
Why?
Because vibrations penetrates the Earth.
It means that photons and phonons, which is the quantum of light, of electromagnetic waves, and the quantum of vibrations, so photons and phonons, are separated by something called boundary.
Hmm.
It means that light propagates only in the free space and not in the matter.
Phonon propagates only in the matter and not in the free space.
Hmm.
So, in order to combine, to combine these two, we have, we, we tried and we successfully combined the two informations given by the photon and by the photon, where we have both of them.
Try to guess where we have both of them.
In the intersection.
Hmm.
At the boundary.
We have the information of the photons and the phonons.
Hmm.
We have the interaction of them.
And there, we were able to retrieve the so-called sufficient statistic in order to perform tomographic inversion and so to go deeply inside the Earth.
Hmm.
So, this is something that we have developed two years ago, and this is new.
And at the beginning, people were not, you know, it is, was something new.
So, it had, it had to pass some time in order to realize that this was possible.
Is some, is something penetrating the Earth?
So, in the case of radar, like you said, it's reflecting off the Earth's surface, pretty much superficial.
Hmm.
What else is penetrating the Earth to even gather the data on the structures?
I tell you this, the satellites flies in the, in the space.
Hmm.
On a velocity of approximately seven kilometers per seconds.
It means that in one second, the satellite has flight, flow, seven kilometers.
Then, this high speed, this high velocity, permits the radar to synthesize a very generous Doppler bandwidth.
Hmm.
Doppler, it means that the electromagnetic waves that we transmit and receive are frequency modulated by the movement of the Earth.
Okay.
If the Earth vibrates because of the presence of seismic waves, the presence of vibration due by the, the cities, the presence of vibration due by any natural, um, phenomena occurring on the Earth while we are observing it by the radar, it means that the Earth is moving.
Hmm.
And if this movement performs a frequency modulation on the return of the signal.
Yep.
So, this frequency modulation is proportional to the vibration.
We can grab the vibration of the Earth.
Hmm.
And this vibration that is located on the boundary has all the information of the vibration present in, uh, um, below the Earth.
And according to this, it was possible to perform an algorithm that, um, realizes tomography.
Tomography, it means, I look inside.
Tomos in, um, Latin, it means slice.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
So, we, uh, can scan the Earth according to slices that are located below the Earth.
Mm-hmm.
The slice, imagine, um, to, um, uncharge, uh, or to extract a vibrational slice from below the Earth.
And here you can see everything concerning the energy vibration on a certain depth.
So, phonon, which is vibration, converts to photon, which is basically a light packet.
Yes.
Which is the unit of an electromagnetic wave.
Yeah.
The frequency modulation then goes to the satellite and allows you to read, uh, vibrational differences in the Earth, which is obviously, uh, you know, kind of correlated with material differences under the Earth.
And you can figure out the structure underneath the Earth.
Is that correct, roughly?
Yes.
Okay.
That's very interesting.
And I think to maybe the skeptic out there, I imagine this is used in other cases, right?
This isn't just used for scanning underneath the pyramids.
Has this been used in commercial industry, in defense, anything else?
As you know, on American Alchemy, we cover a lot of technology that goes beyond human limits.
This is about technology that helps the body catch up and feel good.
I'm talking about the iRestore LED face mask, a red light therapy system that uses clinical grade wavelengths to boost skin cell energy production.
The same exact principle used in the top recovery clinics and bio-optimization labs in the world.
I've been using it most nights, 10 minutes while I'm reading, prepping for a show, or decompressing.
It's completely hands-free, comfortable, and engineered to deliver consistent light intensity across the face.
Not that uneven scatter most cheaper masks use.
It feels like your face is taking a warm bath.
What it's doing is called photobiomodulation, stimulating mitochondria to repair tissue, reduce inflammation, and improve circulation.
You actually feel the calm and rejuvenation after a session.
I've tested a few of these.
This one really stands out for the build quality.
It feels like it was built in a high-precision lab, and it's not just a cheap beauty gadget.
So if you're into real evidence-based recovery tech, this belongs in your setup.
Head to iRestore.com and use code JESSE25 for an exclusive discount.
Again, iRestore.com, code JESSE25.
Red light therapy has really been a game changer for me, so I hope you love it.
It can be used for everything, I suppose, for commercial purposes.
Because when we are able to retrieve the superficial vibration of the Earth in order to perform tomography,
we can use this technique maybe for mining, maybe for crude oil extraction,
maybe for other kinds of applications that can be useful to humans.
Is it currently used for anything?
Like, I've heard that it might be used to map magma chambers and volcanoes.
Of course, yes.
It can be used to map the magma chambers of the volcanoes.
My personal opinion is very important to do this type of facilities,
because I'll give you an example.
In Italy, we have a very dangerous volcano, which is the Vesuvius.
It is located in Naples.
And from 1948, this volcano is not smoking anymore.
So it is accumulating energy.
Oh, wow.
Yeah.
And we know that I'm not saying that tomorrow will erode.
I'm not saying this.
But it has to be monitorized.
I tell you, Italy is very…
Here in Italy, we are focused on depth volcano.
It means that it is very under attention.
There are a lot of in-situ seismograph radars using the so-called interferometry, which measures
the displacement of the earth, are always – also I do it on my work – it is always under attention.
This other method can help scientists to study volcanoes.
Absolutely, yes.
Wow.
I mean, I think it's very important for people to hear that this method is used in business contexts,
when money is on the line, or in the case of Mount Vesuvius, so that another Pompeii doesn't happen.
You know, lives are on the line.
Yes.
It's a tried-and-true method, Doppler tomography, because it's really funny, man.
Like, even in preparing for this interview, you can chat GPT, you know, you're finding under the coffer pyramid.
The response you get back is synthetic aperture radar can't penetrate below, you know, a quarter of a centimeter below the earth.
They don't even mention the Doppler tomography, which is used in all these other contexts, so it's just bizarre.
Like…
I don't know why.
I don't know why either, man.
It's a…
Yeah, okay.
So that's really helpful, that it's used constantly.
And I think it's important for people to understand your background as well.
You do some work with the Italian military that's classified.
You can't even speak about it, right?
So it's clearly useful to them, because they don't want anybody talking about it.
Should I not even be asking about that?
Okay.
I'm just saying the facts that you do it…
Are you not supposed to say it?
Okay, sorry.
I mean, in the US, like, you can say, like, I do work, I just can't talk about it.
But you don't even want to say that you do the work.
Okay, okay.
Forget it.
What was your motivation in the first place to even look below the pyramids?
You know, how…
Did you have a hypothesis?
Like, I mean, most people wouldn't even think that there might be something there.
Yes.
Thank you for this question.
The first thing I did is to move on Vesuvius.
Because I had in my consciousness to make something for humanity.
So, the first thing is, okay, let's see what is happening under the Vesuvius.
And I wrote a paper, it was a very nice paper, and together also with the National Research Council of Italy.
Because we have synchronized the data coming from in-situ seismograph with the radar data and match them together.
Because I suggest to read that paper is very nice.
It is open source also.
Everything is open source.
And here I can say it's in my article or not.
It's in my book.
It's in my article.
So, and then after writing this or something, no money, only for humanity, and continuing this
paradigm only for humanity, according to my friend in 2019, Corrado Malanga, we decided to do something concerning
if it was possible to scan inside the Khnum Kufu or Cheops pyramid.
And then we made the motivation.
The motivation was because Jitza is, I think, the best archaeological site in the world.
There are a lot of things that in my personal opinion has to be discovered and we are doing it.
So, we moved there because we were motivated, very motivated to move in Jitza.
Because Jitza is very important for humanity.
And you go for it.
The past, you know, who we are, who are we?
Because in my personal opinion, people, when they're born, we don't know who we are.
We are here and we don't know anything about our past, our history and who we are.
Truly.
And it really, Egypt is the center of the debate.
If humans have collective amnesia and we don't remember who we are, Egypt is the center of the epicenter
of that kind of discussion.
Because you have people on the one hand like Robert Baval and Graham Hancock and Robert Schock,
who since the 90s have been saying very interesting things about, you know,
possibly limestone damage on the Sphinx.
And, you know, a lot of these structures possibly being dating back to, you know, pre what we
think of as kind of, you know, the Egyptian kingdoms, talking about their mapping to, you
know, processions and to, you know, to Orion's belt at the time of 10,500 when they think maybe
the Sphinx was built.
And you have subterranean chambers in that area as well.
You have Zahi Was, the minister of culture, famously debating them and trying to suppress
a lot of this information.
But admitting that there are some chambers down there, he even went down in certain cases
and then it's often, you know, nothing to see here.
Don't, don't dig further, you know.
So it is, it is this.
And then if you think about Western civilization, the Greeks got a lot from the Egyptians.
And the Egypt, you know, pre Egypt, you have Sumeria, you have a couple of other cultures
we know less about.
But Egypt was far more advanced than a lot of, you know, what was preceding it.
And so it's this really interesting seminal place to look, I think.
I agree with you.
In my personal opinion, they were, they were far, far advanced with respect to others.
We can see how they used to cut the stones very precisely like that.
I don't know if you, you went in, I went for the first time in the Serapeo of Saqqara.
That's something very amazing.
You see these huge, how you say, not sarcophagus.
They are, let's call them sarcophagus, but they are not sarcophagus.
It was very precisely, very heavy.
And so the first thing I can say, how they built them, how they transported them in the site.
We don't know anything about those things.
Yeah.
It's, um, taking, you know, uh, quartz from 500 miles away.
You know, it's, uh, we don't know that how that works.
We don't know how you get.
Also today it's, it's a problem to transport those heavy masses.
Right.
All, all this, all that distance from a part to another one.
Even today it would be hard.
Even today.
And we're talking about, you know, 10, 20, 30 ton stones that it's, it's just, and, and they do in some cases look like they were lathe or something.
They were like, even modern, you know, uh, techniques of civil engineering wouldn't be able to recreate, you know, some of these things.
So it's just, it's just a really amazing.
Like, do you have, for example, like the pyramids, do you have a good theory on how they were built?
Very, very interesting question.
Uh, personally, my own theory, I don't have my own theory on to saying how they were built this, those huge structure.
Um, just to tell you, uh, two, uh, weeks ago, I went for the first time in Egypt.
So I, I appreciate, uh, in, in, uh, in person and those, the pyramids, I went inside the pyramids and I was very amazing for the first time.
How they built those huge structures.
I don't know.
I really, I don't know.
And, uh, you know, before, uh, the study that we did, that we did.
So I'm saying this for me, people, maybe people used to, to, to ask in their self, how they could,
um, uh, realize those, those huge structure, you know, the technology that they used to, to, to use for, for, uh, these, these pyramids.
And if we consider also the structure that, that is underneath, what can I, what can we say about this?
Hmm.
What do you think?
What can we say?
I don't know.
Yeah.
Really.
I don't know.
Yeah.
Cause, uh, Armando Mai, who you collaborated with has some interesting ideas as to maybe the function of these, these pyramids.
Yes.
Armando, uh, we, uh, speak about this every day with Armando, with Corrado.
And we, uh, we, uh, we speak also with, uh, Christopher Dunn that has, uh, a lot of theories, you know, uh, about, uh, energy plants or other kinds of, uh, purposes about the pyramids.
In my personal opinion.
Yeah.
To stay all together.
And work on a common purpose.
We have to go and see in person what there is underneath.
I think Christopher Dunn's ideas are fascinating that it's some sort of solid state electron generator and it can, uh, sort of, it has wave guides for microwave transmission and, you know, maybe it was, you know, hydrogen generator or something.
It's a, it's really interesting and I don't know what to make of it, but it seems very rigorous and smart in terms of like the way he thinks about it.
Um, do you, do you think that there's something possibly there because you have his work preceding the scans that you found where he's hypothesizing all of this stuff.
And then you essentially find what looks like an energy grid.
It looks like coils wrapping around these sort of charged, possibly charged rods or something.
That's what it looks like.
Yeah.
I, thanks a lot.
Christopher Dunn because he endorsed our, uh, research.
So I am very thankful to him because I knew him in person, in person.
He's really wonderful, a wonderful person.
And, um, so I thank him.
Uh, yes, I, I agree with him because, uh, uh, I think he was the, the first person that, uh, um,
gave this theory about, uh, energy power plant or something related to information.
Let's say information.
Mm.
You have a very fascinating hypothesis as to what the pyramid or theory as to what the pyramid actually was.
Well, my first book pretty much describes what I thought it was, uh, in, uh, 1998, which was a power plant.
The book is entitled the Giza power plant.
I describe it as a, an electron harvester.
And I agree with him.
Um, what can I say personally?
Personally, I can say that, uh, this structure, the tubes that are going below the earth, the pyramid, uh, are, uh, something related to information.
Information from the stars.
I can't say anything about this.
Why, why do you think information?
Information because, uh, um, also generating energy is a kind of information.
Information is everything.
Uh, um, I tell you.
And in all this, uh, uh, technical compound, there is, in my personal opinion, an actor that it is always present.
You know what it is?
What?
Water.
Mm.
Water is the principal actor that, uh, is related to all these structures.
What role, why do you say that?
What role does water play in the pyramid?
Uh, water, when, uh, flows, maybe let's say on the, on the pipes like that.
Mm.
It generates a certain, uh, information in terms of a vibration that is very precise.
Because water is the, an important stuff of life that is present on the earth very, a lot, no?
The, the earth is full of water.
Water.
We are water.
And so the pyramids and the water are connected together.
Mm.
And when you say generates information.
I tell you.
Yeah.
You know that we are made of water.
80% or something.
I think more.
Maybe more.
It depends on how you are watching your percentage.
Mm.
I tell you.
In terms of mass of the molecules, I agree with you.
80%.
But in terms of moles, it means number of molecules.
Mm.
We are 98% or 99%.
Wow.
It means that, that 1% of number of molecules are, have the weight of the 20% that you said
before.
Mm.
Because of number of atoms, of molecules that is composed of our body, we are 99% of water.
H2O.
Yes.
Wow.
So that's, that's very important.
That's extremely interesting.
Yeah.
Wow.
You are seeing it in terms of mass.
Mm.
Okay.
That 1% of molecules has the mass of the 20% of all the entire water.
Mm.
Composing my, my, my body.
So 80%, 20% in mass, 99% and 1% in terms of.
Number of molecules.
And that's because of this power law where there's, yeah.
How, how, how does that work exactly?
So you have the, the, the, the, the mass has less number of molecules than the water.
The water has more molecules.
There are 1% of number of molecules.
It means that they have a great weight.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Okay.
So the proteins, the, I don't know, other things that are composing our body.
Yeah.
That is 1% in terms of moles.
Number of molecules.
That's interesting.
Because there are all these studies.
There's a guy named Gerald Pollack who talks about.
I suggest you to, to read the studies of Giuliano Preparato.
Okay.
And Emilio Del Giudice.
That were two former professors at University of Milan.
What do they, what do they talk about?
Yes.
They were the scientists that worked together to Fleischmann and Pons.
Ah, yeah.
So Fleischmann and Pons, for the audience who might not be aware, were proponents of cold
fusion.
Yeah.
So like low energy nuclear reactions.
And they claimed all these over unity results.
And then I think maybe they were sabotaged and, you know, maybe some scientific suppression occurred.
Who knows?
But so, oh, so, so, so, so they had a connection with Fleischmann and Pons.
Absolutely.
Yes.
They studied under them.
Because they, unfortunately, they disappeared both because they were wonderful.
Emilio Del Giudice and Giuliano Preparato.
Does this have to do with deuterium at all?
Heavy water?
On this show, we talk about advanced exotic technology.
But the most advanced system you'll ever deal with is your own body, your own biology.
And the older you get, the slower your body responds.
It's not broken.
It's just a bit laggy.
That's where stem cells come in.
They're basically your built-in repair crew.
And as we age, the signals your stem cells send get weaker.
Qualia stem cell is designed to support those natural repair processes.
They use well-researched ingredients like sea buckthorn and royal jelly that help your body do what it's already trying to do.
What I like is how dead simple it is.
You take it four days a month.
That's it.
No 40-pill stack.
No daily commitment.
Just four focused days to support recovery and healthy aging.
So if you've ever felt like your body just doesn't bounce back like it used to.
Whether it's after a tough workout, getting sick, or just the wear and tear of life, this product is for you.
Qualia stem cell was designed to support your body's natural repair systems.
Helping you heal, recover, and keep going strong.
And right now, you can try it for up to 50% off at qualialife.com slash jesse.
Again, that is 50% off at qualialife.com slash jesse.
And here's a bonus.
Use the code JESSE, J-E-S-S-E, for an additional 15% off that order.
That's at qualialife.com slash jesse.
Your body is built to repair itself.
Qualia just helps it do that better.
A big thanks to Qualia for sponsoring this video.
You know, some of the low energy nuclear people even now doing experiments say deuterium atoms are really important.
Absolutely, yes.
So that's heavy water.
And so I wonder if there's some connection between what you're saying.
Because when I asked you, you know, how should we look into water, you mentioned these two Italian scientists.
And then you mentioned the cold fusion thing.
Yeah, absolutely.
It is very important.
Cold fusion.
Cold fusion is, I'm not interested in cold fusion, but I'm very passionate.
I have a passion in cold fusion.
When two hydrogen atoms are connecting together and they transform in a helium atom, releasing energy.
A helium atom is, has a weight less than two hydrogen atoms.
So by different mass, they generate energy in terms of electromagnetic waves.
And this kind of, let's say, union can be done or forcing the atoms together or persuading them
to be naturally connected.
That's cold fusion is the second.
You have to find a method to persuade, to convince the two atoms to go together, naturally, without forcing them.
That's cold fusion.
Hot fusion is the first one.
But I tell you that hot fusion, the various tokamak that they are designing or other kind of hot fusion given by pumping energy, designing very powerful lasers.
Two lasers.
Magnetic confinement.
Yeah.
I can tell you personally, that is the energy of the future.
Hmm.
It means that we'll never find the present.
What do you mean?
Well, if that's the...
That don't work.
That doesn't work.
It's the energy of the future.
Ah, hot fusion.
No, I agree.
I don't know.
It'll always be of the future.
I fully agree because it's, it's always, it's extremely hard to, to make it work.
And basically for the audience, controlled fusion is the holy grail.
We only have fusion in the form of hydrogen bombs right now, which is obviously a very dystopian thing.
Yeah.
And with tokamak receptors, it feels like kind of like a, like a fool's errand or like almost self-defeating because of the amount of energy input to make the thing in the first place.
And it is very high energy.
And so there's the, all these lore rumors of cold fusion.
I'd say Pons and Fleischmann are probably the most credible of the rumors.
I, I think so.
Yes.
Yeah.
Because, and that would be this groundbreaking thing because you, if you had an over unity,
unity reaction with low energy input, it's like paradigm shifting for humanity.
It's free energy.
Yeah.
And what do they find that Fleischmann and Pons and also Giuliano Verbarata and the Neo De Giudice after,
it was, uh, how can we persuade the two hydrogen atoms to go together?
Because they, there are the, the atomic forces that the most you, you can, you can find those atoms and they, they are, they, they will never go together.
Yeah.
You have, uh, Coulomb's force, which is repulsion, electron repulsion.
So how do you, um.
Persuade them.
Okay.
How do you do that?
Like, uh, where are two people that they do don't, uh, they do not, uh, talk each other.
No, no, I don't want to talk to you.
Yeah.
So maybe a third person comes here.
And persuade you and me to talk together.
Ah.
And that third person was the atom of palladium.
Mm.
Palladium is a special, let's say, material that it's able to persuade two atoms of hydrogen to go together and become, uh, magically an atom of helium.
And the, uh, uh, fusion reaction is done by palladium.
Okay.
And also electricity.
So, uh, deuterium, palladium, electricity, the, um, and electricity, and this recipe allows the, um, cold fusion.
There was problems about the quantity, the amount of energy, no?
Yeah.
That was very little.
But if the research from the eighties to now, uh, were performed, maybe today we can, we can have better results with respect to the eighties.
So when the, when the first, uh, experiment of Fleshman and Pons were, was, uh, announced.
Do you think that the pyramid was a nuclear fusion machine?
Please give me another, another question.
I don't know.
Well, is there, uh, my, my, the more, the more specific question would be when you were talking about water transferring information.
Yes.
Where, where does that leave us as far as what it could be?
Like, is there, is there.
My personal opinion could be, but I say.
Yeah.
Is there any evidence that palladium was involved in?
No.
We don't know.
As I tell you.
Yeah.
You have to go down and see and explore what is in really that Jitza.
What's Jitza?
Yeah.
Because it can't be tombs.
Well, I think that it's funny.
Like it used to be conventional dogma that they were all tombs.
Now you have, you had Graham Hancock for the last 30 years being like,
it's not a tomb.
Now people are like, okay, maybe it's not a tomb.
And so it's slowly, slowly following, you know, do you think that mapping to, um, Orion's Belt around 10,500 BC, there's something somehow important with that?
Because if you, if you basically, yeah, they do map to Orion's Belt.
Orion's Belt plays a very important role in a lot of different traditions.
Even like Ptolemy, you know, said that the soul's path was through Orion's Belt.
I asked Graham Hancock on my show, I said, what do you think the pyramids were for if they weren't tombs?
And he gave me a very trippy answer.
He said something about, you know, ascending through them.
Like once maybe a Pharaoh has died, they're buried there.
And then it's, it's like an ascension portal or something.
When it comes to the pyramids themselves lining up with Orion's Belt, Orion's Belt has always, across many cultures, been the place of ascension of souls.
Absolutely.
It is, it is here in, in, in North America, uh, and, and in Central America and in South America, the, the path of souls, uh, that idea that on death, we, our soul makes a kind of leap up to the heavens and then makes a journey along the Milky Way.
Uh, and that, that journey is full of challenges and difficulties, uh, on which we will be assessed for the use we made of the incredible gift of life.
Uh, that idea is found all over the world.
Do you, have you considered any of these things or?
No, that's not, we don't know.
Yeah.
No.
There is something that Jeebs has to be something that is related to give a better life of the people at the time living there.
So maybe an energy powered plant, something, uh, related to chemical, something related to, I don't know, mining or something, but, or a combination of everything.
So there is something that is related to, uh, make better living people there.
And, and, and speaking of water, aren't there rumors of a water table also?
Yes.
Below the Copper pyramid?
Below the Copper pyramid, there is water.
Okay.
Absolutely.
Yes.
Because we found water in the, in the Osiris shaft at minus 33, 37 meters approximately.
I don't remember precisely.
There is water.
Uh, but I have to, in my personal opinion, I have to say this, water cannot be everywhere.
Hmm.
Maybe we find water in the Osiris shaft.
We move a bit, uh, on the left or on the right or on the north or on the south, and there is not water.
So it's not, uh, um, uh, mathematical, mathematical that we find water everywhere in Jitsa.
Yeah.
That's the first thing.
Then I will explain you what, uh, the CAFRE research project is moving on.
Yeah.
Because it's related to the water.
Because as I told you, water is the principal actor of Jitsa.
Yeah.
Well, but before we get to that, I want to give you one, one more, like the skeptics say you can't go that deep.
With Doppler tomography, we can definitely go a thousand meters deep, a kilometer deep.
It's possible.
Absolutely, yes.
And we have in other cases.
Because, uh, vibrations are traveling inside the limestone and two, you know, I don't remember 2.5 kilometers per second, something like that.
Okay.
Well, sorry if I make a mistake because I don't remember precisely, but the author is that.
Yeah.
And then the, the, the, the image that went viral all over the internet of the coils and the, that's like, you said four by four, you know, 16 pillars, energy grid.
Um, the other critique.
Four plus four, not times.
Ah, so eight.
Plus four.
Oh, so eight, eight pillars.
No, all, all good.
So eight pillars, you know, in this shape of an energy grid.
Yes.
You have, um, Sabina Hassenfelder is this physicist.
Sabina.
She makes this video.
She is very nice.
She was nice.
And she was, I think, pretty open-minded in her video.
But at the end, she said, I think that the AI reconstruction of the image is taking liberties.
Um, because basically for the audience, you have tomography scans.
So that's the raw data.
And then you have what went viral all over the internet, which is these image reconstructions.
That's the, the pillars with the perfect coils that everybody's seen.
So, it's beyond my expertise.
Like, do you think that that's a faithful rendition of what you actually measured?
The, the pillars with the coils?
The shape is that.
Hmm.
The shape of the doppler tomography was recasting a spiral form.
So, we can't say that are, I don't know, copper coils, or they are, what we can't understand,
we can't understand is this.
We can't understand that maybe can be, I don't know, stairs that are going down.
Or, I don't know, it's, they are cables that are going down.
What we understand is they have, it is something that has a spiral nature.
Yeah.
But.
That's all.
Are you, like, a hundred percent sure it's man-made?
Not, it's, we couldn't naturally.
No, no, no.
A hundred percent, yes.
It's man-made.
Yeah.
This, this, like, I can.
Because you don't find things in nature that coil in, in perfect, you know.
It's man-made.
Okay.
So, that's easy to say definitively.
Yes.
You never see anything in any of your other subsurface scans that look anything like that.
No, no, no.
Absolutely not.
Okay.
And then it's a question of what's the material and, you know, but you feel like you have some
decent resolution.
Yeah.
You think that it is these circular pillars.
Yes.
Something wrapping around it.
For sure.
Maybe it is hard to say which kind of material it is.
Yes.
Or for now, maybe if we have hundreds of tomographies with the ground truth, we can also understand
the acoustic fingerprint and maybe we can move into material recognition.
And that's what we are working now.
Because we, we, we, we like to move this technique for mining.
Today, mining is very important.
Also, United States or other countries, we need rare earth materials.
We need gold.
Today, gold is very important.
I don't know.
We, we see the gold price going up every, every day.
Why?
Because, uh, uh, in this moment, the technology is, uh, explode, exploding.
We need, uh, rare earth materials for our devices because there is AI, because there is,
uh, I don't know, NVIDIA that, uh, has to build, uh, a lot of, sorry, by saying NVIDIA
or other, uh, other companies, uh, the graphic cards that are very powerful.
So we need, uh, rare earth materials.
So now we are moving further.
Maybe in, in some years, we, we'd be able to know which kind of material we are dealing.
Hmm.
But now not, I'm not ready.
So what we can say is, okay, that, uh, in that part of, uh, of the tomogram, we have
high vibrational energy and there we have lower vibrational energy.
The peak, the peak thing, the pixels, we can represent that the underneath has a spiral
nation, but we can't understand the type of material.
And the, the AI reconstruction for the image, are you using generic software or your own software?
No, my own software, not AI.
Okay.
Oh, it's your own software.
Yes, yes.
That, your own software, you use that in other contexts when you use...
Absolutely, yes.
...SAR-Doppler tomography?
In the scientific community, it's called, uh, it's called the pseudo-inversion of measurements.
Okay.
In order to retrieve the tomographic analysis.
Yeah.
It's called the pseudo-inversion.
But, but you, you do this a lot over the course of a year.
Yeah.
And you feel confident because you've, in the other cases, based on the software read, in
certain cases, you probably can go down and verify what you're seeing.
Yeah.
And in those cases, they usually check, they usually check out, they confirm what you see
in the software.
Uh, you are speaking about the validation.
Yes.
Okay.
Yeah.
We do, we did a lot of, uh, uh, validation, uh, experiments.
A lot of, uh, because as a scientist, I have to validate, you know, how can I present
my results like that?
No.
Yeah.
It's not possible.
So, uh, you know that validating things that are underneath is very difficult.
Mm.
Yeah.
To go down is difficult.
It's difficult.
Yeah.
But it's not impossible.
Have you done it ever?
Yeah.
Uh, so the strategy that we have, uh, um, that we have, uh, made is this, we know that
there, there is a structure where we know everything about it and in a certain depth.
Okay.
Let's move, let's move there.
And we try to perform tomographic inversion there.
So to see if our results are matching with the reality.
Have you done those experiments?
Yes.
Okay.
Have you done a lot of them?
Echo.
That's another point.
Uh, it's another point of view.
Uh, three or four experiments.
Okay.
I tell you, it's very difficult to do.
Sure.
So we did, uh, measurements of the Gran Sasso d'Italia physics laboratory.
Okay.
Uh, located inside the mountain.
It's 200 kilometers far from here.
And, uh, we depicted the laboratory.
Okay.
Yeah.
That's our measurements and the reality.
How accurate.
Oh, a hundred percent.
They match.
A hundred percent.
Can, can, did you do it double blind?
So you didn't.
Can you explain me double blind, please?
Yeah.
So the way I would do the experiment in order to prove that Sardoppler tomography is really
effective is I would, if I were you, find somebody else who's a good practitioner of
Sardoppler tomography and who can, who can get the scans somehow, I guess if it's, you're
using a satellite, you're using a satellite.
So I don't know, you know, but like somebody who isn't aware like you, that you're doing a
test and you say, okay, get the tomography scans.
And do it you.
And then you create an image based on the tomography scans with your software.
Yes.
And then see if that matches.
Cause you already probably know what the laboratory looks like.
Yes.
I didn't do that.
I will do it.
Yes.
It is important.
We have to do it.
Yes.
But we didn't do it.
But it's still, you've done your own scans and it lined up with what you saw in the,
okay.
So that's pretty, yeah.
Cause I mean, to me, artificial intelligence is just pattern matching.
So the more data you have, the more you're like, okay, I've mapped this.
And then I've also validated and seen it personally and myself physically measured it.
And it lines up.
If you have, you know, a lot of instances of that, I think we can kind of say that there's
definitely something here.
So.
I just want to tell you this.
Yeah.
The rule of artificial intelligence in our technique.
Mm.
Okay.
There is no tool because we didn't use artificial intelligence.
Mm.
Okay.
It's funny.
People keep saying.
Yeah.
Let's forget artificial intelligence.
I tell you how it works.
Okay.
It works like that.
We have measurements.
Huh.
Okay.
Yeah.
We have a model.
And I tell you what's a model.
And we, we can, if we have the measurements and we have the model, we can pseudo inverse the
model.
And so to retrieve the, the, the, the, the result.
Okay.
The result are, is tomography.
And it works like that works.
Yeah.
It works like that works.
Measurements, model, results, not artificial intelligence.
Did the, did the data just come from one satellite or from multiple satellites?
Multiple satellites.
Four satellites.
For the COFRA.
Absolutely.
And they both.
Four satellites.
No.
Or, uh, I-Sight, Capella Space, Umbra Space, Cosmos SkyMet.
Four satellites.
All four.
Yes.
Wow.
And all four gave you the same raw tomography data.
I've got the results.
Yeah.
That's amazing.
That's really amazing.
It is the basic, the basic things.
We cannot announce anything without these basics.
Yeah.
And you've, and you've done four, four or so instances of validation in other cases
to show that structures that you are measuring actually look like what you think they do.
Yes.
I, I, I don't know.
Um, we have measured at also the, the Osiris shaft, which is well known at the structure.
The structure is well known.
And the readings that you got in the synthetic aperture radar Doppler tomography matched?
100%.
Wow.
Okay.
So that's pretty good.
We don't have a double blind because I don't know what's the double blind.
How long does that go?
Uh, 37 meters, the last one.
And then, but the Osiris shaft goes down.
Yeah.
It goes down for, uh, for a while.
I don't remember.
Okay.
It's okay.
I don't remember.
I'm sorry.
No, no, no.
It's okay.
So that's fascinating.
I mean, that gives me a lot of confidence that there's something there.
So, Filippo, what are the next steps of the CAFRA project?
Okay.
The next steps.
Uh, we are moving to, uh, completing, uh, all the, um, scanning.
Uh, we are completing, we are nearly finished, uh, we have nearly finished all the scannings.
Uh, and now we are working on, uh, uh, dealing with Egyptian authorities.
Mm.
In order to, uh, to request, uh, some authorization to go in situ and do some measurements.
Do you think that you'll get permission from the Egyptian authorities?
Okay.
You know, in Italy, we have this kind of, uh, saying like that, that is, um, mixed with Latin.
Chiedere humanum est, ottenere autem diabolicum.
If I ask you something, if something is human, I can ask you something.
But to obtain what I have asked you is another kettle of fish.
Okay.
So we, uh, we are working on, um, uh, compiling a project proposal.
Maybe the CAFRA research project can be at the center.
So me, Armando and Corrado.
And, uh, we can work together with the university.
Let's say University of Ferrara.
No.
And, uh, maybe other, uh, companies that, uh, physically can, uh, work on GIZZA.
So you want to get funding and work with an academic institution and then be able to,
to, and do you, do you think, because historically, and you saw it with Zahi Awas going on Joe Rogan,
you know, very recently.
I discovered, I discovered, I discovered, I discovered now.
You just have these people in charge who are close-minded.
They're corrupt.
Their incentives are to basically force fit any new finding into the country's own history.
And if something involves any civilization predate, predating that country, they're going to have an allergic reaction to it.
So how do you get around that?
I, I'm dealing with that a little bit because I've done some stories in Peru.
And they're, they have their own ministry of culture and they have gatekeepers as well.
And it's extremely frustrating.
Um, and our mutual friend Jay has experienced that as well.
So what, uh, yeah, what, I guess, how, how do you get around that?
How do you get around the politics?
Good question.
Um, I went, uh, to, um, two weeks ago, as I told you before, I went in Egypt.
I, I found a nice country, nice, very nice people.
Um, I don't know if, uh, all of them are over mind, but maybe yes.
I found that they are very friendly
and they love the pyramids.
They love the pyramids.
In my personal opinion,
we are not against them,
but we are together.
We are all together.
It would be the best thing in the world
for Egypt, for tourism,
for national pride,
if they found out that the pyramids
had some elaborate substructure
and some exotic functionality
that we don't know of today.
Today we don't know,
but maybe in a couple of years, yes.
It would be a groundbreaking discovery,
a revelation,
and it would be the best possible thing
for Egyptian GDP in the world.
It would be amazing.
I can't think of a better scenario for them.
And I tell you,
maybe these times,
we are ready to do it.
Yeah.
Who knows?
Yeah, who knows?
We are ready.
I like that attitude.
Yeah.
Yeah, I love that.
The water thing is so interesting.
What do you think as far as,
you say water has information,
and what is that?
I mean,
obviously there's a water table
below the Khafra pyramid,
but why is that significant otherwise
as far as the pyramid structure itself?
Yes,
thank you for this question,
it's important.
Water table,
water table,
while if the Egyptian authority
will give us the authorization
to go there in situ,
and make measurements,
maybe make some cleanings
on the existing facilities,
we are not asking
to go inside the pyramid.
And I tell you,
I tell you,
maybe we are asking
to go on the Giza plateau.
Because on the Giza plateau,
there are,
I don't know,
you remember when you went there,
some existing shafts
that are located
between the Khafra pyramid
and the Sphinx.
There are some shafts,
that are,
that has the entrance
on the surface of the plateau.
Okay?
But when you go there,
you can see that
they are blocked by debris.
So there is soil inside.
And,
according to our scans,
we are confident,
very confident,
that those shafts
are connected
to the underground facilities
that are located
below Giza.
so it is not necessary
to go inside the pyramids
because the pyramids
are something
a bit more complicated.
It's something more complicated
to have authorization.
Maybe it can be simpler,
it can be better
to have authorization
staying on the plateau,
not going inside
the pyramids.
And there,
we can do a lot of things.
The first thing
that we can do
is to perform
in-situ
measurements,
so in-situ
campaign,
using
seismic reflectivity
methods.
Okay.
Okay?
Not Doppler tomography,
other methods.
So maybe to
see if they match
with my methods.
And in that context,
we will be able
to map
very precisely
the water level
under the plateau.
That's the first thing
that in my personal opinion
we can do.
Then we can
measure perfect
and so
match
the in-situ measurements
with my measurements
and see how
the depth
of the existing
shafts
that are
located on the
Giza plateau.
The third step
can be
to
clean
those shafts.
we can
clean them
because now
they are
blocked
by debris.
There is also,
there are also
other things
like rubbish
inside
those shafts
so there's,
they have to be
cleaned,
cleaned.
And while
we are
cleaning the shafts,
we can go down,
down and down
and see
what there is
at the end
of them.
in our personal
opinion,
that's a
service entrance,
a secondary
entrance
that
connects
the
depth
facility
to the
main
facility
that is
located.
Do you think
we can
turn the power
grid back on?
We do like that
too.
Beam sheets
out of the top
of the perimeter.
That's so
interesting.
And I mean,
how,
does Dunn
think that
this is like
a fusion
generator?
Does that,
does he think
that,
that we could
produce over
unity energy
from it?
Chris
is,
has
very clear
idea
and I
agree with
him
that
the plan,
the power,
the Jizza
plateau is
related to
electricity.
or
something
that is
very near
to
electricity.
It's
such kind
of
electron
generator
energy,
electrons.
And
maybe
it can
be
hypothesized
this,
as I told
you,
water is
very important.
Maybe the
water
goes
through
these
spirals
and the
are
made by
piezoelectric
material.
And while
the,
the water
is
flowing
through
the spirals
are
exciting
this
piezoelectric
material
that
generates
electricity.
Something like
that.
I mean,
but it's
only in
hypothesis.
You have to
go there
and check.
Interesting.
And is
Dunn,
is he
interested
in
Pons
Fleischmann?
We
didn't
talk about
Pons
Fleischmann,
about
fusion
reactors,
about
this,
that kind
of
stuff.
But
maybe
the next
time I
will see
him,
I will
ask him
about
this.
Do these
two Italian
scientists
you mentioned
who were
kind of
adherents to
Pons
and
Fleischmann,
do you
think,
do they
hypothesize
that the
pyramids
themselves
have
anything
to do
with
nuclear
fusion?
Unfortunately,
I don't
know.
Because
now the
vote,
they
disappeared.
They
disappeared?
Yes.
What happened
to them?
No,
they
are not
with us
anymore.
Oh,
they died?
Yeah.
Okay.
But you
said
disappeared,
I mean,
not in a
mysterious way.
No.
Okay.
Emilio del
Giudice,
I think,
in 2014,
2015.
Giuliano
Preparata
earlier.
Okay.
In the
beginning of
the 2000s,
something like
that.
They were
very clever.
Yes.
Armando
Mai,
who you
have worked
with and
we just
discussed
for a
little bit,
he has
very esoteric
ideas,
it seems.
He talks
about the
number
237 and
he talks
about
137,
no?
Oh,
was it
137,
sorry.
What profound
mystery lies
hidden behind
this number?
For what
reason did
Richard Feynman,
the great
quantum physicist
of the last
century,
so stubbornly
insist on
suggesting to
his fellow
physicists that
they should
affix a small
plaque bearing
this number
upon the
walls of
their laboratories
and then
meditate upon
it every
single day
of their
lives?
Why did
Leon Liederman,
the 1988
Nobel laureate
in physics,
make a point
of telling
people he
had lived
in a
house
numbered
137?
137 in
quantum physics
is the ratio
between the
speed of
light and
that of
the electron
orbiting the
nucleus of
the hydrogen
atom.
You surely
haven't failed
to notice the
correspondence with
the number
found in the
proportions of
the second
pyramid of
Giza.
Is it a
coincidence?
What do
you make of
his ideas
and maybe
for the
audience can
you summarize
them?
Yes,
Armando is
a very
nice person
and scientist
also.
He is
convinced
that the
number
137 is
related to
especially to
the Kaffrey
pyramid.
I don't
know exactly
his
theories and
I have his
books, I
have to
read it and
I have to
study his
books.
But I
think that
I encourage
him to
go with
his ideas
because they
are very
interesting.
Armando is
a nice guy
and he
will do a
lot of
things with
us.
What do you
think of
Ben Van
Kirkwick?
He just
went on
Joe Rogan's
show and
he talked
about this
large
labyrinth
underneath
the
Hawara
region and
he talks
about
Herodotus
and Pliny
the Elder
and past
historical
accounts of
this large
chamber.
The stories
of this
Hall of
Records and
these rooms
beneath the
Sphinx go
back thousands
of years.
Not just the
Ares but also
Herodotus and
these other
guys also
talked about
that whole
area, the
Sphinx and
everything else
being vastly
more ancient
even than the
pyramids.
Do you think
there's anything
interesting there?
In some
portion of
the Giza
plateau we
found a
mess in
terms of
tomographic
reflections.
So there
are really
something like
a network
of underground
tunnels.
Because when
you watch
the tomography
you see
everything
projected on
a plane.
So it
is hard
to have
the third
dimension
inside the
depth.
And yes,
there are a
lot of
connections.
the shafts
that goes
down are
all
interconnected.
And it's
difficult for
us to make
a precise
reconstruction
of what
there is
what is
connecting
the main
shafts that
are very
visible one
to each
other.
Because he's
claiming I
think the
labyrinth is
like a half a
kilometer or
maybe more,
maybe a
kilometer.
It's extremely
big.
what there
is underneath
there is
very huge.
In fact,
in this
context,
it was,
I think,
Armando,
that me and
I think,
said for the
first time,
that's the tip
of the
iceberg.
The pyramids
are the tip
of the iceberg.
it's just
a hat to
complete
something that
is located
underneath.
It's like a
little cherry
on top.
The substance
is below.
The measurements
are showing
that.
So interesting.
What else did
you say?
You mentioned
finding these
networks of
tunnels and
then obviously
you have the
coils under
coffra.
Are there any
other findings?
In this
case,
I'm sorry,
I have to
quote,
cite also
Trevor Grassi.
Okay.
Trevor.
Because Trevor
gave me for
the first time
the indication
on the shafts
of the shaft.
He told me
because he's
ex that,
me not,
Filippo,
please explore
the depth
of the
existing shafts
that I told
you,
the shafts
allocated between
the Caffrey
and the
Sphinx.
Because from
there you
can find
the entrance
to the
underground
under
Caffrey.
Yes,
because he
is also
making
independent
research
a bit
far away,
but
100 meters
far away
from these
shafts.
And he
found
a so-called
corridor of
rooms
that from
the surface
goes
underneath
and then
it
connects
the top
to the
bottom
and the
is
constituted
by a
network
of
tunnels
that are
located
underneath.
Wow.
Also,
he is
studying this
and he is
100%
convinced
interested because
he wants
to go
inside
personally
in the
underground,
intercepting
this network
of tunnels.
It's
amazing.
Is there
anything
that you've
found
besides
the
network
of
tunnels?
Like
anything
else?
You have
this sort
of...
Ah,
yes.
Yes.
And I
told you,
I told
these
things
on
the
conference
in
Spoleto
and also
in Malta.
We had
a conference
there.
The
structures
that
are
that we
found
in
Caffrey,
we found
the same
thing also
in Menkaure
and also
under the
Sphinx.
Whoa.
Yes.
Absolutely.
We found
the same
thing.
The same,
not
4 plus
4,
but in
Menkaure,
2 plus
2,
a smaller
version
of these
things.
And
in
under the
Sphinx,
only one
cube
going down.
So they
are all
connected.
So the
Giza
Plateau
is not
constituted
by the
pyramids.
That's
Menkaure,
that's
Caffrey,
and that's
Keops.
No,
it is
something that
has to be
considered
entirely.
Yeah,
it's a
system,
network or
something.
So
fascinating.
What do
you,
like,
how has
academia
received,
you know,
these
findings?
Yeah,
I have
to be
to give
an answer
to this,
giving an
answer to
this.
Academia is
wonderful.
very interesting
because there
are a lot
of things
that I
learned
thanks to
academia.
It has
to be
something,
we have
to be
very
diplomatic
with
academia
because
works,
you have
an
hypothesis,
you make
the
measurements
and you
explain why
you had
these
measurements
and then
you do
comparison
with the
reality
and you
explain
the
errors.
So
this is
a
scientific
paper,
no?
You start
from an
issue,
you perform
the
measurements,
reality
and the
errors.
Reality
means
state of
the
art.
You
have
an
innovation,
the
state of
art
and
the
errors.
This
is
academia.
So
that I
agree
because
I am
100%
thankful
of
academia
because
it is
an
institution
and
it is
necessary
to
study
through
the
academia
because
gives
us
a lot
of
tools,
mathematical
the
scientific
tools
and
physics
that
are
behind
things
that
we
do.
Also,
my
technique
comes
from
academia
because
I
studied
this
interior
virtual
radar
from
academia
and
that's
very
important.
When
there is
something
new,
we have
to be
careful
to announce
things.
So,
it is
new
and
has to
pass
time
to
realize
that
the
things
that
we
are
claiming
can
be
valid
or
not
by
the
academia.
Which
I
agree.
So,
in this
moment,
we are
working on
a scientific
paper.
The
scientific
paper
is,
let's
say,
under
review.
Is it
peer
review?
Peer
review,
yes,
only peer
review.
Cool.
Do you
have a
timeline
on when
it might
get
accepted?
I don't
want to
say
something
because
it is
a bit
under
review.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
And
let's
see what
happens.
That's
exciting.
Let's
see what
happens.
I hope
it gets
peer
review.
I mean,
that would
be very
exciting.
I don't
know what
that means.
Maybe
we'll
be
rejected,
I don't
know.
But
if we
be
rejected,
we have
to know
why.
Yeah.
If
we'll
be
accepted
or
100%
we'll
be
some
revision
to do.
If
you're
just
saying
these
are
the
findings,
I
don't
know
how
it
can
be
rejected.
If
you're
saying
we
use
Doppler
tomography
and
all
these
other
cases
that
involve
life
or
death
normal
commercial
business
cases,
so it's
useful in
the free
market
context
where
people
have
skin
in the
game
on it
being
useful.
And then
you're
saying
we've
done
cases
of
validating
that it
works
by going
inside
of a
few
things
that
we've
measured.
and
then
and then
you're
saying
four
different
synthetic
aperture
radar
companies
measured
this
thing
and
you've
got
this
raw
data
and
then
you
have
software
that
you use
in other
contexts
to
create
images
that
invert
the
raw
data
into
an
image.
Why
would
that
get
rejected?
That
seems
super
to me.
I'm
not
a
genius
but
that
seems
very
simple
and
basic
obvious.
I
agree
with
you
but
academia
is
very
orthodox
so
they
have
I
think
they're
orthodox
because
of
what
everyone's
saying
about
the
implications
of
it
because
circulating
the
internet
is
everybody
saying
it's
an
energy
grid
and
it's
fun
to
speculate
about
and
it
could
be
true
but
just
the
findings
themselves
are
the
findings
so
it's
like
I
don't
see
how
you
can
reject
that.
We
are
proposing
measurements
let's
see
what
happens
I
don't
know
yeah
I
just
interviewed
this
Swedish
astronomer
named
Beatrice
Villareal
she's
amazing
and
she
is
similar
because
she's
traditionally
credentialed
like
yourself
you know
she's
well
respected
she's
at
Stockholm
University
and
she's
a
physicist
and
astrophysicist
she
went
to the
Palomar
Observatory
which
is
basically
the
most
prominent
observatory
in use
in San
Diego
in
California
from 1949
to 1957
so pre
Sputnik
pre
satellites
being in
space
she found
all these
transients
that look
like
these
mirrors
or like
light
reflecting
objects
they're
not
stars
they're
not
sun
streaks
they're
nothing
else
and
they're
pre
satellites
and
she
found
where
are
they
located
these
transients
came
from
solar
reflections
at
42,164
kilometers
from the
earth
or somewhere
there
around
interesting
yeah
no
it is
pre
Sputnik
yeah
and so
she's
trying to
find another
observatory
to see if
she can
line it
up
because
people
said
that
the
spots
she
found
are
plate
defects
but
then
she
basically
like
did a
study
of
these
transients
light
reflecting
objects
and she
looked in
the
earth's
shadow
so
the
earth's
shadow
you know
you have
the sun
pointing at
the earth
and she
wanted to
see if
there was
a drop
off
in the
earth's
shadow
and there
was a
drop
off
showing
that they
do
reflect
light
so
they're
probably
physical
objects
yes
because
they
reflect
light
I
would
like
to
read
about
I
will
send
it
to
you
but
it's
another
example
of
and
this
was
just
accepted
by
peer
review
and
I
think
you know
my
sense
is
that
the
people
around
her
did
everything
they
could
to
poke
holes
in
it
everything
and
there's
it's
weird
there's
no one
left
poking
holes
Sabina
Hassenfelder
did a
video
and she's
like
I
don't
know
what
to
say
this
is
interesting
Brian
Keaton
who's
you know
very
well
established
physicist
who
normally
plays
the
skeptical
side
to be
honest
he
came
out
and
he
was
like
I
find
this
very
interesting
maybe
we
should
look
for
corroboration
so
it's
an
amazing
time
where
people
like
Beatrice
and
yourself
can
find
these
bold
amazing
things
and
actually
try
to
get
peer
review
and
I
really
hope
you
do
get
peer
review
to
me
again
I'm
you know
just
thinking
about
it
simply
but
it
makes
a lot
of
sense
to
me
I
don't
understand
why
it
would
get
rejected
in
my
personal
opinion
we
will
need
a lot
of
time
for
review
because
I
tell
you
in
I
don't
remember
we
initially
published
a work
peer
review
that is
online
now
but
the
initial
work
that we
made
on the
Cheops
pyramid
didn't
have
this
such
media
explosion
on
all
the
world
now
with
the
second
paper
I
know
that
the
editor
of
the
journal
where
we
submitted
the
article
will
be
very
I
don't
know
let's
see
what
happens
I
don't
know
yeah
well
I'm
excited
and
I
think
if I
were
you
I
would
try
to
keep
the
claims
as
humble
possible
and
just
give
an
honest
readout
of
what
you
measured
yes
because I
think it's hard to reject if you do that
I think if you insert some of the stuff we're having fun speculating but don't
insert any of that stuff in the period
only measurement
the results
because
model and result
in my opinion
academia is myopic and narrow and not very bold and so if you do that then they'll reject it but
just keep it super narrow that's your way that's the way in
well I'm so excited man I'm so excited do you think that we'll be able to make progress in our lifetime on really understanding what the pyramids are for do you think do you think that what we discover through your work and maybe the follow up work in the coffret project will wholesale overturn our understanding of the pyramids and maybe reality itself
maybe yes
we need time
for continuing the studies
that's
important to say
time is
is important
to stand the ideas that we have
to consolidate ideas
that we have
I tell you that
the technique that we are using now is everyday improving in terms also of
also in terms of
precision
precision and the performance
so the answer is yes
my personal opinion yes
we can
maybe
the final proof is to go there and watch
and see what there is
we have to go inside
well I hope you're given access to do that
because I think it's really important for the world to just understand both our past
from placing humanity in a specific context
but also technologically who knows what it could unlock
who knows
you know
maybe
will be a year
where
if we begin
to
perform
in-sidu exploration
we will know
really more
with respect
in terms of
information
about the pyramids
with respect to now
if
we will be able
until the end of this year
to submit
to the Egyptian authorities
a project proposal
having
a
very
focused
very focused
ideas
on it
so without
going around
so focused
on
specific topics
in my personal opinion
we will have
an authorization
why not
well
that's exciting
if we have
an authorization
if we will have
maybe we can
find
excited
exciting
things
who knows
my prediction is
you will find exciting
things if you're given
authorization
I agree with you
I think
to me
the bigger question
is will you be given
authorization
I think if you get
I think you're going
to find something
very interesting
underneath there
because
if you can't explain
the way you described
it
just the hat
or the little
the tip of the spear
the tip of the iceberg
and that is
literally
a world wonder
like
we don't understand
it at all
how it's built
there are debates
about how it's built
if we don't understand
that
then
and you're telling me
that that's the tip
of the iceberg
and that there's
this whole network
underneath it
oh my god
I mean
the contribution
to humanity
and I hope Egypt
is able to see
just how special
that is
well
you have to
promise to let me
and Jay
come
and film it
you will be
you and Jay
will be the first
to film
oh let's go
maybe we can get
Joe Rogan out too
well it's
it's an honor
to speak with you
I said hello
also to Jay
yeah what's up Jay
Project Unity
go check that out
subscribe
yeah no
I'm just so excited
and it does feel
like these sort of
discoveries are
speeding up
I don't know why
I think people
are kind of waking up
you know collectively
to some of these ideas
becoming more open minded
and yeah
thank you for being
bold
because I know
you come from more
of a you know
a traditional
engineering background
yes
and to be able
to speculate
about these things
isn't so easy
actually before we go
we were
before we were rolling
yes and I have to tell you
also
yeah yeah tell me
yeah
what we did
it is
absolutely
inside
the scientific
compounds
because we did
measurements
yes
that are scientifically
approved
so we didn't do
nothing exotic
yeah
maybe we need to do
a double blind check
has to pass time
no but to me
it's like
using an electron microscope
or mass spectrometry
or something
and just saying
you know
we found these isotope ratios
and then
people are like
well what do you mean
you found those isotope ratios
well it's like
we use this machine
in a million other contexts
they work
and then here it works
and we found this
you're telling me
that Doppler tomography
is used in all these
other contexts
effectively
for commercial
you know
I'm sure
it's used for defense
that's me speculating
so it's like
if that's the case
what's
why not
yeah
why would this be
any different
like it's just an instrument
that we know
works in all these
other cases
so
it's miraculous
one other thing
is we were
before we were rolling
we talked a little bit
about this idea
of extended electrodynamics
and
scalar physics
some people
have hypothesized
that
some of these
ancient structures
involve
kind of acoustic resonance
but also
maybe
maybe tap into
a more exotic
kind of version
of electromagnetism
than the typical
transverse
hertzian wave
do you think
that's possible
have you explored
that
at all
I never
explored
this
but
it does
it doesn't mean
that
I
maybe
I will never
do it
if you ask me
what is a scalar wave
I don't know
I
I can't give you an answer
because I never
studied
this kind of topic
so
but
I am not saying
that it doesn't
that
it does not
exist
yeah
in my personal opinion
all people
academic
not
not academics
everyone
we are
we have to be
open mind
we
I tell you this
we go
in the past
in the
15s
maybe
when
an
Italian
scientist
called
Guglielmo
Marconi
who
invented
the radio
we are
now
today
with
these
nice
things
on the
internet
thanks
to
Guglielmo
Marconi
and
this is
what I'm
saying
it is
exactly
the example
that we are
living today
but we are
today
we are
saying
this
Guglielmo
Marconi
wanted
to
perform
a huge
experiment
so
can I
connect
the
Terranova
island
with
Cornovaglia
so a huge
distance
across the
Atlantic
and can I
transmit
some
information
from one
part to
the other
one
without
cables
only using
electromagnetic
waves
he was
sure
about
this
the
success
that he
will
succeed
this
experiment
because
he felt
it inside
the
heart
all
the
academia
I am
saying
nothing
about
the
academia
is not
something
against
the
academia
no
only
to
explain
you
the
fact
that
is
now
history
all
the
academia
was
saying
no
Marconi
is
doing
something
wrong
because
it
will
never
go
it
will
never
be
okay
this
experiment
will
never
work
why
because
the
transmitting
antenna
and
the
receiving
antenna
were
not
in
line
of
sight
and
so
Maxwell
said
that
the
electromagnetic
waves
are
only
transmitting
in
line
of
sight
it
means
that
I
have
to
watch
physically
the
transmitting
and
the
receiving
doing
that
because
he
wants
to
waste
money
because
it
will
never
work
I
can
tell
you
that
who
was
saying
this
because
it's
history
it
was
maybe
Poencaré
Professor
Righi
Accademia
and
so
the
journalist
from
the
academia
used
to
go
Marconi
and
ask
Marconi
but
the
academia
said
that
your
experiment
will
never
work
don't
worry
follow
me
don't
work
when
they
arrived
for
doing
the
experiment
they
used
to
have
the
Morse
signal
the
Morse
signal
from
the
transmitting
source
was
transferred
immediately
to
the
receiving
source
it
worked
why
because
there
was
the
so
called
third
via
the
third
solution
so
from
one
side
the
theory
of
Maxwell
said
that
this
experiment
couldn't
work
because
the
earth
is
a
sphere
and so
it's
like a
laser
pointer
it would
be
off
on
the
other
side
Marconi
that
he
didn't
study
he
didn't
study
he
wasn't
a
scientist
nothing
he
taught
in his
mind
wrongly
that
electromagnetic
waves
followed
a
curved
path
right
that's
not
possible
it's
wrong
so
the
academia
that
studied
was
saying
that
the
experiment
will
never
succeed
and
they
were
because
they
studied
yeah
and
he
that
was
a
mess
scientific
yeah
because
nobody
or the
academia
and
Marconi
knew
about
the
third
via
yeah
and
what
was
the
third
via
the
present
of
the
ionosphere
conductive
so
the
wavelength
that
was
transmitting
Marconi
casually
he was
interacting
with the
ionosphere
and so
the
electromagnetic
wave
according
to the
max
theory
made
like
that
and
like
that
directly
to the
receiving
and so
it
worked
that's
amazing
and this
gave
the
Nobel
Prize
to
Guglielmo
Marconi
that's
an
incredible
story
because
he was
right
but he
didn't
even
know
why
he
was
right
until
after
he
figured
it
out
it's
amazing
and
Marconi
flunked
out of
school
he flunked
and none
of his
professors
took him
seriously
and
yeah
even
this is the
world
so
everyone
has to be
open
mind
of course
well
electromagnetism
in general
came
Michael Faraday
was the
early 19th
century
he was a
poor
bookbinder
in South
London
who knew
nothing
and he
just
kind of
like
had
revelations
about
some
of
this
because
of
his
heart
inside
he was
feeling
that
it
was a
part
of
him
clearly
and
Tesla
had
all
these
speaking
of
scalar
physics
he had
all
these
ideas
of
where
electromagnetism
in its
current
form
even
with
his
update
of
alternating
current
over
direct
current
vis-a-vis
Edison
even
beyond
that
he was
talking
about
wireless
instantaneous
transmission
and his
experiments
at
Wardenclyffe
that were
sponsored
by JP
Morgan
I think
if he
were to
were alive
today
he would
say
you know
his
experiments
barely
scratched
the
surface
of what
he
thought
the
potential
for
electromagnetism
actually
was
so
the
point
is
just like
Einstein
is
housed
within
you can
find
Newton
also
Einstein
yeah
at the
time
when
he
developed
the
special
relativity
he
was
saying
that
time
is
relative
time
is
changing
heretic
thinking
yes
but
was
successful
so
in
this
context
everyone
has to
of us
think
heretically
absolutely
it means
heresia
in Italian
in Latin
it means
to be
free
free of
mind
absolutely
because
the
heretic
it's
free
the whole
history
of science
is
the history
of heretical
thinking
moving
science
forward
and
scientific
paradigm
shifts
occur
when
there's
a
buildup
of
anomalies
and
then
the
damn
breaks
so
and
each
theory
I love
the
Marconi
example
because
Newton
was
right
but he
didn't
know
why
he
was
right
Einstein
was
more
right
than
Newton
and
his
theory
there's
gonna
be
somebody
who's
more
right
than
Einstein
about
his
theories
and
the
idea
that
this
is
the
end
of
history
and
the
end
of
physics
is
the
biggest
fallacy
of
like
you know
that
we
know
everything
and
it
occurs
at
every
generation
we say
we know
everything
and then
somebody
figures
something
out
and
they're
always
the
heretic
know
and
if
you
can't
find
somebody
who
is
not
part
of
the
conventional
body
of
knowledge
who
you
agree
with
you're
almost
guaranteed
to be
on the
wrong
side
of
history
because
that's
the
person
who's
going to
bring
forward
the trick
is
finding
the right
person
who's
you know
and that's
hard
but
you know
I couldn't
agree with
you more
it's
funny
you know
two days
ago
I interviewed
Marconi's
grandson
and
it's
really
trippy
but
he
said
that
his
grandfather
was
part
of
a
secret
cabinet
from
Mussolini
to study
extraterrestrials
and it
was called
RS-33
in
the Italian
government
set up
this
group
secret
research
cabinet
where
Marconi
was the
president
and
Enrico
Fermi
was the
vice
president
and they
made
some
searches
and
studies
on this
phenomenon
because
they say
that in
Varese
north of
Italy
there were
some
apparitions
of so-called
UFOs
in Magenta
Italy
or do you
know where
specifically
Varese
it's
north
east
Italy
north
east
yes
Varese
it's
north of
Milan
in
Lombardy
between
and
Venetian
land
and it
was
fascinating
he told
me that
personally
like
and he's
the prince
this is
amazing
so it's
funny you
brought him
up but
yeah
I will
see that
interview
yeah
you'll
see it
up
yeah
but
I'm
just
amazed
by it
but
yeah
I agree
I think
I'm not
saying that
these
experiments
that we
did
are
esoteric
experiments
heretic
no
they are
orthodox
yeah
it is
a different
way to
watch
electromagnetics
why
why not
so it
is
inside
the
academic
compound
100%
the point
I think
you're
making
is like
when you're
a hammer
everything
looks like
a nail
and when
you're
an
archaeologist
and you
see a
structure
you just
say
oh
it's a
pyramid
there are
pyramids
in other
parts of
the world
that's
just
this
structure
and then
you come
up with
some lame
you know
a justification
for why
it was
built
you come
up with
some
reasons
that are
kind of
inadequate
as to
how
they were
built
but you're
force-fitting
your own
priors
onto
the
observation
and
you have
people like
Christopher Dunn
who's done
all this
work on
just
engineering
anomalies
with the
thing
itself
and then
you're
contributing
with this
you know
very clear
scan of
what's
underneath
the pyramid
and all
of these
things
don't look
like normal
modern
architecture
so the
idea that
it's just
some
ancient
you know
tomb
is so
obviously
coming from
our own
false
preconceptions
based on
modernity
it's not
based on
a you know
unbiased
reading of
what's
happening
yes
I agree
with you
so I
would bet
on you
know I
hope your
team really
figures this
out and
it's exciting
it's a
really exciting
time in
history
I think
that
we have
to do
something
yeah
maybe
in my
personal
opinion
humanity
is ready
to go
there
and
to go
and see
what there
is down
down
there
because
is
something
yeah
well you
know
you know
Luis Walter
Alvarez
who was
really important
for the
American
atomic
program
he's
depicted
in the
movie
Oppenheimer
and he
was very
high up
in the
Manhattan
Project
you know
he
x-rayed
the pyramids
in the
50s
yeah
so it's
been a
subject of
long-standing
interest
like even
from like
an official
American
government
perspective
for a
long time
and
how
he
x-rayed
I don't
know
exactly
yeah
but it's
online
you can
look
yeah
oh okay
it had to
use a
huge amount
of energy
in order
to penetrate
all the
mass
of the
pyramid
yeah
I guess
so
and I
think
did
there was
maybe
like a
muon
detector
yes
we have
to speak
also
about
the
scam
pyramid
project
because
there is
not only
the
cover
project
but
there is
also
or
much
more
time
with respect
to us
the scam
pyramid
project
scam
pyramid
project
is
using
muons
which
are
sub
particles
that
are
emitted
from
the
universe
they
go to
the
pyramid
and
they
intercept
some
how you
say
detectors
so
the
muons
impress
the
detectors
and
they
carry
the
information
about
the
voids
existing
between
the
top
of
the
pyramids
why
they
go
through
the
pyramids
like
that
yes
the
scam
pyramid
project
is
a
well
known
research
group
they're
using
another
physics
we are
using
acoustics
they are
using
sub
particles
and
maybe
let's
see
if
we
can
reach
them
so
be
in
contact
with
them
maybe
we
can
or
work
together
or
share
our
results
now
because
we
are
in
competition
competition
we
are
have
to
work
together
no
the
way
you
have
to
think
about
it
is
it's
you
guys
against
the
world
it's
not
you
against
know
it's
like
amazing
for
everybody
if
we
can
figure
out
anything
here
so
and
we're
up
against
kind
of
establishment
forces
so
you
know
the
muon
detectors
that's
specifically
for
mapping
the
chambers
inside
of the
pyramid
is
that
right
yes
I
tell
you
yes
and
I
tell
you
why
we
should
collaborate
together
there
is a
difference
between
the
methods
that
we
use
and
they
use
because
we
scan
from
the
space
from
the
so
from
the
space
we
can
scan
underneath
they
use
the
space
particle
to
scan
what
there
is
between
the
pyramid
and
where
they
locate
physically
the
detectors
it
means
that
for
us
is
not
request
to
go
physically
to
locate
the
detectors
our
detector
is
the
surface
of
the
earth
in
my
personal
opinion
we
work
better
with
respect
to
them
because
we
can
detect
things
where
never
a
human
went
underneath
their
technique
is
different
because
they
have
to
go
physically
somewhere
and so
they
will
retrieve
a
tomography
between
the
surface
and
where
they
locate
the
detectors
okay
I
am
hypothesizing
this
and I
I
will
share
this
information
here
if
we
perform
a
joint
project
so
a
project
together
maybe
and
if
we
will
be
able
one
day
to
go
inside
the
shaft
and
maybe
intercepting
an
horizontal
tunnel
constituting
the
network
of
tunnels
that
there
is
underneath
the
scan
pyramid
project
can
locate
their
detectors
inside
the
tunnel
in order
to
retrieve
what
there
is
up
to
there
I
don't
know
if
I
am
explaining
better
yeah
you'll
use
them
in
conjunction
you'll
put
the
muon
detector
there
and
so
they
can
scan
it
makes
sense
yeah
interesting
we have
to work
together
we don't
have
to be
separated
but
work
together
yeah
very
cool
I
love
that
idea
well
on that
note
Filippo
Biondi
this is an
absolute
honor
and a
pleasure
and I
really wish
you good
luck
because I
think what
you're doing
is very
important
and honestly
I didn't
you know
I was very
compelled
by what
was circulating
online
but there
were a couple
of things
that even
I was
didn't know
or was
holding out
judgment on
and after
this interview
you kind of
convinced me
on a lot
of it
so I'm
very very
excited
and thank
you for
doing this
appreciate it
thank you
over the
last couple
of months
we've been
designing
the new
American
Alchemy
merch drop
and I'm
excited to
say that
the 2025
winter drop
is finally
ready
we now
have 30
uniquely
designed
pieces
that really
reflect what
American
Alchemy
is all
about
this drop
includes
epic
t-shirts
long
sleeves
crew
necks
hoodies
tapered
sweatpants
hats
totes
mugs
and tumblers
the Fukushima
Japan
pieces
for example
have detailed
left chest
embroidery
the morning
of earth
designs
went through
multiple
revisions
to get the
fit
exactly
right
and the
iron horse
tee
is something
I think
will be a
hit
for anyone
who loved
the UFO
cowboy
or our
atomic age
shirts
from our
last drop
we cut a lot
of things
that didn't
meet our
standards
and we're
really really
proud of
each of
items
everything
is pretty
limited
so there's
no endless
restocks
once it's
gone
it's entirely
if you missed
anything from
our original
drops and you
want to go out
and represent
now's the time
to go grab
something
so go to
americanalchemymerch.com
to check it
all out
is
there's
the
that
is
the
ante
as
the
there
and
for
the
needs
of
it
and
can
slip
so
that