Two small gray beings came into my room and woke me up and said, come outside.
And I put on these steel-toed boots I had by the bed and went outside with them,
and there was a UFO hovering at a very low altitude over the backyard.
I woke up, and I knew that I had an implant in my toe.
The aliens had been there in the middle of the night.
And I had one more on the side of my head, too.
Whoa.
We found the object, and we took it out.
It looked like nothing that I had ever removed before.
If you can just feel my hair right there, you see that there's...
Oh, yeah.
There's something in his ear.
The line that sticks to my ear.
Whoa.
Some of my favorite interviews have been these guys, they have implants.
You know, they're Close Encounters of the Third Kind, type 2 abductions.
I go in for the post-operation meeting with the doctor, and he said,
I found something in your right nostril that was so hard, I almost couldn't break through it.
How many people do you think are walking around with alien implants inside of them?
350,000 people.
These people are way too powerful to fight, and they're experts at mind control.
They can make you do anything they want you to do willingly.
The beings that implanted you, think good or bad, or...?
Hmm.
The connection frequency starts.
How is this possible?
Nothing too unusual about that.
The existence cannot longer be denied.
We've talked a bit about longevity and life extension on this show.
Extending your telomeres, metabolic optimization, and the through line is always the same.
Most of what determines how long you live comes down to really basic stuff, not these more exotic treatments.
I think about that sometimes when I realize it's 10pm and I haven't eaten all day because I was deep in prep for the next episode.
Which is kind of the story of my life since I moved to Austin.
Occasionally I'll be so deep in work that I'll forget to eat, and then I end up demolishing whatever's closest at midnight.
Guys, this solution is amazing.
It's a game changer for anyone who's busy.
Meals show up, ready to go, you heat them up in two minutes, and they're actually made with real food.
Lean proteins, whole ingredients, no seed oils, no refined sugar.
Over 100 options that rotate weekly.
I've been doing it for a bit now, and it is embarrassingly simple.
I'm not a great chef.
I don't like overspending every day on delivery.
I really don't know why I waited so long for this.
Head to factormeals.com slash alchemy50off and use code ALCHEMY50OFF.
That's ALCHEMY50OFF to get 50% off and free breakfast for a year.
The offer is only valid for New Factor customers doing an auto-renewing subscription purchase.
Do yourself a favor now.
Make healthier eating easy with Factor.
Steve Colburn, I am so grateful that you're here.
This has been a long time coming.
I was just saying offset.
I've been trying to get in touch with you for the last two or three years, maybe.
I've followed your work.
It seems like in UFO world, we seem stuck on the existence or non-existence of lights in the sky.
And there's a whole kind of history of research, deep research from very credentialed people discussing kind of deeper threads, if you will, around close encounters of the third kind, abductions, implants often being found in these people's bodies.
There's a legendary UFO researcher named Dr. Roger Lear, who everybody likes to pay homage to, and I view you as kind of his living heir in many ways.
Yeah, I guess that's about right these days.
I mean, nobody else has taken up the research, and he taught me everything he knew.
So I would very much like to continue the research when funding becomes available.
It's crazy that funding should be completely available.
This is like the most interesting stuff.
So let's just establish for the audience, who is Dr. Roger Lear?
He's known as this sort of alien implant doctor.
What was his background?
How did he get into this?
Well, he was a podiatrist, and he was always interested in UFOs.
He was the most knowledgeable ufologist I've ever met.
And he was at a UFO conference once, and Daryl Sims tried to get him into an alien implant, and he thought the subject was ridiculous at first.
Then he finally said one of his friends convinced him to take another look at it.
So he said to Daryl, well, you know, get some of these people down here to my office, and we'll get them x-rayed and take the object out and see what it is.
And so that's how the research started.
And he ended up taking out 17 objects from 17 different people over about a 20-year period.
We found the object, the first one, and we took it out.
It looked like nothing that I had ever removed before in a way of a foreign body.
And believe me, I had removed all sorts of things from even a hair to paper to metals of various kinds and so on.
I never saw anything like this.
It was a T-shaped affair that was wrapped in a very tight biological tissue, which was this really strange color and texture.
And then we took a scalpel, and we wanted to see what was inside.
That's the idea of the whole thing.
And we were amazed to find that we couldn't cut through this biological tissue.
It came back with absolutely no inflammatory response.
Now, that really makes you want to scratch your head, because how do you get something into the human body and not have the body react to it?
Well, that just doesn't happen.
Maybe there's some weirded-out explanation that I didn't understand from one site.
Maybe two sites, but three sites from two different people, that's just a little too much to handle.
And where was he based?
I found out that Dr. Lear was working in Thousand Oaks when I was working in Camarillo, California, only a few miles away.
And I had a weird experience where I saw these giant raccoons in my backyard when I was at the house alone one night.
And I fed the animals and observed them for some time, and they were about between 75 and 100 pounds, I'd estimate.
I didn't even know raccoons got that big.
And evidently, there were scout animals for the aliens, because I went to bed and woke up about 8 o'clock the next morning and had a bad stinging pain in my toe.
And I had reason to believe it was some kind of an implant, and so I went to see Dr. Lear.
And I don't think he believed me at first, but he gave me a prescription to get the toe x-rayed.
And I knew we were going to see something on the x-ray, but when I did, that changed my life forever.
It looked like a bent piece of wire on the x-ray.
And I didn't remember getting any shrapnel in there or anything like that, so it was quite an experience.
Then he got funding from Jaime Masson to remove it a few months later, and he didn't have anybody to analyze it.
And so, where I was working at the time, I had access to a lot of analytical equipment, so I analyzed it for him, and it turned out to be a sophisticated nanotechnological device.
Have you read my paper on that implant?
I have not. Let's hear about it.
Well, it turned out to have very skewed isotopic ratios and several elements that were in the metallic core, and to the extent that it looked like it probably came from another part of the galaxy, not just another planet.
How can you know that from the isotope ratios?
Well, because the isotope ratios are characteristic of elements from different places, and if they're off by more than a percent or so, that means it's not from Earth.
These were off by up to like 30%.
What were the elements, and what were the isotopes?
The first one, I think it was boron and copper, and there were similar results from other implants I analyzed.
And anyway, the structure of the device was a gray, hard-to-cut membrane, and below that, a layer of material that was similar to bone, like a biological hard part, like bone or mother of pearl.
Then below that, a metallic core that made of meteoric iron with carbon nanotubes inside the metal, and nerve cells connected to the device.
The pain in my toe got worse over a period of days and led to a lot of electric shock-type pain whenever I put any weight on the toe.
And I think that was the nerve cells running in the device.
These devices also produce no physiological reaction in the body, and that's unheard of.
Foreign objects always produce a physiological response.
So there's no immune response.
No immune response, right.
Really interesting.
And could these elements and isotopes theoretically have been produced in some sort of centrifuge?
You could, but in order to produce those exact ratios, it would probably cost millions of dollars and be very difficult to do.
So the question is why?
And why would anybody do that?
Why would anybody do that?
Yeah.
Do you remember undergoing some sort of alien abduction experience prior to that being in your toe?
I didn't remember it consciously, but I underwent regressive hypnosis and remembered aliens putting in the device, yeah.
What was that experience like?
Well, two small gray beings came into my room and woke me up and said, come outside.
And I put on these steel-toed boots I had by the bed and went outside with them.
And there was a UFO hovering at a very low altitude over the backyard over this avocado tree I had at the Fillmore house.
And they indicated that I should stand below the center of the craft and took me up with a tractor beam.
And Star Trek got it right, by the way.
It's like a blue or greenish beam that lifts things, a gravity beam.
And the center of the craft, it was about 50 feet in diameter, similar to Lazar's sport model, if you're familiar with that.
Oh, yeah.
And the center of the device or craft was an airlock that had human and alien spacesuits available.
And there were four doors leading to the four quadrants of the craft.
Then there was a habitation ring around the outside and a pilot station with two pilots and prepared to be thought controlled.
They had their hands in a panel and on top of a panel.
And screens where they were observing different things.
And they took me around to the station at 90 degrees, so the pilot station.
And there was a couch that slid out of the wall.
And this guy indicated for me to lie down.
And it was a taller gray.
And he took out a device that looked like a black plastic handle with a piece of quarter-inch stainless steel tubing on it and touched it to my toe and pushed a button.
And that must have put the implant in.
And there were fiber optics going down the center of this piece of tubing.
And I think that's what activates the device, UV light.
And I think that's what accounts for these red marks you see on experiencers, too.
I think they're mini sunburns from UV light.
Interesting.
And so, how long were you up there for?
About an hour.
They waited for a long time for orders, I think, before actually putting in the device.
I think because they knew I'd start an investigation and they weren't sure they wanted that.
Because a bunch of weird stuff had been happening previously.
Where were you living at the time?
Fillmore, California.
Okay, Fillmore.
And was this during that night?
Yeah, it was a night about 3 in the morning.
They usually come about 2 or 3 in the morning.
And so, finally, after about, being up for about 45 minutes, I go, like, guys, you know, I'm tired.
If you're not going to do anything, then let me go back to bed.
So, they put the device in at that point.
And that didn't take very long once they decided to make up their minds.
Are you communicating telepathically with them?
Yeah, telepathically.
Okay.
Do you see any symbols around the craft?
Yeah, there were some symbols that looked like hieroglyphics.
I'm labeling the instruments on the pilot station and on some of the walls.
They had a, I believe they had a vector symbol, a blue vector symbol on the wall, a pretty big symbol.
And it had two dots, circles below it.
And their uniforms are usually cobalt blue and have either a snake with a snake over a triangle or three orange circles arranged in an equilateral triangle.
And I'm led to believe that the three orange circles arranged in an equilateral triangle is the symbol of the gray alliance.
The, the, the grays are not one species.
There were like several, I believe seven different species of similar aliens that are bound by treaty and come within, come to us from planets within a hundred light years of here.
Where, how are you getting that?
Uh, they, I believe they told me.
Oh, they told you that.
Yeah.
And, uh, what else did they tell you?
Uh, a lot of stuff about physics and, um, propulsion, most of which I can't remember consciously.
Do you remember anything about the physics and propulsion?
Uh, yeah.
Yeah.
Um, they use a combination of, or several methods to create any gravity and they, they definitely have any gravity drives.
And, um, they use, uh, like three different methods to create, um, anti-gravity.
Do you remember the methods?
Yeah.
One of, one of those is a home polar generator.
Um, if, if you take a disc, the basic home polar generator is, uh, a disc, uh, a metallic disc rotating, uh, in a perpendicular magnetic field.
And it creates a voltage between the, uh, the center and the outside of the disc.
And, um, the aliens use a version of that, uh, to create most of their lift where, um, they, uh, circulate, uh, molten metal around the outside of the craft.
That's, uh, magnetic, uh, uh, from, uh, analyzing samples of the material that were dropped.
I think it's usually a, uh, mixture of, um, iron and silicon.
The silicon's probably in there lower the melting point.
And, um, there's a strong magnetic field, um, between the top and bottom of the craft.
That's why, uh, the, um, uh, that's why equipment like, uh, car electrical systems goes out when a UFO is near because of the very, very strong magnetic field.
And, um, um, they also, um, use a method, um, called the Bifield-Brown effect to generate lift where, um, you rapidly charge a capacitor, um, and, and there's a thrust in the direction of the positive pole.
Um, and the, uh, a lot of these things, the entire craft is a capacitor between the top and bottom, um, uh, the top and bottom, uh, of the craft are like plates of a capacitor.
So they told you they used the Bifield-Brown effect, these aliens?
Yeah.
That's really interesting.
And, um, uh, the, uh, according to Bob Lazar, they didn't, I don't remember him telling me this, but according to Bob Lazar, they also use element 115 sometimes to amplify the gravitational effect.
Yeah.
That's amazing.
I'm, uh, I'm obsessed with Townsend-Brown.
So I, I, that gets me excited.
The fact that there's some, you know, corroboration from an experiencer that, you know, maybe that, that is how the craft actually works.
Many institutions and people have tried to either downplay or falsify Brown's experiments.
For example, in 1990, the Air Force tested a Bifield-Brown experiment in a vacuum, but they
only used 19 kilovolts instead of the megavoltage Brown was using.
But in 1956, Jacques Corneon, a French Air Force officer and technical representative for one of France's largest aircraft companies, Sued West, facilitated Brown's experiments in a vacuum in the Montgolfier facility in Paris.
The tests were very, very, very tricky.
It was sensitive to so, so many things.
In fact, finally it worked.
So that was the positive result.
Did they say anything else?
So they're giving you all this insight into the, into the physics?
Uh, they, they talked about time travel quite a bit, um, and the physics of that.
What did they say?
They said that, um, that they have time travel.
They don't like to use it very much because, um, and especially don't like to do long jumps because you could, um, if you travel back in time too far, you could get back, you get on a different timeline and it would be difficult to get back to your own.
Uh, that's the main reason.
Um, there's, um, the many worlds interpretation of quantum mechanics is, um, is, uh, generally correct except that, um, uh, minor decisions, I'm not sure how the universe decides what's a minor decision and what's a major one, but, um, minor, uh, decisions in quantum mechanics, uh, where something happens on a subatomic scale, um, most of those, uh, just collapse on themselves and don't become a separate timeline.
But some do.
Hmm.
So this is this idea that the wave function doesn't actually collapse.
It sort of infinitely branches.
Right.
But you're saying that in certain cases.
It's a combination.
Some, some, most of them collapse, but some of them continue on and become a different timeline.
Makes rough sense.
That's interesting.
Yeah.
And, and the, the, the, the ones that do continue on are as real as this one.
Hmm.
And, um, if you go back, uh, too far and then try to go forward again, there's a chance you might end up on one of those branch points.
Yeah.
Went across one of the branch points and end up on a different timeline.
Did they connect the, you know, quote unquote, anti-gravity with the time travel?
Because Byfield Brown effect and Townsend Brown himself was very interested in time travel because of their relationship between gravity and time and general relativity.
Well, the way they move faster than light is that they, they use the anti-gravity drive to open up a wormhole.
And, um, I'm not sure how they, um, they choose where the other opening of the wormhole is, but they, they can do that somehow.
And then they'll go through it and, uh, go a few million kilometers before the wormhole collapses because wormholes are unstable.
And, um, they can do the same thing with time.
They just open up a wormhole in a different time where the, the, the opening is in a different time that they want to visit.
And the other reason they don't like to use time travel too much is because, um, it's difficult to judge exactly when you're going to come out to the second like they like to do.
Yeah. Well, that seems to be the case. And you have like Travis Walton dropped off near where he was picked up, but not, it's usually not like very precise and there's like sort of missing time involved.
Yeah. Yeah. And Dr. in, um, Travis Walton's case, Dr. Lear thinks he would, or thought he was dead and they brought him back to life.
Whoa. Why does Roger Lear think that?
A lot of the people I talked to on this show, whistleblowers, intelligence insiders, people who've worked on classified programs, they all say the same thing when it comes to protecting your cyber security.
They often comment on the fact that ordinary people basically have no privacy when they're online.
Your internet service provider logs everything you do in the U S they can legally sell your browsing history to ad companies.
And if you're on public wifi, someone with basic computer knowledge can see your emails, your passwords, and your credit card details.
And it's all the more important to think about these things when you're Googling stuff like UFO crash retrieval programs, freedom of information act databases, and reaching out to sources who need discretion.
That's not stuff anyone wants sitting on some data broker's server.
In my opinion, one of the best ways to lock everything down is with express VPN.
One click and your connection is encrypted.
Your IP is masked.
It's not just a VPN anymore.
You now get a password manager, email aliases that hide your real inbox, and full identity protection with dark web monitoring and up to a million dollars in theft insurance.
That's right.
Up to a million dollars in theft insurance, all included for the same price.
Find out how you can get up to four extra months by clicking the link in the description below expressvpn.com slash American Alchemy.
Don't put it off.
Because Travis was thrown like 20 feet by either a weapon or getting a shock from the electric field around the craft, and he wasn't moving when he was flying through the air or when he landed on the ground, and all the people in his logging crew thought he was dead.
That is definitely true.
Did any of these beings tell you why they were doing what they were doing to you?
Did they give you any sort of sense as to why they would implant your toe of all places?
It was a medical monitoring device is my understanding to monitor things like blood sugar and body temperature and things like that.
Why you?
Is it just like this thing that it's like if we go to the zoo, we tag the animals sort of thing?
It's kind of like that, except that they do this to only bloodlines that they're interested in, and they have an MO where they abduct pregnant women from bloodlines they're interested in and genetically modify the fetus.
What determines which bloodlines they might be interested in?
I'm not sure.
That would be a closely guarded secret on their side, but mainly they're interested in Germanic, Celtic, and Native American people.
There are exceptions, but they're looking for some sort of genetic combination that those particular races have in more abundance.
Mm-hmm.
Fascinating.
Okay, so you have this, anything else, by the way?
I feel like with experiences, I'm always like, damn, I should have asked that one more thing about what the being said.
Was there anything else you can recall?
About them telling me?
Yeah, anything they told you.
Well, the part about them being an alliance of seven different races coming from planets within 100 light years of year, I remember that pretty distinctly.
Oh, and they also told me that the Earth is a very important planet to a lot of races, and that planets that have some life are pretty common, but planets that are teeming with life like this are not common at all.
He said there's only four or five like it in the galaxy, and so they want to preserve life on the planet, and they are worried we're going to screw it up.
Yeah, that seems to be a common theme among experiencers as far as what gets relayed.
Oh, and they told me that there's pyramids all over the galaxy.
There are evidently power sources and sources of healing rather than tombs.
You know, it's funny you say this.
I feel like 20 years ago in conventional archaeological circles, they would have said that that's totally quacky.
And now you have people like Christopher Dunn, who's, you know, I don't know if you're familiar with this guy.
He's like a former aerospace guy.
I've heard of him.
He's coming out saying, you know, that it looks like the pyramid is some sort of power plant.
And now we actually have synthetic aperture radar scans underneath the pyramids where it looks like there might be these sort of coiling columns, these hollow tubes that go down possibly a kilometer deep.
So you have increasing speculation.
We know that there have never been any tombs found in these structures.
And we were just talking earlier that below Dandera, you actually have hieroglyphics that translate to stargate.
The Egyptians talk about stargates.
Do they?
Do.
Go to, where is it?
Dandera.
There's actually a couple places.
The literal translation, you can read it on the walls.
I always show people when we go there.
It is, there are two or three depictions of stargates.
That is the literal translation for it.
We know there are actually little chambers where a human could probably lie in and, you know, some of these, I think in the Great Pyramid.
Yeah.
That sarcophagus they called it in the Queen's Chamber is probably a healing device.
I have a theory where gravity is not a pulling force, but a pushing force.
If you're accelerating through space, you experience inertia.
If space is accelerating towards you, you experience gravity.
And zero-point energy is turned into real energy in the cores of planets and stars, and that creates a partial vacuum in the ether that causes the ether to accelerate towards that gravitating body, and that creates gravity.
So you, I mean, this is, there's so many different threads I want to, yeah.
It's like the, you know, the movie Stargate, literally with Kurt Russell, you know, the Air Force actually consulted on that.
Yeah.
And it's like, it's this portal or something, and then it would explain the astronomical alignment, the idea that all the ancient civilizations thought that the soul's actually, the soul moved through Orion's belt, which it seems, you know, aligned with.
But there are some interesting questions I feel like I have to press on that arise from what you just said.
The ether, you know, they say was disproved in the 1890s with the Michelson-Morley experiment.
It wasn't disproved.
Even Einstein said in his later lectures that there could be an ether, although it would have to be multidimensional and have strange properties.
Well, that's the case.
I mean, the ether, I believe they told me this too, but other people have come up with this theory that the ether is composed of tiny particles that are on the order of the Planck mass and the Planck dimensions.
They're like 10 to the 20th time smaller than an atomic nucleus, and they have a magnetic and electric dipole moment and interact with each other much more strongly than they interact with ordinary matter.
And matter going through it without accelerating does not experience a force because it acts like it's super fluid.
But when it's accelerating, there's an electromagnetic drag force that they call the people that believe in this theory called the Rindler flux, which causes inertia.
And you can actually derive Newton's second law by assuming a spatial structure of that nature.
Interesting.
Yeah.
Whoa.
Who's like developed this theory?
I, several, several, uh, physicists, uh, I don't recall their names I found, but I can look it up for you.
Yeah.
I'd love to, you know, you're right that, um, later Einstein said general relativity is not actually incompatible with the ether.
Right.
So that is an important, and then I would also say about the Michelson-Morley experiment, you know, the absence of evidence is not the evidence of absence.
Yeah.
And so we, we, we just don't know, you know, but I do think, yeah, that's this kind of hotly debated, contested thing.
So it's a very interesting theory, but.
In the Michelson-Morley experiment, uh, the ether is probably being dragged by the instrument itself.
That might account for the results, uh, of, uh, no, uh, observable, um, uh, ether movement.
But, um, there was another guy named Milliken, I believe his name was, um, that actually did come up with some positive results for, uh, motion through the ether.
That's interesting.
I didn't know that about Robert.
Robert Milliken was at Caltech and, uh, Townsend Brown actually studied under him.
And, uh, then they kind of got into it because Milliken didn't really believe in Brown's stuff.
Ironically, Brown believed what you said, which is that gravity is more of a push than a pull.
And so you're saying, cause Milliken did a lot of the experimental proving of the Einstein's photoelectric effect from 1905.
Yeah.
But I didn't know that he had something to do with the ether and detecting the ether.
That's fascinating.
Yeah.
He said he detected it and he was a pretty high powered, uh, physicist.
Really?
Yeah.
Oh, wow.
He didn't detect it directly, but he detected, um, Earth's motion through the ether by an experiment on Mount Wilson, I believe it was.
Wow.
Fascinating.
We'll have to look into that.
Um, you know, it's, it's interesting.
We talk, we take so many things for granted that we've never detected like dark matter and the, but the ether is like completely like we're not allowed to talk about it.
It's like a dirty word or something.
I don't, I don't think I believe in dark matter after 50 years of experimentation, there's no evidence for it at all.
So, and you don't, you don't really even need dark matter to explain the results.
The reason they postulated dark matter in the first place is because, um, the, uh, of the motion of the galaxies, um, they, they behave as though, um, there's, uh, either gravity is acting as, uh, an inverse linear force at those distances, or, um, there's, um, uh, a halo of, uh, massive, uh, matter above and below the galaxy.
Well, um, the, um, uh, postulating that gravity is an inverse linear force at those distances is actually a simpler explanation than postulating some unknown form of matter.
Yeah, I think you're right because dark, I would bet against dark matter and dark energy, but dark energy is not one of the four fundamental forces.
It's this sort of, you know, just.
I think dark energy is a zero point energy.
That's what's causing the earth or the universe to expand, uh, more rapidly rather than it's supposed to be slowing down according to Einstein.
But, uh, dark energy, AKA, um, uh, zero point energy is causing the expansion to accelerate.
It's fascinating.
Quantum vacuum fluctuations.
Right.
Yeah, I mean, okay, we could have a whole other discussion on physics.
I want to stick with that.
So you, you experienced this kind of profound thing.
You end up with this, you know, um, implant in your toe.
So you don't know what's happened at that point because you haven't gotten a hypnotic regression.
Is that point?
Yeah, I didn't, I didn't know.
I didn't remember what happened.
I just, I woke up and I knew that I had an implant in my toe.
The aliens had been there in the middle of the night and I had, uh, one, one more on the side of my head.
Really?
You had my, my, my head kind of hurt right there.
Whoa.
And, uh, that shows up in a stud finder.
Okay.
Wow.
And then you get in touch with Roger Lear?
Yeah.
And you email him?
Um, I just went to his office.
Okay.
You just showed up.
Dad has made an appointment and, and went over there and, and, um, told him I had a possible foreign object in my toe.
And in the middle of the appointment, I, uh, told him that, uh, it was, uh, it was a possible alien implant or an abduction related.
And, um, no, excuse me.
I don't think he believed me at, at first, but, um, uh, he gave me a prescription to get it x-rayed.
And, um, I, he, he said to give a copy of the film to the patient.
And I definitely saw something on the x-ray and that was wild.
That is extremely wild.
What did it look like?
Well, I could tell people too that there's a heck of a difference between, uh, strongly suspecting that something like this is going on with you, which I had for years and knowing for sure.
And proof like that, you know, for sure.
Yeah.
Um, but it looked like, it looked like a piece of, uh, bent piece of wire on, on the x-ray and it was, um, it was, uh, larger, uh, in real life when we took it out than it looked on the x-ray.
Wild.
Okay.
So you see this x-ray and then do you have a hypnotic regression and you remember the full experience with these alien beings?
Yeah, pretty much.
Yeah.
And is Roger Lear at that point kind of bought into the extraterrestrial or, or other entity, non-human hypothesis or does he think?
He was, he was excited.
Um, he wanted to come over and check out my house and we found all kinds of anomalies, uh, anomalous magnetic fields, um, leaves and the, uh, the trunk of the avocado tree had become magnetized.
Um, and, uh, in the kitchen, uh, stainless steel knives had become magnetized and the wood of the cabinets and all kinds of stuff.
Wood seems to be very susceptible to magnetization by alien equipment.
Interesting.
I think it's normally it wouldn't be.
Right.
Yeah.
It's either a magnetic monopole or magnetic fields beyond a certain strength leave a residue.
Um, uh, magnetic monopoles make a certain amount of sense.
It would be a, um, it would be a ether that had a magnetic charge to it that would be absorbed into the material.
And it seems to, uh, decay away over a period of several weeks.
Mm.
And how many, uh, implants did Roger Lear remove?
He removed a total of, I believe, 17 from, uh, 17 different people.
Wow.
And how many have you removed?
Um, I, I haven't removed any.
I don't have a license to operate on.
Okay.
But you sort of look into this stuff yourself.
I, I, I attended, I attended the last three removal surgeries, including my own.
Okay.
Yeah.
And how many have you seen?
Like firsthand?
Oh, I've seen probably six or seven.
Wow.
And, uh, does any of part of you or does any part of, you know, from your conversations with Roger Lear think that this could have been human tech?
Um, no, uh, most of them did not look like human tech at all to us.
And there was reason to believe that, that, uh, the materials came from, uh, not only from space, but from other parts of our galaxy.
But, um, we did find, uh, or he did find one or two that looked like human tech that looked like just standard microchips.
Whoa.
And so, so it's such a crazy territory to kind of operate in or think about.
So you think there are maybe a couple that represent, I mean, what would those microchips have come from?
Well, the government's experimenting with implants too, but they're, they're much less sophisticated than the ones the aliens use.
Right.
And they're much bigger.
Yeah.
And, and that would make sense.
I mean, the, I mean, yeah, the government has had like sort of mind control programs.
Oh yeah.
You know, MKUltra sort of stuff.
Yeah.
And they probably have used chips and so, but these things are, they have, so they have isotope ratios that don't normally occur on earth that would cost millions of dollars to create in a centrifuge.
Right.
Um, any other sort of, uh, abnormalities or anomalies?
Well, I, I noticed that, uh, in, in three of the implants that, um, have the isotopic abnormalities, the, the heavier isotopes in those elements were overrepresented.
I, I talked to people who really did analyze the stuff from the real deal stuff and it's super weird.
It's like heavy element, um, you know, Europium, Californium stuff.
It's like in these atomic arrangements that make like no sense.
You know, this is through X-ray diffraction where they can image the shadows of the atomic pairs and stuff.
And it's like, why is all these crazy heavy elements in this like weird ceramic metal hull structure?
And it doesn't, we don't understand the emergent, uh, metamaterial property.
Right.
So it was either, it's either, either they come from closer to the center of the galaxy where there's a heavier supernova.
All these heavy elements are created in supernova explosions where there's a massive cascade of neutrons in one part of the explosion.
Um, and rapid neutron capture creates these, uh, elements heavier than iron.
And, um, uh, it's, so it's either, either that or the elements had been exposed to, uh, a massive, uh, quantity of, uh, of neutrons.
Um, um, either way, it's very, uh, very strange and most likely, um, way beyond human technology.
Yeah.
And a lot of neutrons would be outside the Van Allen radiation belt or something, you know, a lot of.
Or in a, in a reactor or a zero point energy, uh, uh, uh, energy generator.
Also then the, the no immune reaction, it's like neuro, you think of Elon Musk as the tip of the spear with technology and, you know, he had all these issues with the, you know, electrode implants in people's brains where there would be immune reactions.
Even to this day, I believe Nolan Arbaugh, the first patient, I think might need some like tweaking after like the first thing worked because of this sort of immune reaction issue.
Oh yeah.
Dr. Lear told me that, um, um, any foreign object in the body produces an immune, an immune reaction.
Silicone produces the least immune reaction of all substances known, but even that produces, uh, a fair amount, um, as a lot of women that got, uh, silicone breast implants could testify.
But, uh, these produce none whatsoever.
It's just very beyond strange.
Do you notice commonalities in behavioral patterns changing from some of these patients?
Um, it's hard.
I think there are some changes, but it's, they're hard to, to notice.
I know that when I had, uh, my toe implant, it was like very subtle, but it was like, uh, there was some sort of a, of a governor put in my thoughts or, uh, and I felt more free once it was removed.
But it's, it's, but it was very subtle.
Whoa.
And, um, people were telling me that I, I didn't look well, that I had a gray complexion or something when I had the implant.
Really?
Yeah.
So it affected you in sort of a negative way?
Apparently, yeah.
Why do you think, ah, it's so strange.
Ideally, you know, the alien tech or whatever would, you know, be so, so, you know, if it's not creating an immune reaction, it wouldn't, you know, suppress your thoughts in any sort of negative way.
Well, maybe, maybe, maybe what they told me about it being a monitoring device was just a cover story.
Maybe they were trying to produce some changes or something.
Hmm.
It's fascinating.
But, um, they, um, um, they definitely, um, were hesitant to put it in because they knew it'd start an investigation.
And, uh, I, I suspected that I was an experiencer for a year that had missing time experiences and had, uh, no other way to account for them.
But, um, it's kind of easier to be, easy to be in denial if you don't have any real concrete proof.
It's a wild conversation for me because you seem like a very smart guy.
And then a lot of these things are just so, so out there.
Do you, did, um.
I mean, I, I wouldn't even entertain, I'm a scientist.
I wouldn't even entertain a lot of this stuff if I didn't have proof.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
No, it's, uh, you're, you're backing up all your claims.
So it's, it's really amazing.
Um, Dr. Roger Lear, did you find him to be, you know, fully kind of bought into the kind of non-human hypothesis as the origin?
Oh, yeah, he was fully, uh, fully bought into the, um, uh, extraterrestrial hypothesis.
And he said it was 17 or 18 implants that he removed to?
17, I believe, yeah.
17.
And, um, and he had no background in this.
He was just a podiatrist and.
Yeah, he thought it was ridiculous at first too, but, um.
Did he stumble upon a, like there was one of his patients or something and he pulled it out?
Yeah, he went to, he went to, um, a convention, I think the UFO Congress and, um, he met, uh, Daryl Sims there who was, um, the original guy on the implants and, um, uh, he tried to convince Dr. Lear that it was worth looking into and Dr. Lear said, ah, you're full of, you're full of it and everything.
And, uh, a friend, uh, another friend of Dr. Lear's, uh, convinced him to go take another look.
And he, he went back and told Sims that, that, um, you know, if you can get some patients out here that have these things, um, I'll x-ray them and take the object out if it's there.
And we'll find out what it is.
Did Lear ever try to write an academic paper on any of this stuff?
Yeah, he, he and I tried to write a paper and we tried to publish it in the Journal of Scientific Exploration.
And, um, they, um, first they, first they said they were excited to have it.
Then I think somebody got to him and they said that, um, it was ridiculous.
They didn't want to publish it.
And, um, we weren't even saying it was alien.
We just said it was an unknown object recovered from.
Right.
From somebody's, uh, somebody's leg.
And, um, um, they, um, they really, uh, gave us a hard time about it.
And, um, I, I, I'm pretty sure that somebody told him not to publish it.
That's so crazy.
It's like, yeah, cause it's funny.
You can go on chat GPT and they say, Roger Lear has no academically, you know, uh, peer reviewed papers or whatever.
It's like, you tried.
Yeah, we did try.
And it's, it's funny.
I think you always have to sanitize the results and just say, no, we found something anomalous.
Like we don't, we don't, we're not even jumping to conclusions, but even then, sometimes there's this sort of antibody rejection of a lot of these findings.
There's a friend of mine, Beatrice Villareal.
She's a, an astronomer, um, from Stockholm university.
Um, and she's a PhD out there.
And she, uh, uh, basically from the, the Palomar observatory, uh, which was, you know, one of the most prominent, uh, you know, observatories in use in the, in the forties and fifties.
Uh, she noticed all sorts of, uh, these, what look like essentially UFO like objects, these, these light reflecting objects that look like kind of mirrors.
In orbit.
Yeah.
And geo.
They, they, they, they recruited Clyde Tombaugh, the discoverer of Pluto to investigate those too.
That's fascinating.
So there's a history of looking into these geosynchronous, uh, uh, objects that seem to exist in the, the, the, the, the tens of thousands.
And he wrote, he wrote an article, Tombaugh wrote an article, uh, saying that earth had, um, some, uh, smaller moons orbiting at about 500 miles up.
And, um, I know from my own experiences that, that, uh, gray mother ships orbited about that altitude and they launched the smaller UFOs that actually go out and sortie to abduct people and such.
So fascinating.
Cause the other, the other thing is, you know, I go back and forth on the moon landing stuff where I, if I'm, if I'm debating with the skeptic on the moon landing, it's like, I'm, I'm extremely open to us having actually landed on the moon, but there's something's off about the whole story.
Something is off.
Well, they're, they're concealing a lot.
There's a lot up there.
They don't want people to see that.
So it's like, maybe they saw something along the way, you know?
Yeah.
And, um, and there's interesting, uh, that you should mention the moon stuff.
Um, I found out, um, that, um, Apollo 13 may not have failed by a mechanical problem.
It may have been zapped by the aliens cause they may have had a nuclear warhead on board.
What?
Yeah.
How did you find that out?
Well, I, I, I, I can't prove it, but, uh, it was the next logical step in their seismic, uh, program where, um, Apollo 11 put a seismograph on the moon.
Yep.
And so did Apollo 12.
And it rang like a bell.
On Apollo 12, they crashed the ascend stage of the lunar module into the moon and it rang like a bell for hours.
Then, um, uh, on Apollo 13, when they were approaching the moon, they, they crashed the third stage of the Saturn five into the moon and made a bigger bang and rang like a bell for even longer.
And, um, um, so if Apollo 13 had landed on the moon, they would have had three seismographs and would have been able to probably map the interior of the moon a little bit, um, uh, with, uh, the seismic waves that would be generated, um, by another event.
And then the, the, the next logical step would have been to, um, put a remote detonated, uh, small nuclear device on the moon and detonated after the astronauts leave.
So, um, uh, so, but you, you're, you're just hypothesizing that you have no evidence.
I have, I have no real evidence, but one thing that made me really suspicious that this might be true is that, um, I remember when I was a kid, uh, following this mission and, um, uh, when the lunar module was coming back to earth, the, uh, atomic, the atomic energy commission would just going ape over this.
And, uh, they wanted the lunar module, um, uh, put on a trajectory that would put it into a deep ocean trench.
And their level of concern was, they said it was because it had a radioisotope thermoelectric generator on board, but their, their level of concern was a lot more consistent with it being a warhead.
Whoa, that's fascinating.
So they were that freaked out.
Yeah, even though it might endanger the astronauts' lives to do that, they wanted that thing crashed into a deep ocean trench.
And, uh, they've had, uh, RTGs on spacecraft before that have re-entered that they weren't that concerned about.
It's really interesting.
Yeah.
It's funny.
You know, there's a, actually an air force project that's documented called project A119.
And it was literally to nuke the moon as a show force against the Soviets.
And Carl Sagan actually had a temporary clearance.
Yeah, I remember that.
It's a look to look into doing this.
So we know that in the late fifties, obviously before the Saturn and Apollo projects, that this was being considered.
So who knows?
I mean, you might be right, man.
It's really interesting.
Well, I know that, I know that if, um, if there were no aliens on the moon or anything else like that to worry about, I think, I think the greys own the moon, by the way.
And they told us not to come back, uh, without permission anyway.
And, uh, that's.
Do you think they said don't come back without permission?
Well, Armstrong, Armstrong was overheard at a party saying that.
Really?
Yeah.
What party?
Uh, some party in Washington, D.C. with big wigs and several people said that, that he said that, but.
And he said that the greys said.
That's hearsay, but.
The greys said, don't come back.
Yeah.
Until we give you permission.
Something to that effect.
Any other details there?
Um, uh, well, um, some people at NASA, some whistleblowers at NASA said that, um, that he was on a private channel after landing on the moon.
Um, and, um, and, um, said that, uh, that, uh, uh, spacecraft landed on the moon right after they did a few miles, a couple miles away and were watching him.
And, um, um, um, it was probably the same one that they said they saw following him.
Um, uh, the, the whole, uh, Apollo 11 crew, um, said a few years ago on, on television that, uh, that there was some object following him to the moon that they thought it was the third stage of their, of their booster at first.
But NASA confirmed that it, that, that the booster was like 700 miles away.
And this, this object was maybe only about five or 10 miles from them.
Jesus Christ.
And you have, you definitely have documented audio from the Gemini missions, um, them free.
And then there's a literally like, they're freaking out about, um, UFOs.
There's an outage, you know, showing some sort of electromagnetic anomaly present.
And then in the, they have this, um, book, actually the Simpkinson, uh, textbook that shout out to my buddy, Chris Ramsey from the great show area 52.
He, uh, made me aware of this book where this UFO is like airbrushed into the photo for the Gemini 11 mission, where it's this like kind of tongue in cheek joke.
If you're, you know, this is official NASA archivist airbrushed this UFO, which looks like the best UFO photo ever.
Well, the astronauts used to admit to it, uh, long ago before the security was that tight.
And, um, um, and, um, I think they were seeing these things, uh, almost every mission in the early days.
So wild.
How many people do you think are walking around with alien implants inside of them?
Well, the people that they implant, uh, they, they've, they've abducted about 3% of the, uh, American population, uh, according to Dr. Lear.
I think that's about right.
It's probably between three and 5% to take samples.
What is he basing that off of?
Is this like sort of, uh, census style, like extrapolation?
His own research and extrapolation.
Okay.
And, um, uh, based on what I have seen, um, most, uh, most, what I call class two experiencers that are actually at the next level, part of the alien program, um, have implants, but the, the first class where they just take samples from do not generally.
And, um, uh, about, um, I would say a very roughly about one in a thousand people are class two experiencers in this, in this country.
And it's, it might be similar worldwide.
I'm not sure.
Um, so if that's the case, then say there's 350 million people in the, um, in the U S, uh, that, that'd be about, uh, 350,000 people.
It's a lot of people walking around with implants.
Yeah, that's right.
Yeah.
It's like 10, 10 to 15 million for experiencers overall.
And then class two experiencers who get the implants around a few hundred thousand.
And it's a standard procedure for, for them to put, uh, a brain implant into class two experiencers that enables them to, um, access your sensory information to, uh, see what you're seeing and hear what you're hearing and probably hear what you're thinking in real time.
So you're like an, almost an avatar or something like there, you're this perceptual like drone for them or something.
It turns you into a walking bug and it connects you to the gray hive mind.
And they told me that too.
And, uh, all, all individuals in their society are connected to a hive mind, kind of like the Borg on Star Trek, but they have a little bit more individuality than that.
And, um, um, every experience they have is recorded.
And, um, um, uh, they, um, so if, if all these people are implanted, um, then they presumably only put, um, the brain implants into people that they can get.
You can get some good information from.
So being that that's the case, they probably know everything that's going on in the society.
We have Eric Mitchell here who, um, we did an amazing show with yesterday and he's, you know, what you might call kind of a super experiencer.
You guys are friends.
You found a few different implants and Eric, is that, is that right?
Or.
I don't remember what the results were offhand.
Um, my records, uh, got stolen recently, but, um, I'd like to do the, the exam again.
Uh, but yeah, I saw some indications of implants and, and Eric and, uh, we found some dyes on them recently, alien dyes.
We haven't talked about that yet.
So before we get to the dyes, the implants, what are, what are we calling indicators of implants?
Um, well, I have a protocol that, um, uh, is, uh, mostly Dr. Lear's protocol that he, that he, uh, turned me on to.
And, um, you, um, first, uh, inspect, uh, the patient with a, um, a stud finder, a small metal detector that detects conductive objects into the skin and concentrate on any, any areas of concern first, um, where they think they might have an implant from anything they remember, um, or any symptoms they might've had.
And, um, um, um, if, if you record the areas where you get stud finder hits, then go over, uh, uh, the person with, um, a gauss meter, uh, a sensitive, uh, magnetometer.
And if you get, um, if you get, uh, an area that has, uh, a stud finder and a gauss meter hit, um, that's almost certainly an implant because these, these implants, uh, almost always have magnetic fields.
So have you had a stud finder and, uh, magnetometer, you know, this gauss finder, uh, hit for Eric?
I think we had a, I think we had two.
Eric, do you remember where exactly they detected one of these implants?
Uh, back to my neck, um, my arm and Dr.
Lear, uh, he thought maybe the wife might be one in my knee.
It was like a weak signal.
So he sent me a hundred pound Neo, gave me a magnet, which, uh, I should have been very careful opening that box a little more.
Like, uh, you know, it was like a cartoon.
There was probably dangerous.
Yeah, it was dangerous.
Um, but he wanted me to, um, hold it to my name, maybe 10 minutes a day, you know, watching TV or something like that, put it back in the bubble wrap, make sure it's safe, and then pull it back out the next night and keep doing that.
And he didn't think that it would pull, uh, it to the surface.
He, he theorized that it would create like an eddy bubble and eddy effect to kind of loosen it from the tissue and bring it, you know, to the surface, which actually worked.
And so do you have any, uh, like incisions or marks or like, you know, any sort of raised skin where either of these implants are?
Okay.
Have you removed anything?
No.
Okay.
Two weeks before I was supposed to meet with Dr.
Roger Lear, uh, in, um, uh, Eureka Springs, Arkansas, he, uh, unfortunately passed away.
Um, yeah, the, um, the portals of entry with these implants, uh, uh, heal incredibly fast.
Um, mine healed within hours.
So, whoa, you, um, yeah, you're not going to find anything like that.
How many implants do you have like photo evidence of?
Um, six or seven, I think.
Could you send some of those over?
It'd be cool to show them to the audience in post-production.
Sure.
Yeah.
Sweet.
Thank you.
And, um, yeah.
So what are you working on now?
What is, what is, is it Neutron Nano Star Tech?
Yeah, I have a company called Neutron Star Technologies.
And, um, uh, Neutron Star Nano Technologies is, uh, I guess, a spinoff of that.
And, um, I've been, um, um, just, um, trying to get that funded and, um, utilize some of the carbon nanotube knowledge I have to maybe produce some products.
And I've been doing scans on, um, uh, and I've done probably 400 scans on, uh, on people.
And, uh.
So of those 400 scans, how many produce a hit?
Um, well, it's, it's a pre-selected audience, so, um, probably about half.
About half.
Wow.
Wild.
Yeah.
Interesting.
And at this point, are you sort of, you're known as like, you know, Roger Lear's, you know, living apprentice.
And so people hit you up.
Yeah.
Sometimes, yeah.
Okay.
So fascinating.
What, what, how old were you when you had your experience?
Uh, I remember having experience at age five where, um, I think that's when they put the brain implant in, uh, where I remember, um, um, waking up, uh, before dawn and seeing, uh, a bright yellow, um, lit up UFO, um, disc-shaped UFO hovering over my parents' house.
Um, and, um, then I, I watched it for a couple of minutes and blacked out, then, uh, woke up about, uh, eight o'clock in the morning and the sun was up and, um, I, um, had blood all down the front of me and, uh, had a vague memory of somebody putting something up, something up my nose.
Jesus.
And this was, so this was age five.
This is well before the toe experience.
Yeah.
And where are you living at the time?
Oxnard, California.
Okay.
What did your parents do?
Um, not much.
They just, uh, slowly had a nosebleed and I was.
Wow.
I mean, what did they do professionally?
My dad was a dentist, um, and, um, was, uh, a colonel in the Army Reserve.
And, uh, my, my mother was, uh, uh, his assistant at one point, uh, and, uh, bookkeeper at one point and was, uh, housewife the rest of the time.
And they, they, did they freak out when they saw you with blood running down or what was their reaction?
Not really.
I mean, um, uh, my parents were, um, not the type that freaked out about that sort of thing.
Interesting.
Um, that might be, uh, because of alien conditioning.
I, I would.
Did they have their own experiences?
Uh, my father admitted much later that, uh, he had, he'd had, uh, dreams of being on board a UFO.
And he said he, he said he saw a UFO, uh, one time over, um, central California.
Wow.
A cylindrical UFO with a red light on the front, he said.
Um, as a, as a, um, colonel in the reserves, did he have any sort of affiliation with any possible reverse engineering programs or like deeper, spookier?
I don't, I don't, I don't, I don't think so, but I think there was a lot of, he, he was, uh, reluctant to tell me.
And, um, he said he did call, um, the, um, uh, military, uh, the nearest military airfield to, or he had the sighting and reported it.
Yeah.
It's fascinating.
And so, okay.
So, wow.
So you're five years old, you see this bright object.
Do you remember vividly being on that craft?
No, you don't.
Okay.
So you just wake up.
I think they came down into my room to put it in that time.
And you had, and you, where's the implant?
It's, it's, it's, what was it?
It's, it's in the brain.
It's in the brain.
It's in the frontal lobes of the brain.
And do you still have it there?
I'm sure I do.
Wild.
And, um, I've got one above each year.
Uh, apparently, um, uh, I wasn't sure about those.
I saw them on x-rayed barely, but they're really, really small.
Wow.
And, but they started giving off, they started giving off radio signals during a Japanese TV show I was, I was, uh, filming.
Oh my God.
What were you doing?
So I know they're there now.
What were you doing on Japanese TV?
Um, they wanted to interview somebody with implants.
Wow.
And you, since you had, you, you're five years old and you have blood all over and gee, that's traumatic, man.
That's like a tough, crazy thing to go through.
Well, uh, this experience is pretty traumatic for a lot of people.
Yeah.
Um, it's like there's certain advantages to it.
Um, uh, you get to fly in space.
I mean, a lot of these abductions are, take place on great mother ships in orbit.
Yeah.
Um, and, uh, I remember, I remember seeing the earth from space, uh, being up there and, um, but, um, used to have to take the, the bad with the good.
I mean, I hate to tell people, um, this, but these people are way too powerful to fight.
Yeah.
Um, and they're experts at mind control.
They can make you do anything you want, anything they want you to do willingly.
Of the, that's a, I don't even know how to answer to, to, to talk about that in the, in the 200 out of the 400 that you personally found implants in.
Um, do these people have usually UFO experiences associated with the implants or in certain cases are, is it like people coming into their room sort of thing?
Uh, they usually remember, um, seeing UFOs and, or remember being on, on board UFOs, but, um, it's both.
I mean, sometimes they come into your room and, uh, do whatever they need to do.
And other times, um, they come and get you and take you up, up to orbit.
And if they want to do anything special or whatever.
Do you think at any point in time, some of the mind control stuff we discussed earlier, uh, was like aliens were used as sort of some sort of smoke screen for that?
Like it was like, uh, there's a book called, uh, controllers by a guy named Martin Cannon, and he talks about MK ultra, but then the air MK often and how there are implants involved in some of these things and how they would shade people's experiences to make them think that they were alien.
And to be honest, it's kind of a slim, poorly researched book that doesn't, for me, explain everything neatly at all.
But, uh, yeah, what's your, what's your take?
I think that that may occur.
I think that MK ultra might, might do that sometimes, but I think that the vast majority of the, um, experiences people have are, uh, more or less what happened and really are aliens.
Um, I, I have no doubt in my mind that, that the aliens are here and they exist and there's more than one species involved.
Yeah.
I mean, there's so many cases that I also encounter where I'm like, you can just can't explain that with, with, you know, human prosaic tech.
Like, I do find it interesting.
You were at, you were at UCLA in the eighties.
Yeah.
You know, who was head of the, uh, UCLA psychiatry department at that time.
Are you aware?
Um, I probably was, but.
This guy named Jolly West.
Did you ever interact with him at all?
No, no.
He was like a head honcho in the MK ultra stuff.
Wow.
Yeah.
I'm not surprised.
Um, I did used to work at the UCLA Neuropsychiatric Institute as a researcher for about five years.
Okay.
I, I, he probably had authority over that, uh, that branch of it.
He might've.
Yeah.
I don't know, but definitely a spooky, not great guy.
I think he got in trouble for like dosing up an elephant with ridiculous amount of LSD.
And then the elephant died and he's on record, uh, there are letters between him and Sidney Gottlieb and he, he, there's a great book called chaos by a guy named Tom O'Neill.
He's become a friend of mine.
And he basically has this hypothesis that Charles Manson was this MK ultra patient.
And it's a really crazy.
He may have been.
I think, I think that, um, that that guy that, um, shot, uh, um, um, John Lennon was, uh.
Yeah.
I'm okay.
MK ultra guy.
And I think, I think Sirhan Sirhan that shot Robert Kennedy was too.
I think so as well.
Yeah.
So that's this, it's a weird threat, but so there's that stuff.
And then the, do you think, what do you think these, the, the implants are doing when it comes to the alien?
You think it's just, it's just tagging it's biometrics and, and then maybe there's some mind control stuff going on.
It's perceptual hacking.
I don't know.
I don't know all the details of what they do.
Um, um, they keep that, the aliens keep that, uh, mostly secret, but I think some of them are medical monitoring devices.
Some of them are tracking devices.
Um, and, uh, some are, um, the brain implants actually enable them to, uh, hear and see what you're hearing and seeing, seeing in real time.
Um, does, um, does, um, any of the structure that you've investigated, um, kind of allow you to see what the functionality might be?
Like, cause you're, you're, you're looking into, you know, nanotechnology.
So presumably this would use nanotechnology.
They do.
Yeah.
They're, they're sophisticated nanotechnological devices.
Um, most of them have carbon nanotube electronics built into the metal and that's beyond our technology.
Hmm.
Um, and, uh, there's strange structures.
I can show you, uh, some of the electron micrographs, uh.
Please.
And, um, there's very strange structures that, um, would be beyond our technology to form right now.
Uh, I'm not sure what they do, but I suspect that has something to do with, uh, uh, emitting the radio signals.
Of a lot of these people you encounter, um, is it usually greys?
Is it sometimes Nordics or reptilians or some of these other sort of archetypes?
Um, I remember seeing, um, mostly, uh, different types of greys, um, on board, uh, on board the craft, uh, the, the real short worker type greys.
And, uh, the ones about four and a half feet tall that I call the scientist engineer types.
And, uh, uh, I have a handler that's one of those.
And, um, I think most, most class two experiences have a handler.
What's it, what do you, when you say handler, what does that mean?
Um, a contact person that, that is in charge of your case on board ship.
Whoa.
So a being.
Yeah.
Being, yeah.
And how do you, like, are you still telepathically in touch with that handler or something or?
Uh, I have reason to believe I am.
I mean, I think he's here in, here in this whole conversation right now.
Whoa.
Um, what's up handler?
Uh, and, uh, uh, they record, um, everything that, uh, is experienced by every member of
their society.
And that includes class two experiencers.
Uh, when you get the brain implant, it connects you to the great hive mind.
Like I said, this is wild.
Does it, does any part of you think that humans discovered, you know, there's this, I think
in, um, early two thousands, there was this concern of the like runaway gray goo nanotech,
you know, scenarios and nanotech was all the rage in the early two thousands.
And then it's sort of like went away.
And does any part of you think that humans can do any of this stuff like in deep black
contexts?
I think that, that nanotechnology is not that dangerous as long as you don't design some,
uh, some microprobe that's self-replicating.
Right.
Um, and, but, um.
Yeah, that was the gray goo scenario.
Even if, even if you did, I'm not sure it would be all that dangerous, but, um, I think what
is dangerous is AI.
If they ever do develop true self-aware AI, I think that would be extraordinarily dangerous.
Yeah.
Seems like.
The aliens don't believe in it.
So I think that's why.
They, they believe in computers, but they've, they're, they're controlled by, um, by minds.
Do you think there are good and bad factions of aliens, or do you think they're all good
or all bad or?
No, I think there's good and bad factions.
Um.
The beings that implanted you think good or bad or?
Hmm.
They're mainly out for themselves.
Um, but they're not all, they're not scum sucking evil either.
I mean, they, they, they want, um, humanity to mature into a peaceful, more peaceful species
and become members of the galactic, uh, federation or whatever you want to call it.
And, but they're mostly here to, um, mine the earth and the moon and collect biological
samples.
I mean, that, that seems reasonable and not, not bad.
Um, what do you think of modern?
But they don't, they don't care about the suffering they inflict on people.
That's, that's one bad thing about them.
Hmm.
Um, they, they have, everything is for the group with them.
They're, they're a collective mind.
Um, they don't care about individuals.
They, they just care about what's best for the group.
Why do you think they care so much about nuclear?
They seem to show up.
Some of my favorite interviews have been these guys that are often in their seventies and
eighties at this point.
They worked at nuclear bases all over the U S and in certain cases they board crafts, they
have implants, you know, they're close encounters of the third kind.
And I guess what you're calling kind of type two, you know, abductions or something.
Yeah.
Um, yeah, I think a lot of, a lot of, a lot of top military people are implanted and keep,
the aliens keep tabs on them.
But, um, I think they don't want us having nukes because, um, A, it makes us too powerful.
B, it, um, it has the great potential to screw up the planet, screw up a lot of their, their
plans for this place and C, um, it, uh, can damage the planet's life force.
I've, I've reasonably, there's structures in the ether that, um, contribute to life on
this planet somehow.
And a nuclear blast could disrupt that at least in the general area where it was detonated.
And they, they said that also that it, it screws up their communications and, uh, leads to
problems in other dimensions that they didn't want to go into.
Yeah.
No, that, that is interesting about, like, they seem to show up at nuclear disaster.
Like there's this, literally this monk at this Shinto temple in, uh, Fukushima.
And when they had their 2011 famous nuclear spill due to the earthquake, he was like, the,
the UFO showed up and cleaned up the temple.
They were trying to alleviate the radiation.
Exactly.
There's a Harvard PhD named Jensen Andreessen who writes about basically a similar experience
in Chernobyl.
And they, they measured this like nuclear tower before and after.
And so I think it goes beyond just them not wanting us to blow ourselves up.
There's something about the ambient electromagnetic radiation of just the earth that is this perfect
kind of Petri dish, you know, biosphere.
Yeah.
That, that makes sense.
And there's, um, maybe the, maybe the earth is actually admitting some of this, but there's,
there's structures in the ether that, uh, are life giving and that might even resurrect
some extinct species at some point in the time.
And a nuclear blast could disrupt that and radiation in general can disrupt that.
And, um, also the government's known for years, um, the, the aliens definitely have this
technology and the government's known for years that, um, you know,
you can actually affect the decay rate of radioisotopes by certain, uh, scalar electromagnetic
waves.
Um, scalar waves are, are, are a special form of electromagnetic radiation that has a different
structure.
It's a more fundamental form of electromagnetic radiation than the transverse waves they talk
about in the textbooks.
And, um, it interacts with the nuclei rather than the electrons and atoms like transverse waves
do.
Explain what a scalar wave is because scalar physics and scalar waves are often thrown around
in these super hand wavy ways.
Right.
And yet they're often used as terms, you know, like extended electrodynamics, scalar waves
by people who I really respect and kind of aerospace world.
So what's your definition?
They're trying to keep it secret, but, um, enough has got out to know the basics.
Um, uh, a guy, Dr. Tom Bearden talked about this a lot in his books, if you've read any of
those.
Yeah.
And, um, anyway, a scalar wave, a transverse wave, EM wave is a, um, wave that, um, has the
E and the B fields perpendicular to each other.
And, um, the E and the B fields are in phase in a scalar wave, um, the electric and magnetic
fields are 90 degrees out of phase and, um, the magnetic field curves around like that.
And the electric field, um, radiates as if it's coming from a positive or negative charge
point and, um, it, uh, it's like a sound wave in the ether basically.
Um, and they can travel faster than light.
They're not restricted to light speed.
So I've heard similar things to that.
And then the two places I always get frustrated is I'm like, have we ever measured a scalar
wave?
And usually the answer, like, have we, do you think we have?
Uh, I think they have lots of times.
And how would we measure classified labs?
But I, I, I have reason to believe that I haven't done the experiments yet.
I'd love to, to get in the lab and do some, but, um, uh, I have reason to, I have reason
to believe that you, that you can generate scalar waves with, uh, standard radio equipment,
but a different type of antenna.
You'd use a, a, a dome shaped antenna, capacitive antenna with, um, say, um, say a plastic dome
with metal on both sides and you connect, uh, the, uh, electrodes of the, uh, of the oscillator
to, um, uh, each metal, metal piece.
Fascinating.
Okay.
And why do you think that that design would allow you to transmit scalar wave?
Um, uh, Townsend Brown's work basically.
Yeah.
Well, he had an asymmetric capacitor where the negative electrode was larger than the positive
electrode, but I think basically my sense is that the main thing is big electric field
differentials.
If you create big electric field differentials, then you can somehow harness the quantum vacuum
fluctuation stuff.
Yeah.
High voltage has worked better without, I have reason to believe.
I, I, I wish I could, uh, I wish I had some concrete proof for you, but, um, just reading
all this stuff that's available and thinking about it a lot and put this together.
Yeah.
Um, but yeah, I think high voltage, it should work better for that.
It's very interesting.
Yeah.
I mean, high voltages definitely correlate with high electric field strength and then
there are ways to amp up the electric field strength kind of artificially as well.
But, um, so fascinating.
So what are you trying, how do we advance on this topic now?
Is this, are we just in the stone age when we find these implants?
Are we just like, you know, we think this works like X, Y, Z, but we just have no idea
what we're kind of looking at or.
Well, I think the next step is we have to do more research.
Um, on the implants, excuse me, while they're still in the body and, um, try to, um, uh,
measure exactly how much they're transmitting and, um, uh, try to decode some of the signals.
And, uh, after they're removed from the body, I think we need to, um, we need to try to connect
the, to connect the, um, there's, uh, carbon nanotube bundles that are like the main connections
to the device.
We should try stimulating those with, with, uh, uh, different voltages and see what happens.
Mm.
Uh, under, uh, electron microscope or, or under microscopy in general, it wouldn't have to
be a EM for that, I guess.
Is there anybody else systematically looking into this besides you?
No.
And then the third thing I would do is, um, use fast atom bombardment to, uh, shave off,
uh, uh, the devices layer by layer and, um, map the, uh, distribution of elements in each
layer and the distribution of carbon nanotubes.
Mm.
That would be fascinating.
I mean, if you could do some atom by atom, you know, analysis, that would be also just
groundbreaking because if, if these things are fabricated on the atomic layer and then
that's not something that we can do.
Yeah.
They look like they're grown somehow.
That's so wild.
Like they're, like they're biological themselves or something.
Uh, or, or, or nanotechnological.
Like they look like they were grown by some sort of mechanical life.
Like the transformers on the, the movies.
Mm.
Um, uh, that's a hand waving thing, I guess, but that's the best I can do right now.
But, um, putting that, putting a device like that so complex together, uh, by, uh, standard
methods would be next to impossible, I think.
Mm.
And, um, um, the other thing I wanted to say is that, um, when I first got into this, I
thought the aliens are probably only a few hundred years in advance.
In advance of us technologically, but, um, now I think that, uh, it might be more like
a million years in advance of us.
Why is that?
Well, I've, they, they show off once in a while and, and, um, and, uh, show experiencers,
uh, exactly how far ahead of us they, they really are.
Um, um, one incident, uh, that, um, really impressed me, um, was that, um, they, um, zapped
my car with some kind of an energy weapon when I was, um, uh, going to Dr.
Lear's, uh, office to, um, uh, film, um, uh, him, um, testing the implant while it was still
in the body.
And, um, uh, the mechanic said later that the, the computer in the car was fried, like
it was exposed to EMP or something.
And, uh, so I had to walk like that.
They did it when, uh, I was in this cannon, didn't get any cell phone reception.
So I had to walk like two miles down the canyon to get cell phone reception and call him.
And, um, uh, he and the film crew showed up and, and picked me up and brought me to the
office.
And when we got to the office, he goes, Steve, you come here, you got to see this.
And, uh, he'd pulled my x-ray out of a stack of x-rays and, um, um, it was in a stack with
about 200 other x-rays.
And, um, he showed it to me and the lettering from the outside of the envelope that the x-ray
was in had somehow been transferred to the developed x-ray film.
Yeah.
I'm not even sure in theory how he could do that.
So that's like root access to reality levels of manipulation or something.
Something like that.
Um, and, um, another time, um, my son and I were, uh, driving to, uh, our old vacation
place in Bullhead City, Arizona, and we were on, uh, Highway 40 out in a remote area.
And, um, I saw this, uh, this bright white light hovering over this valley about five or
10 miles away.
And, and, uh, it was really bright.
And I go, hey, look, Garrett, there's a UFO.
And he goes, what?
I don't, I don't see anything.
And I'm like, how could you not see that?
It's like as bright as Venus.
And, um, so I was tripping out on that and go, well, you know, and, um, then, um, a few
miles down the road, uh, he started seeing ones that I couldn't see.
It's like they can, they can control who sees them, uh, and who doesn't.
Yeah.
I don't know how they do that either.
Not, not only signature management, but like unique signature management for the person
perceiving.
Yeah.
I have, I have some, some, uh, theories about, uh, how they might manage to cloak themselves
in general by various methods, but, um.
What do you think it is?
Selective, selective, uh, uh, seeing like that sounds, uh, a little hard to do.
That seems really hard to do.
Do you think, yeah, it's like the access to our brains and they have access to the signature
management stuff.
Do you think that we have reverse engineering programs and crash retrievals?
Oh yeah.
I think that's all true.
Yeah.
Do you have any, what's your like, you know, highest conviction, hardest evidence on that?
Cause you seem like an evidence-based person.
Um, well, I, I analyzed some of the, um, the records from the San Augustine, New Mexico
UFO crash and, uh, analyzed a piece of, um, an alien, uh, orb or sphere from, uh, that Jaime
and Masson got ahold of and, um, Was this the Bugha sphere or?
No, not the Bugha sphere, but the Bugha is a different, uh, different design, but, um,
uh, this one, um, was about, about this big round and it had, um, uh, large, um, vaporized,
uh, from the looks of it, um, holes in the, the, the north and the south poles of the sphere.
Um, the, the edges of the holes had been damaged by tremendous heat and, um,
uh, Masson bought it from a farmer that, um, uh, farmed about a hundred miles south
of the U.S., the U.S. border, um, near Brownsville, Texas on the, uh, uh, east coast of Mexico.
And, um, he said that when it crashed, um, it produced an explosion that killed a cow
a hundred meters away.
Whoa.
And, um, uh, if, if there was a strong magnetic field around the craft, which are, or, which
I have reason to believe there was, um, then, um, the collapse of the magnetic field is what
released the energy that, that vaporized the metal at the top and bottom.
Why do you think this whole topic, it's like, it attracts a few really smart people like yourself.
And then you have so much circumstantial evidence, like an abundance of circumstantial evidence.
And then somehow it's like the one smoking gun that we always want is slips through your
fingers.
And I, I'm talking about this as a person who's, um, deeply, my revealed preference
is that I'm like deeply interested in this stuff.
I think there's a there, there, I'm not a skeptic, but it's like this, like, it's always
like the hard drive goes missing at the end.
The photo is too, a little too blurry for like the consensus to believe it.
It's so frustrating.
It depends what you consider a smoking gun.
I think that these, um, uh, extremely, um, uh, skewed isotopic ratios might be considered
a smoking gun.
And, um, the fact that, um, a lot of these, uh, these pieces are nanotechnological devices
beyond our technology.
And, um, like that sphere was, um, a, uh, made of a titanium alloy that, um, had carbon
nanotubes also built into the metal, which I think provided thrust by the, the, the
Byfield Brown effect.
It did?
Yeah.
No, I think so.
I mean, I don't know what else could have made it fly.
Do you have this thing?
Um, not anymore.
It got stolen.
It got stolen?
Yeah.
Who stole it?
My family, if you can believe that.
Oh man, I'm sorry.
Yeah.
That's horrible.
Um, why they, they took it?
Yeah.
I, I still do have, uh, some other alien stuff, but, um, um, but, um, yeah, I, I can't find
it anymore and I have a reason to believe it was in some stuff that they stole.
Jesus Christ, man.
I'm so sorry.
That's messed up.
It's not cool.
No.
Do you have, is it, how does your family view?
I mean, your, your wife is here.
She's absolutely lovely and I can tell she's interested in this topic.
Like, do you have other family and what do they think of your interest in all this stuff?
Uh, well, my ex-wife is a, um, uh, Christian fundamentalist or says she is because of her,
her family's, uh, convictions.
And, um, uh, she's, uh, I think convinced my kids that, um, that I'm, uh, of the devil
or something along those lines.
Jesus.
I'm sorry.
And, uh, and my mother is kind of unstable and also is, uh, I kind of turned my kids
against me as well.
She's, she's afraid I'll embarrass her by going on, on the air, putting stuff on the
internet, things like that.
Well, I'm sorry, man.
I think your brain is a gift to humanity.
So, uh, and so we, we don't know where this object is that was taken from you.
No, I don't know.
Oh, damn.
That's crazy.
And then what about the, um, the piece from, uh, St. Augustine crash in New Mexico?
I still have, I still have some of that.
That's fascinating.
Yeah.
And have you done, you've done isotopic analysis on that and that has isotope ratios
that are weird or.
Um, the isotopic ratios on, on that, uh, were not, uh, that remarkable.
Um, uh, so that material may have, may have come from earth.
It may have some manufacturing facilities on earth too.
Um.
What, uh, material is it?
Like what element?
Uh, it's mainly aluminum.
Okay.
Um, the, the sphere was, uh, a titanium alloy that with carbon nanotubes built into the
metal and small, like half millimeter voids, uh, introduced into the metal to lower the
density.
So it had, uh, tremendous strength, um, and, uh, was stronger than most, any titanium alloy
I know of.
Um, but it was about the same density as aluminum.
And when you say Byfield Brown, you're just assuming that that's the anti-gravitational
force created through this.
Yeah, you could make capacitors out of the, um, the, the carbon nanotubes.
The carbon nanotubes had a capacitive dielectric coating on them in this case.
Mm.
So it seems a reasonable assumption.
So interesting.
And you could use that spherical shape, um, as a receiver for scalar energy.
Tesla was trying to do that, uh, uh, to power, uh, flying vehicles.
Did he have designs for flying?
Yeah, I know he had worked at Warden's.
I think he actually, I think he actually flew some, uh, as a rumor has it.
Really?
Yeah.
Where are those rumors?
I didn't know about that.
That's amazing.
Oh, um, there's, um, a book called Lost Science, I believe it's in there.
Hmm.
It's hard to get ahold of now.
Do you have any footage of the implant being taken out of any of these patients?
Um, I'm not sure if I, I, I may, I may have like one or two, uh, pieces like that.
I definitely have a lot of photos and stuff like that.
It'd be amazing to show as much as we can, just cause I think, uh, the average person,
this is so far out.
Yeah.
I mean, it's, it's way people don't believe it cause it's so far, uh, outside what we're
taught.
Yeah.
And, um, uh, the government's done their best to, um, punish people that believe in this
in various ways.
Yeah.
I, I feel like I have to ask this question, but I feel like it's important for you, uh,
cause you've seen like a very lovely person.
I've really enjoyed this conversation.
If you Google your name, uh, for whatever reason, this OKC bombing thing shows up.
And so I just want to give you an opportunity to address what that is.
A massive car bomb exploded outside of a large federal building in downtown Oklahoma City,
shattering that building, killing children, killing federal employees, military men, and
civilians.
Oh yeah.
Well, I got, I got in trouble with the feds, uh, 30 years ago on, um, a, uh, gun charge,
weapons charge.
And, um, uh, I, uh, got, uh, investigated along with 14,000 other people that were, uh, into
similar things at that time.
And, um, they, um, I, I, there's, I can figure the ATF was trying to punish me for not cooperating
in their investigation by trying to link me to that, that bombing.
Oh, they were just trying to link you to that.
Yeah.
They, they, they never, they, they, they, they.
And you didn't, you never knew Timothy McVeigh or anything like that?
No, they never had any proof of any of that.
That's so weird.
In fact, I found out from a guy that was writing a, that's writing a book on, uh, Oklahoma
City that I was cleared early on in the investigation, but they kept on saying that on the news that,
uh.
That sucks, man.
It almost makes me think there's some sort of campaign against you because like, why is there
so much online that's like.
I think there is.
I think they're, I think they're trying, I think they're, they're taking full advantage of that
whole thing to try to discredit my UFO research now.
Yeah.
And you never crossed paths with McVeigh at all.
You never even met.
No, I met, never met the guy.
That's so crazy.
And he, he didn't have a UCLA connection or anything like that.
No.
Okay.
That's weird, man.
I'm sorry.
Um, well, I, you know, if I wrote down everything that's occurred in my life in an autobiography,
I don't think anybody would believe it.
Yeah.
You know, so, but I experienced it.
So.
Yeah.
I mean, what, what's anything come to mind?
Well, just all, all this stuff.
And, you know, first, uh, they try to link me to this Oklahoma thing and then the aliens show up and, you know, just a very, um, very odd, uh, series of events.
Yeah.
And is there, is there anything about your, is there anything about your father, his history that might be related?
So he said at the end of his life, he sort of admitted that he was, you know, um, uh, maybe, you know, was taken up on a craft.
Do you think he was doing any sort of covert work in any of these areas or?
I, I'm not sure.
I, I don't think he was doing any covert work, but, um, he was, he was, uh, he kept things pretty close to his chest.
So, um, I think if he was, I'd be the last person he would have told.
Interesting.
Okay.
Yeah.
I don't know what would have even been going on at Oxnard specifically, but.
Well, there's a, there's a, um, military base there that, near there that was pretty important at one time, Point McGoo.
Okay.
Point McGoo.
What did they do at Point McGoo?
Uh, tested, uh, a lot of missiles.
Okay.
Uh, submarine launch missiles and air-to-air missiles mostly.
It's fascinating, man.
Well, I really hope you get all the support, uh, for your work.
You, you're trying to raise money for this, this, this company.
Is that right?
Uh, Neutron Star Nanotech.
The economy being so bad right now, I haven't had a whole lot of success, but, um,
I'm still, uh, hoping to, uh, get that, uh, off the ground.
Well, hopefully this gets amplified among people with deep pockets who are interested, I think, in supporting, you know, some of the most frontier science and work.
Oh, um, uh, uh, very, uh, wealthy people have come forward a couple of times and, uh, wanted to support my work, but it, it fell through.
And I, I had, had reason to believe at the time that, that, uh, the government told him not to do it.
Really?
Yeah.
Robert Bigelow was going to hire me for his company at one time, too.
And that, that also fell through.
What, why do you, what do you think it is, you know, with Bigelow and a lot of these guys, it's like, there's this desire to get into this stuff.
And you really want to know, and then things get like dark at a certain point.
Like it's, it's, it's sort of, it's, it's a very, and I find this, you know, uh, with my own inquiries into the topic where like, it's just, uh, it's hard to navigate.
Cause there's a lot of weird stuff, you know, it's, there's a lot, there are a lot of bad, there's a lot of bad energy.
And then there's, there's good energy too.
There are amazing people in this field, but a lot of people are attracted to it for the wrong reasons.
And there's, I think there's even like a, like an old Testament line about trying to use, trying to go into, you know, kind of sacred stuff using with a commercial impulse.
And that being like this really, you know, bad thing to do.
Having said that, I think we live in a capitalist system and like the only thing that kind of works in the modern day is like start a company around the thing.
So I'm not like anti all companies, you know, I used to invest in companies, so it's this weird, but it is this weird thing where I think if, if the motivation is to make money off the thing, it often goes south.
And I, I don't know Bigelow.
I'd love to interview him, but my, my sense is it sort of didn't pan out maybe in the way he wanted it to.
Well, Dr. Lear told me that, that he, he started this aerospace company of his, um, uh, because, uh, he had, uh, an alien experience of his own out in the desert and, um, that, um, uh, they told him to meet them in space.
Who, who said this?
This is.
The aliens told him.
This is Bigelow.
To meet them.
Bigelow.
They told Bigelow to meet them in space.
Whoa.
Really?
Yeah.
So Bigelow had an experience and the alien said, we'll meet you in space.
Right.
And then from then on, he like committed his life essentially to looking into all this stuff, UFO reverse engineering, hiring the alien implant specialist, like really?
On the Bigelow Aerospace, uh, website, there was a little alien, uh, head too.
Wow.
Kind of like he was announcing that or.
That is absolutely wild.
The amount of stories you hear like that, like, um, I think Agnew Bonson, who, uh, he headed up the Institute for Field Physics and, um, you know, uh, uh, at North Carolina Chapel Hill, and he also funded Townsend Brown.
So he was working on all this crazy anti-gravity stuff and hosting kind of the top gravity physicists in the world.
Freeman Dyson, Feynman, um, Peter Bergman, all these guys convened, John Wheeler at the Institute of Field Physics in 1957 for this Chapel Hill conference.
And he and his diaries talks about like the space brothers talking to him and possibly kind of prompting him to look into this stuff.
Townsend Brown had similar experiences where he, he had space brother experiences that he discusses.
So it's like you're being prompted by the beings to look into what their tech is or something.
They, they, they talked to Tesla too, according to what, to his writings.
He said that, yeah.
In Colorado Springs, he said he communicated with aliens.
Did you, um, ever have anything like that?
I mean, I have to ask you cause you're working on all this stuff.
Did the beings ever say, Steve, you are going to dedicate your life to alien research?
Um, I, I don't remember them saying that specifically, but I've always had, um, an obsession with, um, with, uh, uh, this kind of research and, um, certain other things.
Um, and, uh, I think that they do that to a lot of people because, um, once you get obsessed with the topic and you do all this research on it, if they have a brain implant in you, then they know it too at that point.
Um, so they're, they're getting you to do their research for them.
Yeah.
It's like this weird distributed science model or something where like they just have, they're collecting Intel through these different scientific nodes or something.
It's so trippy.
Yeah.
And we're all, we're all maybe their science experiment.
Who knows?
Well, one of the obsessions, uh, part of the reason I got into trouble before I was with one of the obsessions was with weapons.
And, um, I, you know, it's, I think that's, uh, kind of, uh, characteristic with some, uh, some people that are class two experiencers.
There was one guy that was most likely a class two experiencer that, um, that, uh, had a bunch of guns in his house and it was, uh, there was a big to do over that.
So maybe it's a characteristic.
I don't know.
Fascinating.
Well, Steve, I really appreciate this.
It was a lot of fun.
Uh, I feel like I could talk to you for hours.
I can tell we're interested in a lot of the same stuff and, um, yeah, I really, really appreciate your, your time.
Yeah, no problem.
My pleasure.
Awesome.
Thank you.