there was an arm a forearm a hand and three fingers here today's episode of American
Alchemy is truly historic we interview three of the most important UFO witnesses alive today you
mentioned that the being almost seemed to have control of the room what did you mean by that
the feeling was that he understood what was happening he wasn't afraid he was highly
intelligent at least more than I was a neurosurgeon who was face to face with an extraterrestrial
being for three to four minutes while it was recovering in a hospital bed a pilot and UFO
crash witness who held pieces of a UFO in his hands finally we interview a lead doctor who
did the autopsy on a soldier that was likely wounded by an alien being and you won't believe
what they found in this autopsy you might be telling yourself at this point all of this sounds
insane and beyond belief and then you realize how many witnesses on record we have from this case
James how many witnesses do you think you've spoken to total and a witness is anybody who's seen a ship
or an alien body ship maybe 12 to 15 and then the alien body I think it's up to five wow yeah it's
pretty amazing it is literally a modern Roswell but in Brazil in 1996 in fact the UFO material held by
one of our guests today Carlos de Sousa sounds exactly like the crash material at Roswell light tinfoily and
when he bent it it would immediately go back into its original shape like some sort of memory metal
the UFO also looked exactly like a tic-tac similar to the famous Nimitz incident in 2004 from commander
David Fravor also like many American UFO crashes we have air force and CIA involvement here how does he
know that the Americans were involved because they landed without the authorization of the Brazilian
government it was a secret mission and it was a US Air Force plane this event is an open secret in the
Brazilian city of Virginia where it occurred witnesses of the UFO and the beings that emerged from it
range from the local chief of police to this lead neurosurgeon we're interviewing today to nurses to
everyday farmers the former mayor even admits it happened in fact the city constructed a large model
UFO statue to commemorate the remarkable event and now thanks to the tireless and intrepid reporting of
my friend and UFO investigator James Fox over the last 15 years you basically have a complete chain
of events with human on-record witnesses assembled throughout you've mentioned multiple times that there is a
video of him essentially performing surgery on this alien if you had to guess do you think that the
tape is lying around in private civilian hands how you think it's in his house still yes I believe so
many of these witnesses needed to be hounded over decades by local UFO researchers just to come
forward and none of them have made a penny off their testimony oh we go over some wild never before
heard details there's an overwhelming amount of evidence here at the end of the day all of these
testimonies should be a rallying cry to keep turning this case over and keep gathering more hard evidence
as James Fox has done in his powerful moment of contact documentaries without further ado I want you
to sit back relax and prepare to have your mind absolutely blown with the unprecedented testimony of
some of the most important UFO witnesses in modern day history dr italo ventarelli dr armando fortunato
and carlos de soza everyone talks about the bermuda triangle but no one warns you about its colder
weirder cousin in the heart of alaska lies the alaska triangle where planes disappear hikers vanish and the
only thing that shows up reliably is my wild alaskan company seafood box I'm being serious here guys I
definitely don't trust flying over portals but I do trust this fish most seafood I can't even look at it without
wondering if it was farmed in a glowing vat near a nuclear power plant but this fish 100% wild caught flash
frozen off the boat delivered straight to my door like it teleported through one of Eric Davis's wormholes and it still
tastes better than just about anything your cousin microwaves no antibiotics no additives no fish farm
sludge just real fish coho salmon pacific halibut and my favorite the sockeye salmon not all fish are the
same get seafood you can trust go to wild alaskan.com slash jesse for 35 dollars off your first box of
premium wild caught seafood that's wild alaskan.com slash jesse for 35 dollars off your first order
thank you so much to wild alaskan company for sponsoring this episode carlos de soza thank you
so much for being here it's an absolute honor to have you I feel like I know you somewhat from
James Fox's amazing documentation of your experience in moment of contact I want you to take us back to
the day you had this experience with the ufo and just give me as much detail as you possibly can about
what happened moment by moment in 1996 I was doing a course to become an ultralight pilot
and on my graduation the colleagues invited us to go to the farm of one of their grandfathers
to have a barbecue have a good time spend time together you know in between friends
so I told them look I'm going to minas and it was going to be in tres corações which is a city
after varginha which is a closer city I left at night at a small company so I left and went toward
varginha and halfway along the way I stopped and slept a bit to get some rest it was nighttime so the
next day I would wake up early and continue the journey better rested well on that day I woke up
I left early I think around 5 5 15 in the morning very early and I started driving and left when I was
getting close to varginha what happened I saw then I stopped and then I stopped and looked ahead and I saw an object
pass over the road and I noticed that the object was having problems it was smoking from my point of view
at first glance I never never imagined that it was some sort of flying object a ship I thought it might have been a blimp
in Brazil during that time 96 it was very common to have blimps flying over the stadiums to film the football games
so for me it was a blimp that's all just letting you know that I didn't see and immediately think oh
that's a UFO I thought it was just a plain old blimp
but I could see that there were problems and I could see that when it changed angles there was a tear in
the side and a lot of smoke coming out of that tear in other words I thought oh maybe they hit
something a surface a tower maybe a tree a hill and it ripped the side of it and they're losing altitude
they're falling but as every good pilot and human being for that matter you don't think of anything
else the first thing that comes to mind is hang on there are people in there they will need help
because only pilots understand what an aircraft crashes
in that exact moment that's what went through my mind there are people in there they're gonna need help
I'm going to them to help them
and see what's going on and see if I can come to their aid immediately I got into my vehicle which was a small
pickup truck and followed the aircraft so what happened was it simply appeared to begin to lose altitude
then all of a sudden it seemed to gain power and started rising again and I thought well the pilot or whoever's piloting this craft
this blimp as I thought it was knows what they're doing because there's a city ahead of them
and it appeared to not want to fall on the city and so it was increasing altitude
and so I thought wow they're really clever and trying to avoid a bigger accident
so it crossed over again so once again it came started rising crossed again over the highway
and went toward an open field and following it I looked up and I could see the object
all of a sudden lose altitude totally and fall and at that time I accelerated as much as I could
and entered in the very first possible roadway to go to where I believed the blimp had fallen
as soon as I came up to the dirt road I immediately observed the fallen object it crashed it seemed to have bounced
the rear end of the craft which was completely destroyed there were pieces everywhere
and the front of it which was practically half of it slid further and ran into a tree
that's literally what it did it ran into a tree hit the tree and stopped and this rear part mainly wreckage
and from inside the car I was terrified I thought my god there must be dead people in there
to me it was a blimp it wasn't I never thought it was a spacecraft or a UFO or extraterrestrial no way
no way I just thought it was a flying dirigible
and I came down terrified and went toward it
the very first thing that I observed and that really caught my attention was the smell
because at that moment what I was expecting was the smell of diesel fuel or kerosene or aircraft fuel
it's normally a very strong smell
and on the contrary the smell that I felt at the crash site felt like ammonia
it was very strong I don't know what was the fuel or the substance that was there
but it was a very strong smell something different and it began to burn my eyes
so I brought my shirt up over my eyes because of the sting to protect my nose
and immediately it couldn't have been more than two minutes later
coming toward my car was a military convoy
that convoy had a front truck with a jeep
and you could see that there were officers, an ambulance and two other trucks
these tarp-covered trucks from the army
and they stopped in front of my vehicle
a bunch of soldiers got out of the back
and they didn't appear to get out randomly
they formed a V formation to close off the perimeter
and from the front truck
there were officers and soldiers that got out from that jeep
and one of the officers said
look over there
send him away, you can't be here
he shouted
and a soldier, huge, really strong, probably 2 meters tall
really strong
came running shouting
get out of here, get out of here
and just at that time
I could see quite a few pieces of debris on the ground
and I picked them up
and it was kind of curved
and then I was surprised to see how light it was
you know, aluminum foil
that you use to wrap up chicken
to roast
that you use normally in the kitchen
it was that kind of weight
it didn't weigh anything at all
and I thought
well, this is strange
alright
so I said, I'll keep it
and so I crunched it up
and so I made this kind of movement
you know, to put it in my pocket
and what happened
was this foil or this sheet
regained its shape
so I thought
what is this?
I was completely floored
at that moment
and then
that soldier
arrived
took his rifle
and started hitting me on the chest
and saying, get out of here
and I started to question him
saying no
there are people there
who are going to need help
I'm going to help them
I'm a pilot, man
I know what they're going through
I want to help them
and he said, no
get out of here
and I confronted him
and I said, no
I'm going to stay
he took a step back
raised his gun
cocked it
and pointed it at my head
pointing at my head
right here
and said to me
I'm not asking
I'm giving you an order
if you don't leave
I'm going to blow your brains out
then I started shaking all over
I thought, my God
well, no, no, no, no, no, no, no
alright
I'm sorry
I'll leave
he hit my hand
and threw the piece of debris
out of my hand
I went back to my car
steered it out
and I was still shaking all over
because I wasn't understanding at all what was happening
I did a U-turn on that small road
and went back to the main highway
and I was in such a state
where I thought, I can't fly like this
because in order to fly any aircraft
any vehicle
you have to be at peace with yourself
especially when your life's at stake
so you simply can't be all
oh, I'll fly no matter what
that's not how it works
you have to be centered
and there was no way in the state that I was in
so I thought, I'll go back
have some coffee, you know
so I can relax a bit
at that moment when I was going back
the following thought came to mind
look, this is probably a government experiment
because I didn't think it was a
a spacecraft
or an extraterrestrial object
to me
it was a government experiment
that I shouldn't have seen
in other words
I was in the wrong place
at the wrong time
saw what I shouldn't
and they sent me away
to me that was it
period
I turned around
went to get some coffee
and when I stopped
because in Brazil
every gas station
they have
places where you can
have coffee
something to eat
and they're always at the side of the road
I went in
told the young man
could you please get me a coffee
and he said
what's wrong mister
you're shaking
I caught my breath
and saw a black car
it's what at the time in Brazil
we would call an opala
was popular in Brazil
it pulled up
two people
in black suits
and white shirts
one of them with dark sunglasses
one of them took them off
looked at me and said
are you
Mr. Carlos de Souza
residing in such place
your wife's name is such and such
this is your company's name
I
looked at him and I said
what are you crazy?
who are you?
to interrogate me?
are you nuts?
he pointed a finger straight in my face
and said
just a word of advice
you didn't see anything
you don't know anything
if you open your mouth to anyone about this
you're gonna have serious problems for the rest of your life
so leave
get out of here
and keep quiet
I leaned on the counter
with no idea what was going on
no idea whatsoever
the young man behind the counter served me my coffee
and he said
mister
I know some people in the highway police
they can't talk to you that way
so he gave me a little napkin
and a pen
and said
write down the license plate
and I'll pass it on to them
to discover who these people are
they can't talk to you that way
so I got the napkin
the pen
and went to the door
and the car was leaving
and whoever said there was a license plate
the car didn't have one
at that moment my blood pressure just dropped
really
it just dropped completely
I was like
my god
so then
I got back into the car
thanked the young man
and thought to myself
I'm going home
because I'm in no condition to do
anything
I was still shaking completely
just
wouldn't stop shaking
breathing heavily
trying to process
in my mind
what was going on
so
got back in the car
drove to São Paulo
got home and told my wife
this this and that happened
she said
look
don't say anything about it
we don't know what it is
and we're not
going to meddle with what we don't know
fine
a week passed
but it was still on my mind
to me
up to that point
that
was a government experiment
it was no longer
a
limp
it was now
a government experiment
I shouldn't have seen
I kept my mouth shut
and after some time went by
something like
eight or nine months
maybe
the case that became known as the Varginha case showed up in the media
because the Varginha case came about a week five or six days after this
when those girls saw the creature
they saw that being
five or six days after I saw the crash
of the object
in the town of Varginha
and I heard later on from some specialists
that there's a river called the Rio Verde
and from the crash site to this river
there's a distance of about 50 or 100 meters
and the river runs right behind the place where these girls saw the creature
just behind it in the town
I heard about it from the media
you see to me
it
didn't make sense
I'd never been there
it was my first time
so if I were to say
oh I knew it
I'd be lying
and it was
during that time
how do you say
a UFO researcher called
Klaudiy Irkovo
he's already died
he went to the media
in Brazil
and asked for the love of God
if anyone has any information to come forward
because the question at the time was
where did these creatures come from?
if they're here
they came from somewhere
was there a crash?
did something happen?
they didn't just appear out of thin air
they had to have come from somewhere
because you see
I'm not dumb
come on
it hit me
I thought
my God
could it be?
of course
of course it did
so I picked up the phone
and I called Klaudiy Irkovo
at that time
there was only landlines
you know
with rotary dials
especially in Brazil
this technology was still very old
you had to dial the numbers
it was analog
so I called him
and said
is this Mr. Klaudiy Irko?
he said
yes
speaking
if you'd like to know where the ship crashed
I do
I'm pretty sure it's the same ship
because I didn't have 100% certainty
but I said
look
I'm almost sure that this is where the craft fell
all of a sudden
his tone completely changed over the phone
please
give me your address
he took down the address
and in 15 to 20 minutes he arrived
at my company actually
so he arrived there
and I said
look let's talk somewhere far away from the company
at the corner of the street
close to my company
because I wanted to keep it separate
and so we talked
and he asked me how it happened
and I told him
everything that I told you right now
so he said to me
look
could you take me there?
and I said
absolutely
but of course I can't go during weekdays
because I have my company to look after
so we'll go on the weekend
ok
so we went on the weekend
he came with his car
and we went to Varginha
and along the way I told him the whole story
and I took him to the crash site
when we arrived there
he sat down and was like
my god
you know why?
the tree that I told you about
that the ship ran into
was burnt to a crisp
and
from the foot of the tree
there was a kind of
a circle
an elongated circle
all of the vegetation was growing around it
except for inside that circle
there wasn't anything
anything at all
nothing
and he said my god
and it was the shape that I described to him
I told him
and he asked me
what was the shape like?
I said
it was like a cigar
a cylinder
today
it's known as a tic-tac
the same shape
so people can understand the actual shape of it
people like to say
oh there were blinking lights
not true
there were no blinking lights
it was only that kind of aluminum foil
very polished
and the early morning sun
its rays would reflect on it
and it would shine
but there were no lights
oh there were colorful blinking lights
no
there was none of that
only the shine of the actual metal
so he got down there
and he took samples of the tree
took samples of the soil
and took them
months later
and he recorded all of this
using Super 8 cameras
which were big cameras that we had at the time
not entirely sure
you had to use those film rolls
that you had to put in to record
it was the latest thing in technology at the time
at least for us
so he simply
collected those samples
took them to the lab
and some months later
he said
that the lab results
indicated
that the burning of the soil
and the tree
was caused by chemical products
and that they were unknown
in other words
if I had any doubts
they were gone
then and there
and something interesting that happened
that I always like to tell
is that close to the crash site
there were two houses
one small simple place
because it's in the middle of a big valley
and James filmed it there
he filmed it and showed it to us
I took him there
it was a very small house
and the people that lived there
were your typical country people
very modest
they lived there
with their family
so
Klaudij Kovus said
look
if you saw it
these people also saw it
and I said
yeah
I agree
let's go there
so he went down
the owner of the house
started to shout
with his sons and his daughters
get inside
shut up
don't say anything
they went in
and he locked the house completely from the inside
so we knocked
and we said
sir
can we please talk to you
but he kept shouting
go away
I have nothing to say to you guys
I already spoke to the army
go away
and since he wouldn't talk to us
we thought
I guess we'll have to leave then
we can't force anything out of him
then we saw the house in front of it
which was a farm right across from it
filled with cattle
and so we headed up there
because it wasn't plain or anything
first there was a plain surface
then a huge depression
really deep
way down
right next to the river
so we went up
and we knocked on the door of this house
the one with the cattle
and an old man came out
and we said
good afternoon
how do you do
could you kindly tell me
if you heard
anything unusual around here in January
and the man said
of course I did
my entire house shook
and we said
wait a minute
what
I'm telling you mister
it was 5am
I came out to milk the cows
and all the cattle started to get agitated
and there was this large noise
and my entire house shook
and we said
my god
we asked
do you know what it was
he said
I don't know
then a bunch of armed soldiers came
telling us to stay inside
that there had been an accident
and that everything was okay
and everything was under control
oh okay
Klaudia Kuova recorded this
he has this recorded on film
all this testimony
regarding the event
okay
so fine
we returned sometime later
and used a metal detector on the place
they didn't find anything
they said they found these small springs
but all of these testimonies were with this researcher called Klaudi Kuovo
and he died all of a sudden
and his daughter kept them
she's a psychologist
and she's a
how can I say
a very good person
a very calm person
easy going
thoughtful
and she herself says that her stepmother
destroyed all the material
and she still has a part of the material
she kept it being his daughter
so she has that with her
so if you ask me what material did she have
I don't know exactly
all she said was she had a part of it
so I thought okay that's good
oh cool
it's proof
great
I was really happy
and I was asked
why were you so happy?
because
I was tired of being called a liar
when I would tell this story
because you see when Klaudi recorded it
he leaked the recording
at the time
to a TV network called Rede Globo in Brazil
and this network every time would ridicule the case
took away any credibility
oh it's nothing
and everyone
be them from Vajinha
or all over Brazil
started poking fun
at the story
because of them
you know these people from the press
that seem that they've been bought off
to
take credibility away from the story
that's what they did
in other words
when footage of me was leaked
in the media
specifically
a show called Fantástico
which is pretty much watched
all over Brazil
relatives
everyone started poking fun
hey where's E.T.
where's the alien?
because if someone would say
I saw the creature
that's a lie
I never saw the creature
I saw the crash site
there was no time
to see if there was a creature
or anything
I didn't see anyone
because I believe
I arrived something like
three or four minutes
after the crash
just after it happened
oh you didn't see a creature?
no I didn't
I didn't
but you
no it's not true
I just wanted to say that
I too
went with Marco
in 2013
and I knocked on
every single door
of every house
within a quarter
or half a mile
of that crash site
and we found one farmhand
in 2013
I have
I have it on video
and I didn't use it in the film
for whatever reason
but he said yeah yeah
my boss was here
and he heard a boom
like a boom sound
and he said it on camera
oh yeah I know it was known
that was 2013
so that would have been
what 13, 14, 15, 16
17 years after the incident
but I knocked on the small house
and they were new
I knocked on
any house that was
within a certain proximity
and we got one farmhand
to say yeah
he'd heard that there was a big
impact
like a boom
really early in the morning
how can
how can we find this material
that might exist?
can you get your hands
on this material?
he did say to me
about four or five years ago
that her
a lot of her father's archives
were in the hands of his ex
or his
you know
I guess it would have been
and that she was very guarded
with some of that material
that she did get
she did get a lot
she I don't know exactly
what she had I can ask
do you think that she has
the UFO material
the aluminum foil
like material?
no not aluminum foil
no let me explain
there's documentary footage
filmed by him
the aluminum sheet
meaning those pieces
of the craft
were taken out of my hand
by the military
at the moment of the crash
ok?
that's one thing
another thing
is this happened later
the evidence she has
from the soil
from people hearing things
was recorded
by Klaudia Koufou
eight or nine months later
proving all of that
and what I described
ended up connecting everything
like putting the pieces together
everything the girls talked about
everything people in the city
were saying
because it all started there
the first contact
the first moment
happened right there
who is this guy
with the super eight camera
that went with you
to take soil samples
and to look at the burnt tree
who is that exactly?
that's Klaudia Koufou
well look
I know that Klaudia collected the material
and sent it to a lab
now if I told you exactly where
I'd be lying
because look
for me
at the time
it was simply
the crash of an object
I never had much awareness
of this kind of thing
because
I was never really into it
I was always
very skeptical
about this type of phenomenon
you know?
I didn't
really
pay attention to it
in fact
a well-known Brazilian researcher
who is a co-producer of Moment of Contact
named Marco Leao
told me something
years later
now around
something like that
in an informal conversation with friends
he said to me
Carlos
do you realize
you're one of the few human beings
who actually held a piece of a non-terrestrial object
in your hand?
and I said
huh?
you're right
that's true
I never thought about it that way
I never
ever
gained anything
from this
and this is interesting
because
just to
continue
the story I was telling
to
put everything in order
everything that happened
so you can
understand
the whole picture
when it came out in the media
everyone started mocking me
oh
the alien guy
you saw the little alien
people laughed at me
they lied
because when someone is an outsider
they don't have to believe
but when it comes from family
cousins
relatives
that hurts
I was harassed a lot
I was ridiculed
did you ever get a look at the inside of the crowd?
the inside of the craft
because
you know
if part of the craft
crashed on the ground
and then the rest of it
you know
kept going
did you ever see the inside
or any of the components?
no
what I saw
the only thing you could see
was half of the craft blown open
you could see there was something inside okay
just a silhouette
kind of a shadow
because my eyes were like this you know
that strong burning sensation
it was burning stinging
if I said oh
I saw everything clearly inside
that would be a lie
I couldn't see it
if I said
oh I saw the instruments inside
no
I didn't
I wasn't worried about instruments
to me
it was a blimp
I was worried about whether there were people
hurt on the ground
when you smell sulfur
now
or since then
does it exactly match that smell
or is it a unique specific smell
you say ammonia and sulfur
yes
the smell
the smell was
because I was expecting the smell of fuel
and it was a different smell
I don't know what that smell was
if I said oh it was from the creature
that would be a lie
I don't know
I just know the smell at the site
I don't know if it was the craft's fuel
or something else
but it smelled like ammonia
mixed with rotten eggs
you mix those two and put them right under your nose
yeah
it's not a good smell
it was awful
what was the exact color of the craft?
on the outside it was metallic
and on the inside it looked kind of bluish
an undefined color
I can't tell you
oh it was like this
nice and clear
you could see everything
no
that'd be a lie
I couldn't really see inside
because I was at a distance of maybe
from where I arrived
from the rear part
to where it was leaning against the tree
must have been about
100 to 150 meters away
so there was no clarity
especially with that smell you know
there was too much going on
I couldn't say
oh I'm going to look inside
no
I couldn't
I just couldn't see it
how big do you think the craft was?
uh
the object was about the size of a mini bus
like a high school bus
roughly the same size as a school bus
does
do you have any idea
as to whether there was radiation
or you know
anomalous electromagnetic activity involved?
at the time no
I wasn't thinking that
at that moment it wasn't that to me
at that moment to me
it was a blimp
that was in trouble
so
radiation
contamination
that never crossed my mind
if I said it did I'd be lying
it doesn't cross your mind
because you don't expect something like that
it's different from seeing something and thinking
I'm seeing a UFO
it's going to crash
oh
radiation
when you look at an object
and think
it's a blimp
there are people inside
it's going to crash
and those people will need help
that's all you think about
you don't think about radiation
I didn't think about radiation
no
in any moment
I didn't think about it
did it feel like time was moving slower
in any way
or did it feel like
you know
you literally just thought
this was this kind of
blimp
or dirigible
and it had
you know
crashed
no
time felt normal
there was nothing like
lapses in time
or anything like that
no
everything unfolded normally
like
regular time
for me
it was normal
I never felt any temporal distortion
and this was the Brazilian army
clearly
like you could make out that it was definitely the army
yes
it was near the ESA
ok
the
army sergeant school
in Brazil
ESA stands for
Escola de Sargentos das Armas
I didn't know that
ok
in fact the ones who told me that were James and people from the ufology community
that this small road I mentioned leads directly to the ESA
so it would be
let's say
a shortcut
they used
because to get to Tres Corazones using the official roads
you have to take a long way around
you go all the way around like this
and this road went like this
cut straight through
and I didn't know that
they told me
did you know this road leads straight to the ESA
and I said really?
well
I had no idea
I have a really interesting point that I want to make
I don't know exactly what AG1 is doing in my body
but I do know that my microtubules are online
I'm not saying I can feel the force
but my chakras have definitely auto aligned
in fact I used to think I had 7 chakras just like everybody else
and then I drink AG1
now I have 50
just kidding
but I did used to wake up feeling stiff and groggy like my brains on airplane mode
and then I started one habit
one scoop in 8 ounces of water
it's a multivitamin
a prebiotic
a probiotic
and with its adaptogens
it's the only green powder I'd ever bring to a skiff
shout out Chris Ramsey
I take this in the morning and it's the easiest upgrade I've ever made
my favorite flavor is berry but honestly they're all good
AG1 has over 50,000 verified 5 star reviews and comes with a 90 day money back guarantee
go to drinkag1.com slash alchemy to get their best offer
and get 3 free AG1 travel packs
plus free vitamin D3 plus K2
and AG1's welcome kit with your first AG1 subscription order
that's drinkag1.com slash alchemy
again that's drinkag1.com slash alchemy
we're linking that in the description
thank you so much to AG1 for sponsoring today's episode
I've learned some hard earned lessons in life
for example I've learned the hard way
that comfortable clothing usually means comfortable for 15 minutes
and then spending the rest of the day subtly irritated
the rough fabric, the chafing, the lack of flexibility
it all just sucks
that's why I've been wearing chubbies
their everywhere pants are the rare pants that actually move with you
they've got real stretch
the elastic waistband is genuinely comfortable
and they still look really put together
I'll wear them on a recording day
running around doing a million things
and I'm not thinking about my clothes at all
which is kind of the point
same with their shorts and swim trunks that I have right here
they're lightweight, they're stretchy, they fit just right
and you're not dealing with that old scratchy mesh situation down there
you put them on and you're done
for a limited time
chubbies is giving our listeners
20% off with code JESSE
at chubbiesshorts.com
that is 20% off your order with code JESSE
give your thighs the VIP treatment they deserve with chubbies
support our show, use our code
and tell them we sent you
thank you so much to chubbies for sponsoring today's episode
I have a really interesting point that I want to make quickly
because I just talked to allegedly the mechanic who worked on the trucks
that this was the mechanic for the trucks as a military base
and he said that he had to make all these extensive repairs on the suspension
at that time because he was like they must have been flying down pothole dirt roads
because they just did a lot of damage and he had to make all these repairs
wow
I thought that was a really interesting connection
well I also think it's an interesting connection that the
you know Carlos is saying that the material is lightweight
but maybe it's you know a lot of weight
you know if you're putting a school bus on your truck
you know that might have the suspension might break
I think it was more for them when they were racing to get to the site
that they were flying down the dirt roads
because they got there within minutes
so it's speculation right
sure
but it's interesting that we had that connection
and we got to him through the nurse that we met the night
we brought all the doctors together
she was the one that was telling us
Amara was there
I know Italo's telling the truth
I know
and we were like how do you know
and she was shaking
she goes because I was there
wow
we went and met with her at her house
and that her partner was the mechanic for as a trucks
and he's the one that told us
all these reparations had to be made
repairs had to be made
because he was assuming that they were speeding down
pothole dirt roads
just another little piece of the puzzle
an interesting aspect of it
oh very interesting
yeah
and did you hear independently anything about the material being sort of aluminum foil like
or you know if you crumple it up it goes back into its original position
no the only thing I heard was people
first hand witnesses I personally interviewed
and it said it was cylindrical shaped like a school bus
like a cigar
had no control services that kind of thing
and another interesting aspect of it
is Dr. Armando who did the autopsy on the deceased military officer
he
has two friends
farmers
that saw exactly what he saw before it crashed
just another little piece
yeah
the puzzle
there's so many aspects of this story
well you also have
farmers
documented in moment of contact
you also have a guy who looked outside his window
yes
looking at it
and then you show the entire flight path
yes
and then I think what I love
to be honest about Carlos de Sosa's testimony specifically
is you have this very dramatic part of moment of contact
where he's showing you the site the crash site
and to me if you were a liar he would have said here it is
but he gets there and he goes it wasn't here in fact the landscape has changed
and he goes I'm looking for this white house I swear it's a white house it's a white house
and he took you for two hours
yeah I thought this was the I was so disappointed at the time I was like oh my god this is going horribly how could this guy not remember where the spot was and and and then when he sees the actual spot not only do you see different topology and vegetation a different color coloration of the ground locally where he says the spot is but he starts crying and you this is very moving part of the movie where you say a key a key and you break down
and uh I don't know I don't think you can fake that so
yeah it's pretty I mean you have to ask yourself you know why witnesses come forward he's not selling a book he's not selling a documentary we chased him down we found him Marco Leal found him chased him down and he finally agreed to meet with me and then he ultimately agrees screw it let's go back to the since 1996 he hadn't been there since 1996 so it'd been 26 years at the time
wow you know and I was like man if this guy's lying we don't need any more Brad Pitts or Leonardo DiCaprio
exactly and this remarkable encounter you had at this sort of food stand afterwards with this guy who's wearing a suit two guys wearing a suits and an unmarked car
he walks out he walks out a lot of people in the US like to talk about this men in black phenomenon which are you could say they're the first responders when it comes to sort of alien experiences did they seem like they were human and they were coming from intelligence agencies or army affiliated or did they almost seem paranormal or alien themselves
uh to me they looked normal I mean the only thing that caught my attention because I'm a short guy I'm not tall you know not big or muscular was that they were very tall okay they were about the height of someone like James or other tall strong people very military looking you know big muscular ripped
I'd look up at them and like huh okay yes sir they were strong okay but if someone says oh they had weird eyes or something that's a lie a lie they were normal people okay normal human beings just strong and very well dressed
only one of them spoke the other stood next to him just watching wearing sunglasses silent he didn't say a word he finished speaking they turned around and left got into the car and drove away that was when I went to look at the license plate and there wasn't one that's when all of this happened
what's so remarkable to me is that they know all these personal details about you your family your address hours after you see this event and we're talking about 1996
so this is really before the internet before large databases in the US let alone a small town in Brazil so have you speculated about that and thought about how did he get that information
let's correct this story it wasn't hours later it was minutes later
it was minutes 10-15 minutes 10-15 20 minutes at most
so how does he know who you are
this question you're asking me is the same question I've been asking myself for 30 years
that same question I've asked myself for 30 years
how
because that was one of the things that terrified me the most
so much so that when I went back to São Paulo and gave this interview
to
this ufologist
nine months later
I deeply regretted it
because my life turned into hell
at the time in Brazil
all phones were landlines
cell phones didn't really exist
they looked like war radios you know
can you read me over that kind of thing
the technology was very basic just starting out
so 99.99% of the population had landline phones
they had the rotary dials for you to dial the numbers to make a call
and I started to notice that every time I picked up the phone to talk
there was someone on the other end listening
because when what Claudia released aired on Globo when it leaked
you could tell
I even changed phone numbers and it didn't make a difference
that really started to irritate me
and my company
inspections started showing up
audits
tax checks
things like that
you know when it feels like someone is looking for something wrong
where there isn't anything
in other words
looking for the smallest excuse to shut you down
but those inspections lasted days
normally they'd last hours
but these went on for days
and in front of my company
unmarked cars would show up
cars without identification
fake plates
or no plates at all
they'd just sit there watching, watching
when you walk toward them
they'd start the car and leave
they never said anything
and no, I was never threatened with death later
that's a lie
nobody ever threatened me with death
but you could feel the pressure
like they were saying
if you keep talking
things are going to get ugly
something serious is going to happen to you
so you were kind of harassed and intimidated
do you think about
these men in black characters
10 to 15 minutes after
is so remarkable to me
I take back what I said
it's not only unlikely
it's impossible
that they can know that information
in that amount of time
do you ever think
that maybe they were
not human themselves
or they were somehow
protecting or in coordination
with the beings
that came down
in the ship and crashed?
I believe I know just as much
as you do, okay?
It was just as surprising to me
as it is to you
and as I've already said before
I asked myself this question
thousands of times
how did they get that information
so quickly?
I came up with a hypothesis
that it might have been
through my car's license plate
at the time
radios were very common, right?
and through radio communication
they may have gathered
some information
and started passing it along
to those people
that could be it
now listen
I'm not saying
that's what happened
I'm just raising a hypothesis
because that was also
one of the things
that scared me the most
at the time
because the crash itself
to me
had been just a normal crash
of an object
I saw something that
at that moment
I thought was a government experiment
something I wasn't supposed to see
but when they arrived
so quickly
that's when I thought
my God
what is this?
that was truly frightening
and the most interesting part
is that
after all that process
with Globo and everything
being threatened and all that
my wife turned to me
and said
look, shut up
don't talk about this anymore
disappear
so I disappeared
I changed my phone number
moved houses
later I returned
to the same place
where I live today
but at the time
I moved into my father's house
my father
who has since passed away
had moved to the beach
I moved into his house
you see
and basically erased my trail
and what's interesting
is that the current researcher
Max Liao
one day I'm at home
calm and relaxed
when my phone rings
excuse me
is this Mr. Carlos?
and I thought
who wants to talk to him?
burned once
afraid of cold water
who wants to talk to him?
no, please don't hang up
my name is Max Liao
I'm a ufologist
and I'd like to talk to you
about the Varginha case
the reason I accepted
after 26 years
actually 25 years
this first contact
happened about a year or two earlier
was because a week earlier
I'd gone to a birthday party
for one of my wife's cousins
and I don't know where
they got it from
but they brought this story back up
and started making fun of me
some of them had been drinking
a bit too much
and you know
drunk people have no filter
they started crossing the line
that made me really angry
I told him
I said
I'll prove it to you
I even cursed at him at the time
used a swear word
I said
I'll prove to you
that I'm not a liar
I never lied
I never gained anything from this
and I won't lie now
one day I'll prove it to you
I'll have the proof
and then sure enough
Marcus called me the following week
so I killed two birds with one stone
I thought
okay
this is the moment to speak up
do you know James?
I didn't even know James existed
I had no idea who James was
nothing
to be very honest
my life was fine
just the way it was
so
so I
went to the house
of a friend of Marcos
in a neighborhood called Morumbi
in São Paulo
inside a very small apartment
we recorded the interview
I told my story
he said
look let's verify this
I said
yeah that's fine
then he said
wow
your account is exactly the same
as the one you gave 25 years ago
identical
not a single detail has changed
I said
guys
I'm just telling you what I saw
I don't need to lie
all right
okay thank you
when we finished recording
he tried to
give me some money
I told him
no thank you
I don't want it
no I really don't want it
I'm not here for money
I don't need it
seriously
I said
do me a favor
just one thing
take that money
and donate it
to a charity
that needs it
because I don't need
to live off this
you have my word
so I told him
go donate it
he said
but
I said
donate it
he said
all right
so after that
I turned my back
about a year later
he told me
that there was a filmmaker
a well-known
American documentary filmmaker
who was coming to Brazil
and wanted to meet me
he said his name
was James Fox
I asked
who is James Fox
he said
in the United States
he's very well known
you don't know him
I said
sorry man
but I honestly
have no idea
then he
asked me
if I would agree
to tell my story
in the documentary
I said
all right
and then
but I made it clear
I don't want to earn anything
I never wanted to make money
from this story
I never made a single cent
from it
nothing
because I believe
the truth
has to be told
spoken
as truth
you shouldn't take advantage
of others
it's absurd
when people
have a story
and exploit it
charging appearance fees
and things like that
I mean
sorry for the word
but that's bad character
people
who take advantage
of others
in any situation
you have to be
an honest
upright person
with integrity
one of the things
I admire most
about James today
after getting to know him
and I even say
he's like a brother to me
I have a special affection
for him
is
his posture
the kind of human being
he is
he's an upright person
someone I truly
admire as a human being
because he's honest
in what he says
he only seeks
the truth
I've never seen him
hide a lie
he's the kind of guy
that if you're lying
he'll tell you
straight to your face
look man
this story doesn't add up
this is a lie
he'll say it
what does your family
think now
they were so skeptical
you know
just five
six years ago
they were making fun
of you
at this party
now that you've
been documented
thoroughly by James Fox
and two
Moment of Contact movies
what do they say
to you now
what's interesting
is that my own brother
he's American
he's a U.S. citizen
he's married to an American woman
has American children
and has lived here
for over
30 years
okay
and when he found out
he said
man you never told me anything
I told him
this is my story
nobody needs to know
because
being humiliated
being called
oh you're the brother
of the guy who saw the alien
did you see the little alien too
I didn't want that kind of ridicule
for him
or for my family
so I kept it to myself
that's why
at that moment
when I
took James
to the crash site
for me it was like
imagine a
dam bursting
a mix of emotions
all those years
with everything
trapped inside you
unable to talk about it
not telling anyone
not even family
always hiding
and you think
damn
am I going to have to
humiliate myself
all over again
am I going to go through
everything I went through
back then
I didn't want that
for my family
especially not my family
because when you truly
love someone
you don't want anything
bad to happen to them
at all
that's why
with my older daughter
and my younger daughter
I always hid
many things from them
so they wouldn't
suffer bullying
at school
kids making fun
of this kind of thing
like I always say
hit me
hurt me
even kill me
if you have to
but don't mess
with the people I love
they're not to blame
if I made some mistake
take it out on me
not on them
protect them
how
how were you
emotionally affected
after the original
experience
and then the
sort of
men in black
experience
and then you're
getting harassed
you have to start
to think in your head
there's something
and then all of a sudden
you get
corroboration
that these three
you know
girls
see a being
five six days later
in town
you make this connection
that this might not be
from here
it might be ET
it might be
a non-human entity
as soon as you start
to make that connection
how does that impact
you emotionally
and as far as
your world view
after what happened
for me
when everything
came together
when everything clicked
that's when I truly
realized what had
happened
and what hadn't
it changed a lot
inside me
truly
why
because the idea
that we are alone
in the universe
was never
hard for me to accept
in billions
zillions
of planets
for us to be
the only ones
with life
would be like
looking at your own
belly button
and saying
I'm the only being
that exists on planet earth
in other words
that's impossible
our universe is enormous
advanced intelligences
exist
for me
today
the question is
no longer
whether extraterrestrial
life exists
that question is minimal
the real question is
who are they
and what are their intentions
that's the big question
what do you think
I have one contribution
when you're ready
go ahead
I firmly believe
okay
that uh
I don't
want to go on
too long
but I believe
we are a biological
experiment
created by evolved
entities
putting religions aside
everything aside
I don't want
conflict with any religion
because I
believe in all religions
and at the same time
I believe in none
I believe in the essence
of religions
not in church labels
or institutions
makes sense
um
his brother lived
not far from where I am
I think New York
or New Jersey
or something
and so I said
hey man
your door's open
I'd love to have you out there
you can stay with me
put you up in my barn
you can watch the editing process
Marco Leal was there
and so he took us up on it
and we invited him
to stay with us
for a couple of weeks
which he did
and we went hiking
went out to eat
we had a lovely time
we were working every day as well
and in the edit room
I was going through
the interview with
Military X
at the time
Military X wasn't disguised
when he was looking at it
and uh
Military X
I asked Military X
some question
and he's like
he's like
everything that happened
at Virginia
started at Mayer Leany Farm
and he's
he watched that
and he had tears
pouring down his face
because he was just like
this weight off his shoulders
yeah
and I got to witness that
as he saw it
like
it was like
I've been telling you
you can look like
I don't like it
well it sounds like
this has been a process
of constant vindication
over time
because
you see this thing
you think it's some sort of
you know
aircraft or blimp
and then
you have this weird
foil
aluminum foil
like material
then you have this
kind of
very bizarre
men in black experience
where they seem to know
all your personal details
then you hear about
the girls
seeing the being
in town
then you have
you know
military
X
you know
this witness
key witness
involved in the transport
of the being
talking about
how
you know
it all started
around Mayer Leany Farm
which is where you saw
the crash
and then you have
all these tests
being done
on the local soil
and on the
you know
the tree
and stuff
and so
data point
after data point
continues to corroborate
your initial experience
has there been
anything
that's come out
that
has made you
doubt the experience
no
nothing at all
today
ever since
everything
clicked for me
I have
no doubts
none
whatsoever
I'm absolutely
certain
it was an
extraterrestrial object
I saw the crash
I witnessed it
and I say this
I swear it
on a bible
on anything
you want
if I'm lying
I'll do whatever
you want
with whoever
I swear to it
and your testimony
today
your testimony
a few years ago
with James
and your testimony
you know
at this point
30 years ago
pretty much the same
every single time
yes
because it's the truth
I can't
I can't invent
something
I didn't see
I'm telling
what I saw
and that doesn't
change
if you witness
a fact today
that same fact
will still be
the same
100 years
from now
it doesn't
change
and one of the
things that caught
my attention
the most
in all of this
happened
right after
James's
first documentary
aired
maybe later
he can even
confirm this
the crash site
went 26 years
without anyone
touching it
just as I saw
the crash
James even commented
that the vegetation
grew differently
the tree was still there
burned
completely burned
just as it had been
and the vegetation
in the burned area
clearly showed
that the soil
was different
you know
and here's what's
interesting
when the documentary
came out
a person
from Europe
a businessman
called me
and said
he wanted to meet me
and was curious
to visit the site
and that he would pay me
I said the same thing
as always
look
I don't want to make
any money
take that money
and donate it
if you want to go
I'll take you
no problem
I've got time
just pay for my gas
so I can get there
it's another state
you cover the hotel
those things
just pay my food and gas
and that's it
I'll take you there
and show you
when I got there
with this man
we met up in Vagina
and he said
shall we go there
let's go
let me tell you
I was shocked
I sat down
I didn't know
whether to cry
laugh
or panic
I even made a remark
to James
James went there
shortly after that
they had done
land grading
literally
there must have been
around
seven or eight
meters of earth
piled there
before
it was
almost completely flat
yeah
James was there
they said
we're going to plant
soybeans here
and they planted soybeans
what they spent
to remove that
amount of earth
just to plant soybeans
makes no sense
they would have to plant
soy there for a thousand years
just to make a profit
now listen
for me
me personally
what I believe
that happened
at the time of the crash
someone must have gone to them
and said
get rid of all this
and they didn't
like a typical Brazilian response
no do it later
it's fine
that thing we call
the Brazilian way
it's terrible
we always leave things
for later
until the very last moment
that's one of our traits
in this case
I'm grateful
for the little Brazilian way
because
maybe that means
we can get
more of a smoking gun
that something happened
James
have you ever thought of
bringing a
Geiger counter
looking for
levels of radiation
or
metal detectors
you know
you could do
a gravitometer
anything like that
a couple months ago
I have a friend
who's quasi professional
with a metal detector
and we went out there
for a day or two
one we did in the evening
it was so hot
during the daytime
and he
he looked at me
and he's like
man
this whole area
has been all upturned
like it had changed
when we flew our drone
over it
when we were first meeting
with him after 26 years
out at the site
you can clearly see
from the air
a visible difference
in the soil
like just from
oh it's obvious
so obvious
and then it's changed
since then
they bulldozed it
or something
they've shifted
stuff all around
and my friend said
dude I would need
this is a job
and after a couple of days
he goes
I would need
probably several months
out here
we didn't have that time
I think it's something
that should be done
and also
another
a comment
by
the forensic pathologist
Dr. Armando
he said
perhaps we could do
some soil samples
and bring soil samples
and we could take
a close look
because he thinks
that anything left behind
would have been
macro particles
but they could
possibly do so
I'd probably go out there
with a geologist
and find out
where the best areas
of runoff
animal mounds
ant mounds
you know
areas where this debris
would most likely end up
after 30 years
and gather those samples
and get them analyzed
I think another good idea
is like there's
ground penetrating radar
you know
are there things
that penetrate
even more deeply
than you know
a metal detector
like you might want
to speak to
Brandon Fugel
or you know
people who
are dealing with
what they think of
as kind of
exotic underground objects
and you know
how they're
and honestly
I'd do that
as soon as humanly possible
because we're
we're going to be
amplifying this story
and so the antibodies
might come out
Carlos
this experience
must have been
so profound
and
I imagine
it's impacted you
really really deeply
have you ever gotten
a hypnotic regression
to recall
vividly
what might have happened
yes
I did
I did it at the beach
with a friend
a person we call
Saga
he's
well
he says
at least
he told me
that he's one of the
specialists in Brazil
who does
regression hypnosis
and he showed me
some things
that left me
kind of
shocked
if I told you
oh do you remember
what you said
no
he showed me
the video
okay
and that
really shook me
what he showed me
what did you say
well
according to what's
recorded there
it says that I had a
mental contact
with the creature
I don't remember that
if I said I do
that would be a lie
okay
and if you ask
oh do you remember it
no
that would be a lie
I only saw it
in the recording he made
but I can't confirm it myself
I can't say
yes
I remember
I only talk
about what I actually remember
in that hypnosis
he says I became
very distressed
very worried
it even happened
at the beach
we were there
relaxed
and he said
let's do the hypnosis
the regression
and he got scared
this Saga guy
got scared
so much so
that he suggested
let's write a book
and I said
no no no
forget it
erase this
wipe it out
I don't want to know
about this
I don't want to make money
I don't want anything
from this
what was the nature
of the mental connection
and was anything
transmitted
was anything said
between the being
and yourself
according to what's
recorded there
this part is
erased for me
I don't remember it
okay
I'm only going to report
what's on the recording
it says that I was
desperate
trying to get closer
and the creature
was speaking mentally
saying
calm down
everything is fine
go away
it's dangerous
for you here
don't come closer
go away
stay calm
we're fine
you can go
we just want to thank you
for your concern
thank you for worrying
but we're fine
stay calm
we'll talk
but stay calm
stay calm
we're fine
be at ease
and I said
please
I want to help
no
calm down
that's what's recorded there
do you remember this
no
I don't remember it
and don't worry
because I'll make this
very clear to the audience
this is the more
speculative part
that you're not
you're admitting
you're not sure of
and this is
it's a modality
that
a lot of memories
when it comes to traumatic
or very anomalous events
get fractured
and this is a real modality
that helps you retrieve
real memories
in many cases
so we're taking this
maybe
with more of a grain of salt
than the rest of your testimony
but I do think
it's important also
if we're trying to get
a little deeper
into what might have happened
you have to hold it loosely
but I do think
you have to
view it as data
so
you mentioned
that the beings
said they wiped your memory
is that
is that true
they said that they
didn't want you to remember
what had happened
according to what was
recorded there
they told me
that I would never remember
that it would be
very dangerous for me
they didn't want me
to remember
and they would do
everything to make sure
I wouldn't
is there anything else
you said about
the communication
between you
and the beings
in that recording
no
what I remember
is only that
okay
then I started
getting very agitated
in the recording
I started crying
getting extremely agitated
about everything
suddenly
he himself
stopped it
and said
no
calm down
I mean
my heart was racing
I was
you know
really worked up
he said calm down
then he brought me back
ended it
the regression
the hypnosis
right
he stopped it there
after that
he told me
this was one of the
these are Dr. Sagar's words
that this was one of the most impressive experiences he had ever seen in his life
and this hypnotist had no experience with people who've had alien visitations or abduction experiences or anything like that
I don't know
I really don't know how to tell you
I met him on the day of the first screening of James's film
we went to Sorocaba
which is a city
in the state of São Paulo
it's called Sorocaba
where the documentary premiered
and that person was there
and that's where I met him
there was also another doctor there
who wanted to do hypnosis with me
but I tried to schedule it with her
and she was always unavailable
busy
traveling
then Sagar came and said
come on
let me do it
I'm just as much a specialist as she is
I said
all right
and he did the regression with me
after that I never wanted to do it again
and I don't want to
the experience was horrible
I felt very bad afterward
really bad
I don't want it
please
I kept saying
no no no
please
I don't want this
I felt terrible afterward
I can't explain the feeling it gave me
I interview many experiencers
some of whom retrieve more about their experiences through hypnotic regression
and they always say the same as you
they say
we can't say that part for sure is true
we know what we experienced in our waking reality
and then some of these other things might have happened as well
but it's interesting
the one common thing that they all say is
their heart speeds up
in certain case
one of them went into a fibrillation
because he was re-experiencing the beings
so it seems to be this traumatic thing that we repress
and that you know often comes out
I guess you know kind of point blank
my question to you would be
in your hardest of hearts
do you think what came out in that hypnotic regression
is real
and that maybe you did
achieve some sort of mental contact with the beings
if you had to guess
and we're all giving you the grace
to know that you're speculating here
and that you're being very honest about the line
between what you experienced in waking reality
and what's coming out through this more speculative technique
I believe it because I saw the tape
the recording
if I hadn't seen it
I wouldn't believe it
simple as that
if someone came to me today and said
hey do it again
I'd say no
sorry
I won't
I refuse
because I felt really bad afterward
and from the recording
it's impressive
looks like my chest was about to explode
you could see my chest moving like this
it was something anguishing
seeing myself afterward
after I had calmed down
and all that
watching that footage of myself
was very impactful
I thought
wow
I could have had a massive heart attack right there
it was very very intense
so I
I believe it
because I saw the recording he made
he has it all recorded
but if you ask me
do you believe it consciously?
no
I don't have that conscious memory
and what I don't have conscious awareness of
I don't fully believe
I'm very
how can I put it
like St. Thomas
I have to see it to believe it
I'm very
grounded
I don't like
make-believe
or little stories
like
oh I saw this
I saw that
just stories
I'm much more about
reality
did the event happen?
it did
I report the event
period
I think honesty and sincerity
come above everything else
unfortunately
ufology worldwide
not just in Brazil
I mean worldwide
is often discredited
why?
because people invent
too many little stories
you know
and people
just believe them
many times when you start
talking to these people
you realize the stories
make no sense at all
they can't explain anything
they say they saw something
then later they didn't
and it becomes absurd
and that's why I'm
very skeptical
in that regard
final question Carlos
you are a geography teacher
and you're an ultralight pilot
how has this experience
changed
you know
your teaching of geography
knowing
that we are not
possibly the only map
with habitable
universe
and then
when you fly
do you ever wonder
if you're going to encounter
the UFOs again?
first of all
as a teacher
which is something
I truly love being
it's a profession
I genuinely love
teaching
sharing knowledge
it's a unique experience
and
what happened
well to this day
my students never knew
about this story
only after James
did some of them
start to find out
but about 90%
still don't know
they can't connect
the dots
they can't link
their teacher
Carlos
to that story
right?
and honestly
that's a good thing
as a person
I believe this difficulty
exists
all over the world
people are
very religious
many believe
deeply in religion
and religions often
deny the existence
of other forms of life
believing they are
the only beings
in the galaxy
so many times
I hold back
I don't talk about it
I don't comment
to avoid arguments
and controversy
because then parents
complain to the school
principle
oh he's talking about
extraterrestrials
that doesn't exist
my priest said this
my pastor said that
and so on so on
that's complicated
so professionally
as a professional
I avoid that kind of topic
in the classroom
I'm Professor Carlos
a geography teacher
I'm there to explain
geopolitics
geoeconomics
geophysics
in other words
to teach
geography
and
give my best
as a professional
to my students
now
as a pilot
of course
I hope that one day
I might encounter
something like that again
sometimes I even think
if I saw an object
like the
phoenix lights
in the United States
that triangle shape
and I were flying
I'd go toward it
that's a fact
but wouldn't you be afraid
no
I even joked about this
with James once
I said
James if you encountered
a craft and they said
come with us
what would you do
he said
no I have a young child
I laughed
and said
oh no
I'd go without a problem
because something really
I don't know
changed
you know
the world
I don't believe
they're here
with bad intentions
because if they were
they would have
taken over
a long time ago
just imagine
as a human being
that there are
beings
capable of crossing
the universe
with technology
to travel
across space
do you really think
we
as mere humans
would have any way
to fight them
if they wanted
to invade us
they would have
done it long ago
so the only thing
I can believe
is that they're here
to help us
and of course
we hope
that's the case
that's it
there's nothing more
to say
as a pilot
I'd love to meet them
as a teacher
I keep things
separate
for children
teenagers
young people
adults
so things
don't get
confused
professionally speaking
I've spent
23 years
in the classroom
in schools
and
I was also
an entrepreneur
for 25 years
so I can't
mix things up
what I believe
what I know
what I saw
I don't
have the right
to impose that
on anyone else
I don't have that
right
no one does
you have
free will
to believe
whatever
you want
for you
to be free
if you believe
great
if you don't
that's fine too
I respect you
as a human being
as a person
and I always will
Carlos
it's been an honor
I really appreciate
your testimony
the level
of descriptiveness
and detail
with which you
recall
an event
that happened
30 years ago
is absolutely
remarkable
and
I just find
you to be
a very kind
of candid
honest person
I don't sense
any sort
of deception
from you
and
you seem
like a very
deep and
spiritual person
as well
and
like you
you mentioned
Thomas
who wants
to know
I can tell
that you have
that same streak
in you
and you're
a gnostic
kind of
meaning seeker
and
I pray
that you
keep going
on your path
and
that you
get the
truth that you want
I'm very grateful
truly
I only have
thanks to give to you
to human beings
like you
like James
whom I deeply
respect
Dr. Italo
Dr. Armando
serious
people
people like
Valkyria
Liliane
her other sister
all the girls
people who really
lived through this
I'm only grateful
okay
honest
good human beings
like these
who crossed my path
are there any
key details
we missed here
that are worth
retelling
the only thing
I would add is
I'd like an explanation
for why for 26 years
not a single straw
was removed
from that place
then after 26 years
James's documentary
comes out
and they go there
and remove more than
30 meters of earth
I just want to know why
I don't understand that
if they have nothing to hide
why do that
that's all
other than that
everything's fine
that's it
if you ever need anything
I make myself available
at any time
really
if you need me
to anyone
anywhere in the world
the only thing I ask is
please cover my lodging
and food
I'm still human
I eat
drink
sleep
like anyone else
I'm always
willing
to go
anywhere
to report
what I saw
with the utmost sincerity
you deserve that
and so much more
and
yeah it's funny
renovations
26 years later
doesn't make a lot of sense
but
appreciate you being here
Carlos
it's been an absolute honor
and thank you for coming
to Austin Texas
and
I hope we can be in touch
no thank you
as they say
namaste
namaste too
okay
it happened to me
in the woods
I was hiking solo
new year
no phone
no gear
I was just trying
to find myself
that's when I saw it
something glowing
silent
descending through the trees
a UFO
and stepping out from it
wasn't an alien
or an android
it was me
but better
same face
same great hair
but something was different
this guy had perfect posture
he was wearing
the perfect jean
and they start at just $79
6 fits
sizes for every thigh
on this timeline
and beyond
now
2026 me
wears the perfect jeans
they don't crush my thighs
or my dreams
they're soft
but dangerous
for a limited time
our listeners
get 15% off
their first order
plus free shipping
at theperfectgene.nyc
or just google
the perfect jean
and use code
jesse15
for 15% off
that's 15% off
for new customers
at theperfectgene.nyc
with promo code
jesse15
after you purchase
they'll ask you
where you heard about them
please support our show
and tell them
we sent you
hear khakis
and get
the perfect gene
we received an unexpected
request for a meeting
from the chief neurosurgeon
at hospital regional
the doctor requested
the team enter
by the more
inconspicuous back entry
no one knew why
when i asked them
to take us
where the alien
was brought
this is regional
hospital
so it went
regional hospital
and then it went
to humanitas
humanitas
eza
campinas
america
okay
if you film
you have to wear
a mask
and james and i
are gonna wear this
okay
so let's talk
about the context
right
yes
dr italo
venturelli
the head
neurosurgeon
at hospital
regional
was on duty
in the icu
when he had
the most
extraordinary
encounter
of his life
in this room
or which room
this room
right here
the alien
was alive
in this bed
right here
so say
when you approach
the hospital
you say
is this the hospital
where the et
was treated
and they're like
yes
come inside
black out front
you walk into
the reception
oh yeah
he's brought
around the
back
there's somebody
still working
here that was
there that night
i mean it's
it's how do you
hide the truth
right out in the
open
yeah yeah
yeah
yeah no
it seems like
it's a
not even
disputed
at the
administrative
basic
routine
level
which is where
you expect
the bureaucracy
to be told
hey just keep
your mouth shut
and in this
case
they're all
just like
yeah this
is where
we treated
the et
like
and there's
a there's
a plaque
what does
the plaque
say
uh
i have to get
the literal
translation
but this is
the path
of et
came here
to this
hotel
on january
20th
the united
states
came here
to this
hospital
sorry
yeah regional
yeah it's
right out front
i got a photograph
of it i can give
to you
that is wild
i'd love to see
the photograph
i'll send it
to you
show it
so i'm here
with in my
mind
maybe the
most significant
witness
when it comes
to seeing
ufos
et beings
beings from
what seemed
to be another
world
in the entire
and the reason
i say that
is because
of your
background
your pedigree
you're a
neurosurgeon
people depend
on you
to operate
on their
brains
you manage
a chain
of three
hospitals
who cannot
operate
without you
and because
you spent
four to five
minutes in
your own
estimation
face to
face
with one
of these
entities
and so
it is an
absolute honor
to be with
you today
and i can't
thank james
fox enough
for getting
you dr
armando
carlos
de soza
all to
the u.s
this is a
dream come
true for
me so
thank you
for being
here
thank you
for inviting
me
i'm a
very simple
person
raised in a
very modest
manner
i had the
opportunity to
occasionally
help those
hospitals
i had
excellent
teachers
including some
that were
american
like dr
huckton
and many
wonderful
neurosurgeons
both from
my country
and my
hometown
dr
atasir
domingos
marcus
vinicius
and it's
a pleasure
to be
here with
you
but i'm
just a
simple
person
who had
the
privilege
by chance
of seeing
a very
different
kind
of being
so just
for everybody
in the
audience's
sake i
would like
to know
your name
and your
background both
educational
background and
professional
background
my name is
italo
denelli
venturelli
i was born
in sao paulo
i studied
at the
pouso alegre
school
i did my
residency in
sao paulo
and i've been
in minas gerais
since 1983
in the city
of varginha
the place
where i arrived
already had a
very well
established
neurosurgery
service
run by
dr
atasirio
and dr
domingos
toledo
and i was
part of it
they already
had a whole
service set up
which allowed
me to develop
many skills
i already
possessed
and they
taught me
a lot
there
so
lots of
surgeries
it's a
hospital
before
january
did you
have any
interest
in
alien
et's
ufo's
anything
like that
no
i'm a
neurosurgeon
and we
work for
the public
health
system
so we
spend most
of our
time
in the
operating
room
so i
really
didn't
have
any
such
interest
i did
travel
to
egypt
on an
excursion
through a
course
called
bravida
in sao paulo
but i had
no previous
knowledge
only later
did i
try to
understand
what
happened
at that
moment
and you
managed
three
hospitals
is that
correct
in the
past
yes
but no
longer
i was
the
financial
director
of some
and the
technical
director
of others
the people
watching should
also be aware
you just
came off
of a
48 hour
shift
so it
makes me
even more
grateful
that you're
here
i want to
get into
the core
details
so what
happened
january
if you
could walk
me through
it
in as
much
detail
as possible
just play
by play
moment
by moment
i had
operated
on a
child
whose name
was eric
he had
cruzone
syndrome
and a
cranial
stenosis
cruzons
is a
surgery
that has
to be
done
on the
skull
and the
face
we did
the cranial
part
i operated
on that
child
and went
to my
office
nearby
i went
on foot
to my
office
to write
prescriptions
prepare
reports
and worried
about
eric
the whole
time
i didn't
lose sight
of him
when i
returned
after the
hospital
closed
i went
in through
the corner
where cars
couldn't
enter
and a
reporter
from a
very large
company
in brazil
called
heja globo
asked me
did you
operate
on the
et
i don't
know what
she's talking
about
there was
no social
media
at the
time
i thought
they were
talking
about
the
boy
because
he was
different
i didn't
even finish
the sentence
i just
said
that's
no way
to speak
of
someone
so i
moved
on
i went
into the
hospital
when i
entered
the
hospital
we had
a younger
colleague
called
marcus
vinicius
a younger
neurosurgeon
who every
time we
had surgery
to perform
would ask
for certain
instructions
as he was
very young
where to
open
draw
here
don't go
away
sit down
have a
rest
but that
day
he called
me
to an
adjacent
room
and said
look what
i did
he showed
me a
large
camera
with what
seemed to
be a
small
calculator
right next
to it
i looked
and didn't
understand
what it
was
for a
moment
it looked
like another
case of
cruzon
syndrome
it was
a child
it looked
like
one
but i
asked him
what is
this
he said
it's
here
he came
over
there was
a screen
a cover
right
i looked
got closer
and it
was there
there was
a being
there
totally
different
from a
human
being
he wasn't
an adult
he was
like a
seven
year
old
child
covered
here
the hand
inside
here
the hand
outside
very
calm
at ease
the skull
looked like
a drop
the eyes
also looked
like two
drops
lilac
not red
white skin
no foul
smell
at first glance
it looked like
casper the friendly
ghost
you know
from the cartoon
looked like him
but i looked
and the being
looked at me
very calmly
very peacefully
he looked out
the window
he looked back
at me
very calm
and i even
asked my colleague
and he said
what do you think
and we approach
and we approach it
as doctors
if there's
bleeding
pain
agitation
if breathing
is normal
if there's need
for emergency
care
so i said
okay
once again
what do you think
i looked again
it's not bleeding
it's not in pain
it's breathing
normally
no problem
everything's fine
the being
looked at me
as i always say
it looked at me
with a very
beautiful look
not a judgmental
look
not a look
of fear
it had the look
of someone
who understands
very well
what is going on
but it was
a different person
a different being
it wasn't human
at all
it wasn't
a case of human anomalies
it was a different being
i've been dealing
with humans
for 46 years
but back then
about 30 years ago
we knew how to tell
when it was
or wasn't a human
it looked at me
with a very
beautiful gaze
that left
a lasting impression
i usually say
that from then on
it feels like
you turn into
a different person
and at a certain moment
having a conversation
with james
and the boys
they asked me
what i thought
i said
it was a very
beautiful look
it moved me
i said
it looked like
an angel
looking at us
very much so
that kind of look
very understanding
very calm
very tranquil
like it's saying
i've known you
for a long time
don't worry
i know you took
care of me
but everything's fine
i'm back to normal
this colleague
had the video
he showed it
to several people
many people
watched this video
at his house
on his computer
and then james
and the others
were there
looking for the tape
where's the tape
i mean
if you saw the tape
it's wonderful
it's short
but it's a
different kind
of being
it's a being
that changes
the history
of humanity
because it's
the first time
we're seeing
a different kind
of being there
live
but i don't
have that tape
i told james
that if i had
that tape
i wouldn't
need to be
on duty
until today
i wouldn't
need to be
working
as much
as i do
and on
about the tape
and then i said
i don't have
the tape
he's already
dead
but i saw it
as soon as
i said
that i'd
seen it
james
started breathing
down my neck
everyone pressing
me
describe it
and i described
it a little
differently
from what
people saw
some people
said they saw
a green being
others a brown
being
red eyes
protuberances
i saw a calmer
being
i didn't see
all that
i don't know
if they had
already cleaned
him up
at the hospital
i don't know
the answer
that's just
what i think
and very calm
and then we
managed to get
into the hospital
for a bit
and i
apologized
to the hospital
management
but i should
have informed
them
that we
had entered
the hospital
where it
was
after that
we didn't
go in
anymore
and from
then on
james and
everyone else
started pulling
up the story
unraveling the
thread
gathering various
testimonies
from people
who also
saw it
and the big
problem
is that when
you talk
about this
it's difficult
for many
people to
believe you
me too
if someone
told me
i'd say
yeah
maybe
but i can
assure you
and especially
the younger
generation
who comes
after us
that i did
see it
i was there
i mean
there are
more things
than our
earth
and this
planet of
ours
and these
wonders of
ours
there are
even more
wonders
you see
and what
they ask
me about
his gaze
what i convey
is that
it was a
very calm
very peaceful
gaze
which i think
we really
need all
over the
world
so
in january
you
operated
on a
child
and then
you were
asked about
that and
so you
didn't know
about the
the et
being when
you were
asked about
that
and then
you walked
into the
hospital
and
you were
were you
assigned
to look
at the
being
by marcos
venesis
your colleague
or how
did you
just pass
by the
room
or
no he
happens
to be
my friend
i was on
my way
to the
pediatric
department
did he
want to
show you
this being
specifically
he said
i want
you to
see this
right
that's
come see
what i've
done
had you
heard
any
sort of
whispers
around
the hospital
that this
being
was there
no
so this
was the
first time
you just
walked in
you had
no context
and you
just see
this being
i only
realized that
the hospital
was completely
closed down
right
i went
i went in
because i
had been
the director
there
very well
known
wow
and um
so you
you see
the being
what do
what's your
emotion like
when you
see what
it looks
like
how do
you process
what it
looks like
how does
that sort
of sit
with you
immediately
when you
see
you know
this this
figure that
presumably is
like something
you've never
seen before
in the corridor
when he
said come
see what
i've done
whenever
someone says
that to
us who
have been
doctors for
years
we automatically
think it's
an emergency
and when i
went and
saw the
tape
and saw
the being
there was
a mixture
of surprise
and relief
because the
being was
all right
it wasn't
a medical
emergency
when we're
called
it's to
do a suture
to operate
to intubate
it was fine
and like i
always say
when i'm
asked what
did i
think
i could
examine
carefully
it's
conscious
it's not
in pain
bleeding
breathing
normally
it's not
an emergency
you can
think about
it
carefully
what did
marcos
venesis
tell you
about
the being
when he
shows it
to you
did he
give you
any
context
he said
i performed
a procedure
from what
i saw
on the
tape
there was
a little
basin
like this
an emesis
basin
and a needle
holder
he probably
gave stitches
it wasn't
a big
surgery
it was
a small
procedure
on the
tape
because when
i looked
at the
being
there was
none
of that
anymore
he was
just lying
there
with a
surgical
drape
one hand
in and
the other
out
like this
nothing
here
and it's
peaceful
the bed
positioned
upright
like we
do for
neurological
patients
they don't
lie down
completely
otherwise
the patient
might vomit
stays more
upright
and it's
very very
comfortable
and it
looked at me
in such a
beautiful way
i always say
that
you asked me
what impression
i had
to me
he was
okay
he didn't
need us
and had a
very beautiful
gaze
right
a look
without
judgment
physical
characteristics
you've
described this
before but
what exactly
did this
being
look like
human
i mean
humanoid
right
he had
arms
a chest
hal's wife
asked if he
had nipples
i didn't
see nipples
see a
nipple
lying there
like that
neck
very small
mouth
the eyes
like this
as if they
were drops
like that
lilac
just like
elizabeth taylor's
eyes
i'd heard
about it
so when
i saw
it
i was
like
whoa
liz taylor
was probably
an extraterrestrial
right
so the eyes
the skull
in that way
that
teardrop
shape
right
and very
peaceful
there was no
suffering
there
no suffering
at all
there was no
bad smell
no odor
no nervousness
nothing diabolical
a very angelic
kind of being
totally at peace
how tall
was the being
like a seven year old
child
yeah seven
do you have any sense
of the weight
i don't know
a child of about
seven years old
lying down
i didn't see here
you know
i didn't see down
there it was
covered you know
what was the nature
of the surgery
that was done
on this being
i think he only
gave a few stitches
but i'm guessing
right
i didn't see him
stitch it up
he must have
stitched it up
a few times
because the surgical
instruments in the
video were very
small
he didn't have
a surgical kit
many open tools
neurosurgery
is all about
boxes and boxes
of open tools
just like formula one
you know
did you ever ask
marcos venesis
how did you know
how to perform
surgery on this being
were the organs
similar to humans
oh that he already
he knew how to do that
he'd been working
with us for about
two or three years
but that's not much
time for neurosurgery
right
takes about 15 years
for a neurosurgeon
to mature
to gain the experience
to do things
like you guys here
you must have a lot
of experience
to be doing
this whole podcast
right
he knew what
he was doing
he wanted
confirmation
being young
and it was
something so
different
he wanted
confirmation
he wanted to
share it with
someone
and since i was
the one close
to him that day
because he shared
this with other
colleagues
other very
experienced
colleagues
doctors trained
in Belo Horizonte
and many that
were more
experienced than
me
but on that
day
i was
the one
there
so
it's almost
like he wanted
you to review
his work
and just
make sure
that he had
done the right
thing
yes
did he take
anything out
of the head
or it was just
what was the
purpose of the
surgery
i think it was
only to give
some stitches
from the
instruments i
saw on the
table
that i saw
in the video
because when i
went to look
there was nothing
there anymore
it was covered
up
it had already
happened
that's why he
said come see
what i've done
uh
okay so it
was um
not necessarily
surgically removing
anything
it was just
repairing
okay
yes to repair
that makes sense
because if you have
something that's
physiologically very
different than a
human being
uh if you had to
do something more
intricate or
complex on the
organ itself if it
wasn't something you
were familiar with
that would be much
harder obviously
did you learn
anything else about
the physiology of
this being
whether they had
the same
reproductive organs
as human beings
were their bone
structures the same
i can't say
because from here
down i couldn't see
anything it was
covered up
there was definitely
a bone structure
because there was
an arm a forearm
a hand and an
opposable thumb
as it's called
and three fingers
here
when you're looking
at it in the eyes
and do you feel
like time is
slowing or do you
feel any other
sort of special
interesting sensations
what you just said
is true
time slows down
it really does slow
down because he
didn't talk to me
he didn't speak to
me but the feeling
was as i'm describing
to you that he
understood what was
happening he wasn't
afraid he was highly
intelligent at least
more than i was it's
like talking to a
child you're talking
to the child the
child gives you
something you say
thank you it's okay
you can relax
he talked to me as
if i were a child
and what were the
words that were
transpiring was it
first of all was it
verbal was it
telepathic
like everything's
all right i can't
say it's telepathic
i have no knowledge
of you know
parapsychology i get
asked about this a
lot but that was
the feeling i had
the feeling that
everything was all
right especially
because of that
gaze you also have
a very calm gaze
so it was very
gentle very
understanding like i
understand what
you've done for me
here thank you
but i gotta get
going i understand
everything's fine
and he kept
looking out the
window i think
maybe to see his
surroundings perhaps
to see if he could
locate where he was
to situate himself
he wasn't locked
up he wasn't
restrained people
always ask me if he
was tied up of
course not he was
free if you had to
guess how many
witnesses at the
hospital saw this
being many people
say they saw it
nurses the
radiology technician
says he saw a
closed box but
as i'm telling
you it's difficult
to talk about
this subject people
say we're crazy
there's this thing
about neurosurgeons
being crazy
messing with the
human brain right
but it's difficult
to talk about it
many people
ridicule us
so did you
operate on
et was it
hard
marcos venesis
your friend
operated on the
being he
passed away in
between 1996
and 2018
did you ever
have heart-to-heart
conversations with
him like
marcos oh my
god we've
experienced something
profound and
talk about you
know speculate
what was this
being what were
his intentions
with us
at his house
he would show
that video to
all his relatives
all of them
there was a
sofa we'd go
in there was a
computer this
little table and
we'd sit here and
he'd show us then
he'd say did you
see this here
now he never
talked to me about
the military
never he never
talked to me about
any pressure
he was afraid
perhaps to talk
about it and
we're afraid even
today of losing
our jobs of the
government taking
away our own
medical licenses of
questioning us and
you lose your
medical license because
it's your source of
income we're doctors
our whole lives it's
our livelihood so
you talk but with
some reservation as
if you were a
patient you can't go
around saying i
operated on this
patient he had hiv or
he had this disease
i can't say any of
that if someone
overhears that i can
be sued so it was
a very private
conversation where
you speak but you
don't you know
in america we have
something called
hipaa which is what
you're saying you
know patient
confidentiality um
having said that
when the nature of
reality is on the
line i think what
you're doing is
exactly right and
correct and uh
yeah so let me ask
you a little bit
more about the
physical attributes
is there anything
else worth noting
about the the
blood the texture
of the skin any
other physical
attributes
the texture resembled
ours i can't say if
it was soft or not
because i didn't touch
it because i had just
come in from the
street and we have
medical training that
teaches us that when
you enter the hospital
if you don't wash
your hands a nurse
will already note
it down explaining
to others such and
such went in didn't
wash his hands didn't
put on his cap didn't
put on his gown and
the hospital management
then they put it
there the doctor went
in and didn't wash
his hands the doctor
went in and didn't
wash his hands the
doctor went in didn't
put on a mask the
doctor went in you
understand so i
hadn't i had just
walked in i wasn't
in the operating room
i wasn't in surgical
scrubs i was wearing
my street clothes just
looking so i didn't
touch it and i
approached it like
this i didn't get
that close about a
meter like the
distance between us
here but you could
see perfectly that
there was no smell
he was very clean
very calm i didn't
see any blood i
didn't see any blood
stains on the bed
were they taking his
biomarkers so oxygen
level heart rate those
sorts of things was
he being monitored for
no no no it wasn't
being monitored at all
because as i'm telling
you it was an improvised
location clean very
clean because the
hospital there is very
well maintained but it
wasn't an area used for
surgery it was an area
that nowadays is an
icu i'm saying he
i'm assuming gender
did you have any sense
of the being's gender
was it male was it
female no no no there
was none i can't really
say like i'm telling you
i didn't see nipples and
it had the look like that
of a child even many
times there are children
that you you can't tell
many times by the haircut
if they're male or
female it didn't have hair
or fur no fur so i
couldn't tell and in
our world there are
earrings lipstick or
some different haircuts
to differentiate but it
was a very very simple
being you mentioned in a
past interview with james
that the being was like
an angel what makes you
say that and that we
have a lot to learn from
the being you said that
as well yes we do because
it had a look i better be
careful i'm gonna cry
it's a look of
understanding a kind of
paternal and compassionate
look like it's saying i
know what you're doing but
it's all right it's fine
whatever you did to me it's
over now everything's all
right i don't know if they
arrested him or if they
beat him i can't say that's
what they say and a very
gentle very calm look like
go in peace there's hope
in your life keep moving
forward but that's my
interpretation right so
people wonder and ask was
there any contact do you
have this here like an angel
really looked like an angel
the kind of being that
would forgive your sins the
silly things you did in
life are an ability and we
did so little we could have
done perhaps much more for
it right but it's not that
we didn't want to we didn't
know how especially in 96 we
had almost nothing you know
we had the equipment of that
time we didn't have the
monitors we have today
cameras intercoms monitors
blood gas analyzers all those
things that allow you to
instantly diagnose collect a
blood sample take an x-ray you
know back then it was what we
call proctoscopy the doctor
looked and used the cognitive
parameters that we have right from
so much experience let's say our
experience that's why he called me and
i called others many times too and
asked what do you think of this we
talked the doctors talked a lot in
person because we didn't have social
media i'd tell a story you'd tell a
story we tried to operate as a team
because everyone would say something
different like be careful with this i
would do it this way i would do it
that way nowadays doctors are very
isolated and spend their time with
computers and targets which is fine but
it's a different kind of doctor a
different kind of person we had the
day-to-day experience i operate with
colleagues what would you do i would go
this way what would you do now now i
would leave you know that's enough i
always say this to the younger ones
that's enough so you told marcos
venesis you've done a good job and
there's nothing more to do essentially
you've done a good job that's it it's
all good will you call me if you need
anything i will you mentioned that the
being almost seemed to have control of
the room what did you mean by that total
control it understood what was
happening it's like when you see some
children play you're an adult you're
watching children play you're in
control you didn't fall you weren't
hurt you're calm you can touch that you
won't get shocked you're calm the
window isn't open you're aware they're
playing
what was your first instinct when you
saw the being is this being related to
humanity in some way evolutionarily or do
they come from some distant place very
advanced first like i said that
reassuring look indicating that it
wasn't an emergency
because for those of us who work in
hospitals there's like a button here
emergency
code red it wasn't a code red as you
said and mentioned very well time
stops it stops it belongs to him that
time was ours everything else doesn't
exist only that moment right there and
it would look at us as if it were saying
there's nothing but this moment anything
else is another reality and it's really
cool to see since you're asking me and
the words keep coming there's no rush
because the world today is in such a
hurry someone looks at you you're
already doing something else we do three
or four things practically at the same
time and there's no time to give time
the time it needs
you've mentioned a few times in this
interview that there was no smell many
of the other witnesses of the being
have said an ammonia or sulfur like
smell accompanied this being or the
craft crashing odorless no smell at all
if there was a smell it was the smell of
the hospital the smell of those products
we use in a hospital there was no bad
smell nothing at all do you know what
happened to the being so you see the
being how long were you with the being
face to face
initially about two minutes of looking
look this way look that way i turned to
talk to max vinitius okay etc etc i looked
again another one two minutes about three
four minutes in total it's like i told
james i'm going to the u.s but what i
have to say is this it was those four
four minutes but four minutes that felt
like an eternity i was still wondering
this morning we who work in intensive care
we examine a patient and we want to come
back the next day to see how they're doing
if they've improved if they haven't to this
day i still want to go back there to see if
he's left yet you know what i mean you get
worried not all patients we don't get
emotionally attached to everyone but we
do with some with children with the
elderly someone you saved you get
attached you leave and you keep thinking
about them right just last night i spent
the whole night asking myself about
potassium levels and you know overthinking
how did you sleep that night that you
saw the being oh i didn't i didn't
grasp the magnitude of everything that
had happened i didn't have the
perspective i didn't nowadays i have
more of it because of how much it's
talked about how much people think about
it nowadays i have a better grasp like
i said about last night overthinking
things it seems like even now
recollecting this memory it's packed
with emotion were you sad were you
happy or did this excavate some feelings
inside of you that you already had how
exactly would you describe the emotional
impact of this being at first it was a
relief because when he called me and i
saw it i thought it was an emergency
that we would have to intubate go into
surgery when i saw that everything was
worked out i felt at ease after that
a surprise because you see something
different different being
then you start thinking like a doctor
again could there be anything else could
there be bleeding somewhere there weren't
that many monitors so you just keep
looking then you start analyzing then you
calm down again and then looking at him you
you start to get emotional because you begin to see not so much the physical aspect but the emotional aspect the aspect of consciousness you start to analyze other things
consciousness mood whether he has the initiative to do things whether he's mobilizing himself whether he's afraid you see other things and as i said again it's the look that moves me a tranquil calm look i understand everything i appreciate what you've done here but it's time to go
it's time to go
let's go enough is enough he would even look up to the sky to get his bearings
because there's a window there without bars or anything you could see it perfectly
why do you why do you cry when you recollect the experience and what emotion comes up inside of you when you when you just when you think about it because nowadays doctors are criticized for everything they do
the colleague i mentioned max vinisius once we operated on a child and when i went to talk to the mother she started scolding me and he interrupted her saying ma'am he's the surgeon not the person that ran your child over
he did the surgery so when someone recognizes your work it's really great because our technical work is difficult it requires training but the hardest part for us doctors is enduring everything we see there's a quote from a famous gentleman from brazil called chico xavier where he says what you tolerate is just as important as what you know
so you can see that it's a form of recognition it was a being who understood that i was doing my best despite being limited it was the best i could do i was giving my soul everything i could do was being done for him and for me who was saying forgive me for anything but everything we know how to do is being done for you it really is moving it feels like you're still
stuck in that room and can never leave like a little piece of us stays there you leave the robot leaves a little piece of yourself stays there you go back there you know how did marcos venesis say that it affected him
oh a lot he even began smoking more he'd smoke all day i would argue with him and my wife would say stop arguing with him
i'd go in the bathroom and see a bunch of cigarette butts on the floor
marcos venesis smoking you're smoking no no it's not me it's my wife his wife didn't smoke
sylvana would say stop fighting with him so he took up smoking because of this experience with the
being was did it cause him stress no he already smoked but then he started chain smoking
one after the other
why do you think the experience accelerated his smoking
high level of stress you know really high level
stress you see being a doctor is stressful isn't it because wherever you go you're a doctor
if you crash your car you're a doctor if you insulted someone you're a doctor if you did this
you're a doctor right doc
so our lives aren't as simple as people say
we don't earn as much as people say our mental work is immense
you have to be polite even when you're tired
you have to you know you have to answer even when you're busy
the work of a doctor here in the united states you have a wonderful medicine
but the work of a doctor on the front lines
the young doctor is tough
you have to learn you have to see
there are endless meetings many sleepless nights
so going back to the question you asked me when he looked at us
it was already a look of
because otherwise it's just criticism
if you get it right you've done nothing more than your duty
anything you did even slightly different
you know it's like a fighter
he fights 50 fights
and the one time he didn't defend himself
our western society
hurts people
the more successful you become
the more criticism you face
you see artists
great artists
great singers
if they forget a piece of the lyric
all hell breaks loose
and how much effort was put into getting an engineer
you guys
even in your own work
if someone says they can't come in because of personal problems
our world is very cruel
and there was no look of cruelty there
there was a look of understanding
a gentle look
you don't come across a look like that
I have a wife who is a wonderful person
and she sees me that way
but most people are critical
critical critical critical
and this was moving because it was a maternal look
not even a paternal one
it made you feel good
saying you're good
you can go ahead
move forward
keep going
don't dwell upon it
moving forward
a forgiving look
a look of freedom
keep doing what you're doing
go
like Jesus would say
go forth and multiply
be fruitful
you know
did you ever ask Marcos Venesis
what was it like to do surgery
on a non-human entity
what could be an alien being
no he was also very worried
you know
he wanted our approval
so things wouldn't fall on him
nothing went wrong
because I think they took it away
we didn't continue
we didn't see how that procedure went
we don't know if it worked or not
whether it's alive or dead
they said they brought it to the United States
from Area 51
but I don't know if that's just folklore
you know
I don't know if that's true
who said that the being was transferred
to Area 51 in the United States
oh in Brazil the whole story
right Dr. Armand
is that the army took
the story
I can't prove anything
the story was
he was taken
carried to Campinas
to a very famous pathologist
a friend of Dr. Armandus
Palhares
and
that they then took it to Area 51
I don't know
that's what they say right
I'm just repeating what they tell me
were you a witness to the being
being removed from the hospital
did you have
do you have any details on that
no
I went into the room
he was there
I left the room
I didn't see if
he was taken or removed
I did see the army trucks
those trucks with the green tarps
they were all at the hospital entrance
my car wasn't there
I went in because I was on foot
I entered through the corner of the hospital
everything was cordoned off there
you've mentioned multiple times
that there is a video
around the surgery
that Marcos Vinicius performed
and that he would even show
people a video of
him essentially performing surgery
on this alien
where do you think that video is?
I always thought that his wife had it
she's also a very simple
modest person
I think she didn't understand
everything he did
because he really liked
collecting American watches
he collected stuff
you know
related to musicians
he used to love
buying lots of things online
gifts
you know
novelties
a new blood pressure monitor
a different kind of stethoscope
different things
but everyday items
cheap things to buy online
mostly American
so I don't know
if she managed to get it that day
James went there
they searched his whole house
you know
they took his computer
to a warehouse in São Paulo
they didn't find anything either
did they?
I don't know
but as I'm telling you
it was public property
everyone saw it
his whole family saw it
some fellow doctors saw it
but people don't want to talk about it
because like they say in the countryside
we depend on medical appointments
we depend on people seeking us out
if they say
that one operated on ET
don't go to him
that one's a smoker
smoked himself to death
drank himself dry
do you have any sense
of where this video is right now?
I think it's still around there
but they searched so hard
I don't think he
had the insight
to make a copy
and save it
for his wife
I don't know
if he actually did all that
you know what I'm saying?
to think
one day
they'll need that tape
I don't know
if he had the foresight
to keep it
you know?
so if you
if you had to guess
do you think
that the tape is
lying around
in private
civilian hands?
in his house
in the middle of a bunch of CDs
ah you think
it's in his house still?
yes
I believe so
like I was saying
he had the Breitler
watch collection
he had several watches
Omega
he collected a lot of stuff
a lot of CDs
you know?
you seem to be implying
that there's a connection
between his watches
and the video
what do you think
that connection might be?
where he kept it
he kept it hidden
in a separate closet
in his room
once a lot of his things
were stolen
after he
died
that's what his wife says
I don't even know
if the thief knows
what they stole
know what I mean?
because there was
so much stuff
they stole the watch
but there were
many other things
CDs
clothes
Jesus
like you said
no
yeah it was
a place
where he kept the stuff
he gave watches
to a lot of people
he gave away
his watches
a lot of souvenirs
he'd give them away
there have to be
other photographs
other videos
that were taken
at the hospital
do you think
somewhere
a video
a photo
is lying around
in private
civilian hands?
a lot of people
claim that
but you can't
really believe it
James knows
people have already
tried to sell
so many videos
to him
but they're not real
they're
very well
put together
with lighting
props
and lights
and of course
there was nothing
like that
at that moment
it was just
that little camera
actually a big camera
like the ones
from the 90s
you won't remember
you're young
but they were
really big
we put them
on our shoulder
like this
like those
TV cameras
there were no
small tapes
no cell phones
no internet
we didn't grasp
the magnitude
of all that could
happen
I at least
had no idea
about it
in 2023
you gave an interview
to Marco Leal
who's James'
co-producer
on his movies
a famed
UFO researcher
local to the region
and you told him
that you hadn't
seen the being
directly
you just saw
the video
and so
a lot of people
on the internet
and in public
are saying
you know
that's an inconsistency
in his statements
what do you have
to say about that?
well they're right
because I couldn't
tell everything
even in 2023
and I didn't want to
because it's not
as simple as me
being here
to be here
I had to pay people
to be on call
for me
I've exposed myself
to doing a lot
of things
we expose ourselves
to the medical council
censoring us
there are a number
of things
I'm not rich
I live off the work
I do
but when James
went looking for the tape
he looked for the tape
looked for the tape
he's going to offer
a million dollars
to
Marcus Vinicius' wife
if she has the tape
and when they
didn't find the tape
I'm in the ICU
and he's still
interviewing me
at one point I said
I can't prove it
I don't have the tape
Marcus Vinicius died
whatever I say
you either believe it
or you don't
that's a difficult
thing to accept
but I was in the ICU
I thought I was going
to have to be intubated
I had a pulmonary thrombosis
I thought I was going
to check out
I'm done
I had also had
a heart attack
then going back
to talking to James
where's the tape
at one point I said
I don't have the tape
but I was there
either you believe
my word
or you don't
but I was there
I saw it
and I told the whole story
that I'm telling you now
the entire sequence
and how emotional
I get when I talk
about it
I speak mainly
to younger people
I saw it
you can believe it
you cannot believe it
you can tell me
I'm this
I'm that
but it was right
there in front of me
do you believe it
or not
and there are so many
accounts that make
the load lighter
because as Dr. Armando
says he even came
with me
it's hard for one
person to talk about it
it's just my word
nowadays there are
other testimonies
that have revealed
more things
and some Americans
were there to encourage
us to come here
and talk
because they also
have accounts
it's just that they
can't talk about it
either
well in your
in your defense
my friend Amar
was just down
in Virginia
with you
and you were
speaking to you
but there was also
I think a nurse
there who had
worked under you
and for the first time
she started to speak
about this being
and it seems like
from his assessment
it's an open secret
among the hospital
people don't like
to talk about it
but if you really
question them
and they're in a
comfortable private
environment
they admit that
there's something there
I think what people
might be wondering
about in your case
because your credentials
are unimpeachable
in my opinion
but they might be
wondering why not
go from outright
denial
because you're
fear for your life
and because you know
it's hard to talk
about these things
to admitting
that you saw
the being
I think people
might have trouble
with the fact
that you said
you saw the video
and then you go
into seeing the being
and maybe that's
just nervousness
and not knowing
how to react
in these sort of
situations
but
like I said
not even to my
children
or my wife
I told my wife
this
this is a closed
subject
but as I thought
I was really
going to die
and I always said
to James
separate money
from what I'm saying
I'm not selling
anything
nothing
I don't need
to take anything
the little I have
is enough for myself
but people need
to know
that they have it
it's the religious
people who are afraid
I'm not talking
about religion
people say
it's a matter
of national security
that I couldn't
talk about it
so there's some
doctors who treated
a soldier
he was questioned
by the federal police
it's not so simple
to just speak up
people come to
demand consequences
councils demand answers
colleagues demand answers
there are so many
consequences
especially in Brazil
you yourselves
heard the other day
doctors treat a former
president
and the justice system
itself investigates
wanting to see
what happened
why he did this
why he did that
it's not total freedom
that we have
it's a monitored freedom
did anything
happen to you
did any consequences
occur
when you spoke
out about this
no
no but I am afraid
were you ever
threatened
my life is afraid
we're afraid of
everything
being attacked
being murdered
of religious fanatics
coming after us
it's not so easy
to talk
people insult us
on the internet
who gave you your car
I have such a basic car
have you ever been
threatened or bribed
no
it's only on the internet
that they're very offensive
I don't even look
do you know
anything about
possible American
involvement
you know
independent of obviously
what people
residents of Virginia
people in Brazil
might think
no
anything from
the hospital
as far as like
American CIA
or Air Force
it's based on
all the testimonies
and it's suspected
that some military
personnel know
but they can't
identify themselves
they give interviews
by modifying their voice
with their backs turned
something did happen
because so many people
say so many things
that they saw
so many sightings
they're talking
off the record
they tell us
I've experienced that too
an American soldier
I saw him
on the top of my house
but if I say anything
I'd lose my pension
in the US
I should also
defend you here
and say
the way you reacted
I think is normal
for somebody
who isn't
media trained
you're not a media
personality
there's a guy
Dr. Cesario
who's a cardiologist
and he has
a similar trajectory
in the way
his story evolved
where
it is clear to us
and we're about
to speak to
Dr. Armando
who literally
did the autopsy
on Marcos
Cheresi
this soldier
who apprehended
this being
and seemed to die
of a bacterial infection
that we've never
seen the likes of
before
and this cardiologist
who was in touch
with
in close touch
with Marcos
Cheresi
before he died
he would say
things like
Marcos
Marcos would tell me
that he was dying
of this
bizarre infection
it wouldn't stop
and that he thinks
it came
from
a possible wound
or
contamination
from this oily
kind of
emulsion
that came from
the skin
of the ET being
and
then he would say
things like
oh no
but his sister
told me
his sister
and he
wouldn't know
how to react
if you were
interrogating somebody
it would look
kind of bad
but it would look
bad
in so far
as
the real truth
being that
he actually
was in close
you know
touch with
and in communication
with Marcos
Cheresi
and so I just
I also want
people to have
that context
that if you're
not media trained
and you're not
savvy about this
stuff
and you're put
on the spot
by some
you know
UFO researcher
then
you might say
things that later
you know
you regret
as far as
the inconsistency
but it's
very natural
so
the day
we were
at Dr. Armando's
house
Dr. Cesario
is a very good
friend of mine
very reserved
extremely competent
but he also
has his reservations
because he has
been questioned
before
because he
tended to the
soldier
and he went
to the
federal commission
and when I
was asked
was he tied
up
Dr. Cesario
went
I
I didn't
see
was he
tied up
no
did you
ever
interact
with
Marco
Ceresi
at all
no
I
didn't
see
Ceres
no
we're
speculating
now
but what
do you
think
the
intent
of
this
being
was
with
humanity
at
large
so
people
say
that
they
saw
the
ship
being
shot
down
that
someone
fired
on
it
because
was
already
falling
when
it
arrived
that's
what
the
young
man
will
tell
you
he
saw
it
falling
must
have
fallen
there
by
chance
after
being
shot
at
I
don't
know
by
whom
but
the
ship
was
already
shot
down
that's
what
I
know
that's
what
I
think
that
he
didn't
go
looking
there
he
just
crashed
there
so
the
closest
place
with
decent
conditions
was
there
the
other
towns
are
smaller
many
cities
don't
even
have
nowadays
it's
a
much
more
developed
place
but
back
then
it
had
that
hospital
the
regional
hospital
I
want
you
to
describe
the
video
in
as
much
detail
think
this
is
important
because
if
a
video
surfaces
it
should
have
these
details
that
you're
describing
and
that's
good
corroboration
both
for
your
testimony
and
for
the
veracity
of
the
video
so
can
you
describe
the
video
so
I
went
into
the
room
doctor
was
over
here
there
was
a
big
camera
which
I
held
in
my
hand
it
had
something
like
a
calculator
small
here
and
then
the
black
and
white
video
a
being
with
a
slightly
larger
head
lying
down
surgical
material
it
was
like
what
we
call
an
amesis
basin
with
a
needle
holder
forceps
the
being
lying
there
looking
at
the
camera
like
that
without
any
sign
of
suffering
may
have
taken
a
minute
and
a
half
or
two
so
much
that
I
thought
it
might
be
a
child
with
cruzon
syndrome
because
of
the
slightly
larger
head
and
I
asked
him
what
is
this
he
was
beside
me
then
he
moved
over
this
way
and
he
said
it's
right
next
to
me
from
the
video
this
is
what
I
saw
black
and
white
a
child
with
a
larger
head
lying
down
in
the
same
position
he
was
lying
in
head
this
way
body
this
way
long
arms
and
very
calm
and he
was
conscious
he
was
awake
he
had
eyes
in
the
video
you
couldn't
see
if
there
were
pupils
because
it
was
black
and
I
don't
know
who
filmed
it
either
because
if
he
had
surgery
someone
else
intervened
or
someone
else
filmed
it
he
wouldn't
have
had
time
to
film
and
do
that
himself
the
surgery
itself
isn't
shown
what's
is
the
being
it
was
like a
post
operative
period
it
already
happened
he
keeps
telling
me
come
see
what
I
did
he
didn't
do
it
in
front
right
there
and
then
you
understand
and
the
material
that
I
saw
was
this
it
was
just
a
clamp
and
forceps
as if
a
stitch
had
been
done
like
we
do
in
emergency
rooms
so
much
the
location
was
improvised
did
you
see
the
video
before
or
after
you
saw
the
being
he
showed
it
to
everyone
over
and
again
several
times
we
would
go
to
his
house
he
would
show
us
things
he
would
show
us
watches
clothes
instruments
blood
pressure
monitors
video
before
or
after
you
saw
the
being
directly
I
saw
the
video
before
and
then
immediately
afterwards
I
saw
the
being
I
saw
the
video
before
so
that's
why
I
asked
what
is
this
I
thought
can
it
be
another
case
of
Crouzon
syndrome
I
imagined
so
but
it
wasn't
did
you
see
the
video
at
his
house
video
in
the
hospital
I
saw
the
video
as
soon
I
arrived
at
the
hospital
he
called
me
over
and
said
come
see
what
I
saw
come
see
what
I
did
went
down
to
that
area
he
showed
me
the
video
and
I
said
okay
but
I
didn't
understand
what
it
was
I
asked
him
what
this
could
be
another
child
with
cruzons
we're
neurosurgeons
not
craniofacial
surgeons
that
operate
cruzons
we
do
the
cranial
area
cruzons
are
done
by
other
professionals
they
perform
that
so
I
was
left
wondering
what
did
you
do
what
is
this
here
it
is
there
was
a
screen
I
don't
know
if
you
understood
the
sequence
makes
sense
if
you
have
Michael
do
you
have
anything
I
mean
I'm
still
unclear
as
to
what
exactly
the
surgery
was
and
did
he
look
inspect
or
observe
no
the
surgery
was
on
this
side
and
I
was
there
he
was
here
I
couldn't
see
this
part
other
side
from
what
I
understood
and
from
the
materials
on
the
table
and
the
location
it
wasn't
a
major
neurosurgery
operation
involves
boxes
and boxes
of
supplies
there
are
microscopes
microscope
covers
and
different
surgical
attire
not
there
that
was
a
makeshift
procedure
location
that's
where
he
put
it
together
from
what
I
understand
he
put
some
stitches
in
the
creature's
head
from
the
material
that
I'm
seeing
in
the
video
when
I
looked
at
it
later
there
was
no
material
left
it
was
already
clean
it
was
after
the
surgery
I
think
he
only
put
in
a few
stitches
because
there
was
a
needle
holder
why
didn't
you
look
closely
why
didn't
you
inspect
because
he
was
here
and
I
was
far
away
he
was
by
the
wall
I
was
over
here
I
was
preoccupied
with
other
things
as
I
said
we
get
worried
about
whether
they're
breathing
whether
they're
bleeding
if
they're
nervous
if
they're
in
pain
the
window
was
there
and
he
was
right
there
by
the
window
I
didn't
go in
behind
it
to
look
at
him
there
but
the
other
doctor
you
did
speak
to
him
afterwards
about
what
he
had
done
no
he
said
did
a
small
surgery
and
look
what
I
did
but
given
the
location
everything
was
for a
minor
surgery
a
stitch
something
like
that
they
didn't
have
the
necessary
materials
but
like
you
must
have
talked
to
the
other
surgeon
about
what
he
did
to
the
alien
afterwards
no
he
only
said
look
what
I
did
didn't
speak
to
him
after
about
what
he
did
I
thought
it
was
a
valve
I
understood
he
had
put
a
valve
in
the
being
then
afterwards
I
think
he
put
in
some
stitches
that's
all
what
he
did
was
very
vague
I
can't
really
answer
you
but
then
he
would
show
the
video
to
friends
and
family
did
he
tell
that
was
in
the
video
I
saw
look
but
did
anybody
ever
go
what
did
you
do
specifically
they
were
mostly
from
his
family
simpler
people
and
the
doctors
who
saw
it
many
times
we
many
times
we
didn't
even
believe
it
we
really
didn't
could
it
be
a
hoax
could
it
be
a
hoax
but
how
could
he
put
that
together
so
quickly
back
then
I
arrive
and
he
already
has
the
being
there
and
the
film
ready
I
mean
it
wasn't
something
that
was
planned
something
that
happened
right
there
and
then
it's
all
improvised
but
didn't
you
like
I
mean
it
seems
like
you
knew
him
for
years
afterwards
I
mean
didn't
you
ever
just
go
what
alien
why
oh
we
were
very
afraid
to
talk
about
it
we
don't
talk
about
patients
regarding
we
discuss
cases
when
you
have
a few
cases
you
talk
about
them
when
the
team
is
involved
that's
fine
but
otherwise
we
don't
talk
about
like
I
operated
on
that
there
I
did
this
over
there
that's
not
done
and
did
I
understand
correctly
that
when
you
arrived
at
the
hospital
that
TV
Global
was
there
and
asked
you
if
there
was
an
operation
on
the
alien
so
that
means
can
you
repeat
can you
say
specifically
just
because
the
details
are
so
interesting
for
us
did
you
like
when
you
parked
your
car
you
walk
in
because
there's
a
blockade
and
there's
TV
cameras
or
what
happened
there
I
didn't
have
my
car
I
had
operated
and
my
office
was
nearby
I
went
to
write
prescriptions
reports
I
didn't
see
patients
it
was
mostly
bureaucratic
stuff
and
I
was
worried
about
the
boy
when I
returned
it
was
closed
no
cars
could
enter
I
went
in
through
the
pedestrian
area
and
the
hospital
entrance
was
there
the
trucks
were
here
as
I
arrived
the
reporter
came
up
to
me
with
a
microphone
did
you
operate
on
the
ET
I
don't
know
what
she's
talking
about
and
I
think
one
question
I
know
that
the
audience
will
ask
based
on
Michael's
questions
which I
think
are
great
is
if
you
were
brought
in
by
Marcos
Venesis
to
review
the
surgery
because
he's
saying
you're
more
senior
guy
you're
more
senior
neurosurgeon
I want
you to
check
my
work
why
wouldn't
you know
the
exact
nature
of
that
surgery
because
I
hadn't
seen
Marcos
Venesis
yet
when
she
came
in
and
asked
about
the
alien
I'm
out
here
he's
in
there
there's
no
cell
phone
I
haven't
seen
Marcos
Venesis
yet
I
don't
know
what's
going
on
in
there
when
I
entered
the
hospital
and
went
down
to
the
pediatrics
no
not
from
the
TV
reporters
before
that
makes
total
sense
I
mean
generally
like
now
the
specific
surgery
that
was
done
why
don't
you
know
those
details
given
that
he
was
bringing
you
in
to
kind
of
check
his
work
and
review
it
as
a
senior
neurosurgeon
patient
was
okay
that
was
it
just
to
see
if
the
patient
was
okay
because
I
think
it
was
something
so
simple
that
he
had
no
doubts
just
a
stitch
he
was
inexperienced
but
not
that
inexperienced
he
performed
neurological
surgery
he
mainly
dealt
with
trauma
is
the
first
thing
we
learn
because
there
is
so
much
trauma
in
Brazil
he
had
no
questions
he
didn't
think
the
surgical
technique
I
used
was
correct
no
that
wasn't
the
point
it
gone
there
he
would
have
continued
seeing
patients
there
he
was
already
fine
he
didn't
need
me
he
only
asked
because
he
always
asked
it
was
more
of a
sign-off
someone
saw it
here
with
me
I
didn't
do
it
alone
but
I
didn't
do
anything
I
didn't
operate
he
did
it
alone
the
credit
is
his
now
I
don't
know
what
happened
to
him
and
since
I
thought
it
was
a
very
like
so
he
said
to
you
come
see
what
I
did
like
he
always
did
because
it's
a little
strange
to be
like
I
just
operated
on
an
alien
come
see
what
I
did
just
like
it's
a
normal
thing
or
was
he
did
seem
agitated
or
upset
at least
I
didn't
have
a
sense
of
it
until
I
saw
it
until
I
examined
it
until
I
calmed
down
that's
when
it
started
was
a
different
being
until
then
we
view
them
as
patients
at
risk
of
death
you
see
this
as
a
risk
of
emergency
when
he
called
me
it
even
distracted
me
from
there
hurry
to
see
the
other
one
then
and
there
I
realized
there
was
no
reason
to
rush
he
had
already
done
it
the
whole
issue
of
it
being
an
extraterrestrial
all
of
that
came
up
later
but
at
the
time
you
don't
grasp
the
full
extent
of
it
I
know
didn't
the
dimension
of
that
one
day
I
would
be
here
talking
to
you
but
it
seems
like
the
next
time
you
saw
him
wouldn't
you
have
been
like
dude
what
was
that
all
about
like
sure
and
you
had
that
conversation
and
what
was
that
like
sure
but
not
at
the
moment
it
when
did
you
first
talk
to
the
other
surgeon
about
what
you
had
both
about
the
aliens
I
only
spoke
with
Marcos
Vinicius
we
have
other
neurosurgeons
there
and
I
don't
know
if
they
saw
it
or
if
they
talked
that
sort
of
thing
that
you
don't
go
into
detail
about
you
don't
speculate
if
it
were
today
my
God
what
did
you
do
what
stitch
did
you
use
what
kind
of
thread
but
that
was
never
the
point
of
discussion
he
tended
to
the
being
it's
alive
okay
next
it
just
seems
I
think
it's
shocking
in the
sense
that
it
seems
like
you
were
treating
it
like
a
normal
patient
when
it
was
completely
alien
is
it
just
you
were
is
that
just
because
you
did
process
it
later
you
don't
have
all
this
awareness
that
you
are
having
that
I'm
having
now
we
never
imagined
we'd
be
talking
about
this
on
television
it
was
like
a
medical
secret
that
happened
period
nobody
will
talk
about
it
anymore
because
it's
dangerous
to talk
about
it
so
it's
like
when
you
say
this
patient
has
leukemia
or
when
for
the
first
time
HIV
emerged
you
don't
keep
saying
that
patient
is
HIV
positive
does
that
patient
have
HIV
no
you
write
it
down
so
sort
of
a
culture
of
discretion
like
you're
using
a lot
of
discretion
and
secrecy
is
because
it's
private
is
that
why
yes
okay
there's
an
ethics
committee
there's
the
CRM
regional
medical
council
there's
the
police
there's
the
press
anything
you
say
about
someone's
family
member
oh
he
said
my
relative
has
cancer
I'm
not
going
around
saying
that
what
do
you
think
I
don't
think
anything
the
TV
reporter
that
was
out
front
did
you
are
confident
that
they
were
with
TV
Globo
or
could
it
have
been
a
different
did
you
know
who
it
was
sure
because
it
was
written
there
and
I
always
gave
interviews
to
them
about
vaccines
meningitis
do
you
know
was
it
a
woman
or
a
man
woman
do
you
remember
what
she
looked
like
brunette
medium
stature
brown
dress
and I
didn't curse
because it
was
global
TV
you
operated
on
ET
do
you
know
who
told
her
no
idea
I
didn't
swear
not
because
I'm
very
polite
no
but
I
thought
at
the
time
if
I
swear
here
and
it
comes
out
on
global
if
a
doctor
gets
a
bad
reputation
that
he's
rude
crazy
and
in
the
countryside
that
makes
a
difference
and
but
was
she
waiting
when
you
left
the
hospital
was there
any
other
media
there
when
you
left
there
was
and
I
said
to
her
I
thought
she
was
talking
about
the
boy
because
I
was
taking
offense
on
behalf
said
that's
not
how you
talk
about
people
and
I
moved
on
I
didn't
finish
the
sentence
I
said
what a
fucking
lack
of
respect
did
you
when
saw
this
alien
being
in
the
room
did
you
make
the
connection
with
the
TV
with
the
TV
global
reporter
in
her
question
you
say
oh
that's
what
must
have
been
what
she
was
asking
about
no
oh
yes
later
right
I
said
she
was
right
did
the
hospital
ever
take
administrative
action
against
you
because
of
your
speaking
out
about
this
after
no
they
just
prohibited
me
from
filming
inside
and
that's
right
because
once
I
filmed
went
into
the
maternity
ward
with
James
in
the
room
where
it
was
they
reprimanded
me
because
I
shouldn't
have
done
that
they
were
right
the
hospital
is
right
about
that
to
film
something
inside
the
hospital
that's
why
the
hospital
management
had
permission
because
there
are
other
patients
right
it
could
have
happened
that
I
saw
another
patient
something
like
that
the
hospital
management
is
right
it
was
the
only
time
but
they
treat
me
very
well
when
Marcos
Vinicius
would show
the video
how did
he do
that
did he
show it
on the
TV
did he
show
have
the
camera
at
home
home
on his
computer
they
would
come
into
the
room
sit
on
the
sofa
he
would
sit
in
front
of
the
computer
and
maybe
a
CD
or
a
tape
but
I
think
it
was
a
CD
because
he
would
show
it
repeatedly
sometimes
so
people
would
come
over
here's
my
nice
watches
and
here's
my
alien
video
he
showed
other
cases
he
showed
other
cases
we'd
arrive at
his
house
and
he'd
put
on
a
show
yeah
look at
this
watch
look at
this
gadget
I
bought
to
measure
god
knows
what
look at
this
stethoscope
right
here
lots
of
souvenirs
you buy
online
right
look
at
this
Breitling
and
omegas
too
he gave
them
away
to
a
lot
of
people
I
even
my
wife
says
I
used
to
argue
with
him
a
lot
because
he
had
a
stent
put
in
his
heart
and
smoking
buying
watches
there
was a
time
why
was
he
able
to
I
mean
Breitling
omega
those
are
expensive
watches
so
expensive
how
did
he
have
that
much
money
neurosurgeons
at
one
time
made
a
lot
of
money
because
back
then
you
could
operate
and
when
the
patient
stayed
in
different
accommodations
you
could
operate
and
charge
for a
different
accommodation
that's
how
I
built
my
house
but
at
another
time
he
had
a
daughter
he
started
spending
money
on
race
horses
you
know
what
I
bought
a
horse
and
my
daughter
loves
them
it's
a
different
kind
of
money
and
now
we're
paying
for it
to stay
on a
breeding
farm
with
four
stints
in your
chest
that's
what I'd
say
with four
stints
in your
chest
can I
talk to
you
better
not
my wife
used to
say
stop
arguing
with
Marcus
Vinicius
but he
smokes
he
bought
a
horse
do
you
know
if
Marcus
Vinicius
ever
told
his
wife
or
his
daughter
anything
about
his
experience
and
did
he
speculate
about
this
alien
being
himself
in
his
private
life
he
did
sure
that I
can't
answer
his
wife
is a
wonderful
person
but
she's
a
simple
person
I
like
her
very
much
her
name
is
Rosalina
however
I
also
adopted
a
slightly
more
rational
stance
when
she
came
to
talk
me
she
had
a
bracelet
earrings
I'd
say
for
the
love
of
God
walking
around
like
that
you'll
get
mugged
you'll
get
ripped
off
you'll
get
slapped
oh
my
wife
said
stop
saying
that
to
them
I
used
to
say
Marcus
Vinicius
is
dead
he
gave
you
these
things
but
he's
dead
you
need
to
invest
that
money
you
have
a
daughter
he
didn't
leave
a
very
large
insurance
policy
you
know
what
I
mean
so
be
careful
did
you
speak
to
anybody
else
in
Virginia
or
in
the
hospital
who
was
face
to
with
the
being
and
compare
your
experience
with
their
experience
and
if
so
what
are
those
details
from
what
they
experienced
no
I
never
talked
about
any
of
this
at
the
hospital
nowadays
when I
talk
about
it
at
the
hospital
many
people
say
that
the
room
was
really
locked
that
this
really
happened
here
because
on
that
day
people
can
find
details
of
what
they
saw
but
it's
like
when
James's
team
was
in
Brazil
they're
getting
people
to
tell
the
story
to
incentivize
people
like
me
to
speak
and
they
put
the
pieces
together
because
nobody
saw
everything
right
each
one
of
us
saw
part
piece
of
it
I'm
completely
opening
my
heart
I'm
even
talking
about
Rosalina's
things
I hope
she
forgives
me
when
she
hears
this
I
don't
want
to
offend
anyone
you
know
but
this
shows
you
the
level
of
intimacy
involved
but
they
don't
say
what
kind
of
surgery
it
was
there
are
two
other
colleagues
that I
haven't
spoken to
about
this
but
does
anybody
else
say
I
looked
the
being
in
the
eyes
and
it
felt
like
an
angel
it
felt
non
judgmental
peaceful
loving
anybody
else
that
you
know
knowledge
that
was
my
impression
at
that
moment
you
know
has
this
experience
made
you
more
religious
in
any
way
more
spiritual
bit
more
realistic
you
know
a
little
more
realistic
because
I'm
already
pretty
old
I
won't
be
around
for
long
so
mainly
to
give
hope
to
you
younger
people
that
yes
it
is
possible
whether
you
believe
it
or
not
there
are
beings
that
are
different
from
great
pleasure
getting
to
know
America
here
I
found
it
very
beautiful
I
love
Americans
you
saved
us
in
the
world
wars
I
love
Americans
I
had
a
jeep
from
the
war
in
memory
of
the
war
I
really
like
American
soldiers
extremely
trustworthy
and
I
really
like
the
stories
when
Americans
return
from
the
war
and
reunite
with
their
families
those
testimonies
scenes
are
very
beautiful
I
thank
America
for
being
here
and
God
save
America
if
you
had
unlimited
resources
and
money
you
knew
that
there
would
be
no
negative
repercussions
what
would
you
do
to
get
your
hands
on
this
video
what
would
be
the
first
action
steps
for
finding
it
I
go
back
to
his
place
and
I
have
to
go
through
everything
once
again
and
I
would
need
to
hear
this
story
about
the
robbery
because
some
of
his
watches
were
stolen
from
his
house
and
he
had
a
cabinet
in
the
corner
of
his
room
at
the
back
where
he
kept
his
watches
where
he
kept
his
CDs
souvenirs
you
know
that's
probably
where
he
put
it
she
lives
in
the
same
house
she
lives
there
but
about
the
robbery
that
happened
there
I
need
to
talk
her
I
heard
that
many
of
his
watches
were
stolen
but
I
didn't
go
there
I
never
went
back
to
his
house
again
there
must
have
been
during
like
from
until
when
you
started
talking
about
this
in
you
must
have
people
in
town
must
have
talked
about
this
or
you
were
there
when
he
showed
these
videos
and
these
conversations
were
happening
what
kind
of
conversations
did
you
hear
people
talking
about
in
relationship
to
Virginia
and
what
was
or
in
relationship
to
the
alleged
alien
and
what
was
your
own
response
to
did
you
feel
like
I
should
be
worried
or
what
was
that
experience
like
hearing
other
people
talk
about
Virginia
I
work
in
the
ICU
and
there
are
nurses
who
know
the
girls
that
saw
it
Valkidia
and
of
them
so
there
are
nurses
who
know
the
girls
who
saw
the
extraterrestrial
they've
had
it
rough
because
they're
criticized
they had
to change
schools
because
of
bullying
nobody
made
any
money
from
this
they
remain
in
the
same
city
giving
the
same
testimony
they
weren't
able
to
get
their
passports
approved
to
come
here
because
they
don't
have
stable
jobs
right
they
have
simple
jobs
you
know
but
the
three
of
them
stick
to
it
the
same
there's
no
reason
to
talk
about
this
if
it
weren't
for
that
oh
I
won
this
I
won
that
they've
been
promised
a lot
but
they
they've
been
persuaded
to
change
their
stories
to
say
they
didn't
see
anything
you
know
I
met
them
the
other
day
we
talked
about
the
same
thing
the
difficult
part
isn't
telling
the
story
difficult
part
is
being
accused
of
lying
hearing
that
none
of
it
happened
accused
of
making
it
up
just
dinner
together
it's
the
same
thing
it's
not
what
we
had
to
endure
get
to
this
point
you'll
hear
other
testimonies
people
don't
believe
it
they
have
every
right
to
of
course
it's
something
that
changes
everything
but
and how
would you
describe
your own
reasons
for staying
quiet
for so
long
were you
just
afraid
of
people
making
fun
of
you
were
afraid
of
being
fired
like
what
was
the
core
fears
or
I guess
what
prevented
you
from
speaking
out
until
now
to
this
day
because
we
have
jobs
we
don't
have
any
other
source
of
income
it's
the
everyday
work
it's
being
on
call
a
lot
of
nighters
very
little
sleep
car
bills
cell
phone
bills
school
tuition
fees
for
our
kids
the
greatest
fear
is
because
people
really
come
down
hard
on
us
what
do
you
hope
for
the
world
to
understand
through
your
testimony
and
why
are
you
coming
forward
now
and
in
the
United
States
that
is
a
wonderful
question
what
I
think
they
come
to
tell
us
is
peace
because
we
live
in
this
world
in
a
tiny
piece
of
the
Milky
Way
on
the
periphery
of
the
Milky
Way
right
and
we
fight
all
the
time
we
mistreat
our
neighbors
brothers
I'm
not
trying
to
make
a
religious
speech
I'm
not
religious
at
that
level
but
so
that
we
respect
each
other
more
as
Freud
said
if
we're
going
to
coexist
we're
going
to
have
agree
on
what
to
him
about
what
is
he
going
to
excommunicate
me
there's
no
need
to
there's
more
to
it
in
my
father's
house
there
are
many
mansions
so
that's
the
risk
of
being
exposed
by
a
media
that's
much
more
powerful
than
us
it
crushes
us
they'll
spin
a
narrative
that
destroys
you
your
career
destroys
you
as
a
person
they
destroy
your
morale
self
esteem
it's
very
easy
and
very
dangerous
to
talk
about
this
just
as
there
are
people
who
like
it
there
are
people
who
don't
to
many
people
it's
of
no
interest
to
them
it
ruins
their
business
right
it ruins
various
types
of
religions
that
say
we're
the
center
of
the
universe
it
ruins
everything
it's
something
not
worth
believing
in
but
for
some
people
it's
good
to
see
that
there's
so
much
more
so
much
more
we need
to
evolve
a lot
regarding
we've
evolved
a lot
from a
technological
point
of
view
but
very
little
from
a
social
point
of
view
very
little
do you
have
any
information
on
the
alien's
condition
when
it was
taken
to
the
hospital
exactly
what
it
was
bleeding
or
was
anything
occurring
with
the
body
specifically
no
there
isn't
but
the
story
I
know
is
that
if
it
went
to
the
hospital
it
was
an
emergency
they
thought
of
taking
it
to
the
zoo
that's
the
story
they
would
take
were
an
animal
but
then
they
took
it
to
the
hospital
if
my
colleague
took
it
there
and
stitched
it
up
it's
because
he
must
have
been
bleeding
heavily
blood
is
what
then
so
if
it
went
there
and
was
taken
quickly
to
that
place
it
must
have
been
bleeding
that's
what
I
think
otherwise
it
didn't
need
to
be
there
it
was
breathing
normally
it
wasn't
in a
coma
it
wasn't
intubated
because
critical
patients
get
intubated
they
get
an
IV
drip
it
didn't
even
have
an
IV
drip
nothing
had
been
injected
into
what
would
eventually
happen
as I
described
putting
in
stitches
that's
why
I
think
they
took
it
to
the
hospital
and
then
took
it
away
are
you
familiar
with
any
colleagues
friends
other
witnesses
who
experienced
the
so-called
men in
black
phenomenon
of
somebody
coming up
to
them
and
telling
them
they
can't
speak
publicly
about
this
or
again
bribes
threats
anything
like
that
no
there
is
one
from
Dr.
Cesario
but it
was
regarding
the
police
officer
and there
is a
report
from
the
officer
who
saw
a
dead
being
I
saw
a
living
being
I
was
talking
to
Dr.
Carl
just
now
he
was
saying
that
they
have
a lot
of
descriptions
a lot
of
things
he
separated
them
very
well
physics
and
biology
he
is
a
physicist
this
is
a
physical
and
biological
matter
he
says
when
a
living
being
is
involved
it
changes
our
conversation
right
so I
invited him
to go
there
right
he
can
stay
at
my
house
for
as
many
years
as
he
wants
to
do
research
there
there's
a
project
to
research
the
place
there
where
it
was
you
know
where
they
appeared
it's
a
vacant
lot
that's
still
there
today
in
Vagina
the
land
is
fenced
off
but
there
are
visitations
the
story
goes
that
JJ
Benitez
went
there
and
collected
soil
to
see
if
there
was
any
radioactive
material
there's
the
testimony
spacecraft
picked
up
a
piece
with
his
hand
very
interesting
as
well
that's
it
how
many
witnesses
do
you
know
personally
and I
realize
you're
estimating
you don't
have to
come up
with the
exact
number
on the
spot
but
many
people
when you
talk about
it
everyone
has a
story
to tell
I
also
saw
it
I
also
had
an
opportunity
I
play
countless
people
say
it
saying
that
Bobby
Fisher
saw
it
I
was
talking
about
Carl
Bobby
Fisher
was
tired
of
saying
that
the
Russians
did
this
to
him
Bobby
Fisher
look
it up
that
he
would
play
and they
would
come in
and there
were
gurus
Russian
parapsychologists
influencing
that a
person made
a move
but it
was a
computer
generated
move
and they
were in
I study
a lot
I played
chess
I almost
played
professionally
he says
that all
the time
an impossible
move
a
god
move
they'd
say
ah
he did
that
because
the
people
used
to
meet
in
that
room
the
Russians
would
meet
in
that
room
and in
doing
that
he
already
had
a
certain
computer
some
kind
of
calculation
even
those
calculations
from
that
wartime
coding
and they
would
play
around
with
it
and
another
thing
they
had
studied
my
games
they
had
all
my
statistics
they
even
knew
what
I
was
going
he
was
a
genius
one
of
the
greatest
geniuses
here
in
America
so
what's
the
connection
between
Bobby
Fisher
and
the
witnesses
yeah
the
contacts
oh
in
chess
several
people
have
already
seen
it
I
have
a
very
large
group
they
say
they've
already
seen
it
there's
a
lot
here
on
my
phone
I've
seen
it
too
I've
seen
it
too
I've
seen
it
too
people
who
play
the
piano
I've
seen
it
too
I've
seen
it
too
I
play
a
little
too
those
online
forums
a
lot
I've
seen
it
too
I've
got
it
right
here
people
who
play
chess
say
they
saw
the
people
who
play
piano
I've
seen
it
I've
seen
it
come
out
of
the
piano
it's
funny
I
just
interviewed
a
guy
who
is
president
of
the
world
chess
federation
for
years
and
his
name
is
Kyrsan
Ilyumzinov
and
he's
a
president
of
a
Russian
republic
last
guys
to
play
chess
with
Bobby
Fisher
after
Bobby
Fisher
had
already
retired
he
was
kind
of
paranoid
and
he
says
first of
all
he said
he was
abducted
by
aliens
or
taken
by
aliens
invited
onto
a
spaceship
while
he
was
sitting
president
of
his
Russian
Republic
of
Kalmykia
in
and
he
also
says
that
and
this
is
the
more
speculative
part
of
the
interview
he
says
that
the
game
of
chess
comes
from
aliens
and
I
don't
know
well
can I
go a little
further
yeah
go
in order
to talk
about
this
I wrote
a short
story
how
could I
examine
the
ET
if I
didn't
have
a
CT
scan
if I
didn't
have
anything
so
it's
a
chess
game
called
the
Universal
which
is
a
chess
game
it's
not
my
invention
it's
Adriano Caldeiras
the
Brazilian
champion
it's
his
invention
since
testing
the
ET
we
took
him
to
a
place
and
played
chess
so
I
didn't
need
to
make
the
move
he
already
knew
the
move
so
you
wrote
a
short
story
about
the
alien
already
knowing
how to
play
chess
intuitively
yeah
fascinating
the whole
story is
there
you just
need to
know how
to play
chess
my story
is there
it's written
down right
there
very amazing
yeah
I don't
I don't know
what to
make
of it
you know
he also
told the
story of
one of
the greatest
chess
players
you know
playing a
simulation
or something
before he
was about
to play
a big
tournament
and the
moves
made
themselves
and he
attributed
it to
some sort
of alien
intervention
but all
of this
is very
speculative
Dr.
Italo
look it up
James
has it
the
universal
chess
game
fantastic
I'd love
to read
it
amazing
well Dr.
Italo
Venturelli
I'm so
grateful
for you
coming to
the United
States
and giving
your testimony
thank you
to Michael
Schellenberger
guest co-host
on American
Alchemy
who's remarkably
proficient
in Portuguese
and I
really hope
you gave a lot
of details
here
that people
can be
skeptical
but you
gave details
that my
hope is
are corroborated
in the future
let's try
to find
this reporter
from you
know Brazil
from Virginia
was it
TV Globo
and then
let's also
try to find
this video
and try to
find more
corroboration
because as
far as
background
and pedigree
and you
know no
incentive to
lie
all of those
things go
like you're
pretty as
good as it
gets in my
book
and
thank you
yeah I
just I'm
very I'm
very grateful
thank you so
much for
for doing
this
thank you
hi my
name is
Jose
Marcos
Moreira
I'm a
cardiologist
from Virginia
but I
know nowadays
I'm still
in São
Paulo
and I
met Dr.
Italo
since I was
a child
he's a
very serious
guy
man
and I
believe
in his
history
about
the
AT
of
Virginia
because
he's
a very
serious
man
and I
really
believe in
him
and you
have another
friend
who's a doctor
oh yes
and I
have another
friend
his name
was
Fernando
Eugênio
unfortunately
he died
in
and
he told me
he was
passed
in the
hospital
regional
in Virginia
and he
saw the
fit
of the
creature
in the
regional
emergence
and
I
believe
him
because
he was
a very
nice
guy
a very
serious
guy
too
that's
what I
have to
say
roughly
three hours
after the
girls
witnessed
the
strange
creature
military
police
officers
Eric
Lopes
and
Marco
Ceresi
drive
down
this
road
on the
lookout
for
something
unusual
when
suddenly
it
runs
right
across
their
path
it
was
captured
by
Marco
Elixerez
with his
bare hands
easily
and taken
to the
hospital
apart
from
second-hand
rumors
of what
took
place
inside
the
hospital
made
by
anonymous
sources
little
is known
about
what
happened
to the
alleged
alien
the
driver
Eric
Lopes
has
been
in
hiding
and
the
officer
who
handled
the
live
being
Marcos
Cherees
died
a couple
of
weeks
later
so
who
are
you
what's
your
name
and
what's
your
background
professionally
and
your
education
my
name
is
Armando
Fortunato
Filho
I'm
a
forensic
physician
which is
forensic
medicine
I'm a
public health
physician
I'm an
occupational
physician
and I also
have a
bachelor's
degree
in law
I'm
married
to a
Peruvian
psychoanalyst
and have
two daughters
who are
also
doctors
first of
all
I would
like to
thank you
for your
invitation
and congratulate
you
on your
audience
I confess
that in
hundreds of
interviews
I've given
throughout
my life
I've never
initially
participated
in a
prayer
before
beginning
an
interview
as you
did
with
all
of
us
present
here
so
may
God
bless
us
Jesus
Christ
said
I am
the
way
light
the
truth
and
the
life
so
may
we
be
blessed
in
this
interview
and
may
we
bring
the
truth
here
Amen
well
said
January
you
lived
in
Virginia
obviously
I want
to
speak
to you
about
the
autopsy
of
Marco
Cheresi
week
of
what
had
happened
you
heard
of
anything
going
on
in
Virginia
when
it
came
to
UFOs
alien
entities
being
treated
at the
hospital
anything
like
that
when
the
body
of
soldier
Marco
Cheresi
arrived
there
was
no
mention
of
contact
with
extraterrestrials
the
body
was
sent
for
autopsy
investigation
into
a
possible
professional
error
because
he was
a
soldier
in
the
state
military
police
of
Minas
Gerais
and
because
he
had
an
infection
it
seems
that
a
drainage
procedure
a
small
surgery
was
performed
by
a
doctor
within
the
military
police
battalion
and
because
the
illness
progressed
very
rapidly
abruptly
in
a
few
days
the
commanding
colonel
of
the
military
police
requested
an
investigation
into
the
cause
of
death
that
soldier
to
improve
the
investigation
because
he
didn't
understand
how
a
military
police
doctor
could
let
a
soldier
die
we
did
the
autopsy
there
was
an
incision
wound
it
was
probably
a
drainage
procedure
for
an
infection
a
boil
an
infection
in
the
left
armpit
area
and
this
was
the
only
lesion
that
was
found
we
collected
blood
samples
fragments
of liver
stomach
and lung
tissue
and sent
them to
the laboratory
of
Dr.
Antonio
Batista
Macuco
Janini
a renowned
pathologist
in our
city
who was
also a
forensic
pathologist
in Rio
de Janeiro
but in
Varginha
he worked
as a
pathologist
he had
his own
laboratory
and is
a
very well-known
scientific
figure
in Brazil
Dr.
Janini
issued
a report
stating
that he
died
from a
pulmonary
infection
that caused
septicemia
which is a
generalized
infection
regarding the
bacteria that
were found
I'm leaving
Dr.
Janini's
report here
for you
and what
we have
recently
learned
is that
this soldier
may have
participated
in the
capture
of an
extraterrestrial
being
and Dr.
Janini
also
personally
reports
to all
of us
Dr.
Janini
said
recently
last year
that the
bacteria
found
in the
material
examined
in the
laboratory
is not
common
in our
country
and that
the bacteria
was extremely
virulent
and which
are very
progressive
deviating
from the
norm
of everyday
practice
in Brazilian
medicine
and that
he did not
rule out
given the
circumstances
that had
come to
him
that the
bacterium
could be
an alien
bacterium
so
I'm saying
here that
I personally
haven't had
contact with
extraterrestrials
neither has
Dr.
Janini
but the
bacteria
found in
the
soldier
is
leading us
to this
conclusion
indeed
because
Marco
Elixerez's
sister
said that
he had
contact
with an
ET
from
Varginha
so
we have
a new
situation
today
after 30
years
Dr.
Janini
is suggesting
and requesting
authorization
from the
court
it's not
easily done
the first
difficulty
is getting
the court
to approve
the
exhumation
of the
soldier's
remains
of soldier
Elixerez's
remains
and whether
the family
would agree
to it
to investigate
if possible
DNA testing
to better
study the
bacteria
that caused
this infection
in such
a young
soldier
who
had
vigor
and was
healthy
Dr.
Armando
sorry to
interrupt
I want
to just
ask you
point blank
what do
you think
caused this
infection
do you
personally
believe
that Marco
Cheresi
apprehended
this alien
being
and
he received
an infection
from it
that is
more exotic
than
any sort
of infection
that a
person would
get through
something more
ordinary
the infection
he had
is extremely
rare
not
impossible
but its
virulence
and severity
caught
Dr.
Janini's
attention
a scratch
or some
sort of
contact
with an
extraterrestrial
shouldn't
be ruled
out
I would
say that
the first
possibility
diagnostic
hypothesis
is still
a secondary
effect
of surgery
an infection
in the
axillary
skin region
hydrodonitis
but also
as a second
hypothesis
given the
circumstances
I've heard
from the
testimony
of
Dr.
Italo
the
recent
anatomopathological
evaluation
by Dr.
António
Macuco
Janini
and the
history
of Marco
Elixerenzi's
sister
one should
consider the
possibility
of post-contact
contamination
with an
extraterrestrial
during a
military police
operation
him being a
soldier in the
Minas Gerais
state military
police
Is there any
other plausible
story?
Had he received
surgery before
this happened
at all?
No
He was a
vigorous and
healthy soldier
who a few
days prior
had a skin
lesion
drained at
the military
police
medical
clinic
and it's
possible that
the infection
spread
that's the
first hypothesis
but the second
is that he
contracted the
infection
from a
scratch
from contact
with an
extraterrestrial
being
I say this
after so
many years
based on the
testimony
I'll say it
again
based on
Dr. Giannini's
new testimony
from a
laboratory
standpoint
anatomopathological
from the
testimony of
Marco
Elixerenzi's
sister
and also
from the
account of
Dr. Italu
Venturelli
who claims
to have
seen the
AT at the
regional hospital
in southern
Minas Gerais
How many
weeks between
Marco
Cheresi
transporting
this alien
being
and him
passing away
and you
doing the
autopsy
how many
weeks?
I don't
have the
exact dates
for the
supposed
operation
and
infection
I know
he had
an outpatient
surgical
procedure
not in a
hospital
Marco
Elixerenzi
at the
military
police
battalion
on an
outpatient
basis
but that
this
infection
lasted
around
12 or
14 days
he went
through
three or
four
doctors
complaining
about
lumbosciatica
a kind
of back
pain
and then
taking
antibiotics
and any
inflammatory
drugs
but the
infection
spread
and developed
into
septicemia
causing
death
from
generalized
infection
pneumonia
and
septicemia
had he
told
anybody
else
at the
hospital
I think
what's
happened
to me
is actually
from
this
ET
that I
had to
deal
with
did he
tell
anybody
else
this
no
from
what I've
seen
only his
sister
suspects
he had
contact
with her
but no
doctor
I only
received a
body
without a
history
to
investigate
whether
there was
professional
error
or
negligence
anything
any
malpractice
on the
part
of a
fellow
doctor
what
about
cesario
the
cardiologist
dr
cesario
was on
duty
at the
medical
service
that
operated
like
an
emergency
room
and
the
soldier
had
been
there
a
few
days
not
sure
three
times
complaining
of
back
pain
which
was
actually
an
infection
that
was
progressing
noto
cesario
treated
him
like
that
i
don't
know
if
it
was
once
twice
or
three
times
and
also
confirms
albeit
indirectly
that
the
infection
was
indeed
surprising
and
progressed
in a
very
abrupt
rapid
manner
i
believe
cesario
said
that
essentially
marco
shereci
had been
telling
him
over
and
again
that
this
was
actually
possibly
from
this
ET
being
that
he
had
apprehended
but
i think
this
is
from
because
he
goes
yeah
he
said
that
you
know
this
stuff
had
happened
because
he
was
concerned
about
saving
his
own
life
according
to
his
sister
yeah
so
he's
like
he
said
it
and
then
he
goes
according
to
his
sister
i was
like
okay
yeah
if
i was
dying
i'd
be
like
here's
what
happened
i don't
know
yeah
very
interesting
and
what
which
hospital
is
this
that
you
were
at
where
you
did
the
autopsy
coroner's
office
which
in
brazil
is
called
e-mail
the
forensic
medical
institutes
is linked
to the
civil
police
of the
states
and
provinces
it's
the
criminal
investigation
police
that
investigates
crimes
preparing
police
reports
which
are
handled
by the
chiefs
of
police
so
in this
exceptional
case
a
commander
of the
military
police
barracks
opened
a
military
police
investigation
because
the
lieutenant
doctor
who
performed
the
surgery
drainage
was
part
of
the
medical
staff
as
a
private
civilian
who
i'm
sure
has
many
friends
in
virginia
did
you
hear
other
stories
just
organically
come
up
around
people
seeing
crafts
or
bodies
anything
like
that
yes
if
you
walk
throughout
the
city
there
are
always
reports
of
people
who
have
seen
spaceships
people
who
have
seen
lights
in
the
sky
moving
quickly
just
like
spaceships
but
sometimes
they're
confused
with
comets
other
times
they're
drones
but
in
brazil
it's
a
country
that
receives
many
visits
from
these
objects
it's
a
privileged
country
in that
sense
but
there
are
always
reports
and
the
more
you
talk
about
it
the
more
people
hear
about
it
and
start
saying
as
Dr.
Italo
said
very
well
now
people
are
starting
to
talk
about
it
more
frequently
you know
if you
had to
put a
number
on the
amount
of
friends
or
even
just
people
you've
encountered
who've
witnessed
either
the
UFO
or
the
body
what
number
would
you put
and I
realize
that
I'm
putting you
on the
spot
here
and that
it
doesn't
have to
be an
exact
perfect
number
very
few
friends
because
for
example
Carlos
who
said
he
saw
the
craft
with
a
very
strong
and
trustworthy
testimony
he
doesn't
live
in
Varginha
unlike
Dr.
Italo
who
we're
familiar
with
as
doctors
a
person
with
credibility
a
history
of
many
years
of
service
to
neurology
brain
surgery
in
Varginha
and
nearby
towns
people
with
a
reputation
so
their
testimonies
are
very
powerful
and
which
makes
me
give
credibility
to
the
possibility
brought
up
by
Dr.
Janini
that
this
bacteria
that
was
found
with
the
soldier
Marco
Elixeresi
whether
it's
alien
this
backs
the
testimony
of
the
girls
who
are
now
ladies
in
Varginha
who
are
also
reputable
people
and
it
makes
one
believe
in
the
testimony
of
Carlos
himself
who
saw
the
craft
today
just
this
morning
talking
to
and
this
is
forever
listening
at
home
with
the
scientist
Can
has
can
ant
gone
art
and
to
understand
that
And I made the suggestion, Dr. Giannini wants to investigate this bacterium, if possible,
in the remains of Marco di Cerenzi, to better investigate this bacterium,
whether it may have been combined with a bacterium from another planet in the Universe, outside planet Earth.
But the location where the spacecraft is believed to have crashed also needs to be studied,
because metallic residues, things that are not common in our Universe, should be studied more thoroughly.
And that's why I asked Dr. Giannini today, who was in talks with other scientist friends,
about the possibility of undertaking this study or not.
Because the listener here wants the truth, he expects the truth from us.
We have no vested interest. Our only interest here is to tell the truth.
We are very small in this Universe.
There's so much to be discovered out there.
And from what we feel, from what Dr. Italu perceived,
extraterrestrials are at peace, they live in peace.
They're curious, but they live in peace, and can contribute a lot to us.
So, since man has reached the Moon, why not advance a little further?
And of course, it's no longer just the Varginha ET.
He is a Brazilian ET, an American ET, a Chinese ET, a Russian ET.
He belongs to all of us, to the planet.
And why not investigate this better, for ufology to advance further, right?
Even recently, didn't you speak to friends who had seen the craft?
There are people who have seen things like that.
When James Fox returns to Varginha, I'll introduce him to another three or four people,
who report having seen spaceships, lights…
Now, you see the difference, right?
Some say the spaceship had lights.
Our professor here, who gave the testimony, Carlos, said it was tubular and didn't have lights, right?
So, there are things that sometimes involve two spaceships, you know?
So, the witnesses are that common, though.
Like, James, how many witnesses do you think you've spoken to, total?
Well, when I went downtown to the town square, I found a number of people that either saw…
I mean, within an hour, I probably had 12 different people saying different things.
One of them saw excessive…
A couple of them saw excessive military activity they'd never seen before.
Military trucks everywhere.
If you were to add up everybody, though, and put an approximate number on it…
Oh, God.
And a witness, is anybody who's seen a ship or an alien body?
Ship or alien body?
Ship, maybe 12 to 15.
I met another one recently who said he saw it over the hospital, maybe 15.
And then the alien body, I think it's up to five.
Wow.
Yeah.
It's pretty amazing.
Yeah, and one of that includes the chief of police.
I don't know any other case where you have that many witnesses.
Then the three girls, Italo…
Well, the nurse, that would have been six.
So, it could be six that saw the…
Yeah.
Can you speak a little bit to Italo's credentials and kind of Bonafide's background?
Because I think having a neurosurgeon come forward and say he was face to face with an
alien being for three to four minutes is just going to be, A, so earth shattering for so
many people, but B, I think very hard for them to compute.
And I think they're going to often try to throw the kitchen sink of skepticism against this case.
What's your experience of Italo?
And what do you know about him and his reputation and his skills as a neurosurgeon?
Dr. Italo is a very experienced doctor.
Has a lot of credibility.
Very honorable.
Dr. To give this recent account of having personally seen and witnessed an extraterrestrial.
And one of the reasons I'm here is because he's the one who gave the testimony.
So, I trust in him.
Now, of course, it's not common.
Maybe if it were me on that day and I had seen the ET, I would have told my wife, my colleagues,
would have called the hospital and said, look at this, how interesting.
Each with their own reasons.
Each with their own particularities and singularities.
And I respect that.
I don't depend on a private practice to make a living.
He's a neurologist with a private practice.
And this could really be a reason for losing clients in a private practice.
With people thinking he was crazy, that he was seeing things.
It could harm him professionally.
And he justified his reasons.
So that's plausible.
It's understandable.
But it's not common.
I think perhaps most doctors or any citizen would have said, look, folks, there was a different
situation today inside the hospital.
But we have to respect it.
And Marco Charisi's family to this day maintains that his injury was probably due to an alien
being and that he was saying towards the end of his life constantly that he was worried
that he was sick because he had apprehended this being and held him.
And apparently the alien was full of kind of this greasy, oily substance.
And that might have gotten on to him.
And he was asking questions about what might occur if you come into contact with that because
he was not feeling well.
So his sister's testimony regarding the virulence of the bacteria, this leads us to believe that
he may have participated in an operation to capture the CT.
But that's not what I received through the colonel who requested the autopsy.
He's a forensic doctor.
But years later, that's what has been reaching us.
And there are testimonies saying that from Marco Elicerenzi's sister.
And also because of the evidence regarding the characteristics of the bacteria that was found in the soldier.
What did the colonel say when he tasked you to do the autopsy?
What did he share with you about the details?
He didn't speak to me.
The request was for a written coroner autopsy of the soldier.
And it's not common for someone who normally requests an autopsy to be a police chief.
It arrived, and they can also request it, just as the public prosecutor's office can request it for an autopsy.
We performed the autopsy, awaited the lab tests, and about 20 days later we released the report,
after the material from Lotto Giannini arrived.
But I didn't speak with the commander of the military police.
The autopsy was done to investigate an error, a supposed professional error, which was later not proven.
Professional error.
It was a progression of the medical complication.
The doctor who performed this minor procedure, an excellent professional, has a very good reputation in the city.
There were no complications.
The progression of the disease was extremely unfavorable.
Tell me about Dr. Giannini and his background.
I think a lot of people found it very powerful in James' movie,
when you have a guy who's kind of known as the godfather of medical science in the local region.
And he's coming out and he's speculating.
He literally says he thinks that a puncture wound from the nail of the ET is what caused Marco Scheresi's death.
He sent it, and I've already left it with you, signed.
He couldn't be here today because of health issues.
He's almost 90 years old.
But he's keeping up to speed with us.
And made it a point to send us signed and authenticated document so it could be read, and I already left it to your care.
But who is Dr. Giannini?
He arrived in Varginha about 50 years ago, probably 45 or 50 years ago.
He came from Rio de Janeiro and Brasília.
He was a university professor, a pathologist and a forensic doctor in the state of Rio de Janeiro.
He arrived in Varginha and set up a diagnostic and laboratory service, the Propedutic Institute,
which serves practically 90% of its patients through the SUS, the Unified Health System.
He serves the public health service.
He's a reference for doctors working in the public health system.
Today, he and his son, along with their entire staff, serve more than 100 cities in the region.
So, he is a reference in quality.
I'm not going to advertise, but it's true.
He's a man unconcerned with monetary values.
He values quality in his work as a scientist, seeking excellence in care and quality.
And for us doctors, he always has been, and still is, a reference.
Because he's a true scientist.
And in this case, every time it was me, Dr. José da Frota, Dr. Ulisses Fernando, the forensic doctors there,
when we had a more delicate case, when we had doubts, we would call him.
And he'd be very willing, because Varginha is a small town, everything is nearby.
I'll be there in 10 minutes, I'll assist with the autopsy.
And he would assist, which sometimes meant performing the procedure, collecting materials.
Said he'd take them to his laboratory, and giving the results in a week.
And sometimes during the autopsy itself, during the examination, as a great pathologist,
he would already give diagnoses.
So, not only in forensic medicine, and in the area of autopsies, laboratories, biopsies.
He's a huge reference.
So, he has our respect, and we are very grateful to him.
The doctors of Varginha have great respect and gratitude for Dr. João Batista Macucuzanini.
Was there anything else about the body, outside of the bizarre bacteria, and Marco Charisi's stated story that he kept repeating with his family,
that makes you think maybe there was some alien involvement?
Was there a smell to it? Was there anything else about it?
I hadn't met the soldier when he was alive.
The first time I saw him, it was a body, ready to be autopsied.
I never met him. I did meet some relatives.
But not him. I had never seen him.
But the sister's testimony, which is questionable.
It's said that maybe he spoke to the doctors who tended to him at the hospital.
But I don't have the testimony of those doctors that tended to him.
But I heard his sister saying, which was recorded recently,
that he was indeed involved in the capture of the ET.
So, it's a puzzle.
There are several moments we have there.
People close to Varginha, who saw a ship the size of a bus heading towards the city in those days.
For instance, take the testimony of the girls who saw the ET during the day.
Today they are ladies.
It's been 30 years. There were girls then. Today they are ladies.
You see the testimony of Professor Carlos, a geography teacher,
who gives a powerful account of having actually seen the spacecraft and its wreckage,
and that he even touched it.
But the police took it from him and ordered it handed over to the army.
You also see the testimony of Dr. Italu.
So, this makes us believe, in fact, in the existence of extraterrestrials on Earth.
Not the Varginha ET.
But this is a subject that interests the United States, Japan, Brazil, China, Russia.
It's a matter of greater interest to humanity.
We have to search more and advance further.
Have you done any thinking about, theoretically, why this bacteria would look like bacteria
occasionally found from wounds or occasionally found in animals and pets,
but is very rare in humans and very rare to kill a human and to be so virulent?
Do you ever think about, you know, if these beings are coming from, you know, thousands of light years away,
why they would contain any sort of bacteria that might match ours?
Have you gone that far in your thinking?
That's an interesting question.
This bacteria exists on Earth.
It's extremely rare, but it exists, to our knowledge, this type of Staphylococcus.
But also, the soldier, I mean, the alien or extraterrestrial,
came into contact with animals at the zoo in Varginha.
Some dead animals were found at the zoo.
I wasn't aware of this at the time, that some dead animals were found at the zoo.
Which begs the question, could it be that the extraterrestrial could have been contaminated,
coming in contact with the animals and then being captured by the soldier,
and therefore the soldier being contaminated by the extraterrestrial
with the bacteria that was in some zoo animal?
Or is the bacteria, in fact, alien, you know?
That's why we're asking, and I brought this up with Dr. Hau this morning,
that the CIA, NASA should support us with all the knowledge they already possess,
with all their wisdom, technology and diagnostic capabilities.
Brazilian medicine is very advanced,
but American medicine also has its particularities.
Perhaps the two of them together could conduct a more thorough scientific study
of this bacteria, if the exhumation is authorized,
and also of the material that must have residues where the spacecraft fell.
I posed this challenge to Dr. Hau, asking you, the American people, to help us.
Who told you about the ET's interaction with animals at the zoo?
This is already public knowledge. This has already been reported.
James Fox should know about it.
I don't know which animal died. Maybe James, Fox, maybe knows.
There were animals that died at the zoo during that week.
So, James, I'm curious. Do you know what the nature of that interaction was?
I don't think I included that part in the film,
because there's so many different aspects. There were sightings later.
They were like, now I'm coming to the conclusion,
I think there were like a lot more beings than what were initially reported that were seen.
And what did you hear about the beings?
Well, we interviewed the, I guess what do you call a zoologist or the guy that, yeah.
Yeah. Or a zookeeper, maybe?
Yeah, he was a little more than that.
So, okay, a zoologist would be like the scientist.
Yeah. And he talked about that their cause of death was completely unknown.
Never seen anything like it. He said it all on camera.
Marco Leal could tell you more.
But do we know anything about like the specific animals that the ET interacted with?
Was it a cattle mutilation situation? Were they like playing in a playpen or something?
They were exposed to some sort of bacteria that killed him and that he'd never really seen it.
But again, I'd have to, I have an interview with a guy. I just have to reflect back on it.
So those animals ended up dead.
Yes.
Were they typical cattle mutilations with the blood missing and incisions?
No, no, no. More like just got exposed to some sort of bacteria that killed him.
Got exposed to some sort of bacteria.
So that would point towards the bacteria maybe not being animal.
But it's so, it's just, what fascinates me so much about the bacteria is that it's something that's rare but exists on Earth.
Well, here's what Dr. Janini told me, and he told me this on camera.
He'd never seen anything like it before or after.
Is that your experience as well?
Never seen anything like this bacteria before or after, Dr. Armando?
My medical practice is more focused on companies, occupational medicine, and more on private practice.
My colleagues who work in the intensive care unit, the infectious disease specialists, don't see this type of infection, this kind of bacteria, on a daily basis.
It exists, but it's extremely rare.
And normally this infection is treated with antibiotics.
And in this case, despite being a young, strong, vigorous soldier, the bacteria led to his death in just a few days, less than 10 days.
So that's why this bacteria is different.
It's not common, and it's very virulent and highly lethal.
Sounds like the anomalous component of the bacteria is just how virulent and lethal it was.
I think it was like the term used was, you've never seen an advanced bacteria of this strain behave the way it did ever before or since.
And even Cesario, who was working on him, it's like, I threw the kitchen sink that should have, all the antibiotics I gave him should have saved his life, but it didn't do anything.
Like it just, because I've never seen anything like it before or since either.
So it was an adaptation or an evolution of a particular bacteria on Earth, but that they haven't seen on Earth that type of evolutions.
It's the best way he described it to me, as a neophyte, so.
Now I'm offering criticism of the commander.
I don't know if he's alive or not, nor do I know his name.
Constructive criticism, of course, of the commander of the military police barracks.
Because a medical complication, which of course must be investigated, but not with such a fervorous desire to perform a witch hunt, as was done with a fellow doctor, a medical attendant who worked at the barracks,
who spent years having to explain this to the justice system, and that it was confirmed that there was no professional error or unfavorable outcome.
An extremely atypical case, a progressive illness with pulmonary complications, very rapid, which thoroughly stressed his doctor and his family.
Of course, he was acquitted later.
But the commander went a bit overboard in his investigations with this soldier, because the bacteria was not common.
So there was no professional error.
There was a complication, an unfavorable evolution in a clinical case, and a strong soldier.
But it should be investigated.
Dottor Giannini is correct in requesting authorization from the justice system for new studies of this bacteria, if it exists.
But the problem is that it may still be present in the remains.
There may still be surprises.
It's remarkable to hear people consistently of your stature, credentials, academic background, and well-spokenness just consistently talk about friends who've seen beings and crafts or talk about anomalous bacteria.
You know, I think this is a really remarkable case, and I've said this with the other two guests today who I'm honored to have spoken with.
But it's just, I think, the modern Roswell.
It's the modern case that really is just there's so many witnesses.
It's an overwhelming amount of evidence and beyond any sort of threshold of a doubt that something occurred here.
And I agree with you.
I think it's very worthy of investigation.
And so I really appreciate you coming out, Dr. Armando.
And I guess my final question would be, has this at all affected your faith at all?
You started off with a prayer.
You invoked Jesus Christ.
Does this affect your worldview in any way?
Or has this affected you kind of emotionally?
No, it didn't change me.
I'm a Christian man, a doctor with great dedication to the public health system.
I was the municipal health secretary during the pandemic in our city.
I have experience in public health, occupational medicine, and forensic medicine.
So you see, my life, my father was a pharmacist, my mother was a primary school teacher,
and I had great difficulty to study at a federal university, a public university.
So I've always used medicine as a way to serve.
I believe that this Varginha case deserves further study, but the work that our friend James Fox has been doing,
this investigative work he has been doing, is remarkable and deserves our applause.
And Varginha is very grateful to him.
Now, I extend the invitation I made today to Dr. Hal, who is this physicist, extremely dedicated to science,
and to you as well, Jesse, to go to Varginha.
If the ET went to Varginha, why can't you go as well?
Get to know our reality.
It's a pleasant city, a city with a wonderful climate, welcoming people,
and continue these investigations with James Fox's team.
You have a lot to contribute.
And you ask extremely intelligent questions here today.
You're even acting like a police detective investigating us.
Congratulations.
Thank you very much for your work.
Well, when you put it like that, I can't say no.
If an ET being traveled from thousands of light years away,
I can certainly travel probably under a thousand miles.
But I'm very grateful for you.
I really appreciate you coming here and all your kind words.
Of course.
And you're clearly very sincere and earnest.
And was there anything else strange about the bacteria that's worthy of noting?
No.
What I want to bring attention to is that Dr. Janine brought up the possibility a year ago
of performing the exhumation of the remains of the soldier
to see if it's possible to trace the bacteria,
to investigate it more thoroughly.
and with regards to its virulence, its DNA, that is, if it is possible,
but to study the remains, rather the DNA of the remains of the soldier.
But wasn't there something about it?
I'm not understanding.
Yeah, because I heard it yesterday too.
Yeah, yeah.
Dr. Iola was talking about it as well,
that there was some sort of genetic,
it looked like there was some sort of genetic engineering done to the bacteria.
I, you know...
Was there some sort of genetic engineering?
Dr. Janine, who is the professor of the subject,
maybe he can even talk to us via video about it in person.
He also gave a statement that's really good.
It's better to talk to Dr. Janine.
I'll pass it on.
We'll talk to him.
He gave a really good statement.
Yeah.
Because James, you think the bacteria might have been manipulated or edited in some way.
I'm just telling you what was told to me.
I'm not a scientist, but he said he's done thousands and thousands of these things.
He's never seen any bacteria behave in the way that it behaved.
And I believe he said it was a strain that's found on Earth, rarely,
but that it behaved in a way that he'd never seen bacteria.
It was an evolution of a bacteria that he'd never seen on Earth.
Amazing.
Okay, well, to be continued.
High virulence, high pathogenicity, with very rapid lethality.
And this is coming from the Minister of Health,
who was appointed to basically protect Virginia during the pandemic.
So obviously you have, I think, the background to say such things.
The pandemic, yes, three, four years ago.
Dr. Armando, thank you.
Really appreciate you.
James, in typical James Fox form, has sacrificed himself.
We were going to do a one-on-one interview, but we're kind of pressed for time.
And you can get me any time.
Who cares?
I just want to close out in saying that your selflessness just generally in this field is extremely rare.
I think it's the reason that I always, when people ask, you know, are we ever going to get like concrete evidence?
I say, you know, I'm not sure, but I hope James gets it if we do, because you are doggedly persistent.
You've been back to Brazil over the past 15 years, multiple times a year.
I was there three times last year, and I'll be there again in a week.
It's incredible.
And you, again, because we sat down a few weeks ago, you saying, you know, just interview them, is very typical of your orientation towards all of this stuff, which is always give it away, give it to the community.
It's for the world.
And so I truly, I can't thank you enough, because you teed all of this off.
And this is this is going to be a beautiful piece and hopefully new information for the Western world on this.
You know, there's not much more than I think, you know, I can do beyond your amazing documentary.
But I think seeing them in kind of a long form podcast format with another, you know, semi trusted voice.
I think I think, you know, we'll be we'll be helpful in what you're doing in D.C. as well with all of them.
I think we'll we'll hopefully just add fuel to the fire and momentum to this whole this whole cause.
So, so grateful to you and Alini, who's here as well.
And yeah, I don't even know what to say.
And go watch Moment of Contact.
And go watch go go watch both moments of contact.
Go watch this latest one is incredible.
The footage you got is just remarkable, especially with Italo Venturelli, but also with Dr.
Giannini, who you, you know, work closely with.
You have all of these guys who you cannot their their credentials and stature and backgrounds are unimpeachable.
And you have them in tears broken down about this experience.
And you like you said, it's you're talking about, you know, 15 to 20 total witnesses if you're talking about, you know, ships and bodies.
So I'm so, so grateful for you.
Oh, hey, I appreciate I appreciate your contribution, your continued contribution and your continued investigations and support.
We're in this together.
Okay, Marco.
Jesse, I love you.
Oh, my God.
Everybody's very happy here, Jesse.
I love it.
And I love you, Jesse.
Absolutely.
And we love you.
But ultimately, there's people that you can go without feeling and breathing.
Please tell us about creating my mástice.