There's a live arrest warrant out on you now, right?
You can't go to the U.S. now.
I'm on the Interpol Red List.
The biggest military computer hack in all time.
We talked about the case of computer hacker Gary McKinnon,
on which the Prime Minister has expressed very clear views.
Well, I'm Mr. McKinnon.
We have proceeded through all the processes required under our extradition agreements.
I was just a guy, normal guy, interested in UFOs,
happened to have some IT skills, nothing genius level.
You hacked into the Army, the Navy, the Air Force, the Department of Defense, and NASA.
They wanted to put you in prison for 60 years, so...
Yeah, 70.
For 70 years.
And I bought potassium chloride, and I was just going to swallow it and have a heart attack and die.
Oh, my God.
Mr. McKinnon is accused of serious crimes.
The reason that you are here today on this show is because what you found...
He found, he says, photographic proof of alien spacecraft
and the names and ranks of something he called non-terrestrial officers.
I was in my dressing gown up to, like, four in the morning, smoking weed, drinking beer.
Right of my life, really.
The first one I looked at was the one where I saw the picture.
And, um, so I double-clicked this.
But it was very, very slow.
I was on a 56K dial-up.
And, uh, I was just thinking, my God, this is my eureka moment.
Then there's, like, slowly a hemisphere started appearing.
And I'm thinking, fuck, that's a planet.
What the hell?
And then suddenly there's a big, straight, kind of silvery line.
Cigar-shaped object.
I see the mouse moved, and someone else is at the computer themselves.
They right-clicked, disconnect, and boom.
And that was it.
I was cut out.
What do you think photographed it?
Very good question.
This spreadsheet was titled Non-Terrestrial Officers.
So, not on the Earth.
And that was incredible.
I had one very strange experience that I can't explain to this day.
I was suddenly woken up by a really sharp pain.
Then, immediately, I just went, oh.
In my left heel, there were two perfectly circular holes.
Wow.
Weird.
Explain what's going on quickly.
I can't turn my phone off.
You can see my finger is on the power button and both.
This is, like, a hard reset.
That's never happened before.
Absolutely, it's never happened before.
But you're with Gary McKinnon.
Ignition Frequence Drive.
How is this possible?
Nothing too unusual about that.
The existence cannot longer be denied.
Before we dive into the incredible story of Gary McKinnon,
I want to shine a light on one thing his story reminds you of instantly.
Online privacy.
Gary is a brilliant self-taught hacker who pulled off what the Pentagon called the biggest military
computer hack of all time, all from a bedroom in London.
In this interview, Gary goes into extreme detail about what he found in some of the world's
most sensitive files.
And I still can't wrap my head around what you're about to hear.
After hearing what he found, you might think he hit the ultimate UFO disclosure jackpot.
However, the moment he went online, a digital trail started forming.
Think about the moments most of us could get exposed.
It won't look like Gary's story, where he broke into sensitive government systems,
saw something truly unbelievable floating in space, and then had his access cut off mid-session.
For most of us, our risk exposure is usually much simpler, like joining hotel Wi-Fi, airport Wi-Fi,
or even your office network.
Going incognito doesn't hide your browser from the Wi-Fi owner,
and your internet service provider can just log what you do online.
That's why I use ExpressVPN.
It encrypts and reroutes my traffic through secure servers and masks my IP.
I literally turn it on before doing sensitive research for the show.
Like looking into whether mid-century scientist Thomas Townsend Brown cracked anti-gravity in
the 1950s.
That's exactly when I want my browsing to stay private.
So if you're like me, and you like going down crazy rabbit holes,
make sure your research isn't exposed on whatever Wi-Fi you're on.
Thanks to our sponsor, ExpressVPN, you can now get up to 4 extra months of your ExpressVPN
service by clicking the link in the description below at expressvpn.com slash AmericanAlchemy.
That's expressvpn.com slash AmericanAlchemy to get the privacy you deserve.
Thanks again to ExpressVPN for sponsoring today's historic episode.
Because if Gary's story teaches us anything, it's that your online privacy matters.
Legend has it that in 1943, the Navy tried to teleport a ship in what's now known as the
Philadelphia Experiment.
And it kind of worked.
It disappeared, reappeared, and then half the crew got atomically fused into the ship's walls.
Others just vanished.
No one was where they were supposed to be.
Talk about a breakdown in communication.
And you know who was leading the whole project?
My favorite, the mid-century anti-gravity inventor, Thomas Townsend Brown, who literally had a
nervous breakdown that year due to the very poor communication among the team members.
You know what that sounds like.
Your team.
Before you had Quo.
This year, upgrade your system to a workspace that keeps your team from shattering across
dimensions.
If you've ever tried to schedule a meeting across five time zones and six platforms, you
know the absolute horror of losing people to the ether.
That's why today's episode is brought to you by Quo, spelled Q-U-O, the smarter way to
run your business communications.
It's a single streamlined command center for calls, notes, transcripts, chats, even AI summaries.
An all-in-one shared reality.
Yours.
No vanishing.
No fusing into calendars.
Just your team.
Fully entangled and synced across time zones, timelines, even caffeine levels.
Make this the year where no opportunity and no customer slips away.
Try Quo for free, plus get 20% off your first six months when you go to Quo.com slash Jesse.
That's Q-U-O dot com slash Jesse.
Quo.
No missed calls.
No missed customers.
Now back to the show.
This is such an honor.
I am here with, uh, he's been at the top of my list of people I've wanted to interview
for years now.
And, uh, I'm so lucky to have this opportunity through James Fox, the great documentarian,
uh, Gary McKinnon.
Oh, thank you.
I'm glad to be here.
I love your channel.
Um, I've been a long-term subscriber.
So yeah, I really like a lot of the interviews you do and I'm glad to be here too.
Let's, let's just go back to, uh, the early 2000s.
Tell me the year and the day and, and, and tell me about your life at the time.
And then I want to get into the actual, you know, event.
Okay.
Um, I can't remember the day, but the year was 2000, early 2000.
And, uh, my life pre to that, I'd always had a deep interest in UFOs, um, mainly for my
stepdad.
Um, he used to live in Falkirk, which is near Bonnybridge, which is in Scotland.
It's like a Scottish UFO hotspot, uh, many, many sightings, almost like a tourist attraction.
You know, people go there to see UFOs.
And, uh, I had one sighting myself, uh, when I was about 12 and, um, I was looking out of
my bedroom window and I saw this kind of reddish orange glowing light and it was moving in an
arc from there to the horizon.
And it was, um, but it was like Brownian motion.
It wasn't a straight line.
Um, it was like wiggling around and, and just thought, what on earth is that?
Um, and I was also a member of Bufora at the time, the British UFO Research Association.
Yeah, I was hooked from an early age.
And so I guess it only made sense that eventually I'd try and do something to
further my own interest and find out more.
Um, but unfortunately it involved breaking the law.
Sorry, mom.
Um, so, so you, you already have an interest in UFOs.
Had you seen a UFO or like, you know, just that one sight, just that one sighting.
Okay.
But I had my stepdad stories.
He'd seen them.
Um, his brother, my step uncle had seen them.
Yeah.
And, and, um, and so you have this personal interest and then do you have like a hacking
background or like, do you have any sort of like cyber background?
Are you really good with computers?
Um, no hacking background.
I used it, I was good with computers.
I had, uh, I started off an Atari games console in like 78, 79, and then eventually got the
Atari computer, learned to program in basic at first, and then machine code, assembler language,
uh, moved up from that.
And, um, then eventually got jobs in computing, very low level jobs to start off with network
installation, windows configuration.
Um, then did, uh, computer science degree, uh, which I eventually failed because I spent
too much time in the student bar.
Um, but yeah, so I eventually ended up contracting with a bank, it's quite high level stuff, but
doing very basic sort of networking stuff.
Hmm.
So I had a good background in networking, especially windows, knew how they communicated and some
Linux stroke, Unix, Solaris, stuff like that.
Um, so when, I mean, the internet came to Britain in 95, I think I first had the internet.
And, uh, the first thing I searched for was UFOs and, uh, it was very popular, loads of
websites, loads of information and, um, fast forward about five or six years, I read the
Disclosure Project book, Stephen Greer and his team.
And they told you installations, locations, and I thought, I've got to have a look at this.
I wanted it from the horse's mouth.
I didn't want to just believe, I wanted to know.
And so I thought I could use my basic networking skills just to do a scan, you know, a light
scan on American military networks, which, which is mad now.
But back then it was just kind of like a playful idea.
And, um, I wrote a Pearl script, Pearl is, um, programming, extraction, reporting language,
just a scripting language.
And that I could run that across thousands of machines in minutes and find a blank passwords
or passwords that were either blank or password admin, a basic list.
And, um, when you do like wide scale phishing like that, you do, you know, some fish bite.
And that was my basic method to getting entrance to these places.
And so some of these extremely sensitive American military sites had blank passwords.
That's crazy.
I mean, it, although that seems beyond belief, it also makes sense.
Like the government's way more incompetent than often, especially people in UFO world give
them credit for it because we assume they have workable reverse engineered crafts that they
know how to use at will or where.
So like what you would, of course would have passwords set up, but two thousand is early
internet.
We're still worried about Y2K, you know?
So like we didn't really understand how a lot of this stuff worked.
It was this big experiment.
And so, wow.
So that, that sort of phishing thing came up with some, some fish.
Yeah.
And as you said, the government really isn't tailored for this, especially the military.
Um, they don't, well, they didn't then employ specialized IT workers.
They trained up existing military employees in the, you know, basic techniques to run a
network.
So there weren't advanced security aware guys running government networks or military
networks.
And are you, so while you're doing this, are you just like sitting in a apartment or something?
It's a bit embarrassing.
Um, my girlfriend and I at the time, we were living in her auntie's house on the ground
floor.
And, um, I was in my dressing gown up to like four in the morning, smoking weed, drinking
beer, just like right of my life really for, you know, a young ish guy.
I think I was 36 at the time.
So, yeah.
I, uh, you know, I don't think that's, um, embarrassing for you.
I think it's embarrassing for the sites you hacked into.
Um, okay.
So you're, you're, uh, you're getting a little late night buzz and you're, you know, you're
at your, your, your girlfriend's aunt's house and you're just like, I want to find, I want
to know for myself what's going on in UFO world.
You do this blank password search.
You actually come up with some results as far as sites that you can get into.
Yeah.
What do you look at first?
Uh, well, the first thing I had to do was test my method.
So I did that on British sites and we're currently in Cambridge, home of the famous university.
Um, I had Cambridge's FTP server, file transfer protocol server and, um, Oxford as well.
Um, and a couple of polytechnics at the time, which are now universities.
And, um, I realized the technique worked if you, if you cast far enough, a wide net, you
know, something's going to come in.
And, um, then I thought, okay, let's go for the, um, the locations.
And my list of locations all came from the disclosure project book.
Um, and also there was, uh, I forget the title of it.
There was like a hackers network document going around of a list of potential UFO secrecy sites.
And I took some of the, um, names from there, but all that told you was the network names
or the particular department of defense, like sub-department that, that owned that network.
Um, so I used a site at the time, which was called Nihi's IP index.
And this guy had done some work.
He'd used like domain search tools and built a huge list of who owns what subnets.
So I could just grab a block, plug it into my script and scan like a quarter of a million computers in eight minutes.
Typically 5% would respond.
And then from that 5%, a further 5% would have black passwords.
Okay.
Got it.
So you do this like narrowing process and you end up with, what is it?
Like 97 sites that you can get into or something like that.
Yeah.
That was the end result.
Which is a lot of sites.
And what do the sites include as far as acronyms that people would be familiar with
or program names people would be familiar with?
Okay.
So NSA, I got into Fort Meade.
DEESA, Defense Information Systems Agency.
DoD Networks, Basic Army Networks, Navy Networks, USAF, USAF Force Networks.
Okay.
Wow.
So yeah, those are some pretty intense organizations that at the very least we know hold the keys to,
you know, all sorts of, you know, military technology secrets that confer a tactical advantage
to the US if not some of these deeper, you know, more interesting mysteries that, you know, you and I share an interest in.
So what do you do next as far as your search and what do you find?
Yeah.
Okay.
So I'm one guy.
I've got potentially thousands of IPs to search the individual computers.
And once you find a blank password, and these are Windows networks, you need to become the administrator,
which is like, you know, the highest local account.
And eventually the domain administrator, which controls the entire network.
So once I was on one PC or a network, I then attack the domain server and get that password.
And that's through dictionary attacks, password cracking.
I actually used a tool called Loft Crack.
I don't know if that's still around.
And, um, once I'd done that, it's a huge job for one person, huge job.
So I found a program called Landsearch.
This is all commercially off the shelf available software.
And what Landsearch enabled me to do was to type in a search term and it would search every file and folder
on all the local PCs that I had control of, which could be, I think the largest I did was 5,000 at one time,
which took hours, you know, it was a whole lot.
Um, so yeah, that's how I, that was my system for making it doable for one person.
And also it depends on your search terms.
These files aren't going to be called UFO secrets.
Um, so I had to look for things like, you know, secret, top secret, um, just anything just to,
and PDF, PDF documents were particularly helpful.
A lot of stuff was in PDF back then.
Um, and, uh, the redacting they did on PDF back then was not fully redacted.
You could un-redact it once you downloaded the file to your own PC.
So it was a huge network wide document search and just grabbing what I could, spending hours
getting it and then spending hours reading it and trawling through it.
Are you, when you're spending hours reading it, is this like you backed this stuff up on
a hard drive or is it just on your PC?
Yeah, download it to my PC.
Okay.
So it's just on your PC.
Yeah.
And so, so you're going through all this stuff, were there any other things you saw
that were interesting outside of, you know, we'll get to the crazy kind of UFO related
stuff that you found.
Was there anything else that you, that you saw while, while searching through these documents?
I was looking for free energy as well.
I never found anything to do with that.
Um, one thing I have to say, I never found anything to do with solar warden.
Solar warden is a huge rumor that was started by an anonymous poster on the above top secret
forum.
So there's no evidence for solar warden and I have nothing to do with it.
Never heard of it apart from, you know, rumors pertaining to myself.
Yeah.
For the audience, solar warden is, has become associated with these sort of secret space
program, Gaia, you know, people like Corey good, you know, that say that we have like
a terrestrial, you know, we have like humans like in, in like deep space right now.
And they engage in these like 20 years and back commissions or whatever.
And there's like a documentary on it.
And it's like the, it's the worst documentary I think I've ever seen.
I believe in a secret space program, but I don't believe Corey good.
Yeah.
Well, that's the thing it's like, uh, pizza gate and Epstein.
It's you, the best way to debunk the true or to pre immunize the population from ever
actually looking into the truth is to, uh, uh, kind of, you know, inoculate them, send
out stuff that is directly adjacent to the truth and then ensure that that gets debunked.
Cause it's so prima facie ridiculous.
Yeah.
Standard and so technique.
Yeah. So I, yeah. So the fact that there's some sort of standard Intel techniques. So the fact
that, um, you know, uh, uh, a blog and anonymous blog post, and then you have all these people
kind of flooding the zone with secret space program stuff makes me think that there might
actually be something next to that. That might be, that might be true. That dovetails with what
you did find anything else that you found that was interesting before the crazy stuff.
Um, nothing to do with ET or anything like that, but it was very interesting. What, um, on one
site I found the jailers file. Every military base has a jailer and it's just crazy. You've
got guys taking LSD that work on submarines.
Really?
So lots of interesting human stories, you know,
Where they're taking LSD that work on submarines.
Yeah. Well, yeah. Cause the, the soldiers basically, Oh, I'm a submarine. I'm tripping
now. And like, you know, they're dealing drugs. They've got hell's angels gangs bringing in
the drugs. And so that was interesting for human story. It's nothing to do with what we're
here to discuss today, but it's entertaining.
Okay. That's fascinating. I thought, I thought for a second, you were talking about like
MK ultra mind control, like taking LSD at the bottom of submarines and testing consciousness
or something. Okay. So just, you know, recreational spice it up down there. Interesting.
Yeah. And so you're systematically, you're looking for UFOs, you're looking for free energy,
any other, like, you know, kind of terms that are on your mind in going into the search?
No, that was my main focus. And, uh, with UFOs, it was particularly the propulsion. What I was
interested in was the energy and the propulsion aliens didn't excite me so much. Cause I'm sure
they exist. Cause it's a huge universe, but I wanted something that could, um, that we could use,
you know, and I was convinced that it was secret technology, but they knew something about the,
the populace at large wasn't allowed to have access to.
Yeah. Well, I think you were, you were onto something maybe, but, uh,
in Britain at the time we had old age pensioners can pay their fuel bills and energy was a really
sad story for a lot of people. So to have something that was free and yeah, it was just
too juicy not to have a go at finding. Yeah. I mean, it would be hugely disruptive to establishment
institutions. You know, if, if, you know, our energy prices dropped from, you know, 50 bucks
per kilowatt hour to like 50 cents per kilowatt hour, that would be hugely disruptive. It just
would. I think, um, it's a control mechanism, isn't it? And it is well, just like water is
starting to be food has been for a while. Yeah. Anything that's scarce and can be accrued at the
top, I think is totally a control mechanism. And anybody who doesn't think that, you know, um,
having access to a critical threshold of oil has not determined American foreign policy over the
last 70 years is nuts. Like, I mean, you see it with Maduro in Venezuela and then, you know,
worries about what's going on in Iran vis-a-vis that, you know? And so, and like, it's, it's all,
you know, very, very, you know, obviously interconnected. I mean, desert storm in the early nineties
was basically pulled off because Saddam Hussein in overtaking Kuwait controlled the fifth of the
world's oil supply. And that was just unacceptable. Yeah. And one thing about Venezuela is it wasn't
just, um, America's domestic supply. It was what foreign powers could get. China was about to do a
deal with Venezuela. That's right. I think it would only amount to like one or two percent of China's
imports, but it's still something. Yeah. Still something. They're sitting on a lot of oil there.
And you see this, like these crazy sort of game theory dynamics vis-a-vis China taking place with
Greenland and other places. So it's, it all cuts to these. And if you look at like why the U S had
to back down off this recent, you know, trade agreement deal with, with China and kind of
concede some, some things, it was due to a rare earth refinement being basically a monopoly, uh, in
China. And so, you know, these things are like very real things geopolitically. And so if I, I, I agree
with you, I think it's very interesting if there's any sort of novel exotic physics that's stuck in a
compartment in the government, you know, I'd like to know as well. And I even think there are probably
interesting ways to use it geopolitically. Like if you're, if you have it where it's like,
it's some sort of carrot for like, okay, maybe you don't give it to like, you know, gross dictators
or whatever, but it's like a way to like incentivize reform or I don't know, but like just keeping it to
yourself, that seems wrong. Maybe. Yeah. Yeah. But you're right. It's a real hard line to walk,
isn't it? How do you have that public for you, but not public for other countries because you have
spies and totally in there, there are dual use implications for a lot of things. So like a good
example would be, you know, uh, controlled fusion or whatever would, you know, is, is the really
positive, you know, use of, of nuclear fusion, which would allow for, you know, sort of free energy
if you have over unity. Um, but then, you know, fusion also creates the hydrogen bomb.
Right. And so, so like, you, you never know, like if you had some free energy device that
you were putting in a compartment or something, if that also allowed a kid in his bedroom to
blow up the world, like you do have to like do some calculations. There's this guy, Ashton
Forbes online, who, I don't know if you're familiar with him, but talks about, yeah. MH370,
the, like these like orbs wrapping around the plane and then it zaps it. And he's like,
sure that there's like free energy, like, you know, being held by the most fascinating thing
about that was where's the provenance of that video. Yeah. It's never been shown.
It's never been. Yeah. We don't know. Yeah. Yeah. But, um, okay. So what do you, what do
you find next? So, um, there was, uh, a special witness for Stephen Greer's disclosure project
called Donna hair. And she said that when she worked, she was pretty hard. She was, uh, a NASA
launch photographic specialist. I think she has secret clearance. Um, cause she'd get, you know,
very close up photos of all the mechanics and engineering and stuff for launches and the launch
platform under the launch platform. And she said that she worked in, uh, building eight of Johnson
space center, JSC. And the, uh, colleague who worked across the corridor, and this is all something
he shouldn't have done. Um, cause they chatted, you know, had lunch together or whatever. And he,
one day he just beckoned her across the corridor and said, come and take a look at this.
And this is the days of analog photography. And so he's got, um, you know, big like contact
sheets and slides, and they used to be developed under red light and silver nitrate. And he says,
what do you think this is? And there was a huge white disc on this satellite photo of the earth.
And she being a photographic expert herself said, oh, it's just a blob of the emulsion,
you know, the old chemical of the sheets. And then he's grinning and he says,
uh, dots on the emulsion don't leave round shadows on the ground. And there was a round shadow at the
right angle, at the correct angle, the sun shining on the trees. I saw pine trees. I didn't see a
coastline. I don't know where this was, but, um, I looked at him and I was pretty startled because
I'd worked out there several years and never seen anything like this, never heard of anything like
this. And, uh, I said, is this a UFO? And he's smiling at me and he says, I can't tell you that.
So I said, what are you going to do with this information? And he said, well, we always have
to airbrush them out before we sell them to the public.
Because they sell all the imagery to like colleges, universities, you know,
earth shots and magnificent scenes from space. Um, so yeah, his job was to block this stuff out and
make sure it wouldn't get seen. And they didn't have Photoshop then. So I'm not sure. I think,
you know, the airbrush term literally comes from a physical airbrush on the emulsion where they just
blur things. And, uh, you see lots of examples on lists of like lunar photography from Clementine
mission, the lunar orbiter, the LRO, the lunar recordings and orbiter. Um, so I read this story,
absolutely fascinated. You know, here was this highly qualified woman. She'd worked for a long
time NASA and I think the air force previously to that. And, um, and did she say disc? She said
flying saucer. Yeah. Okay. Yeah. She, and she said, so that shape, the circular shape. Yeah.
And the shadow. Okay. Wow. And, um, I was already in Jason Johnson space center at the time.
So I thought building eight. Okay. I wonder if that's still running. Cause she worked there. And
I think the late eighties or the early nineties. So you're in the Johnson space center files on
your PC. Yeah. I was already there when I read that. Okay. Yeah. So I thought, I've got to have a
look. Yeah. I've got to have a look. And I thought, how the hell do I find building eight?
But luckily windows has, um, you can do network commands in a console rather than a GUI of the
mouse. And you can type it like net stat network status tells you all the people connected to the
machine. And there's other commands whereby NASA are great auditors of their system. So they have
these special commands for auditing where you see the machine, the PC, the number, the serial number,
the date, when it was last maintained, all stuff like that and the building it's in.
So I ran those commands that produced a list and I stripped out, I think it was about 1500 machines
or maybe 150 machines. But, um, once I stripped out the building eight machines,
uh, there was only like a dozen maybe. And, uh, I ran the blank password script on them. And I think about
half of them were accessible. And the first one I looked at was the one where I saw the picture and
it was strange. It was, um, I did a lot of network support before that as well. And most users,
desktops are covered in stuff, short cards, emails, like, uh, electronic post-it notes.
And, uh, these were very bare desktops, all the hands, like, uh, two folders, raw
and process and maybe a couple of other shortcuts. Um, so I thought, I've got to look at this. It's
got to be images. It's where she said it was. It looks like images. It says raw, it says processed.
And, uh, I double clicked into the folders and it's a proprietary NASA image format that I can't
run on my desk, not a JPEG, not a PNG. Um, so what I had to do was basically,
there was, uh, what was it called? There was, uh, there was, uh,
there was, I basically had to run NASA software. I had to double click it on the desktop because
my hacking method, although I'd get in there with a blank password, which was CLI command line.
Um, once I was in there, I was using remotely anywhere. I think it still exists. It's like PC
anywhere. It's like you're sitting at the desktop. You can see the screen on your screen.
And, um, so I double clicked this, but it was very, very slow. I was on a 56 K dial up,
which was, um, to give some idea of the speed. It was, if you download an MP3 music file now,
you've got it in a few seconds. Then it was five minutes per megabyte and a song might be three
megabytes and 50 minutes for one song. And no one would even accept that now. So I double clicked
this. It was taken ages. So I canceled it. I turned down my remote graphical remote control thing into
like eight bit color, then four bit color. Eventually I think, yeah, I think four bit
color or two bit color. It was basically four or five different colors. So it was a shitty image.
And, um, but it came on the screen, like, you know, almost like, well, I think it was a few lines at
time. So it was coming in blocks and I'm looking and there's like blackness. Then there's like,
slowly a hemisphere started appearing and I'm thinking, fuck, that's a planet. What the hell?
This could be what she said. Then the hemisphere comes into view and it's very blocky,
but it's kind of blue and white. So I'm thinking, well, it must be earth. And then suddenly there's a
big straight kind of silvery line. And then it's coming down. Then that's, I guess what they now call
a tic-tac, but it's what we used to call cigar shaped object. And this thing was admittedly,
it's low resolution. It's coming down slowly, but this thing looked very kind of smooth
on the outside. There was no lines where there would be like plates fixed or screws and bolts
and stuff. And, uh, I was just thinking, my God, this is my Eureka moment. Confirmed Donna
Hare's story. Not that Donna Hare's story needs confirming. Um, yeah. And it got to,
I got the whole ship, you know, in view. And then it started to go below that where I would see the
rest of the, the, um, the sphere of the earth, I assume it was the earth. And, um, it was just
amazing. The only manmade, possibly manmade thing that was there was like geodesic domes, like radar
stations, uh, one atop below and both sides. And I thought, well, that's strange. It's kind of manmade
looking, but not manmade looking. And then I've got graphical remote control. I see the mouse move
someone else, the person, someone else is at the computer themselves and they're moving the mouse.
They've right clicked on the local area network icon, you know, right next to your clock on the
bottom, right of your windows taskbar disconnect and boom, that was it gone. I was cut out and I'm
sitting there like waiting. Oh my God.
Baited breath in my Eureka moment. Come on, come on, come on.
Oh my God. Anything else on the cigar. So smooth. No, it doesn't seem like rivets or seams.
It's hovering above the earth. Do you notice anything else?
No, just like a very smooth cylinder. The geodesic domes.
And so the little dome dome on top dome on bottom. Yeah. And either end.
Yeah. And on either end. Yeah.
Or that could just be the kind of cigar tube, like the closure of the cylinder.
Sure. Sure. Sure.
I suppose. Yeah.
That is fascinating. Yeah.
So interesting. And did you ever speak with, you know, yourself or through intermediaries
with Donna Hare? Oh yeah.
Yeah. And did she say that's the disc that I saw? And I just, because I think of disc with her and
then cigar Tic Tac with you. Yeah. She saw that one photo of disc, but she also spoke to, um...
Okay. So these are probably different images. You're just confirming that the same building
probably has a whole lot of images that they're sitting on.
Yeah. Even though it might be 10 or 20 years later, apparently this is still the place where
there's images. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. UFOs or exotic craft that are being airbrushed out.
It is proof that at least, I mean, it's really interesting that you have a whistleblower come
out with, nobody has any evidence for her claims at this point. And she says, you know, I, this is
where we process the images. I was shown this image, building eight Johnson space center,
you independently, you know, halfway across the world, hack into Johnson space center, look at building
eight. And then one of the first things that pops up on your screen is an image of a UFO hovering above
the earth, which is clearly not the exact same UFO, but it's, you know, it's definitely exotic.
It's nothing, you know, it wasn't a rocket. It wasn't ISS. It wasn't like a space lab or,
Well, it doesn't sound like a satellite to me, a cigar, like rotating around.
Yeah. There's no antenna either. There's nothing, no, like telemetry or sensor looking stuff.
Doesn't it? Yeah. Yeah. That is wild. I mean, and then also now we have the, uh,
lucky hindsight, you know, in, in, in 2026 of commander David Fravor's experience of 2004,
just a few years later, uh, off the coast of San Diego, where he sees a tic-tac object and they
have, you know, apparently radar. We've seen the FLIR imaging, the thermal imaging of this thing. It's
for everyone to see the Pentagon has verified that that's real.
All four of us, because we were an F-18F, so we had pilots and WIZO in the backseat,
looked down a small, saw a white tic-tac object with a longitudinal axis pointing north-south
and moving very abruptly over the water, like a ping pong ball. It rapidly accelerated in front
of us and disappeared. Our wingmen, roughly 8,000 feet above us, lost contact also.
And then you have a lot of other witnesses. You have his co-pilot, you have another plane and two
pilots in that plane. You have, you know, a whole lot, you have the, obviously radar.
Some guys on the ship. Exactly. So are you the first,
like other, I mean, there, I think, I believe there's some other tic-tac and cigar, like there's,
you know, I think flying, there, there are air force documents from the late forties,
um, that describe, uh, uh, flying butane tanks. I don't know if you know about this.
Yeah. David Grush, you famous UFO whistleblower has talked about this. And then in Robert Hastings,
great book, UFOs and nukes, which talks about UFOs showing up at nuclear installations all over the
world, including in the UK, actually at Rendlesham forest in 1980, really famous case. Uh, he talks
about, um, tic-tacs or cigar shaped objects often being sort of like a mothership and saucers flying
out of the tic-tacs. Yeah. I think that was at Maelstrom AFP in America as well. Similar thing
happened. Yeah. Like definitely a mothership kind of configuration. Yeah. No, a ton has happened at
Malmstrom actually. So it's definitely likely that in certain cases, some sort of tick, because a tic-tac
or cigar is one of the most common descriptions people have. There's a case we were just talking
earlier, you know, uh, thank you, James Fox, great documentarian for the intro to Gary. It's a great
guy. And we were saying that he sort of single handedly resuscitated this obscure Brazilian UFO
crash in 1996, the Virginia case. And there's a guy, Carlos de Sousa, who's a ultralight pilot
geography teacher who literally saw the crash and he felt the material just like in Roswell with Jesse
Marcel. It feels the material and it's, it feels like a, you know, memory metal. I could see quite
a few pieces of debris on the ground and I picked them up and it was kind of curved. And then I was
surprised to see how light it was. So I said, I'll keep it. And so I crunched it up. And so I made this
kind of movement, you know, to put it in my pocket. And what happened was this foil or this sheet regained
its shape. So I thought, what is this? I was completely floored.
Yeah. It sprung back into its original shape and guess what the shape of the craft was that he saw
that crashed. Right. So cigar tic tac. Yeah. So yeah. Lots of, uh, synchronicities there.
What was your first instinct when you saw it? How, how did you feel? And what did you think,
you know, often I think like if you're taking like a multiple choice test, it's like your first
instincts off and right, you know, and then you second guess yourself. So do you,
did you have like a, an on the spot interpretation?
I'm not an aeronautics expert or a space vehicle expert, but to me, you know, I, I watched space
stuff with interest since I was a kid and it wasn't your normal space stuff. So I knew that.
Um, but there wasn't, you know, I didn't know if it was extraterrestrial. Yeah. I still don't,
obviously, you know, it could be something manmade, but it was definitely something secret
because it was nothing like, like we already have up there.
Dan, did you, uh, have any sort of like instinct of, I mean, the obvious question is like,
is it ours or is it theirs? Yeah.
Yeah. That's a big distinction. Well, I think because of Donna Hare's story,
my instinct was that, yeah, it was alien because that's what she described. She described
unknown things in high res NASA satellite imagery that they had to airbrush out because
I don't know, maybe they thought it would panic the public or they had no explanation for it.
And what does she say as far as why they airbrushed it out and didn't just admit, you know,
yeah, we're surrounded by these cool exotic objects.
Yeah. We shared a few emails. She's passed now, unfortunately. God wrote her soul.
Um, and we had one, I think it was like two and a half hour, three hour phone conversation.
And, um, she thinks that just like a lot of us do that a lot has been hidden.
Uh, it's been hidden for reasons of control. Um, but it's weird when you try and extrapolate from
this, you think, well, wouldn't you use technology like that in a war? If you had that, would you use
it openly to your advantage or so to me, that tells me that it's still unknown even to the
people with the highest authority on this subject. I think that's right. If it's not well known and
it's flying with impunity over our nuclear sites and in sensitive airspace and in space next to,
you know, our recon satellites and stuff, you would be extremely embarrassed to, you wouldn't be able to
admit, you know, you know, but if, but if you did know what was going on, you would just tell the public,
like, yeah, we, not only do we know what's going on, but then you try to signal that,
you know, what's going on and you've like reverse engineered it because you'd want to,
you know, kind of soften, you know, the enemy sort of thing. And so I actually think some of
modern disclosure might be, you know, Intel tactics to try to like, say that we know more than we do,
but also recruit on the topic because like, actually they don't really know what's going on.
Yeah. I think you're absolutely right. Embarrassment is a huge factor.
Yeah. Um, even just my, my hacking wasn't embarrassment. So if they're
embarrassed about something like that, can you imagine? Yeah. I mean, it's just indeterminable.
It's, it's hugely different. Um, and also fear. Cause I mean, why, you know, are they here?
Yeah. What are they doing? And why are they
interested in nuclear missiles? Is it for protection of us? Is it that we destabilize
some kind of interdimensional thing or, cause you know, we're fucking with atoms.
Did you get this? Yeah, right. We are, we're doing a lot genetics, atoms, biowarfare. So,
so you, when you saw this thing, did you get the sense that it was
moving in a predictable orbit? I mean, it's, it's a static image, so you have no way of knowing,
but did you get the sense that it was like moving in a, in an orbit or that it was like
just kind of maneuvering around or?
Well, I've seen photos of the low earth orbit stuff. Um, and this looked to be
maybe, I mean, I have no idea of the scale of this thing. Um, but with the hemisphere,
it was way beyond low earth orbit. Okay.
But I don't know. I mean, you know, there's a, actually a Wiki leaks, uh,
email with John Podesta on it. That's been deleted from the internet, but still, if
you go on the way back machine, I think, I think there's some like Reddit forums that discuss this
definitely a real email. And he is talking with, uh, kind of a contractor from some aerospace
corporation, I think in California. And he mentions that the, the, the contractor,
I think the guy's name is Bob fish said they're having lunch together. And this is him recalling
it in the email. And fish says, uh, yeah, we spotted some, uh, fast walkers today. And, um,
they were, I think this was in specific reference to the DSP, the, uh, defense support program,
which I think is this very deep geo stationary kind of recon thing that the air force does.
This was the air force at the time, because now space force would do it, you know, post 2019. But
I wonder if you saw a fast walker because also if you, um, uh, uh, uh, try to FOIA fast walkers,
which John Greenwald did, uh, the space force gets back and says, we, you know,
clearly there are some records, but we can't, we can't talk about them. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. Wasn't there CIA for you to do with fast walkers as well?
Maybe, maybe. Yeah. It might be the CIA actually might not even be space for it. I might be getting
that wrong, but yeah. Interesting. So, but I guess one question would be like, was it lateral to the
earth? Like, was it moving? Yeah. Lateral to the earth. Cause I think it wouldn't make sense to me if
it was like vertical to the earth. Like if the, if the butt was facing the earth, I'd be like,
that doesn't feel like an orbit, like it's in a predictable orbit. You know what I mean?
Yeah. It was definitely, it was lateral to the earth. It was at 90. Yeah. So that, yeah, it is,
it's horizontal. The horizontal. I wasn't seeing it end on. So you're right. It was in a position to
be rotating around possibly in orbit traveling past or just traveling past. Yeah. Yeah. Or
yeah. Okay. Yeah. So it wouldn't be, it wasn't like going directly at the earth. It was like moving
laterally somewhat. Okay. So interesting. Any other detail? I guess you could, you don't,
you don't know color, right? Because it's silvery white. I mean, it was very, I was in like, I think
two bit color. Okay. But, or maybe four bit, but yeah, it was very kind of blocky and there's
definitely white, silvery white. And did you see any sort of, I guess, I don't know how you'd see a
shadow, but like, did you see any sort of so far out from earth? Yeah. Interesting. What do you think
photographed it? Very good question. Yeah. Now, yeah. So this takes me to, um,
I referenced the disclosure project a lot. Cause that was the root of a lot of my locations and
research at the time. And, um, one of their witnesses, I forget his name. He was DIA
and he got a lot of the information to do with the satellites. And he, he, he was the one that
said most of these satellites are actually pointed outlets and they're not like low earth orbit
communication satellites. So I assume if you've got very far out satellites looking outwards,
you can also rotate them and look inwards. So that's the only thing I could think of.
Okay. So that is fascinating. You see that. How are you feeling when you see that?
Oh man. I was ready to inform the press, tell the world, oh my God, look, it's true. And NASA knows,
and NASA has no for ages. And Donagher was right. And for them, boom, disconnecting.
As it's loading. Yeah.
So it hasn't even fully loaded. I saw like just under the bottom half of the ship.
Yeah. And, um, yeah, then disconnect.
And you have no reason to lie about this. You've never made any money off of this. Right. And if
anything, you were kind of, you know, put, put on a witch trial, like there's sort of this witch
hunt for like 20 years where there's like, you know, blanket extradition was attempted to be applied
to you where, uh, they wanted to put you in prison for 60 years. So 70 for 70 years.
Mr. McKinnon is accused of serious crimes. On his visit to the White House, David Cameron spoke to
President Obama about the case and both agreed they could find an appropriate solution.
We talked about the case of computer hacker Gary McKinnon, on which the prime minister has expressed
very clear views. You said you would work together to find a solution. So have you found one?
Mr. Well, uh, on Mr. McKinnon, uh, we have proceeded through all the, uh, uh,
the processes, uh, required under our extradition agreements. Uh, it is now in the hands of the
British legal system. Uh, we have confidence, uh, uh, in, uh, the British legal system coming to, uh,
uh, a just conclusion. Uh, and so we await resolution and, uh, we'll be respectful of that
process. Well, we had talks and they said, look, if we just come along, don't fight it. You do between
eight and 20. Like, that's a good deal. No, thank you. I'll fight it. Um, and yeah, and that was
actually horrible. It was very depressing. Um, I found out my own government because governments are
made up of individuals and individuals have ties to other individuals in the DOJ and the CPS.
Some of them wanted me gone to just as a favor to the U S not because of anything to do with right
or wrong or truth or justice, just as a favor political porn. Um, so that was awful, but not
just for me, my family, you know, your mom and dad. And it's like, oh, weren't there some allegations
of a meeting that was had at the American embassy out here where it was like, we want his head or
something like it was very extreme language use. Yeah. Ed Gibson, who was attache to the
U S embassy in London at the time, met with my lawyer and he said, we want to see him fry,
electric chair reference. Jesus Christ.
Well, she told me that Karen, amazing lawyer, stuck with us all through this and fought and
fought and fought. Yeah. I was just, I mean, we already knew they played dirt. Cause I mean,
people have to realize, you know, politics isn't about people being safe and well looked after.
It's about the state, the furtherance of the state and its objectives and the protectors,
the protection of your state to foreign states. So, uh, yeah, no, that is definitely the, the lay
of the land as is national security. And, uh, you know, I just find it, I find it interesting that,
okay, you have guys like Snowden and Assange where, wherever you lie with them, which like,
whether you think they're courageous and ideological and in a way that really, you know,
exposed all sorts of, you know, uh, uh, issues with the Intel world and mass surveillance and stuff.
Um, or whether you think they put like, you know, Americans abroad in danger or whatever,
which I think there are like, there is some nuance there. Like, I do think some people in the Intel
world who talk about this say, well, there, there's some real like bad effects around, around the
stuff. Yeah. But, but, but I was just getting to the point of whatever you think of those cases,
like maybe there's some, you know, like a more gray area or debate to be had or whatever. In your case,
you're just, you're smoking weed in your girlfriend's aunt's little flat and it's like 4am.
And you're just like a dude who's interested in UFOs since you were a child and you want to figure
it out. And so I, it's just like, to me, if it's the U S like, get your shit together. It's the issue.
That should be your, you should be, you know, it's almost like they might've, uh, lashed out so much
at you because they were embarrassed. I mean, that you literally like it's, it's on you. It's
not on this like poor English citizen who has no clearly, like, I don't, I don't think you're like
particularly ideologically set and like destroying America, you know, it's Chicago. Yeah. Yeah.
So anyway, well, we'll, we'll get to that kind of more meta conversation, but you also found some
other pretty crazy things, uh, while you were, while you were searching in your, uh, girlfriend's
aunt's flat. And so, yeah, what else did you, what else did you find besides this tic-tac?
I think, um, I was on a Navy system at the time. I can't remember cloud of weed, et cetera, but, um,
there was a spreadsheet Excel spreadsheet and it was called cause I was saying earlier about my search
terms. It was UFOs, ET, terrestrial, anything spacecraft, anything I could think of, which probably wouldn't
be in the title of the document, but, um, this spreadsheet was titled non terrestrial officers.
So not on the earth, which isn't necessarily alien. It could just mean space based Marines or, you know,
secret space force. Um, and that was incredible. It had ship names, it had, um, material, the material,
the military spelling, not material. Um, and it was transfers of weird chemicals like
melibdenum and other weird things that are hard to pronounce, uh, ship to ship transfers and fleet
to fleet transfers. And at the time I looked up the ship names thinking us Navy must be boats, nothing,
absolutely nothing. What do you remember the names of the people?
No, I remember, I don't remember any of the names of the people, but the, there were long lists,
you know, I think it was just initial surname. I don't think they were first names. Um, and the
ship names I was expecting like USS Lincoln or, you know, Navy ships, but there was none of that.
Everything I, and it wasn't Google at the time. I think it was Alta Vista, the biggest search engine
at the time. Um, and none, none of it was seagoing vessels.
So you see a list of non-terrestrial officers, and then you also see chemicals. What are the names
of these chemicals? Yeah. Uh, melibdenum, um, barium, something was in there. They were very exotic.
Do you remember the exact, so what is, what is melibdenum? Have you looked up what the uses are
of this? Yeah. I remember melibdenum, I can't even say it now, melibdenum. Um,
they're very exotic. They used in like, uh, magnetics, um, lots of very kind of exotic
industrial processes, a lot, a lot to do with metal hardening, if I remember right, like metallurgy.
Um, like you make an alloy and it makes it stronger than the original two components.
So again, that time now, years later with the research, you've done the people you've interviewed,
it's all making more sense, especially when he, when we come to the biofield brown stuff and dielectrics
yeah, we'll get to that. And like nano deposition of thin layer materials.
Yes. Yeah. Thinly layered, thinner than, uh, you know, a human hair or whatever,
micron layered. This one sample is engineered in layers thinner than microns through a process
unknown on earth and for a purpose we can only guess. Multi-layered bismuth and magnesium sample,
bismuth layers less than a human hair, supposedly picked up in the crash retrieval of an advanced
aerospace vehicle. Nowhere could we find any evidence that anybody ever made one of these.
Okay. This is fascinating though. So you see a list of how many non-terrestrial officers?
Oh man. Um, so my screen at the time was the old
like 800 by 600 monitors. I think it might have had 10, 24 by seven, six, eight resolution at the
time. So your typical Excel spreadsheet without zooming in when you just load it up was probably
24 lines. And I think there was about one and a half or two pages. So maybe like 30, 40 names.
You don't remember any of the last names? No, sorry. You're killing me.
No, I'm kidding me. You gotta give us a little breadcrumb.
Yeah. Yeah. This is one of the main like criticisms of me. Why didn't you take a bloody screenshot?
Just alt print screen, alt print. But I did actually, I downloaded that Excel spreadsheet.
Uh huh. And when I got arrested,
all my data was taken to ONI, Office of Naval Intelligence.
Hmm. So they still have my hard drives. I've tried to get them back for years. And they said,
no, it's still a long going investigation. You can't touch it.
Office of Naval Intelligence is the oldest intelligence agency in the US. I think it's 1882.
And it's often deeply implicated in UFOs 1882 1882. So the national security act, which created the CIA
was 1947. And, um, you know, and then you had the OSS before that, which was kind of this wartime
foreign intelligence effort. Yeah. But no, Office of Naval Intelligence well predates all of that.
And you had Thomas Townsend Brown doing a lot of spooky science work for the Navy.
And, uh, yeah. And then you have this guy, Harold Malmgren, who kind of ended up giving me kind of a,
turned into kind of a deathbed confession at the end of his life. And it, uh, it was wild. I mean,
he was like the office of Naval Intelligence knows the most about this issue. And once you go in that
door, the door shuts and you can't get let out.
Well, he said, more nothing. Naval intelligence
are going to be around asking you questions about your study.
They're going to get curious. And if they talk to you for any length of time, they'll say,
holy shit, you really know a lot. They're going to offer you special access.
It's how they operate. I said, what does that mean? You'll open the doors. You'll have full entry.
The doors will shut and you'll be no exit the rest of your life. That is a closed system.
And he kind of implied that they approached him in certain cases. And because of the fact that it
was this closed system, he didn't want to engage. Wow. So very interesting. So, so they end up with your
stuff. Yeah. Wow. Yeah. They were, um, when the British police at the time was the NHTCU,
national high tech crime unit in the UK. Um, at first they said to me, oh, you'll get six months.
It's a computer misuse act 1995 in Britain. Six miles community service, no time. And then they
went to America and visited O and I and other top brass. And when they came back, the tone had totally
changed. That was just really serious. Um, which of course eventually turned into facing 70 years in
prison. So it was a huge, like using a hammer to crack a nut. It was, you know, David and Goliath,
the whole thing. Yeah. So wild. Yeah. Well, it's like you said earlier, I was just a guy,
normal guy, interesting UFOs happen to have some IT skills, a little bit of hacking, black
passwords, nothing genius level. And then next thing, you know, oh, it just blows up.
Let's try to make an example of you. So, so, so when you think about those chemicals
and you know, we're, we'll get into our mutual interest in Thomas Townsend Brown and anti-gravity
experiments. So you think that they could have been used to create special alloys or what you
might call metamaterials and UFO world, uh, which allow for greater thrust in these anti-gravity
experiments. Like one thing that is true about the Bifield Brown effect and this anti-gravity
experiment is that if you use an insulator in the middle, that is considered a high K
dielectric, which means it stores and discharges easily a lot of electromagnetism, a lot of, you
know, electricity, it stores electric fields in it specifically. Um, the, the thrust you see in
the experiment is, is much greater from the, the negative electrode to the positive electrode.
So do you think that, you know, I guess barium is actually in Townsend Brown's documents? Like
he talks about it all the time. Yeah. Strontium titanate. Exactly. So, and then what was the
other, I can never pronounce it? Molybdenum. Molybdenum. And, and do you, and you looked into
that and that's for like creating alloys? Yeah. I think it's a, a strengthening alloys,
but a long time since I looked into it, but I think that's what it was. It was like a strengthening
alloy. Any other chemicals? It might've even had a shielding. Um, not gravitational shielding,
but like, uh, radiation shielding or some kind of, I think maybe similar to lead, but I'm not a
physicist. So don't quote me. But it's super interesting if it's used on like current space
vehicles, like people should go out and look that up because if it is, you know, that might be a,
an interesting lead. Yeah. Do some patent searches. Yeah. Yeah. Any other chemicals?
Molybdenum, barium, strontium. Strontium. Yeah. Strontium. And strontium is also mentioned
in brown stuff, I believe, or? I can't remember any others. Okay. And, but isn't,
strontium, I believe is one of Gary Nolan's pieces that he has at the, you know, Stanford lab
that he thinks might be UFO metamaterials that come from crashes, I believe has strontium in it.
Yeah. And it's a good dielectric. Um, I forget it's K constant, but I know it's high.
So it's also a high K dielectric. Yeah.
This is crazy. So you have a list of non-terrestrial officers.
Yeah. Yeah. So.
And then what is the fleet to fleet thing mean?
This was fleet to fleet transfers. Cause it was a, it was one spreadsheet, but it had taps.
So there was the officers names, there was ship names, and there was material, a material transfer.
Do you remember the ship names? No.
Okay. But what, okay. What, when you're looking at this, what is your instinct as to like,
cause there are all sorts of wild interpretations people have, you know, and people make up the
secret space program, solar warden stuff. What was your, you're in the moment. What are you thinking
when you see this?
Well, that's exactly where I was. I mean, I imagine you were me, UFO guy, you know,
quite an active interest. Um, and then finding this. And so obviously that's where my first
thoughts go. So I'm thinking non-terrestrial officers, that's the baseline for the whole
document. So they're not on earth, but I was thinking, well, they could be, they're probably,
it's probably people. They're not non-terrestrial cause they're not human. They're non-terrestrial
cause it's non-earth based. So it's out in space. So space force was my first thought.
It's gotta be a space force, uh, obviously secret. Um, and then with the chemicals and stuff
and the ship names then, and fleet to fleet transfers. So there's more than one ship
and then exotic materials. And so, you know, it's kind of two plus two equals four.
Yeah. Obviously it's to do with my mindset. That's what I was looking for. So that's how
I interpreted it. Well, you know what I would do if I was office of naval intelligence and I hated
Gary McKinnon, you know what I would do? I'd make up some BS secret space program, call it solar warden,
send people down the wrong trail when actually I do have real, you know, deep space fleets and transfers
of these. So, but the, and show the warden did come off to me. So yeah, it did. So, so, but, but
like, I'm still trying to get to the, so the trend, what do you think that fleet to fleet transfer of
what of people? I think the chemicals, because first you have the people, then you have the ships,
then you had the, um, chemicals, metal elements. Okay. And do we think that
the material is being transferred between humans? Do we don't think that the material is being
transferred between extraterrestrials and humans, do we, or do we think the material is being
transferred between humans? I think, yeah, ship to ship. So I guess maybe this was kind of like a
logistics train. Like a supply chain and space or something. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Just a basic,
cause you know, the army is all about, or the Navy or whoever is all about logistics. Right. And a lot of
these materials, if they are layered extremely thinly and you have kind of atomic layer deposition
style stuff, we know that manufacturing in space and in zero G environments allows you. So a lot
of these materials that go, it looks like it was built in zero G. Like, this is so crazy. No faults.
No. So like, maybe they built it in zero G and then they're like conflating it with the UFO stuff,
which actually just shows up around nukes and in other contexts or whatever. But like,
they might've built it in zero G. Yeah. Yeah. That's the old cams razor explanation,
isn't it? That's the simplest. Okay. So there's like a space supply chain where
humans are manufacturing these exotic materials in space that you literally couldn't
make physically impossible enough on earth. Yes. Yeah. That's fascinating. I don't think,
has anybody ever explicitly tied together your thing like this, like we're doing now?
No, this is fresh and unique. I love this. This is fascinating because if you,
I mean, that makes sense. That makes sense. Like the other stuff doesn't make sense. I mean,
sending people 20 and back into through the sun into a portal or the, and maybe that's possible.
I don't know. Yeah. Super soldiers on Mars. No. Yeah. Super soldiers on Mars. I just,
we need more evidence if I've all entertained, you know, whatever, but you need evidence,
you know, you can't, you can't just, uh, yeah. I'm open to all stories. Yeah. But this is fascinating.
Okay. So you, it's like a space supply chain logistics, it's like a space factory essentially,
where they're creating these metamaterials that you can't make on earth and you need deep space to
create them. Yeah. And then, so the non-terrestrial officers would just be humans overseeing this
supply chain, this space supply chain. Yeah. This is really good because I never even saw it in that
way before. Ah, this is fascinating. Yeah. And what's ironic is they're probably making space travel that
much easier by creating these high dielectrics. Yeah. Which involve greater thrust in the Byfield
Brown effect. Yeah. So they're like making like, you know, their own program more powerful. Yeah.
With to fit. Ah, this is fascinating. Wow. Wow. All right. I like that. I like discovery as we go.
Yeah. I mean, who knows, but like that makes speculation, it is speculation, but it,
the idea that we have people in deep space or we have like literal alien, like men in black style,
like aliens walking among us. And then we put like Navy suits on them, commander suits on them.
They're like, you're a non-terrestrial officer or whatever. That makes less sense. Both of those
make less sense. Yeah. Just don't look at his huge armor shaped eyes. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
He'll crawl out of his skin suit occasionally, but like, you know, it's like that we're stuck between
those two options like that, or, you know, it's like aliens in like, you know, military garb or,
uh, you know, uh, uh, you know, uh, literally humans that we've spent that we've sent into like
super deep space or whatever. I've never believed in any of the stories of, um,
alien contact with governments. I think it's just outlandish.
Mm. Mm. Mm. Yeah. No, I think a lot of that stuff is pretty ridiculous. It feels like passage material
that like is meant to send people down the wrong trail or something. Yeah. At least it doesn't feel
like there's a ton of good evidence. I do think there are a lot of weird abduction cases where
people experience things, you know, and, and, you know, have you ever had anything like that or?
Uh, I had one very strange experience that I can't explain to this day. Um, it was back in 2006.
Mm-hmm. Uh, my girlfriend and I are in what we call a bed sit in the UK, tiny flat on the first
floor, not the ground floor. And, uh, we'd gone to bed, we'd gone to sleep and I was suddenly woken up
by a really sharp pain in my left heel. Mm. Mm.
And it felt like two or 3 AM felt like I'd been, I was in deep sleep. It'd been a few hours. I'm
like, what the hell is that? Like I kind of leaned forward to check it out. Like something had bitten
me that immediately I just went, oh, I was asleep again. In the morning I woke up and weirdly,
I don't know why I'd gone to bed with my socks on or at least one sock on. And then I remembered
what had happened during the night and I pulled the sock off and in my left heel, there were two
perfectly circular holes, both about five millimeters in diameter. And one still had
a flap of skin hanging off it, like a hole punch used for paper, but about these, this far apart.
What? I know. And I thought, what the hell? I'm on the first floor. It wasn't, I was trying to think
of every possible conventional explanation. Was it a rat with perfectly symmetrical five millimeter
teeth that come to my bed and bit me in the night, but I'm on the first floor, you know, not the ground
floor where like rodents could be, um, no explanation whatsoever. Um, I can't say much more than that,
because, but I did, um, later as I got more into electronics and electromagnetics, I did like scans
and stuff. And then didn't come up. Couldn't find anything wrong. But a few years later,
I found out, cause this is some, this is something I'm always researching and looking for an answer.
Cause I still haven't got one. There's a company. I don't know if it was Verisign. There's some
chipping like electronic chipping company and their process was exactly like that.
No way. Yeah. A double injection. Um, and then years later, I've got two bumps that formed where
those holes were and then moved around. And I still have those bumps on my hill today.
Do you think a human did that? Do you think an alien did it? I'm thinking some kind of government
tracking, government tracking, which I feel ridiculous saying it. Well, do you feel ridiculous
saying? Cause you had a, a 20 year, you know, uh, prime ministers were negotiating with American
presidents on your behalf, uh, because the American government had it out for you. So I don't think,
you know, I think for a normal person being like, you know, they, they wanted to chip me or whatever,
like that might be a little paranoid, but yeah, uh, I think in your case, I'm not so sure, man.
Yeah. But even so I wasn't running away, you know, I was on bail. Everything was safe. I was
contained as they would put it. Uh, but yeah, I just can't explain that. It's just weird as hell.
Interesting. And do you still have that in your foot?
I still have the bumps. Can I see him?
Yeah. I hope no one's got any foot fetishes or the opposite.
Maybe you can start an OnlyFans after this.
All right. Striptease time.
But you've not done this before.
This is wild.
Are we ready?
Yeah.
So this company Veritas.
No, I think it was VeriSign or something.
VeriSign.
I might've, it definitely began with a V, but I can't remember.
And they do these little chip implants.
Yeah. So when I woke up with the holes, they were kind of around here in the corner,
but now they've, they've moved slightly. So one's there. It's a lesser.
Whoa.
And the other one's there.
The other one's big.
Yeah.
Like that's like very easy to spot.
Yeah. And that's the other one.
Okay.
I think that's shrunk over time, actually.
Yeah. It feels smaller.
Yeah.
Whoa.
Weird.
The company Gary is talking about here isn't called VeriSign. It's called VeriChip. And yes,
it's done work in human microchipping. In fact, the company has produced a tiny RFID microchip
about the size of a grain of rice that implants under the skin, transmits a unique ID when scanned,
and links to a database with personal or medical information.
This chip is essentially a permanent tracking and identification tool.
To think something so small can connect you to everything that matters.
When your life and all you love are on the line.
The chip was introduced to the market in 2002, just a few years before Gary's experience in 2005.
And according to Gary, the company's double injection method would cause something that
looks exactly like the two bumps on his foot. I'll let you decide if that's a coincidence or not.
If you look a little deeper, VeriChip's corporate lineage runs through applied digital
solutions. And prospectus filings showed that the implantable microchips themselves
were ultimately sourced from a subsidiary of Raytheon.
What we do saves lives. It protects peace and democracy throughout the world.
Yes, that Raytheon. One of the largest defense contractors in the world.
Deeply embedded in military systems, missile guidance, radar, and classified electronics.
By the end of the 2000s, VeriChip themselves had secured the rights to technology that would
allow the chips to detect viruses from inside the body, including strains like H1N1.
The proposal described an implant that could determine whether a virus was present,
what kind it was, and how serious the threat might be.
At that point, the device would no longer just be identifying a person.
It would be monitoring their unique physiology and biomedical data.
Completely dystopian, to say the least.
And even more dystopian knowing that this tracking technology was likely used in retaliation
on an ordinary citizen like Gary McKinnon.
So if that were surgically removed, what do you think you would find?
I don't know. Maybe two lumps of unanalysable material. I don't know. I didn't have so much
good equipment back then, but now I have really good stuff for electromagnetic analysis, radio
frequency analysis. And I'd rather do that first before having it removed.
You should do all that.
Yeah.
You should do it like tomorrow.
Okay. I'll ask my local doctor.
I'm just saying, I'm just saying, you know, you don't want, uh, the names to go missing,
like in the, you know, non-terrestrial officers, like you want it, you get like, do it now,
you know? Yeah. Yeah. Figure it out.
Uh, so I joke, we're, we're in between your implant experience and then this possible space
supply chain for anti-gravity materials. And I don't know where to go. My head's exploding.
Um, but, uh, yeah. I mean, is there anything just going back to the materials thing and the,
the fleet to fleet transfer? It's just so fascinating. And it's fascinating that you're
into Townsend Brown too. It's like, you have this like hermetic connection to this whole subject.
Like you were meant to like, see that or something like, like what do you do anything else as far as
takeaways from that document, you know, and, and interpreting it because it was James Fox came out
with the program and he, he, you know, uh, did this great piece on you, but I think a lot of people
do take what you found and run with it. Um, as far as just the people out there, like their
interpretations of it when they see, you know, uh, people discuss it. Yeah. So you're, this is your
interpretation that it's some sort of supply chain in space or something or, well, we, we stumbled on
that together, together, I guess. So yeah, I, I really connected it in that way that it was a
supply chain. It just came to my mind while we were speaking. And in light of what we both know
now, it does make sense in terms of potential propulsion, the materials that might be necessary
for that as a dielectric or, so it's pretty amazing. No, it makes total sense. There was a
company called made in space that tried to do this for a while. There's now a probably more
promising company called Varda space, which does this. It's like factories in space. At the end of the
day, you can think of the value proposition as this is we can do special chemistry because we
can essentially turn off gravity for the manufacturing engineer. And then often
commercial companies are doing things that have already been done in classified settings.
And so the stuff that was done in classified settings might've been this, you know, who knows?
I mean, right now, I think we, it's like we have that are known like six people in space,
like six astronauts, like on, you know, the ISS and on various space, I think the, you know,
Chinese space station, they have an astronaut or two. So the idea that how many officers were on this
list at least 40 ish, 40 ish. So maybe they're in space or maybe they were also in, maybe they were
in orbit or maybe they were just managing this non-terrestrial, you know, uh, kind of atomic
layer deposition process or, you know, materials manufacturing or something.
Yeah. I've always thought they weren't aliens. I thought this is bound to be,
because it says non-terrestrial, obviously it's not extra-terrestrial. So in other words, they're
on a fleet that isn't based in space and on earth.
When we talk about a speculative secret space program, we should establish something clearly.
There really was an uncontested, very real and now declassified secret space program.
The US Air Force ran its own classified manned space effort alongside NASA's more public facing ones.
In the 1960s, while the world watched Saturn V rockets rise under the banner of Apollo,
the Air Force was developing the Manned Orbiting Laboratory,
a military space station designed for reconnaissance of America's enemies and other orbital operations.
17 military astronauts were selected. A modified Gemini capsule was built.
Titan III rockets were assigned. Launches into polar orbit were planned from Vandenberg.
And then in June of 1969, exactly one month before the Apollo mission reached the moon for the first time,
the Manned Orbiting Laboratory was canceled.
Advances in automated spy satellites made human observers redundant.
Vietnam was draining resources. The Apollo program was imminent.
So the classified space program was folded.
But in defense culture, cancellation does not necessarily mean disappearance.
Programs are restructured. Personnel are reassigned.
Infrastructure is absorbed into deeper compartments.
So what happened to the military astronaut program?
Where did the classified orbital expertise go?
And what was really going on with the classified space program?
In 1993, former Lockheed Skunk Works director Ben Rich was speaking at a UCLA alumni event.
Rich had overseen programs like the U-2, the SR-71, and the F-117.
Stealth aircraft that had lived in total secrecy before becoming public knowledge.
At the end of his presentation, according to multiple attendees,
Rich's final slide showed a black disc-shaped craft flying into space.
He closed with the famous words,
We now have the technology to take E.T. home.
Was he just messing with the audience?
Rich would end up dying just two years later.
But towards the end of his life, he would privately say things that sounded very similar
to this UCLA speech.
Things about prodigious American space capabilities the public could barely dream of.
Just before Ben Rich passed away, when I was talking to him,
he told me, at the end of a 45-minute conversation, he said,
Jim, we have things out in the desert, and he wasn't referring to Area 51.
We have things out in the desert that is 50 years beyond what you can comprehend.
And I can comprehend a hell of a lot.
And he said, if you've seen movies like Star Trek or Star Wars,
we've been there, done that, or decided it wasn't worth the effort.
Ben Rich's son, Michael Rich, was the president and CEO of RAND Corporation for decades.
RAND was the Santa Monica-based, federally funded research and development center
evaluating the prospects of Project Orion, nuclear pulse propulsion craft that could theoretically
carry very large crews, reach Mars or outer planets, and enable long-duration missions.
Not coincidentally, RAND has also conducted comprehensive research on the non-engineering
side of deep space travel, crew psychology and isolation, life support logistics, radiation
hazards, resupply challenges, cost and national priorities. RAND Corporation also happened to be
intensely interested in the gravity-manipulating deep space propulsion work of Townsend Brown.
His work going dark after he showed them a demo in 1967.
President Ronald Reagan may have also inadvertently left a hint around secret
American space capabilities in his diary entry from June 11, 1985.
Lunch was with five top space scientists. It was fascinating. Space truly is the last frontier.
And some of the developments there in astronomy, etc. are like science fiction, except they are real.
I learned that our shuttle capacity is such we could orbit 300 people. You read that right.
Not one shuttle crew. Not a single mission. 300 people in Earth's orbit. In space.
If you ask your favorite AI conversation agent, it'll tell you that we only have
10 or so people in space today. But we somehow had the capacity for 300 in the 80s?
In 2020, Haim Eshed, former head of Israel's Defense Ministry's Space Directorate,
essentially the father of the Israeli space program, publicly claimed that American astronauts
and alien representatives were operating on underground bases on Mars. These bizarre
hints have stacked up over the decades, and maybe they are mirrored in one of the most famous
fictional versions of a secret space force, Stargate. With visible cooperation from the U.S. Air Force,
the production of the show Stargate leaned on real-world military structures and culture.
In fact, two sitting Air Force Chiefs of Staff, Michael E. Ryan and John P. Jumper,
appeared on the show as themselves. These guys literally ran the Air Force and were showing up for
cameos on this show. The lead actor on the show, Richard Dean Anderson, was later made an honorary
Brigadier General, in recognition of what the Air Force described as the program's positive portrayal
of the service. The show's central premise? A classified off-world program run by the Air Force
from a hidden command facility. Show it. Of course, the military connection might have just been due to
some fans among the Air Force staff. Or maybe it was just another tiny hint towards something really
big going on in secret. Strange stories of a parallel space program are apocryphal, but they are more
abundant than you might think. Like this stunning revelation shared with Ross Colthart on Chris Ramsey's Area 52.
There was a conversation I had with someone who I trust, who got very emotional and described
a friend of his dying on the moon. Wow. And what do you make of that? I didn't know what to make of it.
It's important to remember that the public didn't even know the NRO, or National Reconnaissance Office,
existed for decades. The parallel classified Air Force astronaut program wasn't fully declassified
until 2015. So is it so crazy to think we might have experimented with covert human spaceflight
and exotic material supply chains since then? The benefits of building materials in space cannot
be understated. Matter in space, because of its lower-gravity environment, behaves in ways that are
basically impossible on Earth. Without gravity, there's no convection, no settling, no buoyancy,
tearing materials apart as they form. Liquids stay perfectly mixed. Crystals grow with extraordinary
purity. Optical fibers can be drawn with almost no internal flaws, potentially outperforming anything
made on the ground. So it's also not that crazy to assume that we've experimented with this technology
for extremely high-value metamaterials used at the highest levels of aerospace. Now where would
such a program be headquartered? NASA's Johnson Space Center in Houston is not only where McKinnon
found UFO-related images and spreadsheets. It's the NASA complex that specifically focuses on human
spaceflight. The notorious line, Houston, we have a problem, refers to mission control at Johnson Space
Center in Houston. So if you were operating a manned spaceflight operation involving a material
supply chain, that's exactly where you'd put it. I should be clear too, like, both of us aren't trying
to fully pour cold water on UFO crashes. Like, I think... No, not at all. I think, like, I think Roswell
happened. I think that Virginia happened in 1996. So it's always yes and in the UFO world. Like, it's
all like all the... But I think intentional conflations also are systematically done by the
intelligence world. And it's important to be able to parse through all these things.
Yeah. And of course, it's human nature to super associate stuff with something you want to be true.
So we can all fall down that hole as well. Yeah, no, of course. Well, I'm officially shocked.
This is crazy. I mean, the Navy does do, like, the most exotic materials stuff as well. Like,
there's this place, Naval Surface Warfare Crane, that does this. Battelle Memorial Institute does
a lot of exotic material stuff as well. And so, yeah, I really, I do wonder if, you know, yeah,
some of this is human made. And then if you say it's of alien provenance, then it's this, like,
perfect, you know, kind of black box where, like, people can interpret it however they want. And...
Yeah, it's a great shield, isn't it? Good umbrella.
It is. And then the fact that... And what's wild is that, like, you're now experimenting with
materials. Like, you literally have materials in mind that make the Bifield-Brown effect. Like,
you're interested in these antigravity experiments that involve some of these chemicals and materials
that you saw. Yeah. Which is wild. Yeah. Well, the, um, yeah. It's, um, yeah,
since 2007. Since I first read about Bifield-Brown. How'd you read about it? How'd you come across it?
I don't remember precisely, but it was... Because that's early.
Yeah, it was undoubtedly researching UFO stuff. But antigravity stuff specifically would have brought
me to that. Um, but yeah, what attracted me was the fact that you can, you can do this in your,
you know, home garage or shed or whatever, you know, you don't have to be a scientist. You have
to be a scientist to understand the mechanism, which no one has yet does. But you don't have to be a
scientist to do it on the bench and try some experiments because all it, a capacitor, two
conductive plates in between them sandwiched, uh, an insulator, a dielectric that stores electric
charge. So, you know, what, what's complicated about that? Um, and if you read all the
so-called research into the BB effect, none of it's exhaustive, none of it. It's all, oh,
I did five kilovolts at DC. I did 10 kilovolts at AC. Obviously Beulah went very far. There are a few
people that went far, army research laboratory, but no one's done a huge battery of tests with
a multitude of dielectrics, a multitude of, uh, different plates, the mass of the plates,
not just the material. Uh, is it AC? Is it DC? Do you use a side wave? Do you use a, a ramp wave
or a triangle wave or a sawtooth wave or, um, how long is your pulse? What's your delay? It's
the, there's so many, well, there's quite a few parameters compared to a lot of stuff,
but for a home experimenter, it's doable within a few hundred hours, I think. And I, I've probably
done about 60 hours all told I've done thousands of hours of reading, but probably 60 hours experimentation.
Wow. Wild. Oh, so you've done 60 hours of running the actual experiment. Oh no, no, no. Like, like
research into materials trying. Yeah, I did try. I mean, I started off with lifters.
Okay. Yeah. Try and get a baker foil. And that was, yeah, it's interesting. Yeah.
But it's bolts of wood and baker foil. And there, there was, there used to be, uh, a website called
blaze lamps and, um, they had some really well-informed guys there, ex aerospace that knew all the,
like, um, aerodynamic mass and stuff. And they said, just like army research laboratory, they said,
there's no way that this battered, you know, metal foil sheet, which isn't even perfectly smooth,
like an airplane wing. There's no way that aerodynamically that can be pushed just by
ion flow, just the way, uh, ARL said it was like at least 10, 20% above what could be achieved by iron
flow. Which is exactly what Brown said. And so for the audience, Townsend Brown is this mid
century, very mysterious, uh, inventor who started with the Navy, then joined, uh, Martin Vega, which
was, you know, pre Lockheed Martin merger, uh, you know, the year that skunk works formed and then
kind of popped up in all sorts of, you know, three letter agency contexts and was, you know,
shoulder to shoulder with elite American military brass, people like Curtis LeMay, you know, just this
very mysterious figure who consistently claimed that he would get these positive results in these
anti-gravity experiments or what he called electrogravitics. There's even a video of him
popping champagne from the Bonson lab at the Institute of field physics in North Carolina,
which we know is the CIA outpost studying anti-gravity and literally convening all of the best,
uh, theoretical physicists on the question of gravity in 1957. And it was all sponsored by Wright
Airfield, which is where all the UFO rumors come from. They were literally paying for this,
you know, for a lot of this research. Yeah. Weird connections. Um, and so if you take
what he claimed about his own, his own experiments at face value, you'd have this crazy update against,
you know, SpaceX and like chemical combustion, it would be this like total paradigm shifting thing.
It's not, it's not a small deal. It's a really big deal. Yeah.
And the thing about Brown is we almost know, we know for a fact that he was one of the number
one radar guys in the Navy. There's an FBI file from 1942 or three that basically says he knows
more about radar than anybody in the Navy. Whoa.
And that's, that's number one. Number two, electro hydrodynamics, which is not electro gravitics.
It's the manipulation of airflow with electric fields, which is how that the tin foil, you know,
balsa wood, uh, you know, DIY, uh, uh, foilers work and fly. Uh, but it's also what made it into
the B two stealth bomber. And I'm pretty sure I've, I kind of have the receipts on that too. So like
that's, so you have these two things where he's like the best, like EHD, you know,
electro hydrodynamics and radar. And then he's claiming that he could also merge electromagnetism
and gravity, which is the Holy grail of physics theory. And so it's like, okay. So like he's right
on two out of the three things, but he's a total quack on the third thing. And there's so much smoke
around it. And then now you have the lead electrostatic scientist at NASA who could
is the global authority on being able to tell you that this experiment is only attributable
to conventional electrostatics. And he's saying that, no, this is, it works. It works in a vacuum.
So you can't do it with ionized air physics in its, in its current form, cannot explain this.
And his own experiments, Charles Buehler, who you mentioned, are derivative of Townsend Brown's
work. And so like, I think there is so much smoke. There's a Japanese experiment that you mentioned,
the Musha paper.
Yeah, Musha, Takeda.
And, and, uh, they say that they get, uh, you know, uh, a successful result. In that case,
I think they submerge, uh, the whole thing in, in, in transmission oil, which also you can't
ionize transmission oil. Like, you know, that's not going to work. Um,
so, uh, yeah. Are they coordinating with these people in the U S for like, you know,
are they like some deep state thing in Japan? Like, I don't think so. You know, it's like this
global thing. So yeah, this is wild. So I, and when I, we were setting this up and, uh, you know,
I was talking to you on the phone and you were like, yeah, I'm super into Townsend Brown. I was
like, what, this is going to be the best interview ever. Well, yeah. I really enjoyed your,
I call it your Bifield Brown special. I don't know if that's what you, I'll take it. Yeah.
It was called the Bifield Brown special. Yeah. Yeah. Well, thank you. Well, well,
kudos to you for being into Townsend Brown in 2007, because, uh, the Man Who Mastered
Gravity by Paul Shatzkin was this great biography that only came out in like, I think around the
pandemic and he created, he had this other version of it that wasn't really edited super
neatly or concisely. I think that might've come out in like 2009 or something. And he kind of
stepped away from the project, but 2007, like you're talking about Townsend Brown being on the
dark corners of the web. Like the, like you gotta like, you know, that's where I used to live.
Yeah. It sounds, sounds like it. Yeah, man. Um, and wasn't Paul LaViolette who first introduced the
idea of the B2 using that? Yeah. So here's where I think Paul LaViolette got wrong. Cause he wrote
this great history of anti-gravity and he talks about microwave beam propulsion alongside Townsend
Brown's Bifield Brown effect. And you know, he's a really brilliant guy. He had his own theory called,
uh, uh, sub quantum kinetics. Oh yeah. His whole. Yeah. Which was fascinating.
Uh, and he seems like just a brilliant, brilliant. I would have loved to have interviewed him. He died
a few years ago, sadly. He's dead. Yeah. It sucks. Yeah. No way. I was in email contact with him. I
thought up until two years ago, but obviously got that wrong. And we were going to have a, I was going
to start a podcast and he was going to be my first interview. Oh dude, that would have been the best
thing. But he said he had hip problems. He was undergoing hip surgery or something. So he,
oh man. Okay. Yeah. Yeah. No, it's a real bummer. And, uh, but I think where he,
and it's an amazing book and everybody should read it, but I do think he, he says that the B2 had
like an anti-gravity drive. And I, I don't think that's correct. I think. I thought he just said the
leading edge. It was like a capacitor. Yes. So the leading edge was one plate and the trailing edge was
another plate. Yeah. So, and I think he's, I think he's right about that,
but I think that just manipulates the airflow like that just makes the airflow. Yeah. It's like,
reduce the, you know, lift to drag ratio. Yeah. It wasn't a full or increase, increase the lift
to drag ratio. Sorry. Yeah. So it made it slightly faster. Yeah. It makes it more aerodynamic and
faster. I mean, maybe there's some real electro-gavitic thing happening, but there's no, there'd be no way to
like fully say because it's happening, not in a vacuum. So like maybe there is something, you know,
actually happening there that is, you know, top secret and it's super, yeah, it's top secret,
but I also don't know why they would necessarily declassify the B2 if it was using electro-gravitics
per se. I will say there is a guy named William Gunston, who is the preeminent aerospace journalist
in the UK, um, or was, uh, and, you know, as part of like the Royal air society and has all these awards
and stuff. And for, um, I think it was like air international magazine. He did like a history of,
you know, aero engine tech since world war two. And then he gets to Townsend Brown and he goes
with Townsend Brown, like, you know, I will refrain from talking about, you know, leading edges charged
to millions of volts, positive followed by trailing edges charged to millions of volts, negative,
because I don't want to end up in the tower of London.
And then he says that, and then he caveats it a little bit more. So like, I don't know if that
caveating is genuine, you know, unsuredness of what he's saying in the tower of London,
which for the audience was a place of torture, was a place of torture.
Does he mean professionally or like as a whole, like giving away secrets?
Or if he's literally saying these are state secrets and, and then I don't know if the caveats are
like, I don't want, you know, I really don't want to be implicated for having said this. So I'm
going to sprinkle in some doubt or whatever. I don't know, but it's interesting.
Yeah.
But, um, so, so you, you, you are, do you want to pull off one of these experiments or?
Oh, hell yeah. Um, I'm planning it by April, the latest I've been, um,
distracted for a while and had to do other things. I'm only doing these experiments in a 10 by 10 foot
shed and, um, they're not expensive, but they consume a lot of time. Yeah. And I have, I'm
basically doing industrial processes in a, in a garden shed. So it's, it's a bit, I've got, but I,
the first thing I bought, cause you have to eat this stuff to a thousand degrees, the calcium copper
titanate, uh, to a thousand degrees. And then I had to buy a 10 ton hydraulic press. Uh, I bought a gas
furnace and then because of the geometry and stuff that, that wasn't unusual. So then I bought an
electric furnace, which is much smaller and, you know, easy to manipulate this tiny disc.
So cool.
It's only 40 millimeters across. I'm starting off very small. Um, so I've got to make that
into what they call a green body, make that solid. I bought really high quality silver paste as the
plates. Uh, but then after that, you have to think of when you've got these two plates at 30 kilovolts
or more, you get arcing currents, you get sparks basically. Um, so I have to find a way to stop
that. And my first thought was to have very small discs on top of the 40 millimeter diameter calcium
copper titanate, the CCTO. Um, but there's, there's other ways to do it as well. So I've got to,
I've got to figure out a path and then completely cause I really want to see it float. I want to
stand there in my shed, turn the on switch on and see this thing rise.
That would be amazing. If you made something levitate, you would kind of,
the haters would have nothing to say. Yeah.
What do you say at that point? You say it's ionized.
Video is not real these days. It could be AI.
Yeah. Sure. That's a good point. Would you do this in a vacuum chamber?
Uh, yeah, eventually I do have one vacuum chamber. That's, that's for my resin and it
only goes down to like minus 99 MPA or something. Um, but I mean, Gravitech has done it in a vacuum
chamber. They used to contract for NASA.
Who's Gravitech?
Gravitech is under a different name now, but they've, they've got, I can send you the videos.
What's his name? Uh, not Henry, Henrik something. I've had a few emails with him as well.
Um, yeah, they've done it in a vacuum, a proper vacuum, like, you know, minus hundreds of tall.
Um, shout out to Gravitech. I want, I want to check that out. I've never heard of that.
He's got a different company now, but I've got his email. I'll send you.
Oh, please.
Yeah. Get him on, man. He'd be, he'd be glad to.
I'd love to.
And he now does stuff for satellites. I think like private satellites, uh, not using this.
Actually, I don't even know enough to comment, but yeah, he's, he's done it in a vacuum.
Interesting. And it is less.
Why wouldn't he pursue it? Like, you know, more substantively after that. Sounds like
he just went straight to satellite.
I think, yeah, I think he wants to be commercial, make money, do well for himself. Um, and probably,
maybe that's as far as he wants it to go. It works in a vacuum, but also you have like, uh, Jean-Louis
Nordin, the French, um, kind of YouTube scientist, I want to call him. I don't know his credentials for real.
He's done it in vacuum tubes. Um, he's isolated the electrode in vacuum tubes. So, but I don't know
what the pressure was. So this is, I mean, yeah, so you're right. There is this whole global community
of DIY independent creators, aerospace professionals who in their private life just want to pursue this
or UFO nuts or whatever outside of, you know, whatever they're doing. And, uh, most of them
say that there's a, there, there, there are very few people that say there aren't that they're there.
The ones that do, I believe there's, um, you know, an air for the guy, his last name is Tally
and he's an air force guy. And I think he consistently use this very low voltage and tries
to explain it away. And I even, I spoke to this one Navy scientist and he was like, Tally's just
a bad actor. Like he's like brought on the scene. Like he's, he's like this guy in UFO world named
Sean Kirkpatrick. Who's the former arrow director. Who's like brought on to like, you know, dismiss.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. So we know, um, uh, Tim Ventura or propulsion. Yeah, I do. Yeah. He's a good
guy. Yeah. He had that guy on that did, um, had similar effects with very low voltage, like five
KV, five kilovolts. I think it was Bueller now or because Bueller thinks it's the electric. Yeah.
So this is the, the NASA electrostatics. Cause there was a previous Bueller in my old documentation
for like pre two thousands. Whoa. Unless that was his dad or maybe it was cause he maybe,
what's he like mid fifties now? Maybe it was him. Yeah. What in, in your old documentation?
Yeah. Yeah. I've got documents with a Bueller and I didn't think it was him, but maybe it is.
Well, we'll have to, we didn't do that doc swap. We said we'd do a doc swap.
Oh yeah. Yeah. Oh shit. Yeah. I'd love to. Um, yeah. Do you, do you have like a lot of
compiled information about this sort of stuff? Oh, sweet. Cool. Yeah. Interesting.
Huge zip file. Uh, and in terms of free energy, there's one thing, um, I found that I found,
but I found the guy that discovered it. Um, so Lindsay's law, um, stops the motor rotating because
of, you know, the, uh, counter electromagnetic force. If you look at the formula for that,
um, the, the strong element of that is the inductance of the coil.
Hmm. And this guy found that if you increase the induct, his name is Thane Hines. If you increase
the inductance of the coil, then the rise time of the opposing magnetic field that slows the turning
of the motor down when you're applying power to a load is delayed, just like delaying timing in a car
engine. And he found that not only could he delay it enough to stop the counter, the C, CEMF
counter-electro-motor force dragging, creating electromagnetic drag. When it's past a certain
point phase angle, it assisted the rotation. Wow. Yeah. Yeah. So your standards electric
generator is a disc with magnets and underneath it coils. And he found that when, um, so the magnet
is spinning around, it gets to what they call TDC top dead center above the coil with his method,
because it delays that opposing, because when the magnet, so let's say it's a North pole facing down
and it cuts into the coil that creates a South pole in the coil that opposes the incoming movement of
the magnet. And then when the magnets moving out of the coil, it creates a North pole, uh, North pole,
which accelerates it out. And he found that when you do this stupidly simple, but incredibly effective
time delay, um, the CEMF rises in such a way it's late on the income. So the magnet gets pulled in
and it's early on the outgoing. So the magnet gets pushed out. So it accelerates the incoming and the
outgoing. And he took it to such an extent that eventually there's no opposition at all. And you can
actually reverse, you're not reversing Lenzi's law, because that's an inaccurate physics statement,
but you're reversing the effect of Lenzi's law. Yeah. And I did a small experiment. I'll send you
the video. Um, I did the most simple magnetic emoji you can. I had, um, a cylinder shaped magnet,
which is diametrically magnetized. It's not North on top, South on the bottom. Each curved half is a North
and South poles. I had that in a vertical shaft rotating, and I show it with a normal generator
coil, which when you attach it to a load, the power input needed increases to support the load.
And, um, the rotation slows down. Well, when I put his coil on, which has higher inductance,
when you tell that call to power or load, the rotation speed increases and the input current
goes down the complete opposite of motor theory, motor generator theory. Whoa.
That's the one and only thing I've seen and been able to replicate the works in terms of free
energy. And this guy is now, he's got contracts with Siemens, Phillips with him. He's talking to
China. It's about to blow up. Whoa.
And I've been following him since about 2007 to on over unity.com. The first forum I saw him.
Fast. What's his name?
Thane Hines.
Thane Hines. Where's he based?
He's Canadian physicist.
Dude, you are deep down the rabbit hole of alternative propulsion and energy.
You've got to interview this guy.
I would love to.
He's like your general kind of crazy man genius. He's, um, not so good at social interaction.
Yeah.
But he's got it, man.
It's typical of somebody who makes like real breakthroughs like that,
you know, for them to be not always like the most-
I think he's got a lot in his mind.
I think he's got a lot in his mind as well.
Yeah.
It's fascinating. What do you think this chip in your foot, like, does it, does it ever like burn
or buzz or-
No. It's sometimes close.
No.
So there's nothing, basically you've gotten no incremental information on it outside of-
Just a couple of lumps that have moved over time towards the inside of the arch of the foot.
Strange. Have you ever, uh, had a sort of like, any sort of men in black experience or experience
with, you know, strange men in suits showing up at your place or-
No, but my lawyer had her office and her car robbed.
Really?
Which is obviously not. Men in black are small earthly powers.
Mm.
Um, no, nothing. Men in black.
Mm. Did, uh, did. Okay. So when, when you hacked in
to all of these sensitive American military sites, how did you get caught and what happened next?
Oh man. Yeah. I got, uh, got lazy, got egotistical.
Um, I thought, oh, I can go anywhere I like, look at anything. And, uh, I started making direct
connections instead of jumping through various IP addresses. So I was making direct connections to,
you know, the target and I was using like free AOL signup CDs. So I wasn't being at all, you know,
like a professional hacker. I was just, yeah, I thought I could just do it. I thought, oh,
these guys don't even know, don't even have passwords. They wouldn't even know I've been here.
Uh, but yeah, eventually, um, obviously when that guy right clicked the LAN icon and disconnected me,
that was NASA. And they reported to BT, British Telecom, which is my internet service provider at
the time and said, who's this IP at this time. And they said I was, uh, in fact, they didn't have my
name at first. I don't know if my internet account was my girlfriend's name or if we were using her
aunt's internet or something. But the horrible thing was when they came with the national high
tech crime unit, they came to arrest me. The warrant was for the whole house and they came early in the
morning, arrested me, my girlfriend, my girlfriend's aunt's daughter, who was only like 12 or something
at the time. So it was quite a horrible experience with extended family and all my fault.
And, uh, why are they arrested 12 year old?
Uh, well, just to question sure. Not, not arrest on the, not to jail.
Yeah. Yeah. That's still, uh, it must have been traumatic for.
Yeah. Cause they didn't know who the person was. They knew it was someone at that address.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. And, um, and unfortunately, yeah,
my ex-girlfriend's cousin, he, he was quite, um, anti-authoritarian and quite alternative mate.
I think they thought it was him. Oh, it must be him. He's got purple hair.
He must be the guy. Oh, so yeah, I'm laughing now, but it's horrible. Cause it affected so
many other people, you know, Mike's stupid curiosity, but James mentioned something about
guys looking over you at your bed or something like, like at night or something.
Oh, no, that's probably when I was arrested. Cause I was arrested in my sleep,
Wait, so, so you were arrested in your sleep?
Yeah. The national high tech crime unit. I I'd been up all night playing galactic
civilizations for some big space game and, um, and probably smoking still as well and gone to bed
late. So I was asleep at eight in the morning. My girlfriend was getting ready to go to work.
Knock, knock, knock. She's in her dressing gown. They're patting her down and pushing her into a
room. Then they come into my room. I'm in bed and I've got, let's got it. Gary McKinnon. I'm Jeff
Johnson from the national high tech crime unit. You're under arrest for computer misuse. So it's
yeah. And then from, from that point onwards, the UK was like, okay with more of kind of a slap on the
wrist sort of thing. And then it was the U S that was like, no, we need to extradite him now. And then
what you mentioned, they changed the extradition laws to make it this sort of blanket thing that
applied to you. Yeah, definitely. So, uh, when I was first arrested, um, the national high tech
crime unit who were the arrested body said to me, you'll do six months inside, maybe community
service, maybe no jail time. Uh, cause under UK law, all I did was unauthorized access. You know,
I didn't break anything or steal anything or make money or anything like that. And, um, but then these
officers went to America at O and I, and I must say office of Naval intelligence, cause there's
another O and I, there's an intelligence sister. I think investigation or something, but I don't
know. Yeah. And, um, when they came back, they had a very heavy tone, a completely different tone about
them. We were very impressed by meeting with the top brass in Washington and, um, yeah, oh, this, oh,
this guy caused $5,000 of damage on every PC he was on, you know, which is just stupid.
How do you damage the hardware? If you just do this like software hack that we're calling a hack,
but you're using like off the shelf stuff. Yeah. It's like PC anywhere. Yeah. But I think
what they call damage is the time it took them to take them offline. The machines are unusable for a
while, investigate them. So as you know, you know what, it feels like kind of white hack hacking to me,
cause you didn't actually end up using any of the files in a way to hurt the U S or their, like,
again, you can say what you will about Snowden or the Sandra, any of these guys. Like there's
nothing you did to like knock the U S down a leg as far as their tactical ability to like,
you know, do things. So it's almost like a white hat hack because the costs they incurred to take
the stuff down and reset them, they would have needed to do anyways. That would have been,
what if like a malicious person had like, you know, kind of traded all these servers,
that's what I'm saying. Yeah. So they're actually extremely lucky that you did what you did.
$5,000. Where are you buying your PCs from? No, they should. I mean, you literally white hat
hackers get paid. So like, I think, I think they should pay you. All right. I'm just saying.
Please send the email. Yeah. You know, I'm serious. It's like you literally, you didn't
do anything showing malintent. Once you got the info, they got the info back and then they reset
ideally their computer networking and architecture in a way that, you know, these sort of phishing
attacks couldn't be done. These are basic things that you're using. Yeah. So I just like, I think
it's like insecure. It almost sounds like somebody in, in, in like middling bureaucracy, who's trying
to cover their ass. Like this took us all this. Well, you should have done it before. Yeah. What
are you doing? You're not doing your job. Yeah. Yeah. If it was some super sophisticated quantum
error correction that you had figured out in 2000, that would be one thing that would be like, okay.
And then you used it in this sort of detrimental way to American national security.
I decrypted NSA. Yeah. But otherwise, I mean, I don't know, man, that feels like a kind of crazy.
Okay. So then what happens to the extradition laws? Oh man. So yeah, the original extradition law,
which I think was 1989, um, was a good basic law. We accuse this British citizen of having committed a
crime in or against America. Uh, we have this evidence and it's a crime over here and it's a crime
over there. So we should have him in America to stand trial, totally fair, totally reasonable.
Um, but then, I mean, this is the weird thing in law, computer crime is a weird thing. It's a gray
area. Cause it's not physical. Where, where's your bum at the seat when you commit the crime. There's
lots of like questions that are legally intransigent, you know, like, how do you place this?
Um, so what happened was I was arrested in 2002 and in March, and then I was re-questioned by the,
the LHTC, you went to visit the DOJ in August. Then they came back, then they re-interviewed me
in November, 2002. And that's when their tone had changed, very serious. You're accused of harming
military systems that could be used in prison. And that's when, you know, things really got serious
for me. I thought, my God, this is just blown out of all proportion. Um, but we were protected by
the extradition law because there had to be evidence of malintent, et cetera. And I, when I did my police
interview, I completely admitted to what I'd done because it was all on the hard drive. You know,
I said, yeah, it's all on the hard drive. I went there and I got this document, went to another place,
got other documents. So I was open about it, thinking, oh, six months, like they tell me,
I'll be fine. And they said community service. So I can do both. I'll be fine.
Although I wouldn't have liked six months in prison. But, um, when it came to November and
then they threatened extradition, then on paper, it was 70 years in jail, 70 years. It was like 10,
seven counts, 10 years per count. And I just, I just went crazy. I thought, this is absolutely mad.
What are we going to do? And, um, there was a lot of, um, like the, the UFO community in America
wanted me to stand trial in America. I was like a martyr.
Right.
Yeah. So it'd be great. He'll come over. He'll, they'll open all the secrets and he'll make it.
After. But what America actually said, the DOJ said that I'd be tried under military order number one,
which is Guantanamo status, totally secret, no media, Jesus, no media cover, no family visits,
you know, me in an orange suit with my red hair, joking, sorry. But yes, it, it went really scary,
like really scary, like over the top, like, well, you know, Kafka, Kafkaesque. Yeah.
As many people said, damn. Hey, you must've been, uh, you must've felt horrible. You must've been
like the, the, you know, world's out to get me or the, the most, uh, powerful nation in the world,
uh, you know, is out to get me. Yeah. And, uh, that, that must be a scary feeling.
Yeah. Well, it started in late 2002 and by 2008, because we lost so many court cases and hearings,
I've given up all hope. And I thought there's no way I'm going to give my fucking life to a foreign jail.
And I bought potassium chloride, one of the three chemicals in the lethal injection. And I thought,
if I get that decision, I'm just going to not inject it. I, I looked up the amount, how many
grams per kilogram of body weight, and I was just going to swallow it and have a heart attack and die.
Since I came into office, the sole issue on which I have been required to make a decision
is whether Mr. McKinnon's extradition to the United States would breach his human rights.
After careful consideration of all of the relevant material, I have concluded
that Mr. McKinnon's extradition would give rise to such a high risk of him ending his life.
That a decision to extradite would be incompatible with Mr. McKinnon's human rights.
I have therefore withdrawn the extradition, extradition order against Mr. McKinnon.
That was incredible. Theresa May.
So yeah, it's heavy.
That's heavy, man. That's really intense. And, uh, I'm sorry it got to that, uh, place. Cause that's,
it's ridiculous. If you look at the fact pattern, it's just insane.
Yeah.
And again, I'm saying that some of these other whistleblower cases, there are nuances to them.
You know, I'm, I'm saying yours, I think it's an absolute witch. That's, that's crazy.
Yeah. I agree. It's just crazy. Um, yeah, I don't even know what to say. I'm so sorry. I mean,
that's just awful. I'm sorry on behalf of my country.
Well, you're not the government, Jesse. So that's true.
I don't have to forgive you. Okay. Well, yeah, it's just not a good, uh, representation, but,
um, yeah, well, America is a great country and the people are great. It's just, um, there's been some
very bad governance since world war two, in my humble opinion. Yeah, no. And on this side of the
pond as well, the British as well. Sure. Yeah. No. And it's crazy that you were,
I mean, Gordon Brown, uh, David Cameron, uh, uh, Theresa May, all of these UK prime ministers
were thinking about you. You were this really important case because the X you, you said that
the extradition law was changed to literally like right after you did what you did.
Yeah. This is one thing I didn't mention. Um, we saw a draft of the new extradition treaty through
our lawyers and it was written a British extradition treaty with America was written in American
English, which is kind of a clue as to who's calling the shots and, um, you know, American
spelling and an English legal document. And also a lot of the phrases were almost verbatim taken from
some of my charges. So I think it's, um, it's not that there's anything special about me, but it was
what I did at that time, the American DOD systems were getting like 250,000 attacks,
hacking attacks at the time. If you read the general accounting office documents at the time
and still to this day. So I think they needed to do something and then needed to increase the punishment
and they needed a poster boy. So timing is everything, isn't it?
Yeah. Because there had been big hackers before you, right? Like what's the name of the guy who
hacked into the DOE department of energy and like atomic lab, Matthew Bevan, Matthew Bevan.
Yeah. And so this was like an actual hack on really sensitive stuff by kind of a more professional
hacker. Is that safe to say, or, or also kind of like a vigilante?
Yeah. No, I think he was more skilled than I was. He didn't just do blank password hack. He found,
you know, weaknesses in protocols. Okay.
So he was more advanced, but, um, and yeah, and he was early, he was in the nineties.
And then what happened to him?
He was basically.
Slap on the wrist.
He did go through some shit. Don't get me wrong, Matthew, if you're listening.
Um, but yeah, he didn't face a long term.
There were a few of these cases before you where I think in a certain case, it was like,
a hundred thousand computers ended up with malware, you know, who was.
Oh yeah. Well, I mean, yeah.
If you want to know who's the most successful hacker, it's not a person. It's a virus.
Yeah.
Like the love, love. What's it? I can't remember the name,
but I'm talking about specifically there's precedent for UK based hackers hacking into
us systems, which neither of us are suggesting anyone do, you know, it's not, you don't hack into,
you know, national security stuff, you know, this is, this is a lesson, but, uh, in, in,
in those cases, they did worse stuff than you.
Yeah.
Uh, and, and they just got slaps on the wrist and then you're this like UFO interested,
you know, you want to know if there's like free energy or whatever, like for your, for your own
edification.
Yeah.
Like not because you want to do some like, you know, terrorist thing or like undermine,
you know, American supremacy in any way or whatever. And like, they just come after you.
Yeah.
And so they changed the.
Which tells you, yeah, what's, what's important to them. Is it someone like cleverly stealing money
in a cyber forward way, which a lot of people have done or is it some, is it UFO truth? Is that?
Yeah. Well, no, it, it, it might show that that actually,
you know, hit a trigger point like the, the, the like cigar shaped tic tac object,
you know, flying in deep space, you know, that might be this really sensitive thing that they
just really don't want to talk about. And then the non true, the space supply chain thing. I could see
that, you know, they don't want to talk about that either, but as a counterpoint to that, that
information was already out. Donna has the shirt was out. So it's kind of, if it's already out, why go
so heavy on this guy as a counterpoint to that, like there's proof that you got into these sites,
Donna here, it's always going to be this kind of like single sample size. And if one story told,
and you can always be like, that person was crazy. Yeah. But like when your case, like they have like
a, you know, there's a live arrest warrant out on you now, right? You can't go to the U S now.
I'm on the Interpol red list. You're on the Interpol red list. That's crazy. I don't even think I knew
that. Hopefully I'm good. But, um, yeah, like, like, you know, with, with, I think in your case,
there's no arguing with the fact that you got into these sensitive sites. So the fact that you're
saying you saw a tic tac, you know, in deep space, but above earth, and then you saw these non-terrestrial,
maybe 40 some odd officers, like, you know, that's, that's like pretty, it's like a little
deeper, you know? Yeah. Yeah. But like, to the point that like, you shouldn't be blamed. It's
like, you didn't sign something. You didn't, you didn't like sign up to like, you weren't like
working at one of these places. You were like high in your, I'm trying to think how I would
manage that if I was Intel. I was like, how have we managed this guy? And then I think they were
probably quite happy when I got diagnosed with Asperger's in 2008, 2009. Okay. He's mentally
ill. It's fine then. Right. Right. Right. Like a put away. I would put him in the mentally ill draw.
Do you ever think like the, the chip is somehow either monitoring you, you, A or B it's like
feeding you ideas or anything? I don't know what you mean. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. You'd start
glitching right now. Yeah. Yeah. Do you ever think it has some sort of, I don't know? Uh,
no, my mind feels the same as it always has. Okay. But I do want to do some further scanning with my
more modern nothing. You should. Yeah. Yeah. So interesting. I wish doctor, what was his name?
The guy that used to scan implants. He's dead now. Roger Lear. Roger Lear. Yeah. I wish he
was around and could come to the UK. Yeah. He'd be the perfect guy. Yeah. I might know of somebody
else who can help you out. So later. Yeah, exactly. Explain what's going on quickly. I can't turn my
phone off here. Look, look, yeah. Let's document all of this. You can see my finger is on the power
button and both. This is like a hard reset, but my fingers on the power button and volume up and volume
down at the same time. And nothing, nothing. That's never happened before. Absolutely. It's
never happened before. It's insane. But you're with Gary McKinnon. And I'm with Gary McKinnon,
who is, has a live arrest. I famously said, I didn't do it. This was the, you know,
everything I'd hoped it would be this conversation is so fun. And, uh, I really hope you pull off this
Byfield Brown effect. I think it would be this beautiful, uh, kind of, I don't know,
vindication, you know, I'm not saying what you did was fine, but I think you were completely
persecuted in this horrible way. And, uh, I love the fact that by the way, the UK rallied behind
you and you ended up, you know, singing with, uh, you know, David Gilmour, you know, the lead singer,
the Pink Floyd, you know, and like you have all these people, you're like kind of this people's
champion. Crosby, Stills and Nash, man. One of my favorite hippie bands from when I was young.
Wait, what, what did, what Crosby, Stills and Nash, they were like rallying behind you as well?
Yeah. They did. Um, they just like mentioned me in one song at one of their gigs, but you know,
thousands of people. I didn't know that. Yeah. So cool.
You've seen all these bands I'd love when I was little. I was like, God, it was,
it was crazy. Cause you're really depressed, but you're seeing all your musical heroes.
Yeah. Vouching for you.
But you're also, didn't you, you sang with David Gilmour.
Yeah. And, uh, Chrissy Hynde and Bob Geldof, but I didn't actually only sang in the same studio at
the same time with Chrissy Hynde. So I didn't get to meet David Gilmour or, uh, Bob Geldof.
Okay.
Unfortunately.
Well, wild. Thank you, Theresa May for making the right decision and, uh, you know, let it,
letting you go. And, uh, I think the U S should drop their arrest warrant and, uh,
I think so too, that I could go on holiday.
Yeah. Uh, yeah. So you can go and, you know, go on a nice vacation and, uh, yeah,
hopefully next time I see you, it's in the States. And, uh, yeah, that'd be fantastic.
It'd be great.
Thanks for a great interview, man.
Absolutely. Gary. No, it was an honor. It was a lot of fun. And, uh, yeah, hopefully,
you know, I think we made a little bit of progress here too,
in terms of piecing some things together.
Yeah, definitely. Yeah. Logistics supply chain.
Exactly.
Oh, sweet. All right.
Alchemist. Did you enjoy that? If you want the full picture, head over to the American
Alchemy magazine we just launched on Substack. That's where we deep dive into all sorts of crazy
topics that we don't have time to fit into every video, with weekly articles exploring all of the
strange, forgotten, and conspiratorial corners of space, history, and high weirdness. So join up
today at our free or paid tiers on Substack. I am including the full link in the description of this video.
We'll be right back.
We'll see you next time.
Thank you.
Thanks.
Bye.