the Allagash Lake we're up there for the experience for the pure pleasure of canoeing
and being out in the wilderness what happens when you get back to camp well we looked on
the other side of the lake and here's this sphere of light and it's moving like a balloon moving
very very slowly what the hell is that over there when I saw the light I noticed it had a weird
quality to it so I looked at it through binoculars and then as soon as I got him in focus the light
went like that whoa like a lens closing in on itself and then it was right behind us and I
was like oh Christ we are not gonna make it back and then I'm struggling to get up and I see this
face bending down to look into my eyes and they began a clinical examination of me so you were
laying horizontally what did the table feel like very sterile an emergency room setting in a way
what did the beings look like a bulbous head with large eyes no nose like us slit area in the chin
are you freaking out freaking out I'm beyond freaking freaked out
do you know if you have rh negative blood I do there you go
and then they came for me I was terrified he kind of like reached up in the air with his long thin
articulated arms and he had this thing in his hand that looked like a flattened pocky puck
and they put one on on the outside of each one of my shins and then I couldn't move my legs oh my god
on his legs for several years hair didn't grow there it was like a bulb patch on it
whoa really and both shins and his identical twin brother Jack had tumors growing in the exact spots
didn't even get a damn t-shirt I mean no souvenirs
Jim Weiner Charlie Fultz thank you both so much for being here I have uh followed your story
for many years and so it's an honor to be in person uh with you both you guys experienced
something absolutely remarkable and kind of mind-blowing in 1976 in Allagash in Maine
yeah on the Allagash water system yeah and it was you two and it was his identical twin brother
identical twin brother Jack and then another guy and another guy another friend and okay so let's set
the scene what is going on in your lives at the time so you're in your mid-20s well um I was a
college student at the time going to college on the GI Bill um and my goal at that time was to become
a school teacher to teach art to children so I was a dual major I was printmaking and photography
so I figured during the three months where I wasn't teaching I could do artwork to supplement my
income well uh that was where I was with my education uh Jack had and Jim had just graduated
from Mass College of Art I think that year the year before Jack did I never I didn't go to I wasn't at
Mass Art at that time at that time I was at the uh program in artisanry which was a
uh crafts program being run by Boston University and Benjamin Franklin Institute and so you guys are
both artists what are you all all of us were artists all four of us all four and what what are you like
personality wise are you guys sort of irreverent and rowdy or are you sort of humble and quiet
yeah we're average mid-20s you know yeah males you know uh we were enjoying the experience of the
wilderness uh we had uh started planning the trip the previous year uh acquiring gear just
slowly accumulating all the gear that we would need plus the meals ready to eat uh type of pack
pre-packaged food that we brought along with us as well and you guys were pretty good outdoorsmen
right you had some skills when it came to kind of surviving outdoors on your own yeah kind of I mean
grew up fishing out in the country you know doing fishing camping that sort of thing where did you live
at the time was it in Maine or in Massachusetts no we were living in Boston yeah I was going to college
I was living in Brookline actually at that time and the twins were my next door neighbors literally
yeah just on on the other side of the driveway was their house so you guys have known each other for
a very long time over 50 years yeah over a half century yeah I mean at that time I was studying
uh ceramics at the program in artisanry I was working with two amazing um potters one's name was
Bill Sachs who was a potter in western Massachusetts out in uh West Hadley the other one was a guy named
uh rich what was rich's Richard Hirsch uh who was uh uh master raku potter and are you guys best
friends oh yeah what him and me yeah I don't know this guy yeah sounds like a one-way situation yeah
evil brother sorry Jim you got the short end of the stick here yeah it's okay
so you guys are you clearly there's a lot of prep work that goes into this trip you guys are kind of
you know figuring out the food situation yeah what equipment we needed what clothing being prepared for
the weather because it was at the end of summer and as you may or may not know about New England
weather Mark Twain said if you don't like the weather wait a few minutes it'll change
and the weather up there at that time was abnormally hot and dry it was one of the
hottest Augusts at the end of the year that they had had so we had gear uh for the next level degree
of coldness was the primary gear that we had uh we as I said had climbed Mount Katahdin uh two days
prior to beginning our canoe trip and uh when we were climbing up the mountain I had to take my blue jeans
had to take a knife and make them into shorts because we were so soaked with sweat uh from climbing the
mountain that our clothing or mine was like grabbing me and restricting my movements hiking and jeans
never a good idea well that's true you can make them shorts though yeah there you go yeah you got
innovative so I think maybe one of the most interesting parts of this whole experience that
is kind of inextricably linked with it you can't kind of separate it is just the landscape of Allagash
itself oh absolutely it's beautiful up there describe it well originally the Allagash water
system which is now a national park system was originally part of the logging industry prior to
logging trucks going out into the forest you sent teams out in the forest they would cut the trees
put them on the lake float them and that was they were moved down the Allagash river all the way to
like Fort Kent and Allagash uh the village of Allagash and then that was where they would get out on the
St. Lawrence is it there or St. Francis St. Francis yeah that separates Canada from the U.S.
and uh they would run the logs down there uh we ran in on our very last day of our canoe trip
we met an old logger uh his name was Harry Smith really interesting character uh told us a lot about
the early logging days and log jams and what you had to do to unjam them and that was incredibly
dangerous because you had to get out there and pry the logs loose until the water could grab them and
get everything moving again so the Allagash system uh still has part of an old railroad that they would
go in to the forest load up with limb lumber or logs and and take them out that way as well
and now uh it is all just a recreational uh environment yeah it looks very primitive
i mean you don't at least when we the places we were at you didn't see cuts you know areas that
were clear cut or anything like that there's no houses all just wilderness i mean gray herons are
flying over all the time you see moose deer yeah uh bears all kinds of stuff you have to um make sure
you keep your foodstuffs off the ground you have to tie them up in a tree somewhere off a branch so
the bears don't get at them the um rangers come every day to collect your trash so that doesn't
lay around the other thing you have to do when um before you even go there is you have to
they only have designated campsites and so you have to tell the rangers what your itinerary what
your itinerary is like so in case you go missing they have an idea of which campsites to start
looking for you looking for you so um and they come and check you minute you land on the lakes when we
flew in we flew in on a bush plane um within minutes um two rangers came and they come and
they check your gear they go through your gear to make sure you're not carrying any kind of contraband
because the allagast runs into canada and they check to make sure that you have enough
food food first aid and camping things to survive up in the wilderness because we were there for what
two weeks yeah 17 days 17 days so you know they're they're pretty strict about who they let stay on
the waterway and pass through the waterway and if you're not out at the end of like the 17 or 18 days
then then they start trying to find you had either of you experienced anything anomalous in your life
had you oh yeah you had yeah yeah described jack and i when we were kids growing we grew up in
the allentown area of pennsylvania we used to have these things happen at night in our house where
we'd be sleeping in bed we both shared the same room and we'd wake up in the night and there'd be
something pulling the covers off our beds whoa um or we'd see fit like figures moving around in the room
they um we saw uh balls of balls of light floating through the house on occasion did you ever
communicate with any oh yeah we did with our parents and they used to say oh you're having
nightmares shut up did you communicate with any of the beings or the no no we went straight to the
bottom of the bed scared scared shitless and you guys thought it was a ghost didn't you
yeah we used to call him harry the ghost he used to call our names sometimes like i'd be
in in the room doing something and i'd hear this jim a real deep voice jim jim and i thought it was i
always thought it was my father was there any history either to the house you were in or to your
family no my father built the house himself anything around your family experiencing paranormal
stuff prior to no this but my parents um saw a bean in their bedroom one night okay hooded bean
in their bedroom a hooded bean which we never i never knew until ray fowler interviewed her whoa
and then she reported it to ray and so she wasn't open about it with you she was open about it to
ray fowler open about it to ray we'll get she but he's a never mentioned it to us wild so um you know
we used to have like to be like knocking on the walls at night when we try to sleep and if you go
into our basement um we had a my father had a little pool table in the basement so family members he had
a large family brothers and sisters they would come to the house every other weekend or so back in those
days families like that's just what they did super random question but do you know if you have rh negative
blood i do there you go yeah my dad and you did too and your dad no no my dad your dad did but you
did you do jack and i have rh negative that's fascinating because that's a commonality among
experiencers this missing protein that seems to for whatever reason well when we were when we were like
six years old um we both broke our arms like within a day of one another like when you have
identical twins if something happens to one twin you you know wait a few hours it'll happen to the
other one it's like some entanglement yeah it's like definitely entanglement there anyway we had both
broken our wrists and uh opposite arms opposite arms same fracture location in those days literally
entanglement yeah in those days doctors came to your home yeah we had a family doctor that you know
would come to your home if you called them and so i was in just unbelievable pain i was in unbearable
pain so they called the doctor and the doctor came to the house and he said well i'm just going to knock
them out because if you can't handle the pain i mean i was flipping out so he gave me a shot of
something to knock me out and a minute later jack goes out cold i don't know exactly what ag1 is doing
in my body but i do know that my microtubules are online i'm not saying i can feel the force but my
chakras have definitely auto aligned in fact i used to think i had seven chakras just like everybody else
and then i drink ag1 now i have 50 just kidding but i did used to wake up feeling stiff and groggy
like my brain's on airplane mode and then i started one habit one scoop in eight ounces of water it's a
multivitamin a prebiotic a probiotic and with its adaptogens it's the only green powder i'd ever bring
to a skiff shout out chris ramsey i take this in the morning and it's the easiest upgrade i've ever made
my favorite flavor is berry but honestly they're all good ag1 has over 50 000 verified five-star
reviews and comes with a 90-day money-back guarantee go to drink ag1.com slash alchemy to get their best
offer and get three free ag1 travel packs plus free vitamin d3 plus k2 and ag1's welcome kit with your
first ag1 subscription order that's drink ag1.com slash alchemy again that's drink ag1.com slash alchemy
we're linking that in the description thank you so much to ag1 for sponsoring today's episode
jack goes out cold whoa i'm sitting there and the doctor they actually wrote it up he wrote up a report
and they wrote it up in one of the local newspapers and shortly after that these two guys showed up at
our house and they wanted to talk to my father and mother and they claimed that they were from some
institute institute somewhere that was studying twins and they wanted to take jack and i away to study us
what institute i don't know which is it called the the round table institute i don't i don't remember the
name of it do you remember where it may have been um duke duke the ryan institute it may have been
the ryan but i'm not don't quote me but anyway what year what year was this was oh so they're seven
late late 50s yeah well the ryan institute yeah anyway my father it could have been freaked out yeah
and literally threw them both out of the house and said if you ever come here again or if i ever see
you around my kids again i will what's fascinating because that time in history was when children
started to be tested in programs that were kind of adjacent to mk ultra but also yeah you know they
were interested in ufo stuff too there was a guy named andre puharic i don't know if you're familiar
with him but he was an early kind of architect of mk ultra he was a northwestern uh scientist and and
uh i think he was a medical student there uh but just got very interested in consciousness and he
had a place in austin in upstate new york and he recruited what he called the space kids and it was
like a camp for high psi you know high psychic ability children and they would often you know
channel these beings they would call the nine these sort of you know alien entities the first set of
what really were the space kids were younger some of them were seven years old up to 12 or in in in
teens interesting so i wonder if you were you know maybe they were tracking us it was that did that
eventually evolve into montauk so montauk i believe was yeah i think it would have been around the same
time i think it would have been yeah 50s 60s i believe that there was like this machinery they found
at montauk and blanking on the name of the author of the book but preston something could be i had i
had the book at one time and i've given it away already yeah but no but that's sort of so then i mean
that uh hold the montauk experiments which we now think are probably real inspired uh you know stranger
things and stranger things is you know hit netflix show which is around the doe and national labs basically
recruiting children and doing psychic tests with them and 11 this character in stranger things which
is like the biggest show in the world right now right is based on this so i do think yeah yeah yeah
it's fascinating yeah so maybe they were trying to recruit they may have had something to do with it
but my father didn't like these two people at all yeah i don't blame him yeah so that happened when we
were kids and then in 1973 in the spring of 1973 i was attending mansfield state college in upstate
pennsylvania it's almost on the border of pennsylvania and new york state teachers college and i was
i was an undergraduate there and um they were involved in this project with beavers
because um they were having problems with every time a big storm would come through they'd have a
lot of flooding there was a river up there i forget the name of it but it would flood and ruin everything
and so they decided what they were going to do was parachute beavers into the countryside all around
it it's it's really up in an area of pennsylvania that's really wild in fact they they filmed um
the deer deer hunter movie is that the name of it yeah deer hunter yeah that's where they filmed it
it's like you can you can walk for 75 miles in any direction up there and you don't see a single
house it's really you know primitive interesting anyway um so i was i was um gotten they got me and
two other friends of mine up there involved with this where they dropped they'd parachute in these
beavers they parachuted in beavers yeah they parachuted in beavers to build beaver dams to
control the water table wow which i thought was a great idea because how else do you get into the
water table when it's there's nothing there except trees and forest and so what we had to do myself and
my two friends was and they had other students doing this was we had to go out into like all
these old logging roads and whatever and and find beavers and you know marco you know put them in a
database so i was out one day with these two friends of mine and we're driving around a little vw bug
we're driving around looking for beavers we never i don't think we even found any
but we were coming back and it had just become nighttime and we were driving through uh a cow some
pasture it was this huge pasture with uh two ruts for try tractor ruts in it and we were driving and
it was dark so that it was but up there in that part of pennsylvania it's um uh what they call the
night sky places where like you can go out and look clear skies clear skies or you know it's like
we're virgin black virgin black there's no light pollution and uh so we were driving across we were
lost and we were driving across this pasture this huge pasture and on the end of the pasture
there was a tree line and so we were going towards this tree line and then i noticed i looked up above
the trees and i noticed there was this group of stars that looked like the little dipper except they
were moving and they were moving in a really strange way it was like instead of like just going
in a constant plane pace or plane they were tumbling like a slinky they would this whole they were
maintaining the the dipper shape there was probably six or eight of these lights they look like you know
bright bright stars but they were tumbling end over end and it was coming like right down towards where
we were and then um we were like i was like what the heck is that so i stopped the car i said we got
to get out and look at this thing so the three of us got out of the car and we're watching this thing
and it's just walking out of the sky like right for us and then all of a sudden out of nowhere this
car comes opposite us on this tractor rut so we're like oh jesus so the car gets around us
and then when when the at one point it was like on a hill and when the car lights went up it it hit
these lights up in the sky and then they stopped coming down towards us and they started going parallel
to us and while they were they kept maintaining this tumbling thing except they then they were
changing shape like they were it was like they would go in at one point they were like a v shape
and then another point it was more like an amoeba type shape but it just kept tumbling end over end
the whole time so i said let's signal it because it was only you know a thousand maybe two thousand wasn't
that far up in the sky and so i had a flashlight in my glove compartment and i took the flashlight out
and i blinked the flashlight and all of a sudden one of these starlight lights like went off like a
a big amber flash bulb in this like it turned into like a tube of light almost like a blob of toothpaste
kind of light came out of it and then it it did a couple more tumbles and then it just
this is the first time i've ever seen anything like this it was going like this tumbling and
then all of a sudden it was it just reversed it didn't stop and wait you know one blink of an eye
it just stopped and then reverse it just reversed itself and then it walked back up into the sky and
disappeared that was in 1973 fascinating yeah wow so that was a year before or that was
three years before this allagash event so you had had like this whole kind of backdrop of anomalous
experiences multiple yeah except i we never we never subscribed them to ufos ufos i mean we grew up
in you know i was a grew up in farm country in pennsylvania just like ghosts or yeah ghosts or you
know lights in the sky lights in the sky you know it could have been you know helicopters yeah we knew
you know i mean i didn't know what it was and so we nobody talked about ufos and those you know i grew
up in a family that was um conservative very conservative so like we didn't talk about
ghosts unless something weird happened and then my family oh yeah that's that's harry don't worry
about it's only harry the ghost yeah so he would casually you dismiss it but he would casually
yet a name for this ghost yeah because that's how much it would appear we called him harry
interesting yeah okay so you guys let's cut back to 76 you guys are at allagash you this you know sort
of beautiful landscape sounds like they have a rigorous protocol for kind of onboarding you
you know oh yeah camping out there you get there uh at what point do you start canoeing
well right after we climbed katahdin which was the first uh three days we were in northern maine
went down to millinocket uh and got some supplies uh then climbed katahdin broke camp the next morning
took the supplies we had purchased in millinocket and we drove north and east of baxter state park
to a outfitter at shin pond and at shin pond uh a friend of ours in fact the guy that came down this
last saturday uh we were using one of his canoes uh a friend of ours named charlie had lent us
uh a groman uh aluminum canoe for our trip and had taken it to shin pond and this guy had
had it strapped to the pontoon of the airplane so he would take two passengers and the gear for those
two guys and the canoe that's all you could put in that little plane besides him i had a volkswagen
beetle had a far more complex instrument panel than this airplane had it was i mean it was as simple
as simple could be you got a choke you got an oil pressure gauge and you got a gas gauge and that
was it yeah two canoes the one that our friend loaned us and then we brought another rented one yeah
describe your first anomalous sighting on the canoe well the first sighting we saw of it was
on our second day on the lake system we were on chamberlain lake and that was a lake that runs north
south and we were going north and we were trying to get up to the allagash river uh or the allagash
stream which flows in from allagash lake and that is totally primitive up there uh area uh the only way
you can get up there is by pulling up the river and we didn't know how to pull uh but we attempted
paddling and paddling but didn't do us any good yeah however to get back to the first sighting
uh we had passed two teenagers on our way north and they were fooling around on a little island
and we got up to this site called uh mud pond and uh we didn't want to camp with other people there
were people across from us in a sheltered area from the wind and we had decided to take this one
spot but when we got up there the wind was like just coming down on us like crazy and we're like we
don't want to be dealing with this all night long trying to put our lean to shelter together because
all we had was a a big uh uh tarp that we used as a tent you know because you can use tarps for
multiple purposes and we were using it for shelter and as well as keeping our gear weatherproof
well at any rate uh the weather forced us across the lake and where this other group of campers were
and they had asked had we seen these two kids we'd seen earlier and we told them where we had seen them
and so they were getting worried because you know there's two teenagers a member of their group and
well and it got dark by this time so out there it's so black at night you you can't really see
your hand this far in front of your face so we were out with them as well looking with our binoculars
across the surface of the water seeing if we could i'd find them and they ended up taking the campsite
that we had abandoned uh and a member of this other group said what the hell is that over there
and we looked on the other side of the lake and here's this sphere of light and it's moving like
a balloon moving very very slowly but it's like moving into this wind so i'm trying to figure out
the treetops yeah i was trying to figure out what the hell is that uh but then we spotted these kids
and so okay and we looked back this light and it wasn't there so i looked at it through binoculars
because it had when i saw the light i noticed it had a weird quality to it how so it just didn't look
right to me it didn't it wasn't like a pure white it was more like a yellowish white and it it there's
just something about it that didn't seem right to me so i looked at it through binoculars and and then
as soon as i got them in focus the light went like that like a like a lens closing in on itself and then
it just vanished and i thought well that's that's kind of weird but i didn't think anything more
about it because we were we had to set up camp so you know it was just this weird light but i had
never seen a light do that before like just implode in on itself wait 48 hours
you'll see it again and what was odd which we we didn't know at the time but it was
like the the direction that it was in line to us was over eagle lake the area that we were camping
at two days later so it was almost like it was where you were going it was like patrolling that
area or something it was patrolling the area that's interesting that reminds me of when you hear
commander david fravor from his 2004 nimitz incident and he says you know we were you know dispatched
to go check out this tic-tac object and then the tic-tac was already at the rendezvous point that he
was going to next it was like they sort of know your intent or some trajectory or it had been there
for a while because there was a there was a witness uh logger who had witnessed the this same craft up in
that same area that they were logging fascinating okay so you guys kind of you know note that this
is anomalous but you don't you try to kind of you know keep moving forward yeah well i mean we're not
there to see a a light disappear in the night sky i mean we're up there for the environment for the
experience for the just pure pleasure of canoeing and being out in the wilderness what happens when you
get back to camp well well that night the first night we saw it nothing i mean we just turned in
got up the next morning and continued our canoe trip that was when we tried to get up to alagash lake
do you guys even talk about the first sighting no not really at all no okay no i mean it was uh
was like uh i got bit by a mosquito type of thing yeah so you probably said something when you were
looking through your binoculars right yeah i said well this is this is a strange light yeah and when
it kind of winked out i thought well that's kind of weird but i mean maybe maybe it was a helicopter
maybe it was a balloon or something and that's just the way it went right okay so then the next day
after that we had canoed up tried to get to alagash lake but found it impossible we'd spent like eight
hours trying to go upstream until we got to a point where we said well we're not even at halfway mark
we turned around and it took us uh about 15 minutes to go back down to where we started so
we set up camp uh right there on the river that night in this camp location the following morning
is when we canoed down to the eagle lake portage area so it was a three-quarter of a mile portage
that we had to carry our canoes and all of our gear so how we rigged it is that we lashed two poles
uh ran perpendicular to the canoe and uh then the four of us would just pick up the ends
uh and with the canoe in between us and then walked the canoe over to the other lake went back and
retrieved a second canoe and then got out on the water and we were going to camp at pillsbury island
that was our goal it's kind of in the middle of eagle lake towards the southern end of it but there was
a canoe about i don't know a quarter of a mile in front of us and that is where he be be lined
straight too so we're like well we don't want to camp with other people anymore so we went to our
secondary which was smith brook campsite we set up our camp for the night and then we decided hey
let's try and catch some fresh fish so we can supplement have a fish meal or something
so we built a fire because it was getting dark so we built a fire that we knew would burn for
close to three hours and went out on the lake and we had to navigate through standing trees logs in
the water and it took us maybe about 25 30 minutes to work our way through all this obstruction
to get to the site that we were fishing at which was maybe about 500 yards from our campsite yeah we
were all in one canoe charlie was at one end of the canoe the other guy was at the other end jack and
i were in the middle and all we had was paddles and fishing poles and that was it you know and a
flashlight flashlight so i'm setting up in the front of the canoe and you know we're having no luck at
all fishing when the other guy goes what the f is that as you know we have a new starship of course we
have a health care center on board ask what my new favorite product in it is iris stores alumina
face mask some billionaires are rejuvenating in underground light pods i'm doing my own version
in my living room this mask is like a med bed for your face it's lightweight super convenient cordless
and runs red blue and infrared light therapy all at once the same type of technology nasa studied for
skin healing in space it's safe for your eyes too so you don't have to sit there like a statue
you can live your life i wear it when i'm reading meal prepping or investigating life's mysteries
without feeling like i'm staring into the sun 10 minutes of light and my skin looks and feels so
good finding red light therapy was a revelation for me i've definitely had a few late nights reading
about magnetic pole shifts but with this mask i look like i actually slept did i that's debatable
it's warm wireless convenient and makes your skin feel super soft and iris stores kicking off their
spring savings with some very big discounts right now you can get the elite plus alumina face mask
bundle at an exclusive deal when you use code jesse at iris store.com that's jesse j-e-s-s-e at iris store.com
please support our show and tell them we sent you what the f is that so we all sort of like turn and look
toward the back of the canoe and i see this aspirin tablet sized white circle and i'm thinking that is
the freaking moon you moron but then i noticed that it was moving and it was moving faster than moon
moves it's moving at about like this speed right here and it's hundreds of hundreds of yards away
from us and so we just sat there bewildered looking at this thing and then it kind of like makes a left
turn and then it starts coming straight toward us totally silent yeah and so we're watching it and
watching it and then we notice as it gets closer the tops of the trees are illuminated and this thing's only
about 15 feet above the tops of the trees just coming straight toward us and when it was about
less than 100 yards away from us directly across i thought i wonder what the hell it'll do if i flash an sos at it
so i had one of those square battery flashlights with the handle and the push button i put my hand over
the lens turned the light on and then i three short three long three short and then this thing stopped
i mean it just no sound whatsoever just stopped moving and all of a sudden this big cone of light
blue light blue light like a neon blue but it looked like a a giant glass straw you know it looked like
it was open a void in the center of it or something and this light starts from the bottom of the sphere
coming out across the lake toward the canoe and that was when i realized the sphere was coming with it
at the same time this thing was big it was as big as a two-story house oh yeah i mean it was like
huge wow and how far away is it like a under 100 yards from you when i flashed the flashlight but when
i dropped the flashlight it was about 75 yards from us in closing wow and so do you think it reacted to
this uh sos flashlight yeah immediately yeah and it came closer yeah and all i could hear behind me
were jack and jim screaming paddle charlie paddle uh-huh and as i said if i could have uh ran across
the water like a jesus christ lizard i would have been doing that what um emotions are going through
you guys at this point well i was self-survival self-survival it was like weird i do not want to deal with
this out here yeah i don't know what this is but i i know as much as i really want to know at the
moment because it was you know it was big it was huge yeah and you're like uh oh that's not a
helicopter because it was absolutely silent yeah it wasn't disturbing the trees or the water i mean
you can hear a loon a quarter of a mile away yeah and this thing didn't make any noise at all and it
had this weird kind of life to it like it was roiling this and the surface of the surface of
this thing was like roiling it was alive it was like it was a some sort of plasma yeah exactly yeah
yeah something going on inside yep well you know what it um one of the things that impressed me the
most uh that i recall about it was you've seen halos around the moon right sure this thing had a
halo around it as well as it approached us you could see the definition of this halo
and the the sphere itself was kind of was you know in constant motion
yeah and i remembered i'm i remembered um you know you're like paddle well the other guy with us he
was he was just like catatonic he just sat in with the paddle across his legs and just stared out
and we're like paddle paddle paddle and he's like sort of help us a little here so charlie what's
his name by the way this other guy who's catatonic chuck yeah and um it's the reason i go by charlie
so there's no confusion and uh so we're like chuck paddle and he just did sat there staring out into
nothing and so it seemed like only a few moments from the time we started paddling to the time that
jack and jim and i were standing on the beach we weren't in the canoe we're standing in front of
the canoe on the sand of the beach yeah and uh this sphere had followed us all the way across the lake
didn't chuck also prior to this feel like you guys were being watched he had so that's what he said
yeah yeah i mean i the last thing i remembered before we were suddenly at the shore at the camp was
looking back to see where this thing was and i thought well it's still like you know 70 yards
away except it was like instead of being back here it was like right there it was right behind us and i
was like oh christ we are not gonna make it back and then that's the last thing i remembered until we
stopped at the our canoe campsite i think went up on the shore of the campsite and so there's a little
blackout period little sort of missing time well yeah but i mean your memory at least where well i
mean but the thing about it is is in the total context we weren't aware of anything like this
at the time at the time but but now recalling it you remember this bright plasma like object 75 yards
away oh no no we remembered the whole plasma incident like it just happened last night and then and then
you remember that and then it just sort of flashes directly to like you're going up onto shore right
to the campsite there's nothing in between that in your memory no no as a matter of fact i the i had a
very vivid memory of my eyes focused on that campfire and that was all that i was that was my goal my
objective was to reach that site because that was the only indicator of where a campsite was
uh without that campfire you know the shoreline is identical at night it's dark when you're going
on to shore and the campfire is in sight do you guys feel differently physically than well this was
before you blacked out a little bit well this was the kicker when we got to shore the three of us
were standing on this in the sand i reached down in the canoe and i picked up the flashlight again and
i gave it another sos but this time all it did was it just went away from us to the opposite side of
the lake once it got to the exact opposite side of the lake it ascended up and away at a 45 degree angle
yeah i remembered when we got onto the shore turning around to see where it was and i remember it
hovering right over the water and this cone of light was coming down onto straight down under it
on the water really like it was there was a beam like it was sitting on a beam of light and it was
close i remember thinking if i had a stone i could hit this with a rock and it was only about 40 feet
above the surface of the water and the surface of the water was like a mirror it was like glass
at night and then it did that same winking out i remembered looking that was when it went up in
the sky and then it just went and then it and and when you could see it sort of close up could you make
out how big it was and the and the shape it was circular it was still spherical it was still and
it was still like maybe two and a half story house give a sense of the diameter yeah triple
yeah easy and was it always uh kind of white light or that's how i remember it kind of a whitish yellow
what the the the best example i could give you to envision what we saw would be go into a dark room
with a 25 watt light bulb look at the light or turn the light bulb on look at it turn it off and then
close your eyes the after image that you have would be about as close to what we saw as i can think of
for example fascinating so you guys are going on the shore and you flash the sos again and the thing
kind of you know just zooms up goes across the lake and begins to ascend up and away from us yeah when
it went it it flew weird i remember it reminded me of like when you have a frisbee and you're tossing a
frisbee back and forth and sometimes the frisbee will go at a certain and then skips up and then keeps
going and then it skips up again that's how this thing it was like it was going up a stairway
what happens when you get back to camp well this is while we're in camp watching this thing going up
okay for some reason i felt that this thing was about to take off at a high rate of speed
so i took the flashlight which i was still holding in my hand once i had signaled it the second time
and i looked at the sweep hand on my watch noting to where the sweep hand was or the second hand
then i looked back up at this thing and then it shot off into the night sky
so i didn't observe it skipping i just meant that probably happened when i was looking at my wristwatch
but when that thing took off within eight seconds of the time i spotted the sweep hand
till the time the thing was a pinpoint a light in a night sky eight seconds had elapsed
and uh i turned and i looked at the campfire the campfire had flames about one inch high
the campfire had completely burned out but i didn't say oh my god what happened to the fire
i mean because fires burn out you expect that but i was puzzled by the fact that the fire was
exhausted so i asked everybody should i throw some wood on the fire and build it up and they're like
fuck the fire man i'm exhausted i'm going and i all of a sudden just felt exhausted so it was like
that adrenaline that puts you into the afterburner rocket across the lake to get back to your shoreline
safety that adrenaline is now dissipated and exhaustion hits you that's the way it felt like
but you somehow intuited that this thing was going to shoot off that you felt like i did
sort of i did but i didn't i didn't know why at that time it took uh uh us going through hypnotic
regression to learn the answer to that and the fire the fire is significant too right yeah yeah
extremely so so so explain that well the fact that we had only been out on the water
less than 30 minutes when we encountered this thing so it should have taken us about 20 minutes
to get back to shore but it seemed like only took a few moments for us to get back to shore
and when we got back to shore the fire was extinguished so that was a three-hour period of time
that is that missing time that everybody talks about and the the fire initially was set you know
it was an intense fire it was yeah yeah yeah yeah it was it acted like a lighthouse uh-huh because i
mean you have to have a point of reference to get back to if you're going to be out on the water at
night because as as he had said before you know you can feel the heat from your hand but you can't see
your hand so it was this was a bonfire explicitly for visibility at far distances correct yeah it's
going to be big yeah yeah and so it's not so big that it would start a forest well i mean if it would
have been windy that would have been a different thing but it wasn't windy at all that concern about
it i mean it's called a long burning fire or sometimes an upside down fire you build it
to last to burn a long time rather than quickly and the fact that this was basically out by the time
that you guys got there or you know all but out uh shows you that maybe there was some some missing
time involved well we didn't think about it that was so weird because fires burn out this is a this
is a pattern that you notice in retrospect after piecing everything together yeah in fact we hadn't even
you know made that connection it was ray fowler that made the connection he said this is missing time
where you knew you were paddling toward a fire a fire that you were looking at but yet when you got
there the fire was out that's also a common trope with alien abductions you have you know travis walton
coming back with a fully grown beard yeah uh you know and actually it was the one year before you
guys right it was 75 75 uh nine months nine months before us yeah and i had never heard of travis
at that time about travis oh yeah and we didn't know about anybody back we didn't know about any
of this shit back then we were novices it was all new yeah which is one of the reasons we were so
intent as i said to james to share this knowledge with the world i mean you know this hey something
comes down into my neighborhood and kicks my butt and i can't do nothing about it i want people to know
yeah did you did you guys report it to oh yeah when the ranger came to collect our trash we said
hey you know did anybody see anything weird uh-huh uh last night and he's like what what do you mean
they have that main accent you know and we were so we told him what we saw and he was like he kind
of give us this weird look yeah he said well i don't know what two guys were smoking last night
no you didn't say you i'd stop you know and we were like no this this is something that we really
saw this thing was like how could you how could somebody else not see and in fact we asked other
people when we passed other people on the lake system we said hey did you see anything weird
you know last night or a couple nights ago they'd say no we were all in bed by you know
dark and you guys had six more days right on the hiking on the no no we had like about two more
weeks oh you guys had two more weeks on this trip yeah so so how much does this change the dynamic
between you guys are you guys talking about this a lot well that night we didn't talk about one word
we just more or less all drifted off forget about the fire everybody said so we all drifted off
climbed in our sleeping bags and you know closed our eyes and then the next morning as we're breaking
camp and eating the only thing we could talk about was this thing what the hell was it it happened to
me in the woods i was hiking solo new year no phone no gear i was just trying to find myself that's when
i saw it something glowing silent descending through the trees a ufo and stepping out from it
wasn't an alien or an android it was me but better same face same great hair but something was
different this guy had perfect posture he was wearing the perfect jean and they start at just
79 dollars six fits sizes for every thigh on this timeline and beyond now 2026 me wears the perfect
jeans they don't crush my thighs or my dreams they're soft but dangerous for a limited time
our listeners get 15 off their first order plus free shipping at the perfect jean dot nyc or just google
the perfect jean and use code jesse 15 for 15 off that's 15 off for new customers at the perfect jean dot
nyc with promo code jesse 15 after you purchase they'll ask you where you heard about them please
support our show and tell them we sent you your khakis and get the perfect jean what the hell was it and we
immediately said well i had to be a ufo because i said it's nothing military because i i'm familiar with
what we have militarily i've been in enough hueys to don't wasn't no damn helicopter well it didn't
make any noise it was totally silent and as it flew off it had to be going faster than the speed
of sound it just had to be because that's how quickly it speed of sound accelerated yeah no no
sonic boom mock one but no boom no boom totally almost feels like it's gliding through space time or
something yeah i don't know how you know breaking newton's third law how it does that but there was
no sonic boom and that thing took off like charlie said all you saw was a streak behind it how how
much are you guys talking about it for the next couple of weeks so you talk about the next day oh we
talked about it for like the freaking next year everybody that we knew yeah literally everybody
that we knew and a lot of people that we didn't know we shared this experience of the seeing this
thing and being chased by it by week two are you guys starting to speculate about ufos non-human
intelligence aliens no i mean we we just said it was a ufo because it doesn't it didn't move like
anything i'd ever seen or any of us were ever familiar with like shooting off into the night sky the
way it did and we didn't have any sense of contact with any beans or anything like that it was just
this weird craft that we saw sauce and chased us across the lake scared the crap out of us and
and then we were off and gone but to yeah to get back to me shining the flashlight to put that in a
little bit of context remember i said i used to work on nuclear submarines yeah and i worked with
reactor system submarines uh operate with a bubble of air inside the between the outer hull and the inner
hull they have a bladder like fish have a bladder and you fill it full air to maintain a certain depth
well apparently when i was uh on board this craft inquired about their uh power system you know because
i was curious about it and it was relayed to me that it works like the submarine working with a bubble of air
they can match gravity fields so if you set it for you know like minus x that might be like 80 000 feet
up in the sky and set it for minus one and you're 12 inches above the water and they can move between
the in fact uh uh the uh encounters that the aircraft carriers had in california in uh
2004 they had a craft at 80 i think it was 81 000 feet it was like over 15 miles straight up in the air
and they sent planes up to that area and when they could just start seeing it on their instruments
it dropped down to 24 inches above the water surface in under one second
hmm i think it was it was right above the water and it moved to 30 000 feet and seven-eighths of a
second and then yes it then it zoomed up to over 80 000 so yeah but i mean that's another thing that
kind of disturbs when you're reading information you get a lot of conflicting information and well i think
i think you're actually right because well some of them are radar i think the radar thing was more
similar to what you said and then the the you know i think maybe visually yeah but but it's like
i've heard podcasts on the allagash many many times yeah and they're mixing this person up with that
person and yeah well even ray did that in his book he kept getting jack and i mixed up so so you get
back you see your families what do you what do you say to them and how do they react well i mean half of
my family believed me and the other half thought i was squirrel bait you know what squirrel bait is
don't you no what's squirrel bait nuts that's funny there you go so but over
the last 50 years and especially most especially over the last uh 15 years uh there's so much more
more information coming forward uh so many more reliable credible people were coming forward uh like the
prime minister from canada for paul hellyer came forward describing uh his ufos the information he had
the uh supreme uh supreme air force commander of the belgian uh military and you know decades ago way
before uh we were even aware of ray fowler um came forward said these things uh were real cooper well gordon
cooper uh who was one of the mercury 7 astronauts uh jim and i gave a presentation in uh portsmouth
maine in 1995 was it it's either five or six and 96 i think it was yeah and gordon cooper was one of
the speakers as well we had we spent basically the weekend with gordon cooper he shared with us that
in 1957 that uh he was on the base and they had a craft land physically land on the base
so he was in a jeep with three photographers a cinematographer who had a 16 millimeter movie
camera and he was shooting film 35 millimeter photographer was shooting film and a four by five
press camera photographer and he said when they drove straight out there was this uh sort of like
kind of like a tic-tac shape thing that was on the ground on tripod and when they approached
the legs like retracted back into it and then it just went straight up in the air when they were within
about three or four hundred yards it just went vertically straight up and i said well what did
the films look like gordon said never saw them as soon as we got back they were all confiscated
and this saucer flew right over them and put down three little gear and landed out on the dry lake bed
and they went out to um picked up their cameras and moved on out toward him filming
and he left it off put the gear back in the well and climbed out at a very high rate of speed and
disappeared that is so nuts yeah well he i think spent more time in space than anybody prior to him
in the mercury oh yeah yeah he was one of the mercury seven yeah fascinating did he say anything else to
you well about seeing uh when they were orbiting he saw uh well not they each astronaut orbited by
themselves and you know because they only had seven astronauts they only had seven capsules so
cooper said that he had witnessed and i guess he was on the radio back with
the ground control and then they like they often do switch to another radio frequency to get off of the
public radio frequencies um who the hell did we meet some guy from australia that um had
been recording and when they switched to a different channel he was able to switch and because he knew
where that channel was and he switched over to that channel and he uh recorded uh some uh of the die of the
interchange going back and forth it's it's amazing how much information is out there and has been out there
but it was just in tighter circles the circles are expanding now yeah i think that's right and but
gordon cooper is saying that he literally experienced the ufo while he was orbiting earth
yeah as an astronaut yeah in the mercury missions right that's amazing and he had seen that one in
before the mercury program because the mercury program didn't start until i think like 59 58 yeah 58 59
and uh so by 1969 when we landed on the moon i was stationed over in europe uh i remember that
night incredibly well because all the bars you know it was nighttime for us over there all the bars were
open and they all had these tiny little black and white tvs that were all snowy and were watching
uh the astronauts on the moon so we all grab our beers or whatever we were drinking and we went out
in the streets thousands of us americans were all toasting the guys on the moon with our beers
now the moon belongs to us because we got our flag there that's funny so so but did he just describe this
ufo that he saw at all while he was orbiting earth with the other astronauts or uh just that
it had come uh in proximity with him and i think he said it was green if i'm not mistaken but i don't
know i might be confusing that with other at other astronauts that had had uh encounters so you guys
still have some missing puzzle pieces with your own experience for a decade plus right for 12 or so
years yeah we never really started um looking at it until the late 80s so what what exactly
kind of spur catalyst what was the catalyst to jim and jack both at the same time in two different
states jim lived in massachusetts jack in vermont with his wife they both started experiencing these
identical nightmares and well similar similar yeah i don't know if they were identical but well
for lack of a better word they were identical in as much as they had the same four people the two
twins me and the other guy yeah and so back to the entanglement thing you guys are experiencing the
same yeah things at the same time he would but even then we didn't know what was going on i remember
he used to say man i had like a really strange dream last night where there were like these
things he's like humanoid things and and i was like yeah jack come on it's a nightmare you know i
have them too yeah i have the same kind of dreams it's just a nightmare don't worry about it and it was
you charlie jack and chuck in the dream just like yeah it was you for at allagash exactly yeah that well
that was the only time that we had ever done anything together like that i mean so the dream
is just you guys are sitting there and you what what happens like being in a doctor's office
um strange things are being done to you with no explanation so you're are you guys on a craft
well we we somewhere with after the hypnotic regression we discovered that yeah we it seems
we were on this craft apparently so you're having dreams that are sort of adjacent to or flashbacks you
know um point to something else having occurred and then that catalyzes this desire to get a
hypnotic regression well jim had had a an injury uh and he developed epilepsy temporal libic
epilepsy and he was having a lot of seizure activity so he was at the beth israel hospital
uh being followed for that and they were going to do a sleep deprivation study on him and he had
all these wires glued to his head and they said while you're waiting around you want to read a book or
anything and he said yeah yeah so they brought in a tray of books and
and one of them was uh whitney streber's communion
and when i saw the face on the cover i flipped out
yeah i was like why why are you giving me this book to read i don't want to read this
and i like i for some reason i didn't really know why it was just like this face just
negative reactions had this extreme negative reaction and i didn't want to have anything
to do with it and i made a big scene and then a few minutes later one of the neurologists came in
and said uh jim what just came down here and i was like i don't want to talk about this
and he was like well um it's kind of weird don't you think and i was like i don't care what you call
it you know it's like i don't know i just don't like this i don't want to look at this book anymore
it was like a visceral allergic reaction more like a visceral reaction to it and um i got really upset
and then you know this is oh by the way common for people experiencers to see the cover specifically
of communion whitley streber's book and a lot of stuff cut bubbles back up comes up comes back up and
sometimes it's this and then other times it's like uh whoa that looks familiar yeah yeah and
and so he he left and and after the test was done the eeg um he came in he said you know
i'm gonna ask you a kind of personal question and i said fine what do you want to ask he said have
you ever seen a ufo and i remembered like looking at him like what the heck is going on here and i
said well yeah as a matter of fact i have yeah and he said oh you want to talk about it and i said
um not really you know i really want to kind of concentrate on the seizures you know i'm having
these problems with seizures i think that's a little bit more important than talking about ufos and
he said well you know i know this guy one of my professional people i know who turned out to be
john mack no way yeah yeah who's this neurologist he's uh what was his name jonathan silverman i think
it was and was he affiliated with he was affiliated with yeah and harvard medical school yeah yeah so um
did you sense anything nefarious about him or you felt like he was an honest actor no i think he was
an honest actor and um and so uh i said uh well yeah you know i i have had a ufo experience and
and i was telling him about these nightmares that i was having thinking they were seizure
activity and he said you know jim i think you really need to talk to somebody
like john mack or somebody who
deals with people who have seen ufos i could tell he was trying to be gentle about walking around this
topic so i wouldn't flip out again because i was i was not happy and so i said uh you know i really
i really want to just concentrate on the seizures you know let's concentrate on the seizures so i tried
to avoid it for a while and then a few days later he came into my room and said look you know this guy
named ray fowler raymond fowler is gonna he's a ufo investigator he's gonna be at this um conference
uh which was pretty close to where carol and i live now it was a library marriott hotel there was a
marriott hotel near us and he said he's gonna be doing he's gonna be speaking at this uh or he's gonna
have a book stand or something like that at this thing and i i want you to go and talk to him and
i was like i don't want to talk to him and he said look you really i really want you to do this
so he talked me into doing it and that's how i met ray fowler and i remembered when i met him he was
selling some his books and he said oh you're the yeah your doctor talk called me and and so i'm
expecting you and i said you know and he goes uh well why don't you just start at the beginning and
tell me about this ufo that you saw so i told him about it and at first i thought he was bored
and i was like oh yeah i've heard this a million times yeah you know and then i said i'm my charlie
and myself and my identical twin and then he went what did you just say and i said charlie and i and
this other guy and my identical twin he said oh you have an identical twin and i said yes and then
he said okay i want you to start all over again and then i could tell he was giving me his attention
so why was why was that somehow i don't know this role and you got a base population and a control
population if you're going to do any type of medical experimentation so that's interesting
two identical twins yeah that boat that's interesting i also think from an investigatory
perspective if he's speaking to you first he can get your whole testimony then he can isolate your
brother yeah and then get the same testimony and kind of you know compare and contrast and so it's
probably from his vantage point you know uh the potential for high confidence is really there yeah
which is exciting and and that's exactly what he did with the regression sessions you know
we filed the report that was the first thing we did and then he said you know would you like to do
hypnotic regression have you ever done you ever been hypnotized i said no i'm not even sure i can
be hypnotized i mean isn't that kind of a controlled show something some kind of weird thing you know that
people believe in but it's not really true not science you know it's not science it's not it's not
accepted in a court of law so i mean how could it be legitimate he's like no it's just kind of this
like super relaxed state you know it's not no big deal so i said yeah sure we'll do it so we all
four of us agreed to undergo um regression multiple regression sessions and then we promised
we agreed that we would not talk about them between us we would not report anything we remembered
from these sessions so no collusion no collusion totally isolated yeah and what comes out of the
regression session pretty similar stories yeah something that i didn't think that happened at all
i thought was christmas there's nothing to this story we're out fishing this weird light came up on
top of us we paddled away we shined a flashlight at it it flew away that's the whole story the whole
plant nothing to it so after being hypnotized then i was totally quiet with myself even i didn't even talk
to myself i'm for like the next four hours i'm just trying to access absorb and accept
what i had just re-encountered that i didn't know that i had encountered to begin with yeah why the fire
had burned out why i knew that this thing was going to go at lightning speed uh because of its power
source works off of gravitational fields when it's within the limits of a planet that has gravitational
fields describe in detail what transpired based on your regressions between you seeing this you know
plasma ball that's glowing 75 yards away and then you guys kind of walking onto shore well uh first thing
i remembered in my regression was looking at my toes and thinking well that's odd
what the hell happened to my socks and then i'm thinking where the hell are my shoes
where the hell are my clothes and the fast thinker that i am then it's like where the hell am i
and i'm like getting cold and freaked out and i'm like looking around and just beyond my toes i can see
jack and jim and this other guy setting on this bench like they're waiting for a damn bus
and in my mind i'm screaming i couldn't articulate but i'm like screaming get off your asses get over
here help me get me loose you know what's going on and at that time i was probably about a first degree
black belt in martial arts shotokan karate goshen jitsu ishiro pukalon both and aikido so i studied
mostly aikido for many years but at any rate i could take care of myself in a fight you know i'd i'd had
people attack me with knives and weapons and i defended myself successfully but here i am
butt naked
and i'm as helpless as an infant i i just it was rough for me to kind of cope with that for a while
and uh then i'm struggling to get up and i had that sensation of movement i look up and i see
this face bending down to look into my eyes so i dropped my head didn't move his way as quickly as
i could and i probably only moved my head like another three or four inches till i was making
contact with the surface i was laying on and i couldn't go backwards any further so you were
laying horizontally on a table yeah on what did the table feel like uh kind of like a
chilly like this room is chilly yeah it felt chilly uh very sterile uh very much like uh an emergency
room setting in a way and then uh i recall this panel coming down from somewhere above my head
and it was over my chest and it basically covered my entire torso and then this blue light came
straight down out of it and it had like definite dimensional quality to it the light did i mean
it isn't like like take your flashlight or anything you shine it and the light spreads and travels
this was focused it was localized into one shape and that was emitted straight down onto my torso
and there were like two beings to my left uh doing whatever to this panel i had this one at my head and another
at my feet and they began a clinical examination of me for lack of a another term at all what did the
beings look like like what did the face look like when you're lifting your head up and you see this
other head above yours leaning down yeah well i got i got artwork of it in the computer but and and it's in
the book as well uh a sort of like a bulbous head with large eyes no nose like us and no mouth like us it was
sort of like a slight slit area in the chin no ears like we have protruding they were like just a a lump
and uh not like a lump or a blob or anything but like a slight bump out from the skull are you freaking
out freaking out i'm beyond freaking freaked out
i mean here i was an individual i mean hell i i defended myself against seven armed kids
in boston a number of years ago i had seven kids come at me with weapons and you know i i had no fear
of them whatsoever i just told them they'd made an error in judgment just they i just had to let them know
that they had truly made one with your words and with your uh your moves well yeah i let them know
a thing or two so there you go but at any rate i couldn't do diddly to protect myself or do anything
so i mean at that moment on that craft um but i was told not to resist not to fight i wasn't in any
danger just comply and everything will be all right and i'm there like oh i can do that were you told
telepathically yeah when i was well you you've had the experience of being on a roller coaster
when it drops and your stomach stays up around your shoulders sure i had a physical sensation like that
but it wasn't my stomach it was like my mind when i looked into these eyes it was like
uh two magnets grabbing one another instantly and i mean it was like i understand what you're asking of
me um uh i'm i believe you instant instantaneous comprehension of their intention absolutely
interesting absolutely and so i'm they're like oh okay well i'm not gonna get hurt i'm gonna get
released so all right were they gray in color yes yeah yeah they were grayish in color do you remember
how tall uh under five feet uh spindly uh uh their hands had four digits uh uh not five or three
as are portrayed in a lot of our science fiction films uh their hands had four digits that hang
straight down and the center of the hand had like an articulation ability so they would have four
opposable digits where we only have one our thumb uh these these beings had four opposable digits and
that was the way all their technology was geared too toward their hands uh just like our world is
designed designed because of our hands how our hands work to use tools um but they had like a clothing on
it was i didn't for lack of a better word it's like a spandex type of appearance where like
tightly conformed to their body um but they also uh one of them also had this wand uh like a magic wand
that was maybe about this long or so jim can tell you more about that because of something that he
attempted to do i'll go back to the canoe when we were paddling back to the towards the beach
the the campsite the last thing i had remembered consciously was looking up and seeing this craft
like right behind us the next thing i remembered was going up to the canoe but under hypnotic regression
i remembered it being right over on like literally on top of this and that this beam came down around the
canoe and it was a hollow like charlie said earlier it was it was like a tube
where our hose where the sheath of the hose is made out of light and it was moving like when you
see um dust moats through sunlight you know it's moving that's had this quality to it but the inside
was dark and i remembered looking up straight up into the top of this tube and it was dark in there
but there was something moving i could tell there was still something moving up there and i remember
thinking oh shit this is bad and then the next thing i remembered was uh being in a room
um chuck rack and charlie were sitting on this bench and i think i think i remembered i was standing near it
and jack was um and jack was um out in front of me with um these beans and then one of them had this
wand that had a thin wand with a bulb on the end of it like the end of your finger
and he was doing he was pointing it at jack and they were doing they were like taking his wrist and
rotating his wrists and his arm to see like how it rotated i thought at first they were going to hurt
him because they were like trying to twist and turn it all these different ways and i was like oh
cripes man they're going to break his arm and uh and then they had lifted his head back and they were
like examining his throat and they had another thing that looked like it was a little flashlight like
a pencil light flashlight that they were looking in his eyes with
and um and then they i remembered them uh walking him away into this other area there was like a
a hallway of something and they took them in through there and then um they came for me
and they were doing the same thing to me and then when they went to um walk me through this area i didn't
want to go because i was terrified i thought that's it we're going to get dissected this is this is not
going well at all and i didn't i didn't get any messages saying just relax or we're not going to hurt
you i didn't get anything like that and i didn't want to go through this this doorway or into this
other area and one of them that had this wand took it and they jammed it in my rib in between my ribs
you know and i was like i then i got i didn't hear anything it wasn't like a verbal message but i just had
this understanding that if i didn't cooperate i was going to be in trouble that i had to cooperate
was there any sort of surgical implantation of anything or removal of anything well um i remembered
them taking sperm sample and um and then at one point i remembered uh this was over two sessions the
first session that the first hypnotic session um i remembered their bodies but i couldn't get their
faces for some reason i just could not see their faces or i didn't want to see their faces and then
in the second session their faces finally came through and i remember screaming they're bugs they
look like bugs they had this kind of it looked like a like a shape of an an you know they had a
bulbous top head and had these big eyes that were more laterally situated rather than in the front
no nose slit for a mouth and i couldn't tell if if if if it was the actual head or whether there was a
mask there of some sort and and i thought they'd look they reminded me of like an ant head or an insect
head are there any details from each of your individual isolated regressions where you were
kind of separated from each other any details that were inconsistent between your accounts or
did they all line up some small details were different like i remembered the um the device
that they used to get the um to store the semen i remembered it being more like a tubular shape
mm-hmm with a round bottom and uh there was a neck a smaller flange on the neck
um but like when they took the semen from me i was like i was so terrified you know my
johnson was like three inches inside of me you know it was like you are you are not getting there
and so then i had this i got this impression that um things are gonna you better change your ways or
you know so i i actually like forced myself to get an erection and then they brought out this thing
for me to you know ejaculate in whereas jack remembered uh more of a conical shape device with a
with a wand coming like a spike coming out of it or a needle coming out of it that they actually
inserted into his penis to get the sample so that was different between his recollection and my
recollection or it could have been different instrumentation or whatever yeah it could have just
been because of the way i mean i remembered they let me sit up to do it i remember saying i can't do
this laying down i got you know let me sit up and then i i was able to function and um and then uh
there was another time i don't know if they did the same thing to jack or not i can't remember but
at one point i remembered laying on a on a on a table and there were two two beans at my shoulders
behind me and two at my feet and two next on either side and i remembered thinking i mean i was
terrified and i didn't trust these things and so i at one point i'm almost ashamed to say i thought you
know maybe if i kill one i can create a distraction and get out of here i can escape and as soon as i had
that thought because i had these really like thin pencil like necks and he's like thin necks i thought
oh i could get my hand around there and just and as soon as i had that thought they the ones who were
near my shoulders and on the side they moved away so fast it was like a blur and then um one of the
ones that were at my feet just it was weird he kind of like reached up in the air with his arm
they had these long long thin articulated arms and when he came down he had this thing in his hand
that looked like a flattened hockey it was like a hockey puck but it wasn't like perfectly round it was
more like of an oval shape and it had rounded edges instead of the sharp edges a hockey puck has but it
was like the size of a hockey puck maybe a little smaller and they put one on on the outside of each one
of my shins and then i couldn't move my legs like no matter how hard i tried i couldn't move my legs
did you ask them any questions about who they were and where they were from or no i didn't yeah
didn't even get a damn t-shirt i mean no souvenirs you know like i said earlier it was like i got the
clear impression that these whatever they were they were following a procedure yeah it was you know
step one step two step three step four i don't remember them putting me in any machines
jack they got a lot more out of jack than they did me because i was like so terrified all the time
that ray thought i was going to have a seizure so they had to keep bringing me out of the hypnosis
so i wouldn't have a seizure because i would be like freaking out during these sessions but it was
almost like the beings were in some sort of automated assembly line and they were following in a sense
in a sense they weren't totally automated um just a footnote about what jim had just mentioned about
these discs being placed on his ankles uh on his legs for several years thereafter i don't know if it's
that way now hair didn't grow there it was like bald patch on it whoa really and both shins and his
identical twin brother jack yeah had tumors growing in the exact spots on his legs what tumors tumors
benign or we never knew because the tumors were removed uh at the teaching hospital where they
removed them in vermont uh their pathology department was unable to ascertain what type of
biological they were looking at so they sent it to the air force institute of pathology
down around washington dc it was signed for by a major or no by a colonel a doctor who was a rank of a
colonel because they have one of the best uh pathology uh science labs in the world got it yeah when
they removed this thing on his shin it looked like a piece of um bubble gum pink in color hard
and they said in the report that it resembled the type of growth that is common when you have um
uh bone marrow taken out of a bone you get this kind of tissue that grows on the wound that's what
they they said they didn't know what it was but that was what it that was the closest thing that they
could describe it as whoa did any of you guys end up with any implants anything inside of your body
i don't think so i used to have a head of hair does that count no uh oh okay i uh i have like a small
punch biopsy scar up near my scrotum that i had never known before uh if you were to take like an old
uh pencil the ones that had the brass barrel and the rubber eraser in them pull the eraser out and
stab it into something to take a plug out that's the size diameter and very shallow maybe about uh
not quite an eighth of an inch deep uh right here on the inside of my leg you describe the beings as
clinical very clinical yeah we were like the chimps and they were like jane goodall so they were about
their business kind of yeah right the best analogy i can come up with is like when scientists go to
the you know arctic and they see a polar bear and they dart him and then while he's anesthetized they
measure his teeth and look at his you know what's that what's a polar bear got to say about what
happened i remembered when under the hypnosis i like the way i saw things was weird it was like i
had tunnel vision i could see clearly you but out here everything was fuzzy and unclear did all of the
hypnotic regressions line up because all four of you did yes yeah yeah over a period of about almost a
year uh-huh do you have the audio uh ray certainly has i don't yeah would i be able to listen to that
it's the some of the hypnotic regressions are are word for word in his book would i be able to
listen to the audio well you'd have to get ray okay if he even still has that stuff okay uh but if you
do go to the library or get a copy of his book the allagash abductions um it has direct quotes from the
regression okay uh questions as well as our responses and their analysis and their analysis
of them it's the best book on the case did john mack over see any or did did john mack review any of
the uh hypnotic regression audio or any of the material there i don't know what john he must have
over the years because we've known john for many years 20 over 20 years yeah over 25 before he died
um after we had after ray had gotten finished with his investigation i was um he said it because
during the during the investigation he said i don't want you to read any books i don't want you to
talk about it to one another or really anybody else because i don't want to like pollute yeah
well hopefully now he would you know after having written his book hopefully the audio the raw source
material he would sort of open source because well if anybody you know if anybody should uh be in
possession of it it should be you guys i mean we could have purchased the complete manuscript i mean
and that includes all of the hypnotic regressions transcribed verbatim word for word uh but you
know that thing was like literally yeah they're really almost a foot thick well hey of paper now we
have a little thing called ai and you run it you run it through and you just say you know describe
you know these accounts and give us a summary and then you can query it and you so i think i think
it'd be really cool to to get these things kind of digitized and you know and then run it through
the ai and you'd be able to ask it questions and stuff sounds like you found a project for yourself
oh i'm ready let's do it ray yeah yeah i'll try to get in touch with ray and that'd be cool um
fascinating what what was john mac like uh i uh am a long time you know admirer of his obviously you
know rest in peace well i went to his his support group for a while after ray was done with his
investigation um and jim real quick just for the audience for basic context john mac was the head
of the harvard psychiatry department and uh brilliant guy he actually even wrote the pulitzer prize winning
um i believe lawrence of arabia yeah that's right uh uh he's an expert on him the the prince of
disorder and um and as really kind of a mystic in his own right but also obviously academically as
credentialed as it gets and towards the end of his career he started to uh because he was a clinician
see people who had missing time and get into the whole you know alien abduction phenomena and was
actually childhood friends serendipitously with bud hopkins um who was this you know amazing
aggregator of a lot of these experiences himself so go on yeah so anyway my impression of john when i
first met him was i knew that he was a psychiatrist and he was affiliated with harvard and he had
credentials up the kazoo and so when i went to his support groups i noticed that they were
in my from my perspective i saw two different camps of people one camp which i considered myself
a member of was the nuts and bolts i called it the nuts and bolts you know i i want to see
physical evidence i want to see physical beans and then the other camp was more of a like
um people who thought that they were most that they're that their experiences were more ethereal
uh multi-dimensional sure beans that weren't physical but communicated more of a consciousness
conscious consciousness based and that these people seem to think that the aliens were our
saviors that they were going to save the human race and they were here to uplift our consciousness to a
level where there's no more hate or war and all that stuff which was fine i didn't have a problem with
it i mean but i did notice that and i think john was more the second camp because of his training as a
psychiatrist he you know because what a psychiatrist job to do their job is to heal people you know and
these people all had like serious problems dealing with this stuff it's like even though they even
though we all believe that we actually that these experiences were real for us it still creates all
kinds of psychological problems you know how to deal with other people who don't who think you're crazy
yeah or i think you're you know subhuman for some reason there's something wrong with you because you
have these beliefs that are out of the box and so it's it my impression of john mack was that he saw it as
his mission his mission to help these people become you know self actualized again where they could be
they could live with their experiences without pain or fear or anxiety kind of re reintegrated back into
society and right probably simultaneously and still be able to live with their experiences
you know because that was that was the difference between him and the rest of the community the rest of
the psyche psychiatric community rest of the ci psychiatric community especially at harvard which is why they
tried to kick them out yeah was that no these people are you know they're they're lunar there's
something wrong with these people and john was saying look i've given them every kind of psychiatric and
psychological tests i can think of they're all coming out as normal people and neither of you had any
kind of mental health history prior no the only mental problems i had was from the seizures
um because i'd have auras you know i'd smell things or hear things sir um how many beings were on the
craft well hard to say yeah yeah it really would be because there were people or beings in the
like control room area that we were ushered through on our way into the exam area and as we left
we passed because that was where i inquired about their power system their propulsion system and so
you've you learned some stuff directly from them about the propulsion system or well i was explained the
way you would explain something to a six-year-old you know that it uh it operates in a similar fashion
to the way a submarine can work at different atmospheres in the water different levels by the amount of air
that it keeps in its inner hull to maintain that depth and they could match gravitational fields
and so that was the way they were sort of examining uh example a to what we do this is
so like where your submarine works this is the way our craft works when it's in in a planetary
gravitational area so it would like you mentioned with the submarine you have a certain amount of
air between the inner and outer hull which manages the depth and you're saying that they're doing
something similar where they're modulating gravitational fields interesting yeah that's fascinating very
yeah yeah well it's good you know think about that i'll mull that over well i mean it's just like
we can do things magnetically that um where you take the two very powerful magnets and you have
the same polarity you have all this resistance if you try touching them to one another
uh and their ability was to match and a gravitational field to propel them away from
from a denser field to a less dense field i don't know it's the only way i can think of yeah did you
have any sense of where they came from why they were taking you know samples from you guys no it's
interesting because the kind of you know gammy you know semen and egg sample thing comes up a lot
that's very common it's almost like there's some intergenerational alien breeding program and that's
kind of where you end up with a lot of these yeah guys don't don't we do the exact thing same thing
to animals sure on our planet yeah we domesticate animals all the time we breed them we create new
species we do the same thing with people and like you know dynasty families it's wild to think that
but it's it's true and sometimes i think about these um gray alien beings and you think about what
an evolutionary biologist would say a human is evolving into given that we're being domesticated
right now that is not a controversial thing to say we are you know testosterone is dropping off a cliff
uh sperm count is dropping off a cliff for men we're losing you know the melanin in our our skin
that happens over a long period of time so you end up with these beings that you know they lose the
melanin in their skin the the their prefrontal cortex is larger because decision making is probably more
important with the advent of you know the ai white collar work age their ears and nose become vestigial
we're not hunter gathering their eyes become more slit-like because we use more screens
and their their bodies are sort of wiry and spindly because our physical bodies become less important
and they develop some sort of you know latent telepathic power which you're now seeing you
know the telepathy tapes and like you know people starting to lend more rigorous scientific credence to
the idea that maybe we we have this mind matter sort of thing and so they've selected for all the
stuff that you would expect humanity to select for it's very interesting that's right yeah yeah i mean
i've heard from some people at some of the conferences where they believe that they're actually us from
the future yes yeah that exactly there's a guy named mike masters and then i somehow think that
you know that's a really interesting theory that's important and then it's somehow too simple like
there's something else going on too you know but it's it's it's always hard to theorize the problem i
always have is the interdimensional stuff against the physical i mean if they
if if they can travel interdimensionally why do they have craft what do they need a craft for
yeah yeah yeah you know it's like what yeah it's almost like some of these things are symbolic memes
that change over time and that would be the jacques valet idea i mean are they is is that craft that we
saw really something physical or just something they wanted us to see as physical i don't know did did
any of you so okay so the the the physical evidence would be like the ankle your hair not growing
around your ankle your brother having tumors in the same spot tumors in the exact same spot anything
else as far as like a physical you know remnant of the well one of the things that
has always fascinated me personally was the fact that all of us or the three of us most certainly had
uh major changes and the direction of our lives and our artwork after the allagash where i was training
myself to be a school teacher to work with children teaching art i ended up becoming a medical artist
working with medical scientists medical researchers and being aware of all kinds of new technologies
the technology i mentioned that they use to look at our chests or at our torsos
um when i was a medical photographer i would use ultraviolet light sources and ultraviolet film
infrared film and infrared light sources to photograph human bodies um because with ultraviolet light
you can see through the skin and see the blood vessels much clearer than you can with your naked eyes
um so we use magnetic fields to look inside the human body now to look at soft tissue eyes and your
MRIs prior to that was your x-rays and then cat scans then you can use ultrasound
uh sonic waves and tomograms the whole nine yards all these different radiological tools
so i was talking with a physician about this and uh and he said well he said that's just like when
you know uh defibrillators first showed up in the world you know they were these
experimental paddles that you touch the heart or you know to restart the the heart's function
and that all of these technologies that these beings have were slowly catching up i mean if you stop and
any rational person stop and think in 1903 which was 123 years ago two bicycle builders from ohio did the
first manned flight not a glider they weren't gliding from a high elevation to a different elevation or a
different location they took off from a low elevation and landed at a higher elevation that was flight
66 years after that
we were walking on the moon
in 66 years
now
these
entities
these these these beings that we don't know where they come from
uh they have science that's
you know even
patting us on the back saying thousands of years ahead of us
they might be hundreds of thousands of years ahead of us
uh the milky way galaxy
there are more stars and planets in the milky way galaxy than grains of sand on planet earth
that's what i've been told by astrophysicists and that is a number that just is almost incomprehensible
for me
and uh that uh the technologies that we have and we're developing
like sound technology without speakers
uh
bone conducting headphones
yeah
send the vibrations through your cheekbones
and i hear better with these than i do listening to people
yeah it's fascinating it
you can bypass the ear canal through vibration
yeah
beethoven went deaf famously and he would uh chew on this rod
and that would allow him to hear once he went deaf
which was obviously very important for him as this amazing
composer
um speaking of very advanced technology
maybe the most shocking thing
that you said charlie right before we started rolling
which i got so excited about is
i've been researching this guy named john norseen
yeah
and he is uh you know this interesting engineer who has this lockheed patent
for essentially how to fly a ufo with your mind
how to use sort of biofeedback from the brain
in order to control remote control
remote pilot a craft
and he he talks about brain prints
the idea that we have fingerprints
but you might also have a unique
kind of uh
oh yeah
electromagnetic signature
just like iris or whatever
iris yeah
so fascinating guy who seems well ahead of his time
and i have to think if there is you know
uh legacy ufo crash retrieval program
which i do believe
um they are either tracking him
uh you know and he's now since you know
he's passed away
but they were either tracking him
or they were working directly with him
would be my guess
and so this is fascinating
because you said that john norseen
you spoke to john norseen
and he was at allagash
in the 19
in 1976
in august
when you guys were there
and experienced your abduction
that's right
he read our report to the ranger
that same day
that's what he told us
whoa
he read your report to the ranger
that same day
and what what did he say
he was doing there
he said he was doing a ttr
um
tag
trace
retrieve
exercise
with a subcutaneous
device
that they were testing
that they could
monitor
they could monitor
sort of like gps
field agents
you know
it would tell them like
blood pressure
heart rate
that sort of stuff
so
he would
location
what exactly
he would put like this like
rfid chip
or something
on
some other
military folk
and they would sort of
you know
uh
go off
and into allagash
and they were testing
to see how well
they could track
these people
exactly
that's so fast
that's what he told us
and
does any part
of you guys
think that
because you know
i think about
some of these
narratives
with like you know
ufos showing up
around nuclear
sites
and i don't
it might not be a
coincidence that
you're uh
you know
uh
you're uh
in the navy
in a nuclear
capacity
there's a nuclear
air force base
or was at the time
in the 70s
up in northern maine
what was the name
of that base
do you remember
oh it wasn't an
air force guy
loring
air force base
yep
um
but this was near
was it near
allagash
yeah 90 miles
away from allagash
okay
interesting
in northern maine
and it was a secret
nuclear base
they had a
uh
episode
it was either
1975 or 1976
where craft
were coming
over the base
and these
laser type
beams were coming
out and they were
mapping the nuclear
stockpiles
and this is around
the time that you
guys had your
experience
I don't know
if it was around
the same time
you said 75
75 76
yeah
yeah well that's
around the same
time
yeah
well there's like
a many
reported incidents
over uh
our nuclear
missile sites
where
these craft
would appear
above them
and then all
the missiles
go offline
all their
computers shut
down
yep
and uh
they go
into a
massive
freak out
oh yeah
I've interviewed
a lot of those
guys firsthand
and I think
they're all
legit
so 90 miles
away you had
this air force
base
they reported
ufos showing
up within a
year or two
of your
experience
with lasers
shooting out
of the ufos
seeming to
sort of you
know track
or do
well they were
they were
definitely mapping
the bunkers
and that's a
common thing
you hear
yeah that
they're sort
of you know
uh testing
the tip of the
spear of human
defense and
you know knowing
you know either
to protect
ourselves protect
their resources
you know some
of the people in
the national
security state
say there might
be you know
doing isr
and doing
recon I
don't know
but I don't
believe that
I don't I
don't believe
that yeah
yeah I
don't buy the
whole the
the idea that
they're a
threat and you
know I think
they oh if
they wanted to
do something
yeah we
couldn't do
diddly
that's right
and they would
have done it
years ago
why why it's
like they are
so advanced
it's like yeah
why do they
need to like
you know play
around with us
before before
you know it's
like what at
what point in
your isr
you know recon
do you say
okay we can
like take these
guys out like
they can they
can clearly take
us out now if
they wanted to
I mean good
or yeah you
look back at
artwork from the
renaissance era
and you have
a lot of
depictions of
like UFOs in
some of these
pieces of
artwork yeah
yeah no it's
clearly a it's
a across
civilizations and
across millennia
phenomena so if
they were gonna
threaten us I
mean they would
have done us
way before the
neanderthal were
bred out yeah
and that's another
thing a lot of
people think the
neanderthal were
killed by
crow magnum
and homo
sapien sapien
which is what
the species we
are but they
got literally
screwed out of
existence I want
to stick with this
John Norseen thing
because I think
this is really
interesting so he
was doing TTR
this sort of
tracking thing of
other you know
fellow military
combatants or
something seeing if
they'd go out in
the field and
track I believed
him I mean he
was he's I got
to know John
pretty good how
did you meet
him we met him
at a mutual
friend of ours
down in Newport
would bring
together
experiencers and
she's somebody
that and
researchers was
he an experiencer
Norseen no he
was working with
an artist in
Jamestown across
the bay what was
he doing when
you met him do
you know what
his job was
John I don't
really know what
his job was he
was telling us
things and then
he said well I
can't really tell
you what I'm doing
now because I
would probably end
up dead in some
hotel room somewhere
and I was
thinking what
happened to and
I was he ended
up dead in a hotel
room yes exactly
no way down
Tennessee was it
I don't remember
somewhere I think
it was a heart
attack but he
told us at
Ann's yeah he
said because he
was talking a lot
about stuff that
everybody knew he
shouldn't be talking
about but it
just seemed like
science fiction
yeah it seemed
like I even said
to him you know
John isn't that
a bit out there
about this what
he was drinking
you know I mean
everybody was
drinking wine and
he was and what
did he say it was
his job title in
the 70s in the
in 76 when he
was at Allagash
do you remember
primarily the
research function
yeah I think he
said he was doing
government research
he had to be
working with the
military because
they were you
know TTRing
agents in the
field and no
part of you guys
thinks that your
experience was some
sort of smoke
screen for like
covert government
experimentation I
don't think so no
I asked John that
personally you asked
you asked I asked
John that I said
John you know is
what we saw up
there and I mean
did you did we
like stumble into
something that we
shouldn't have
stumbled into and
then you nailed us
and and hypnotized
this or gave us
drugs or something
to make us believe
that we had this
abduction experience
to cover your butt
he said no
and he believed in
what he said yeah
no I could tell he
was telling the
truth he said we
wouldn't do that we
just go away
no I mean you
with a story
nobody's gonna
believe
right sure yeah
yeah exactly it's
not like you guys
have like had an
easy time since
yeah you know
yeah it came out
with your story
no I almost
wonder if the
you know meta
phenomena of the
UFOs showing up
around the tip of
the spear of human
defense and
ingenuity they're
showing up at
nuclear sites and
at particle
accelerators and
things where we
are literally
messing with sort
of space time
itself you could
imagine them maybe
being interested in
a you know chip
tracking uh you
know human
experiment and
them showing up
around that so
you know I think
the kind of easy
lazy skeptic thing
would be to say
that oh it's a
it's a smokescreen
for some MK
Ultra thing yeah but
maybe the more
interesting and
possibly true
narrative would be
that their
activities which
were seemingly
covert might have
attracted the
phenomena itself
well that's what
John that's what
John told me
there's Alexander
Graham Bell let's
go down and listen
to what he's
saying exactly but
you're saying that's
what John literally
told you that's
what he believed
too that that's
interesting that the
the experiments that
he was conducting
was may have been
just attracting
these things when
did he and he
ended up dead in a
hotel room I don't
know what year it
was in fact that
was it followed a
really weird uh
email that I had
gotten from him
because he he
had contacted
me via email
you know he
was a he was
an RVer he
was one of the
early RVers yeah
and uh remote
viewers yeah
and um he had
sent me an email
and said and
and some of the
other people from
Ann's and he
said listen I'm
giving a lecture
on my latest
research at the
uh Naval College
in Newport do
you want to do
you want a VIP
pass to come and
and attend it I
was like oh
yeah
yeah so he
said okay I'll
get it all set
up and then at
the end of his
email you know
he was into I
forget what the
term is for this
kind of use of
language semiotics
semiotics yeah he
was really into
that yeah and um
he at the last
sentence in his
email said um
uh nor uh I he
said I I RV'd the
upcoming um
lecture uh John
not heard nor
seen whoa and I
remember calling
Ann and saying
hey Ann what the
heck is this last
sentence mean John
not heard nor
seen I know he's
in the semiotics and
stuff so you know
not nor seen is his
last name but John
not heard nor seen
and then just like
two weeks after that
he was found dead in
a motel room so
Jesus Christ so
that was some sort
of code where it's
like he he remote
viewed his own
view it and he
wasn't there and
this was code to
say he's not heard
nor seen yeah I
mean what else
could that mean
oh my god I mean
what and this is
nuts and he
probably was working
on program stuff
who knows I mean
he was working at
that time with this
artist this amazing
artist in Jamestown
Duncan Laurie is
his name he's a
sculptor glass
artist but at
that time John
was working with
him on life
energy R is
around like rocks
and plants and
things like that
bioenergetics
yeah very
interesting very
yeah well this
is a wild and
very interesting
interview I feel
like we go on
forever but
Charlie you had
because you were
in the Navy you
had a very
interesting you
know UFO
experience that
that I want to
get into
yeah in May of
1970 we were
off the coast of
Spain doing what
we had gone out
there to do and
it was just after
we've knocked off
working for the
day waiting for
the call to
evening meal
there were about
24 of us that
went up on the
main deck
have cigarettes
kick around
kill some time
until it's time
to go eat
we had a
commissioned
officer who was
a lieutenant
a highest ranking
enlisted which
was a chief
petty officer
and then
descending ranks
from there
and one of the
guys said
what the
F is that
and so we
all kind
of like
turned to
look toward
the stern
of the ship
and just
as I
was looking
back I
saw these
two
lights
coming
toward us
I mean
faster than
you could
swing your
arm
from your
shoulder
to directly
in front
of you
and come
to a
stop
these
things were
going faster
than that
and came
to a
complete
stop
and we
observed
them for
almost two
minutes
two full
and one
of these
points of
lighter spheres
ascended so
quickly that
it went from
like a point
of light
to a
line
and was
gone
just
snip
nip
but
less time
than it
did
for me
to say
that
snip
nip
and it
was
gone
and then
about
30 seconds
later
the other
one did
the exact
same thing
and they
both went
vertical
straight up
so fast
you just
couldn't
believe what
you were
looking at
so we
turned to
the officer
that was
there and
we said
sir what
the hell
was that
and he
looked at
the chief
then he
looked at
us and
he looked
at the
chief and
he looked
back at
us and
he said
if I
were you
guys I
wouldn't say
anything to
anyone anyhow
because no
one's going
to believe
you and
this topic
is closed
and with
that he
turned and
ran up
into
officers
country
and I
never
forgotten
that verbatum
quote
nobody's
going to
believe you
anyhow
and this
topic is
closed
I think
they believe
you guys
now because
now you
have
directors of
national
intelligence
directors of
the CIA
presidents
saying we're
looking into
this stuff
yeah you
got pilots
using their
cell phones
to photograph
freaking UFOs
that aren't
from here
yeah it's
the evidence
is becoming
pretty overwhelming
and I think
the consensus
is rapidly
shifting
and you
said
and this
is I
think
going to
be also
if we
find
corroboration
for this
really you
know healthy
vindication
for you
know
allagash
as well
oh
absolutely
may 1970
USS
Holland
is where
this occurred
correct
and so
off the
coast of
Spain
and this
thing was
seen on
the starboard
side
and maybe
it's still
in the
logs
so to
anybody
who has
any experience
with the
Freedom of
Information Act
and knows
how to
you know
send those
requests
try to
get this
stuff out
yeah if
you can
access that
stuff
I'd be
certainly
interested
in knowing
what was
reported
awesome
can we
talk a
little bit
about a
more about
how this
experience
has affected
our artwork
sure
because
there were
two things
that changed
well we
talked a
little bit
about
yours
just
touching
and a
little bit
about
Jack's
obsession
about
mathematics
this happened
immediately
after we
returned to
Boston
and before
we went to
the Allagast
Jack was
doing
endangered
species
well he was
doing like
really tight
kind of
illustrative
silk screen
designs
one of them
is in the
museum of
art in
Washington
D.C.
snakes
poster
and
devil's
pup
yeah
I don't
know if
the devil's
pup
fish is
but
anyway
and then
he was
also doing
these
kind of
like
what kind
of painting
it is
abstract
expressionist
painting
of
landscapes
that was
the kind
of work
he was
in
and then
like
immediately
after coming
back from
the Allagast
he like
just
became
obsessed
with this
this like
all this
kind of
weird
mathematical
stuff
he was
building
models of
like
casododecahedrons
out of
straws
and
he was
incorporating
grids
in
all of
his artwork
and
in very
incredibly
intriguing
ways
and
it was
one piece
that I
really loved
I would
like to
know
whatever
happened
to it
tossed
grid
salad
oh
that's
Craig
a friend
of ours
oh
Craig's
got that
anyway
and he
was
like
you know
we live
together
you know
and I'm
his twin
so like
no secrets
and I'd be
like Jack
what the hell
is going
on here
you know
like what
are you
doing
and he'd
go I
don't
know
but I
have to
do
this
I have
to do
this
and
and like
it just
like kept
going and
going
and going
and years
later
somebody
came
our friend
Mike
Asherman
came
to the
house
this was
this guy
is like
a brilliant
MIT
programmer
and scientist
he helped
them build
their tokamak
at MIT
and he came
over one night
and he was
looking at
Jack's artwork
and he goes
you know
I know
what this
is Jack
this is
get this
book
Secrets
of
World
Grid
and
anti
gravity
by
David
Hatcher
Childress
and that
go to
this
page
this chapter
in here
you'll see
Jack's
what's
the math
behind all
of this
stuff
what
yeah
and this
guy's
building
tokamak
yeah
wild
so it's
almost like
your brother
was channeling
something
frontier
science
and the same
thing happened
to me
when I came
back
before I went
up to the
Allagash
I was making
production pottery
bowls and cups
and platters
and plates
and things
and teapots
and when I
came
when I was
like just
days after
this event
in on the
Allagash
I had this
epiphany
I mean it was
like an epiphany
it's the only word
I can think of
to describe it
all of a sudden
this thing
came into my
head
fully developed
that I could
if I worked
with clay
this way
I could do
this like
really unique
kind of
of
creations
with clay
that are
they're so far
total opposite
of production
pottery
and I became
obsessed with
this stuff
I almost got
kicked out
of the program
because of it
but I stayed
with it
and I managed
to convince
them that this
was something
legitimate
that I really
wanted to
some of the
most amazing
amazing artwork
and then in
addition to
that
I became
obsessed
like my
brother
on ancient
architecture
places like
Teotihuacan
and Tiwanaku
Baalbek
and the
temples in
Southeast Asia
Angkor Wat
and Angkor
Tom
and the pyramids
and I
just became
obsessed
because I
had this
you know
that's also
common
among
experiencers
they'll say
I've become
obsessed with
the pyramid
I have a
buddy
you guys
might be
friends with
too
Mario Woods
from the
Ellsworth
Air Force Base
abduction
experience
South Dakota
and he
he goes
after
it's gonna
sound weird
but after
my experience
I just
became
obsessed
with pyramids
yeah so
did I
and
and I
had this
this belief
which I
still have
I
believe
that these
sites
these
structures
architectural
sites
are a
form of
macro chip
technology
that they
they're not
just ceremonial
places that
people went
and prayed
to their
gods
yeah I
believe that
that they
actually used
these
structures
for some
kind of
purpose
a functional
you know
because
I agree
why did
they have
huge
sheets
of
mica
brought
to
Teotihuacan
sun
pyramid
from
two to
three thousand
miles away
in South
America
and then
put them
under
the floor
structures
of the
temples
I mean
mica is
used in
the electronics
industry
and so
like why
would
why would
they do
that if
it's not
decorative
and it's
not just
in the
pyramid of
the sun
it's in
all the
other
pyramids
in that
immediate
area
they all
have
those
they all
utilize
this
mica
so you
know mica
is is
a um
it's used
as an
insulator
to make
capacitors
hmm
another point
very interesting
yeah
and I've
always
and that
was like
just something
that
creating
strong
electric
fields
yeah
I'm reading
a book
now it's
called
seeds of
knowledge
stones
of power
I think
it is
and I
can't
think of
the
author
I just
started
reading it
this past
week
found it
on Amazon
where these
researchers
went to
all these
pyramid sites
in
Mesoamerica
Europe
Egypt
and they
took measurements
of the
electrical
fields
field energies
of these
locations
and they
claim in
their
argument
in their
book
that these
peoples
the
Incas
and the
Aztecs
the Mayans
the Olmecs
were using
these structures
to make
their seed
more
virulent
and that
so they
started doing
tests at
these same
sites
with bags
of seeds
or whatever
containers of
seeds
and they
found out
that they
increased
yield
per acre
like three
to five
times
it's like
electroculture
or something
yeah
bioelectrics
fascinating
well
Jim
Charlie
this was an
absolute honor
it was a lot
of fun
and
yeah
it was
really amazing
to hear
your story
and
you know
I hope
people start
to you know
use the
Freedom of
Information Act
to try to
get to the
bottom of
the 1970
experience
as well
that'd be
interesting
I'd like to
know
and I want
to give a
shout out
to the
great
James Fox
for the
very generous
introduction
here
and thank
you both
for your
time
well you're
very very
welcome
it's been an
honor
Jesse
oh my
all mine
head to
americanalchemymerch.com
to grab
official
americanalchemymerch
and support
the show
directly
and while
you're there
the cowboy
ufot
is a fan
favorite
we always
keep in
stock
along with
the atomic
age design
thank you
all so much
for following
and supporting
the show
you
Thank you.