All these people conducting the seance were bringing in these nine, maybe extraterrestrial
beings, maybe beings that go to the nine Egyptian gods, but it's like a council.
He really was a genuine believer.
I'm Andrea Pujaric. I'm a physician by training, a research scientist by choice.
We have tape recordings of him meditating in the king's chamber.
What?
And they brought through this information. Apparently they're channeling this Egyptian god.
And there are nine, there are specifically nine Egyptian gods.
So he gets this called metallic voice. That was some sort of, you know, alien intelligence.
This is what, you know, you hear a lot about this with the UFO abduction stuff.
Like these, these people like weren't looking to be in the spotlight.
It took about two years for me to basically earn the trust of these space kids.
It's like stranger things in real life.
You know, one neat solution that would explain everything away would be mind control, right?
Delgado, implanted radio receivers in the heads of bull.
Delgado has remote control of the animal.
You have a guy who's being able to play the bull like a video game.
I'm revealing for the first time a lot of things that even my closest working colleagues do not know.
There's reason to believe Buharic may have been a double agent.
He says it.
Really?
Tape.
This is one of the craziest interviews I've ever done, man.
The glistening sequence size.
How is this possible?
Nothing too unusual about that.
The existence cannot longer be denied.
I'm here with Greg Malazzi.
This has been a long time coming.
We've had a lot of interesting offline conversations.
You made an amazing documentary called Mind Traveler about this very mysterious mid-century scientist named Andrea Puharic, who is like this zealot of American conspiracies.
He's this architect of MKUltra and early CIA mind control techniques, but also seems to be channeling aliens through what he calls the space kids, this like collection of kids who he recruits who are psychic.
He's the inspiration for Star Trek, incidentally.
Like, he is one of the most interesting people I've ever encountered.
And you've made this amazing documentary on him, so I just can't wait to dive into this, and I appreciate you being here.
Oh, thanks, man.
I appreciate you having me.
Absolutely.
So give me a little bit about the origin story for Andrea Puharic.
Who is he, and how did he come to be one of these kind of renegade spooky scientists involved in mind control?
I guess you could start it at Northwestern University.
He went there.
He was a medical student.
I think he started in 47.
And so he was there doing all sorts of stuff with the nervous system.
He was very interested in that.
And he was doing, like, normal medical training.
And he was actually part of the Army Specialized Training Program.
Have you heard of this?
No.
It's this special program where basically they recruit students who they believe could be, you know, useful to whatever they're planning on doing in certain categories of the Army, whether it be medical, so forth.
He was a medical doctor.
And he was part of this program.
It's very strange.
Kissinger was part of this program.
A bunch of other weird people.
Kurt Vonnegut, the author.
What?
Yeah, you could look it up.
It's really weird.
So he was part of that.
Basically, it was like sort of a recruiting program.
And they saw something in him all the way back in 47 when he was a medical student.
And he very rarely, in fact, I've never even heard him mention this in all the stuff I've listened to and read about him.
So for whatever reason, you know, he didn't talk about it.
And that could have been his first, you know, step into that world, the military world.
But that happened when he was a medical student, like way before the Roundtable Foundation, the first lab he had or anything like that.
What did this military program, this Army program involve?
You can, even on Wikipedia, there's not much about it.
But again, I think it was more like looking at certain institutions, certain places for people who are special.
I mean, Army specialized training, you know, and he was considered special at that time for what he was doing.
And they just saw something in him.
And he was brought into that program.
I don't know what it did exactly or, you know, what, like, yeah, the day-to-day or anything.
But he was part of it as well as, like, again, a list of other people.
Like in all areas, right?
Again, Kurt Vonnegut, the author, like all these people were a part of that.
Where was he a medical student?
Northwestern, Chicago.
Which, you know, is a very prestigious school.
Absolutely.
Evanston.
And I think also Jalen Hynek was, you know, his astronomer, Blue Book, was Northwestern too.
Yeah, yeah.
Okay, so he's in the Chicago suburbs and he's a medical student.
How does he get into, like, telepathy and mind control and things like that?
I came up with a theory of the nervous system that I called the Puharich theory.
I visualized the nervous system as being embedded in the cell tissue of the body,
just as the roots of a tree are embedded in the ground, which gives it nourishment.
But the tree also has a similar network radiating into the sky.
Perhaps man does as well.
And he, too, gains nourishment through a touchless process.
And if dynamics can be transferred, why camp thoughts?
So, he was, yeah, a medical student.
And there's a guy also at Northwestern at the time named Warren S. McCullough.
Do you know who that is?
No, who's that?
You could do an episode on him.
He's like, you know, a Puharich on steroids, sort of, back then at least.
But he was this very far-out researcher into, basically, ESP stuff back then.
He was very interested in, like, you know, altering drugs, psychedelic drugs, mind-altering stuff.
For the audience, ESP is extrasensory perception.
Yes, yeah, yeah, extrasensory perception.
So, he was at Northwestern, this guy, McCullough.
I think I'm pronouncing that right.
But he sort of took Puharich under his wing and, from what I understand, was the first person who introduced him to, you know, whatever weird science, if you want to call it that.
Because he was one of these guys, McCullough, who would, you know, on his off time, do all these, like, strange experiments with radio frequencies and that kind of stuff.
And I think, like, in the academic setting, he had to, you know, put on a suit and tie and, like, not talk about that, basically.
But he also was very involved in intelligence stuff.
Like, he was always getting sort of, like, we have letters from, like, CIA and stuff back then who were kind of going to him with questions and so forth.
McCullough.
McCullough, yeah.
Interesting.
Yeah.
And he actually, there was an archive in, I think, it wasn't Northwestern, it was some bizarre archive I found years ago making the film.
And, you know, I know you had Annie Jacobson on, like, she's in the film.
And she was trying to find records on McCullough because, you know, it was really interesting.
It was part of the Puharich story.
And somehow we found this, like, big stash of archives of his that, again, were these letters from CIA and the Navy and everything sort of, I guess, wanting to recruit him.
But in those letters, there were letters from McCullough back to these agencies saying, you know, you should check this guy Puharich out.
Like, you know, he's, I work with him, he's young, he's very smart, and he was older, like, much older than Puharich at that time.
I think he was probably, like, you know, in his 70s or 80s or something.
So, you know, he passed on.
But basically that, I think, triggered Puharich to get very interested in the subject.
So he became almost, like, obsessed with it.
And he sort of had this moment back then where he's like, I'm either going to choose the traditional academic path or I'm going to choose the, you know, path of ESP telepathy.
And he talks very openly about, like, making that choice.
I was unexpectedly put in contact with Henry A. Wallace, vice president under Franklin Delano Roosevelt.
He was impressed by my quest for the existence of telepathy and granted me a large sum of money.
Additional benefactors emerged, including the heirs to two of the wealthiest families in the world, the Astors and the DuPonts.
I was able to get a barn. I started working in the dead of winter in 48th and in Maine.
We lived in a big 50-room house on the seashore, which was a lab and residence and so on.
It was called the Roundtable Foundation.
And so he opens the Roundtable Foundation.
So there's a lot going on with how that even opened because it's a huge lab.
It's like a massive barn.
It's on the coast of Maine, Rockland, Maine, it's called.
So, you know, it's this huge place.
He's got, like, a staff, you know.
And the thing with Puharich, I learned, like, he tells a different story of how the Roundtable started and how we got the money and everything to what we kind of figured out was really going on.
What'd you figure out?
Well, it was all, you know, government-funded at that time.
It was the CIA?
Uh, everyone. Army, Navy, CIA, something called the, um, something Armor Foundation that was somehow tied into the Army.
But, but basically any, any of those places back then, I mean, we have letters, um, uh, of, of all of them.
You get Army, you name it.
I mean, they were just, like, flocking to this place, basically giving him money to do research.
And this was, yeah, 49, 50, very early.
Fascinating.
And you think their preliminary interest was mind control, telepathy, anything beyond the purview of kind of normal materialist reductionist physics that might be able to be weaponized or confer a tactical advantage to the United States?
It's, it's, it's complex, but yes, the short answer is yes, but I think obviously there was an interest in ESP and in what he was doing and in this idea of, okay, what if this is real?
I mean, he speaks a lot and we, you know, we've uncovered like hundreds of tape recordings of his, um, that no one's ever heard.
And so, you know, he talks a lot about like, they were just obsessed at that time with like, what if this were real?
What are the implications?
What if somebody could basically remote view?
I mean, he was doing remote viewing and this is something like, I don't think is really out there.
Like way, way before SRI seventies, like we're talking early fifties.
Whoa.
He's basically doing what would be considered remote viewing.
Do you think Hal Puthoff was aware of Puharich's kind of foundation that he set with remote viewing?
Cause the story is that, you know, official American remote viewing kind of started with Hal Puthoff and Russell Targ and Stanford Research Institute.
It's not, yeah, I'm not trying to make bold statements, but that's just, that's not, you know, true.
If you look, if you're looking at it from a like research, when did this start?
Because we have like all of the, um, round table research, which is so much, I mean, even all the time we spent on the film, it's, I still haven't looked at it at all, but they basically detail the experiments going on, which were, you know, your classic ESP stuff, you know, like the cards, all that.
But no, they were doing like what would exactly the definition of like remote viewing.
And so, yeah, I think they were, they, you know, intelligence community, so forth, were, were just very intrigued with what was going on there.
So it's a combination of kind of, you know, these military factions and then these kind of blue blooded elites.
Yeah.
Sort of.
And, um, what exactly is going on there?
So who is he recruiting to do these experiments and what sort of experiments is he running at the round table foundation?
So, I want to take a moment to thank one of today's sponsors, Z-Biotics.
I've been using their pre-alcohol product for years.
And when the opportunity came up to work with them, I jumped at it because it's one of the few things I actually drink before a night out with friends when it's time to celebrate a special event.
And that little decision I make before I go out changes everything.
Z-Biotics pre-alcohol probiotic drink is the world's first genetically engineered probiotic.
It was invented by PhD scientists to specifically tackle rough mornings after drinking.
Here's how it works.
When you drink, alcohol gets converted into a toxic byproduct in the gut.
It's a buildup of this byproduct, not dehydration, that's to blame for the rough days after drinking.
Pre-alcohol produces an enzyme to break this byproduct down.
Just remember to make pre-alcohol your first drink of the night, of course drink responsibly, and you'll feel your best tomorrow.
I have Z-Biotics before my first drink of the night, and I wake up feeling totally normal the next morning.
As you'll know, if you're older than, say, the age of 28 or 29, is not usual.
So go to zbiotics.com slash jessie to learn more and get 15% off your first order when you use jessie at checkout.
Z-Biotics is also backed with a 100% money-back guarantee.
So if you're unsatisfied for any reason, they'll refund your money.
No questions asked.
Remember to head to zbiotics.com slash jessie and use the code jessie at checkout for 15% off.
What exactly is going on there?
So who is he recruiting to do these experiments, and what sort of experiments is he running at the Roundtable Foundation?
So, again, it started with a lot of just basic ESP stuff.
You know, can somebody pick up on what's written on a letter in the other room?
A lot of, yeah, like the card guessing.
And then he obviously built a Faraday cage there, and I think, you know, was one of the first people, as far as I understand, doing ESP tests in a Faraday cage.
Where basically he would, like, put people who claimed to be psychic in the cage, and it was his belief that that could sort of, you know, block out anything from the outside, and it would really help the psychic focus and be able to do what they could do.
And he had, I mean, Aldous Huxley would go to the Roundtable Foundation, right?
And obviously Aldous Huxley is known probably best for a lot of his science fiction work, but also, you know, the Doors of Perception, where he talks about his experience with Mescaline.
And then, you know, if you really get into the maybe deeper kind of architectures of his thinking, like in perennial philosophy, he's like clearly this kind of deep esotericist.
And so he was hanging out at the Roundtable Foundation, too.
Yeah, they were good friends.
In fact, on Buharic's book, The Sacred Mushroom, which is how I got into this whole thing, I had read that book when I was much younger, and I was really interested in all that stuff.
And, you know, what's the book?
DMT, The Spirit Molecule.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, I was really into that, and I came across The Sacred Mushroom, Buharic's book, which is very interesting.
Have you read that?
DMT I haven't read it.
DMT I think I have it, but I haven't read it, yeah.
DMT The premise is basically, you know, and this was also the research he was doing at the Roundtable, was, you know, taking a certain type of mushroom, in this instance, the Amanita muscaria, you know, gives people ESP abilities, and they did extensive research on that there.
DMT But on the cover of that book, you know, Aldous Huxley gives a blurb for Buharic and calls him, you know, the greatest mind in parapsychology.
But yeah, they were good friends.
He was there all the time.
Again, very interested in what he was doing.
Really thought Buharic was, like, on to something.
Yeah.
DMT Yeah, and the Amanita muscaria mushroom is a very interesting mushroom.
It's the kind of archetypal, you know, emoji on all of our, you know, cell phones, or iPhones, at least.
DMT But it also, I believe, John Marco Allegro, who was a, you know, a scholar of various, you know, ancient languages, he came to the very heretical conclusion that the Eucharist itself was an Amanita muscaria mushroom.
DMT And so the actual transubstantiation involved this, like, mushroom, and that maybe what Jesus underwent was some sort of kind of pagan mystery ritual that allowed him to sort of gain the magical powers that he achieved in the book of Acts, and that that whole thing had some kind of hermetic meaning that, you know, isn't just maybe a literal reincarnation or something.
DMT Yeah, yeah.
DMT And so that, I assume that must have, because I think his, the name of his book is similar. It's the sacred mushroom in the cross or something.
DMT Yeah, yeah, it is.
DMT So was there maybe some influence there with Buharic?
DMT I'm sure there was. You know, from what I understand, when Buharic's book came out, it was, you know, it's now sort of like a cult classic, but at the time it was like, you know, controversial, because basically people just didn't believe in what he was writing.
DMT Yeah.
DMT And that, I think, kind of kick-started the, you know, way people looked at Buharic as being, you know, kind of like a kook.
DMT Yeah, yeah, yeah.
DMT But he clearly wasn't.
DMT Clearly, but he was, he also was amongst, he was kind of a pioneer and had a few peers who were also at the forefront of their fields.
DMT People like Albert Hoffman, Karl Ruck, and Stanislav Grof, who thought of themselves as creating what they called the new Eleusis, based on kind of, you know, past mystery rituals, the Eleusinian mystery rituals.
DMT Yeah.
DMT And they involved Urgod and psychedelic substances and, you know, these sort of, you know, Persephone's quest style. You know, you go down, you descend to the underworld and you come back up.
DMT You know, you gain knowledge of your primordial soul. And so, Buharic was, you know, he was amidst this backdrop. He was, he was sort of on his, on his come up, which, you know, maybe isn't a coincidence.
Buharic We are the positive principles of cosmos. We penetrate, visit persons. We work through this body, but it is under our control.
DMT The very first time that Unde heard about the Nine was through Dr. Vinod.
DMT I've never seen people like this that I've studied, Dr. Vinod, had become a channel for a civilization somewhere out there from outer space. It's so alien to our thinking, we can't even comprehend it.
DMT They call themselves these beings, the Nine. What is the Nine? They said, well, it's hard to explain to you. We're not personalities, as you think of personalities. We're more like laws or principles of the universe.
DMT The part of Buharic's story where I think things sort of change in his life is when, you know, this instance happens when they first channel the Nine.
DMT Which was in 52. And it is correct. All these people were there. Again, these were people who were like benefactors, who were interested in what he was doing.
DMT But it all started with this guy, Vinod. You may have heard this name. He was an Indian psychic. He came to the round table again through recommendation of somebody Buharic was working with.
DMT And the story goes, he shows up in Maine, goes to the round table foundation. And the first night he's there, he just unexpectedly falls into a trance. And, you know, they're like, what's going on here? Someone grabs a tape recorder, which we have the tapes of.
DMT And he goes into a trance and he just starts speaking, you know, saying, you know, we are the nine and where we're coming through to you now and just kind of on and on and on about a lot of philosophical new age sort of stuff, basically.
DMT I mean, it's really, really, it's a lot. I mean, there's thousands of pages, literally, of transcripts of what they recorded with him. But that's how the story goes of how the nine first appear as basically this guy, Vinod.
DMT But mostly Vinod. So the interesting thing about this guy, Dr. Vinod was his name. He was friends with Gandhi, right? They were really close. So this was something I learned like way later into the process of the film. Because, you know, this was, as you know, it took like almost 10 years. And it was mostly because these new facts and things would just like come up that I never knew. Or somebody would say, hey, have you seen this?
DMT And so Vinod, like I only really discovered a couple years into it, but he was an interesting guy. And he was on a tour at the time in the United States, going to like rotary clubs and dinner parties, like lecturing about theosophy and spiritualism and all sorts of stuff like that. And it is very, very little information on this guy. I mean, we tried to dig up like everything we possibly could.
DMT But that's what we know about him. He was a professor at a university in Bombay. And again, with Buharic, like he never mentions any of that. His version of the story is this guy, they just randomly came in, fell into a trance, no context, you know, never mentions it.
DMT So that begins this like, okay, what's really going on here? Because he clearly has a background that's interesting that he just never mentioned. And then when Vinod leaves, eventually, I think 54, he goes back, and it never talks about him again. You know, there's this huge moment in his life, the nine first comes through, through this guy, and he just sort of like, never talks about it.
DMT I think that's where the conspiracy starts, as far as what people believe to be like, I guess, a psyop. I mean, we don't have to get into that now.
DMT No, I want to get into the psyop elements of it. But it sounds like fundamentally, he's a believer in extrasensory perception, psychic abilities, right?
DMT He's not cynical about those things, or is it Buharic?
DMT No, yeah, that's, I think, a big question. And even now, I always think, but I mean, yeah, there's just no question he was interested in that.
DMT Yeah, and earnestly, or do you think it was some front?
DMT Oh, earnestly, yeah.
DMT Oh, for sure.
DMT Because, and we'll get into this in a little bit, but there are also possible prosaic explanations around exotic electromagnetic wavelengths that can cause, you know, thoughts to be implanted in people.
DMT And stuff, which is nuts. But I think he wouldn't reduce everything to that, would be my rough understanding personally.
DMT No, no, no. No, definitely not. Yeah, there's a lot to get into there. But basically, so what did the nines say?
DMT Yes.
DMT And so, again, it's really, it's a lot. So I have to give a shout out to Dick Russell.
DMT Yeah, I do.
DMT So he's awesome.
DMT Great guy.
DMT And he's written some amazing books. And so he was friends with this woman, Marianne Schennefield, this, you know, allegedly amazing psychic. She passed away, but I got to know Dick. And he said, you know, I met Buharich once. In fact, I tape recorded an interview with him. It was 94, literally the year before Buharich died slash was found dead mysteriously. But he recorded an interview with him.
DMT Because at the time, Dick Russell was wanting to write like a definitive book about MK Ultra. And he wanted to interview these people involved in it. In fact, he has one of the only interviews, as far as I know, with Sidney Gottlieb. He spent a whole day with him. He literally told me to show it up at his house and said, hey, you know, yes or no, will you let me interview you? And he said yes. And so he has that. So that this was part of that research he was doing for a book.
DMT Just for the audience real quick, because I know we're getting into what the Nine said. But Sidney Gottlieb was known as the kind of U.S. version of Joseph Mingle, a poisoner in chief, an architect of MK Ultra from the technical staff services. So that's wild. Dick Russell spent a whole day with him.
DMT So what are the Nine saying?
DMT So yeah, it's a lot of the sort of usual, I guess, channeling talk where there's this idea that there's been this surveillance of Earth and that they've been monitoring Earth and they've been seeing the negative things happening.
DMT They've been seeing wars, they've been seeing nuclear weapons, and they're wanting to help, basically. The general message is this idea that they are wanting to help the human race, you know, basically not destroy itself.
DMT This, you know, goes on way through the 70s when Buharich, the Nine, come back. But it was basically a lot of, yeah, trying to help humanity. It was a lot of, like…
DMT You've probably heard a lot about how they, sometimes these channelers are, you know, what is it called, like remote writing when someone's in a trance?
DMT Automatic writing.
DMT Yeah, automatic writing. There was a lot of, like, very complex equations that would come through that would, the Nine, meaning Vinod in a trance, speaking as the Nine. A lot of, like, write this down because you'll understand later what it means sort of stuff.
DMT And we have this notebook that he wrote everything in. It's really, I mean, maybe, I'm sure you might know somebody who could look at this. I mean, I'm just making the film. I mean, I'm very…
DMT Well, we should see if any of it checks with actual science or math or…
DMT Oh, it's crazy. They would say, the Nine, they would say, you know, okay, look, you're contacting us through a psychic.
DMT But if you want a clearer feed, a clearer transmission, you have to put the psychic in a Faraday cage. And on top of that, you should tweak the Faraday cage and build it this way and use this type of metal and use this type. They were telling him and constructing him how to, like, build the Faraday cage in a specific way that would, like, help this transmission.
DMT Whoa.
DMT Because you can hear the tapes. It was a lot, it was very, like, stalled speech and waiting. And then when they did the Faraday cage sessions, it was, like, just boom, they would talk. So, I heard that and I was like, okay, well, that's weird, you know?
DMT So crazy.
DMT Because, like, again, there's a lot of it that you could just say, oh, you know, this could have been made up or whatever. But when it gets to that, it was very, very specific stuff. You know, copper, they were big on copper. You need to use that.
DMT And it needs to be, you know, these dimensions. I mean, really specific stuff. And they would follow it. So, they were basically, like, following instructions from the nine.
DMT And you see the results get better as far as their channeling.
DMT You see the results get better. And that, again, to me, I just thought, that's interesting. Because it's not just sort of, like, you know, spiritual mumbo-jumbo stuff.
DMT Hand-wavy stuff that's, like, totally unfalsifiable.
DMT It's, like, literally, like, the transmissions are coming. When you say that it's getting better, it's just, like, more gets channeled, like, more substance.
DMT Yeah, more information clearer.
DMT Yeah.
DMT Just sort of more precise. And the other thing, too, was, again, it was this thing with copper where they would also say, okay, what you need to do is you need to get the—this is really crazy because of what happens later on in his story.
DMT But they would say, you know, you need to have copper touching your skin. And so, you would need some sort of, like, bracelet or something that would kind of, like, constantly be touching your skin in order, again, for, like, the transmission to be better. And they would do that.
DMT Whoa.
DMT And what's crazy is one of the space kids that I met and that we interviewed for the film, she whipped out this—this was, you know, only a couple years ago.
DMT She whipped out this bracelet she had that was, like, a copper—a little copper plate on this bracelet that she said, like, they all had to wear when they were doing their channeling sessions with him decades later.
DMT So the copper thing is strange. And Puharic obsessed over that. And that's the other thing. To me, you know, being a little skeptical, I was like, well, someone of Puharic's, you know, academic abilities, like, clearly, he wouldn't take the time
DMT And the energy, like, to look into this stuff as deep as he did, you know, like, he, like, obsessed over this. He would go meet other academics, hey, does this check out? And, you know, he really, like, was obsessive about this being legitimate.
DMT And Phyllis Schlamer, who later wrote The Only Planet of Choice, which channels the Nine, I think she talks about the Nine with respect to messages around the Earth being a bottleneck of consciousness, right?
DMT And like, other planets being more ascended, and these Nine really trying to help raise consciousness on Earth, which might sort of sound like a cliche, but—
DMT Yeah. One thing that they were doing at the roundtable was that this psychic, this one particular psychic, would claim that at a certain time of night, they would see an orb, and they would go outside by the ocean, and they would see
DMT Orbs. And this happened, and the only, you know, evidence I have is Buharic's own writing, because we have all of his journals, and he writes this in his journals, where he literally says, like, this psychic would just blurt out, you know, 11 o'clock, you know, tonight, and they'd go out, and they would see an orb.
DMT Whoa.
DMT And I just thought that was interesting, because there's so much talk of this orb stuff going on currently.
DMT I don't know a whole lot about it, but I just—that kind of rang a bell where I'm like, oh yeah, he wrote about that. And he did many experiments where he allegedly took photos, which of course, you know, weren't in the big stash of photos we had from back then, but he—that's what he claimed, that there was like orb activity.
DMT Whoa.
DMT This would have been, you know, early 50s again. Yeah.
DMT So trippy. Yeah, no, that almost sounds like Chris Bledsoe or something, these people who seem to attract these orbs. And it would make sense, because those people also seem to be sort of high psi, or, you know, you know, have higher kind of mind-matter capabilities, or whatever. There's some—seems like there's some sort of correlation there.
DMT The connection Lavenda makes is that all these people conducting the seance, bringing in these nine, maybe extraterrestrial beings, maybe beings that go to the nine Egyptian gods or whatever.
DMT Yeah.
DMT We don't exactly know what these nine beings are, but it's like a council. And later, the nine plays prominently, because this channeler, Phyllis Schlamer, like, gets all these messages from the nine, along with a lot of the kids and stuff.
DMT But that all of the people in this original seance with these blue-blooded elites are also entangled with the JFK assassination, which is so crazy.
DMT To make a long story short, there's a seance that's held in late 52, early 53. I think it was the New Year's Eve of 52 to 53. And there are nine people involved in the seance. Now, these are not just some casual nine people you pick up, like, you know, your neighbors or something, right?
DMT This was a DuPont and an Astor and a Forbes. I mean, everybody that represents the blue-blooded Brahmins of American society, old money people, were at a seance, a freaking seance, right?
DMT In the woods in Maine on New Year's Eve with Andrea Paharic. And one of them is the guy who was the inventor of the Bell helicopter, right?
DMT Is that Arthur Young?
DMT Arthur Young. So Arthur Young is there with his wife. His wife is Ruth Forbes Payne Young, right? She had a lot of names. She was excessively nomenclatured.
DMT And so you have, you know, Ruth Forbes Payne Young. She's a Forbes. She was married to a George Payne, Lyman Payne, and also married to Arthur Young.
DMT So in that seance with the, you know, these kind of blue-blooded elites that Paharic is convening, I think one of the people who's close with Mary Bancroft, who's Dulles' mistress, is a woman named Ruth Forbes Payne.
DMT Yeah, Ruth Forbes Payne.
DMT And so she's a Forbes first, so again, go into the blue-blooded elite thing. But I think her daughter is Ruth Payne, who takes in Lee Harvey Oswald.
DMT I know.
DMT And Lee Harvey Oswald is living with Ruth Payne, and I think gets a job at the Texas Book Depository in Texas, in Dallas, through Ruth Payne.
DMT And then ends up, you know, maybe not being the lone gunman, but, you know, attempting JFK's life.
DMT And in her home, she opens her door to some refugees, you know, people who are recent immigrants from Russia. Lee Harvey Oswald and his wife, Marina.
DMT And their kids.
DMT Whoa.
DMT So they're living with Ruth Payne in this house in Texas.
DMT She gets him the job at the Texas School Book Depository.
DMT And so it's these weird entanglements where, and the nine believed themselves to be sort of agents, or sorry, the group in the seance believed themselves to be,
DMT To be agents of these extraterrestrials, right, like to be acting on their behalf.
DMT And so, like, and I know Puharich would stop at airports and try and meditate because he thought he would be bringing about world peace and that the nine would speak to him through his watch and stuff.
DMT Yeah.
DMT And so I wonder sometimes, was it all good or was it bad?
DMT I mean, I don't think, you know, the assassination of JFK was good.
DMT He seemed like a great man who was resisting really dark forces.
DMT Yeah, yeah.
DMT So it's a strange story.
DMT Oh, I just want to hear something really strange about that.
DMT Oh, yeah.
DMT So.
DMT Legend has it that in 1943, the Navy tried to teleport a ship in what's now known as the Philadelphia Experiment.
DMT And it kind of worked.
DMT It disappeared, reappeared, and then half the crew got atomically fused into the ship's walls.
DMT Others just vanished.
DMT No one was where they were supposed to be.
DMT Talk about a breakdown in communication.
DMT And you know who was leading the whole project?
DMT My favorite, the mid-century anti-gravity inventor, Thomas Townsend Brown, who literally
had a nervous breakdown that year due to the very poor communication among the team members.
DMT You know what that sounds like?
DMT Your team.
DMT Before you had Quo.
DMT This year, upgrade your system to a workspace that keeps your team from shattering across dimensions.
DMT If you've ever tried to schedule a meeting across five time zones and six platforms, you know the absolute horror of losing people to the ether.
DMT That's why today's episode is brought to you by Quo, spelled Q-U-O, the smarter way to run your business communications.
DMT It's a single streamlined command center for calls, notes, transcripts, chats, even AI summaries.
DMT An all-in-one shared reality, yours.
DMT No vanishing, no fusing into calendars.
DMT Just your team, fully entangled and synced across time zones, timelines, even caffeine levels.
DMT Make this the year where no opportunity and no customer slips away.
DMT Try Quo for free, plus get 20% off your first six months when you go to Quo.com slash Jesse.
DMT That's Q-U-O dot com slash Jesse.
Quo.
DMT No missed calls, no missed customers.
DMT Now back to the show.
DMT I want to hear something really strange about that.
DMT Oh, yeah.
DMT That's why you're here.
DMT This woman who I got to know very well, who's in the film, she was Puharic's assistant for many years.
DMT And starting in, I think, 63, basically, she worked with him, I think, until like the mid-80s.
DMT And she's amazing.
DMT She's from Hawaii, very nice woman, but she met him in New York.
DMT She was a student at NYU, and Puharic was working.
DMT This is a whole other thing to get into, but he had started his company there called Intellectron Corporation.
DMT But she started as sort of an intern at this company, Intellectron, which was basically a biomedical research company.
DMT We can get into that.
DMT But basically, she told me a story that she was working at Intellectron the day JFK was assassinated,
DMT And that these men in suits, she says, came into the offices, went into Puharic's office, said something to him that seemed very serious, and they left.
DMT And she said the whole rest of the day, Puharic was out of sorts.
DMT What?
DMT This could be as simple as, you know, how horrible that the president was shot, or it could have been something else.
DMT But she was very specific to say, I remember this happening.
DMT It was very strange, but to finish the nine thing, basically, in the fifth, the roundtable ends in 57, I think, right?
DMT Meaning they, for whatever reason, I mean, I think I know the reason, basically, he moved on to Intellectron, which I can talk about.
DMT But he, you know, he claims that we ran out of funding, the benefactors lost interest, and it shut down.
DMT But all the while, he was getting money from the army.
DMT I mean, there's records of that.
DMT But so the nine stopped, allegedly.
DMT And I think Lavenda, I think, talks about this, but a lot of the early nine-related conspiracies start around that time, too, with this idea that it was a PSYOP, or that it was this early psychological warfare experiment, where can we get, you know, certain groups of people to believe in something?
DMT And to what extent?
DMT And a lot of people think that that was, like, the nine.
DMT They think that's all it was.
DMT They think any sort of, like, real channeling or anything is just, you know, is fake.
DMT And that it was all set up as this sort of psychological warfare experiment, which, you know, there's reasons to think that that could be true.
DMT But that's where a lot of that, you know, starts.
DMT You know, I think that's possible.
DMT But you think about, like, when did MKUltra start?
DMT It was probably, there was probably stuff going on before 52, but really the Korean War is, like, when, you know, conventionally it's dated to.
DMT And the idea that they were that sophisticated at the very start of MKUltra, where they could convince these sort of elite members of society that they were in touch with these specific extraterrestrial beings, and that those extraterrestrial beings were constructing Faraday chambers that were able to, like, make the messages they received more effective.
DMT Like, like, this elaborate sort of magic trick, that seems a little beyond the pale to me.
DMT It's a big mystery.
DMT I mean, even, like, I'll admit it, the years and years I researched, I mean, even I don't know, like, a lot of people I talk to who are interested in this stuff and know about the film and so forth, like, they think that I know all the answers.
DMT And like, I even, I wish I did.
DMT And it's not like I'm hiding something because I'm worried that, you know,
DMT I'm going to be a monitor.
DMT I just don't, you know?
DMT Yeah, yeah, yeah.
DMT I know what was in the archives.
DMT And a lot of the film, for me, was like, okay, what, what do we know?
DMT What is a fact?
DMT And let's, like, work off that.
DMT Yeah.
DMT And so it was really just like, okay, here's the transcripts, here's what they were saying.
DMT Speaking of what are the facts, we have to get back to this Intellectron thing.
DMT Yeah, yeah, yeah.
DMT Like, so you're, is the implication of this story that this company had something to do with the assassination of JFK?
DMT Or like, were these men in tweed suits raiding the office, the CIA?
DMT And were they, they thinking that Intellectron had something to do with this or?
DMT So, so Puharich, yeah, he leaves the round table, he moves to New York City, or he moves to Ossining.
DMT A lot of people know this in relation to Puharich because he lived there most of his life.
DMT Upstate New York.
DMT Yeah, it's, you know, an hour on the train north of the city.
DMT You know, Mad Men, of course, the show?
DMT Yeah.
DMT Like, I didn't even realize all the characters, they all live in Ossining.
DMT Like, Don, I guess there's, I remember watching it, but there's some reference, like, they live in Ossining.
DMT So it's a very, you know, wealthy area.
DMT And all of a sudden, Puharich has what's considered like a mansion there, basically, a huge house.
DMT He moves there, he tells his family that basically he just got this contract to study basically more of what was going on at the round table foundation.
DMT But there were specific people who needed him to move to New York.
DMT So they moved there.
DMT I mean, his family life is a whole different thing.
DMT He had, his wife sadly committed suicide around this time.
DMT Really?
DMT Yeah, he was very, like, you know, distraught about that.
DMT What happened?
DMT I received a grim call from Ginny's father.
DMT Jenny had quietly leapt from the hospital roof into eternity.
DMT I wept for Ginny.
DMT I wept for my failure to keep her healthy and happy.
DMT I wept for our three daughters who would never know a normal upbringing.
DMT I cried out to God in crushing despair.
DMT But so they move to New York.
DMT He starts this company called Intellectron.
DMT He gets a Annie Jacobson helped figure this out.
DMT He gets a grant for $300,000, which at the time would have been like at least a million dollars or more from the Atomic Energy Commission, which is strange.
DMT And we have all the documents that we found that prove that they went and visited him.
DMT They gave him this grant.
DMT So he starts this thing, Intellectron, which is basically labeled as a biomedical research company.
DMT So they have an office in Hell's Kitchen.
DMT And again with Puharic, I just, it's, it's, I have to, to stress like there is always these instances in his life.
DMT This one being the, the really the first, but it was sort of the round table too, where like all of a sudden he just has this company.
DMT And this, and the, and these employees and this fund, you know, all of a sudden it's just, you know, kind of expensive to have a big office in New York City and all this, and all this state of the art at the time, electronic equipment.
DMT Well, it sounds like in classic intelligence world front sort of stuff.
DMT Well, I'll get to that.
DMT How does Epstein have a huge hedge fund?
DMT Oh yeah.
DMT He just always had, and it's always this company.
DMT Yeah.
DMT And basically in, this was early sixties now, 62, 63.
DMT This is when he starts the, the hearing experiments where basically he claims that deaf people would come into the office and they would do research on them.
DMT And basically they designed a, a device which would enable deaf people to, to, to hear basically by emitting a certain frequency that would somehow bypass like the, the normal way we hear and go directly to the hearing center in the brain.
DMT And it was this breakthrough medical discovery, which, you know, go figure goes completely quiet.
DMT No one, no one ever hears about it.
DMT Yeah.
DMT But that's when he first starts this whole, you know, radio frequency stuff, voices in the head kind of stuff, which again was under this, you know, we're researching on deaf people.
DMT We're, we're doing this, you know, in a medical sense, we're helping people, but that's when these, you know, men in suits show up.
DMT That's when once again, he's getting contracts from, uh, Navy, uh, CIA, again, almost everyone that was involved at the round table was back in this intellectron situation with him.
DMT And so that, I think the connection, I mean, I don't want to just jump to conclusions, but I think what I've often thought with this JFK thing and why to Melanie is assisted and seemed like such a big deal is that.
DMT It may have had some tie in with a mind control, sort of like a Sirhan Sirhan situation with Lee Harvey Oz.
DMT I mean, I know that's like a pretty crazy, bold claim, but that's, that's just what I've thought.
DMT It's not that.
DMT Because, um, yeah.
DMT They were doing that.
DMT This is, we're talking, and again, this is something I don't think a lot of people know.
DMT And I think people don't realize a lot of that MKUltra stuff happened much earlier, but they were doing this work in 62, 63 of like send basically sending messages to, to people's heads, you know, and, and we have footage we have.
DMT We have, I mean, it's, it's real.
DMT The people from the Atomic Energy Commission write very clearly in letters we found.
DMT Like we went, Annie Jacobson talks about it, I think in her book, like one of the guys is like, I don't believe you, you know, test me.
DMT And just, and, and, and did the test on himself and it worked.
DMT And then it goes, it goes dark.
DMT And Intellectron closes.
DMT And all of a sudden it's on to the next sort of, you know, mysterious company.
DMT Deep Black program or yeah.
DMT Some other front company.
DMT Yeah.
DMT That's really, really trippy.
DMT Is there any explicit connection between Lee Harvey Oswald and Intellectron or that sort of speculation on your part?
DMT I haven't looked, but I just think, you know, if you want to go there, it's like, like Lavenda says the whole connection there at the round table.
DMT And then this weird incident where they seem to make a big deal about telling him about the assassination at that exact time, that exact year, they're researching ways to, to be able to send messages to someone's mind to do something specific, Manchurian candidate, et cetera, et cetera.
DMT Apparently Dulles did not want the fact that Ruth Payne had actually been at the summer house or whatever.
DMT I think that summer, right before JFK was assassinated, he did not want, you know, that at all on record.
DMT I think Mary Bancroft like started to talk about it and he like, you know, he kind of acted like he didn't know what was going on when like, you know, he would have reacted earnestly if he hadn't, he clearly did know what was going on.
DMT And obviously Dulles was probably, you know, among a very short list of people, if you, you know, if you, the intersection of capabilities, motivation to, to take out JFK, Dulles has to be on anybody's short list.
DMT Yeah.
DMT And then to further kind of steel man there, maybe being a, a there, there, we know that Jack Ruby was an MKUltra patient.
DMT I mean, like 95%, you know, like you have letters between Jolly West and Sidney Gottlieb, who's definitely the kind of architect of MKUltra, you know, and, and Jolly West was, you know, UCLA psychiatry, but clearly very involved in Operation Midnight Climax.
DMT Yeah.
DMT And maybe brainwashed Charles Manson.
DMT And he sees Jack Ruby, who never remembers killing Lee Harvey Oswald in his jail cell alone, no cameras comes back, comes out and says, uh, Jack Ruby has had a psychiatric break.
DMT And then Jack Ruby, you know, who was fully lucid, but just didn't remember having shot Lee Harvey Oswald talks about Jews dying outside of his cell and just like literally cracks.
DMT So very, very strange, you know, possible connections.
DMT Well, the other really strange thing at this time, um, was that Pujaric is working with someone named Jose Delgado, who he probably might know who that is.
DMT Delgado, an old friend of mine, brilliant researcher from Spain, implanted radio receivers in the heads of bulls.
DMT Delgado has remote control of the animal.
DMT Do you realize the fantastic possibilities if from the outside we could modify the inside? Could we give messages to the inside?
DMT He was a guy from Spain. He was a researcher. He was involved with a lot of this sort of mind stuff in the 60s, late 50s, 60s.
DMT But I think he's mostly known as somebody who did experiments with implanting, putting an implant in the head of a bull and basically being able to remote control a bull and basically say, go this, stop, go left, go right.
DMT He was able to do it. There's literally footage of, of the experiment happening.
DMT And Pujaric, we later found out was, was close friends as Pujaric says himself with Delgado.
DMT We found letters between the two of them during this time.
DMT And it was nothing too sinister. It was mostly like, hey, I'm going to go to this conference. Are you going to be there?
DMT But they clearly were close. I mean, there's some people I met during the process of this who were like, don't, don't even go there. And don't talk about the connection you had with Delgado. But, you know, I was interested to-
DMT No, it's fascinating. You have a guy who's being able to pacify a bull and play the bull like a video game. And that clearly was the heir to MKUltra, which was mostly sodium pentothal, LSD, that sort of thing. It's chemical based.
DMT If in the early 60s, we had chips that could control animals, and you had heirs to MKUltra, like MKUltra, which were done, I believe at the Science and Engineering Institute in the Northeast as well.
DMT Yeah.
DMT It's like, well, of course, you know, we're going to be way more advanced on that stuff now. It's, it's creepy to think about. It's one of those things you don't even want to think about it.
DMT Because the second you do think about it, you get into reality being far weirder than we could ever imagine.
DMT So yeah, if you think, okay, they're putting an implant in the head of a bull, like you say, basically remote controlling the thing. Why wouldn't you try to do that to a human being? I mean, why wouldn't you? And I think that was going on at Intellectron. I mean, I'm sure of it.
DMT Because there's this way too many, there's way too many connections. I don't have a document that says, here's the experiment we did. But that whole decade of the 60s was such a odd decade for Buharachi was so like, quiet. Like all there's all these records of the roundtable, you know, tapes, photos, everything.
DMT And all of a sudden, you get to the 60s. It's like nothing really, very little documentation, very little, you know, photographic evidence of what he was up to. And all of a sudden, the 70s, boom, picks back up. There's 100 photos. So it's very mysterious decade. And it was just, it just so happened to be when he had this company in Electron.
DMT Yeah.
DMT With these very odd connections, Delgado.
DMT I think it's becoming super clear that.
DMT And the other thing too, not to cut you off is I, I've,
with all this stuff in this film, I've gone to like the ends of the earth to try to track down
nothing, absolutely nothing. This place never existed in Electron. You would not find,
the only thing I ever found was there was a guy, a pretty interesting guy actually, his name is Beardsley Graham.
He was involved in NASA in the 60s, early 70s, colleague of Buharach's, but he was like,
I guess, he was somehow involved in Intellectron as like an outside consultant or something.
DMT And in his archives at Berkeley, there was like a couple documents that had, you know,
in Electron letterhead and it was like correspondence. And that was like the only thing I could find.
DMT And even in that, it was nothing revealing. It was, again, it was just like records and sort of like,
you know, financial records, which again, didn't point to anything.
DMT Yeah.
DMT You know, so, so there's just, this place did not exist, but it very much did.
DMT It's so crazy.
DMT It very much did. Well, it's, I mean, now I feel like it's one of these things that's slowly shifting,
you know, and I think more and more people are going to start to recognize the fact that MKUltra
had a role, not only in the JFK assassination, but in the RFK assassination. You mentioned Sirhan Sirhan,
DMT who had written in his diary right before he shot RFK, just like over and over. It was like
some neuro-linguistic programming was coming through him. To this day, does not remember having shot him.
DMT He's like, you know, I must kill him, must kill him, you know, sort of thing.
DMT Yes.
DMT And you have RFK Jr. now who's head of the FDA. He himself has gone deep on his father's death.
DMT I think he was 14 at the time. And I think he recognizes that he was actually shot
from the back and not from the front. So there was this other gunman again, just like JFK.
DMT I think he thinks that, you know, MKUltra was involved, you know, this guy,
William Jennings Bryan, not to be confused with the 1890s, William Jennings Bryan,
DMT Was this kind of mysterious, deep, statey figure who I believe was tight with Sirhan Sirhan.
DMT And so, you know, I think these things are going to start to come out that MKUltra was far
more pervasive than we ever realized. And there's even a book called, I don't know if you know about
this book, The Controllers by Martin Cannon.
DMT Yeah, yeah. He mentions Buharich in that.
DMT So let's, this book is insane. What's the thesis of this book?
DMT As you know, a lot of the guests I sit down with, whether they're physicists,
intelligence officers, people who've worked inside black programs are operating at a really
impressive level mentally. Sometimes I feel like I'm a chimp talking to human beings. Often their
work takes a toll, and a lot of them track their health obsessively. Regular lab work,
obscure biomarkers, often things that most people never look at. Meanwhile, last time I went to a
primary care doctor, they ran maybe like eight biomarkers, and they told me I was fine and sent
me home. This massive difference between the ordinary, broken, and limited healthcare system
and what elite people are doing to track their health got me interested in superpower.
The beautiful thing is they make elite-level healthcare accessible. They'll literally send
a licensed professional to your home or you visit a nearby lab. One simple lab test and you get over
100 biomarkers. Heart, liver, thyroid, hormones, metabolism, vitamin levels, even environmental
toxins. After that, their app builds you a full action plan, supplement suggestions you can buy
directly through them, nutritional guidance, lifestyle adjustments. They even give you your true
biological age and you can track that over time. And it's not just a one-time snapshot. Each test
builds on the last, so you're actually seeing progress instead of starting from zero every year.
Make this the year you stop guessing about your health and you start getting serious with superpower.
Not only did superpower reduce their price to just $199, but for a limited time, our listeners get an
additional $20 off with code ALCHEMY. Head to superpower.com and use code ALCHEMY at checkout for
$20 off your membership. After you sign up, they'll ask you how you heard about them, so please make sure
to mention American Alchemy to support the show.
What's the thesis of this book?
It's basically about this idea of the fabrication of alien abductions, right? That's at least a big
part of it.
Some of them being chip implantations done basically for MKUltra purposes. And people being tricked into
saying, oh, this is your guardian angel or whatever.
Well, there's a whole thing. We can get to that later. But the whole an electron thing,
basically, to cap that off, it was, yeah, one of many of these very, to me, it became very obvious
fronts. I mean, there's just no question about it, you know, that he had. And they were doing all
that type of experimentation. Again, there's footage of them doing an experiment on a woman.
There's no sound, but it's obvious what's happening. You can see, you know, she's in the
other room. She's behind a wall. They're in the other room. He has his device that he invented in
the early 60s called the TD-100, which I've told you about. And this basically enables like a certain
frequency to be sent to somebody. And, you know, it's kind of like a situation where if you're
exposed to this frequency, it's at a certain wavelength that only you can hear and anyone else
around you can't hear. And this kind of ties into what he was doing later in the 70s. But they're
doing an experiment on a woman using this, and it's very clear what's happening. And it's very clear
it's working. This was, this was like Neuralink, basically.
And you could, you could, you could send or implant thoughts to a person.
Yeah.
That's crazy. And so how exactly did it work? You played a tone and then you would.
Well, there's two things. One of the things he invented back then too, which again was Puharic
says himself was classified. And you've probably heard of this as the tooth implant.
A device could be inserted into one of your back molars. That acted as a transducer that
could send signals across the facial nerves into the hearing centers of the brain.
It took about a month of daily therapy. They would have their hearing improved significantly.
It was extraordinary because it was a totally new way of understanding how we hear.
You could send signals to someone secretly. It had a lot of potential.
We gave a demonstration at the Pentagon. We fitted this device to this general.
And we had somebody out in the hall broadcasting. And he said, God damn it, I hear it. God damn it,
I hear it. The bastard did it.
It was basically a radio receiver that would be, uh, I guess at one point it was Puharic kind of
says it, says it as though you could slip on some sort of thing. Like on, like anyone could just kind
of like slip this thing on their tooth. But in other instances, it was very specific about
it being like a, like a real, like cat, what do you call it? A, uh, molar or something that would
really be put on your tooth. And that would basically, uh, be able to receive a radio signal.
It would pick it up here and it would send it through the nerves of the face that would basically
connect to whatever air in your brain, uh, you register, you know, sounds. And so, so you could be
again, and you could, you could clearly see them doing this. And this was very short,
a short distance. Like I said, a woman right across the, the room and you can clearly see
they're, they're, they're able to do it. So you can imagine if the research continued
at what length can this go? Can this be in another town? Can it be in another state? Could it be in
another country? So that's what they were, they were experimenting with. But so the first part of it
was the tooth where you could send the message to the tooth implant, hear it in the head. And the
second part was, uh, an offshoot of that where basically from what I understand, you sort of just
bypass the whole tooth thing. And it's a very specific radio frequency that I guess you can't tune
into like on a normal frequency band or a radio. Do you know what frequency? No, he doesn't talk
about it. That would seem to be extremely classified would be my guess. It's a lot to do
with sine waves. Yeah. I must, I must say again, like I'm, this is not my forte. Like a lot of this
I stumbled into, but it was this idea that again, you would bypass the tooth and the, in the, in the
frequency would essentially just be sent directly to the head and be picked up in that same area that
the tooth was essentially connecting to. Yeah. Just to also substantiate what you're saying to the
audience who might think we're crazy. Uh, I mean, bait as early as Beethoven, he was deaf and he used
something called bone conduction where he would bite onto, uh, a conductive rod while he was playing
piano that would bypass his ear canal and the vibrations would literally play in his brain. And so
he would like de facto be able to hear his own playing without actually kind of, you know, hearing
it through his ear canal. Yeah. So that is a thing. Uh, there's a story of, there's a kind of
apocryphal, but I think substantiated story, um, around Lucille Ball who had just, I've heard about
this. Yeah. It's in the telepathy tapes and she had gotten a tooth filling or whatever, and she's
driving and she starts to hear the radio in her head because she still has some metal in her teeth.
I think there's a story with Puharich where some guy works at a metal mill or something.
Yeah. That was his first, um, aha moment is that they got a mental patient, a guy who claimed he
was hearing voices, but his family's convinced he's, he's, you know, sane and we're worried
because they want to put him in a mental hospital and we don't want that to happen. So, you know,
can you check him out? So they, they bring him in, they get to know him and he, yeah, he says,
okay, I work at this metal factory where I guess it basically is a grinding metal pieces and this
kind of thing. Annie Jacobson talks about it too in her book. Puharich's theory was that this metal dust
had somehow collected on his teeth and in essence acted like a radio antenna. We found out he was tuned
to station W-O-R in New York. And they put the mental patient in their Faraday cage, which blocks out
all electronic signals. And the mental patient suddenly is no longer hearing voices, is like
perfectly sane. And sure enough, soon as we locked the door, the sound ceased. Open the door, the sound
would come on. That's pretty remarkable of Puharich to think that all through and to test it in the
laboratory. And that kicked off like all of this research where it said, okay, well, if that's
possible, like what else is possible with that basic idea that that's, you know, real.
Yeah. And if you can bypass the ear canal with vibration, whatever is processing the audio
ultimately in the brain, we know that you can turn molecular mass into frequency. Everything has a
quote unquote resonant frequency. This sounds woo woo, but what I just said is fact. Could you then use
some sort of electromagnetic, you know, radio wave or some wave that connects directly to the brain and
that kind of gets in a freaky territory because you end up in sort of psychic warfare, you know,
that's ubiquitous or whatever in widespread, like it's kind of weird to think about. But I mean,
if you're saying that was possible back then, it's just wild. And then you mentioned sine waves.
I just interviewed a guy named Dan Sherman. And you texted me when you saw the interview because
you said it, you felt like it kind of comported with a lot of the stuff you had been studying
around Puharich. If Puharich is doing this stuff in the sixties, then it kind of makes me believe
the Sherman stuff a whole lot more, which was happening in the early nineties around messages
he's downloading. But it, maybe it does beget the question, you know, is the Sherman stuff
genuinely, you know, extraterrestrial or were people beaming messages that were extraterrestrial
to test the veracity of the messaging or whatever through him? And I don't know, you know, I don't
know the answer to that question. I don't think he was lying. And I think the program is real.
The genesis of it was in 1947. We came in contact with an alien species and in 1960, they started
a project. It was called Project Preserve Destiny. And it was designed to genetically manage fetuses,
human fetuses, so that they would have the heightened ability to do this particular thing that I was
going to school for. And he said, I'm going to play a tone and I want you to mentally hum that tone.
And he said that you will eventually feel a connection. The line will change. When I saw the
sine wave move, I went, Oh, okay. Well, there's a mental disconnect there that that's not supposed to
be happening. This is not, this is not possible. Yeah. Do you think that it was kind of a development
from, um, you know, what you were looking into with Puhari? I'd have to imagine it was.
And that's always the question, you know, you said there are a lot of sine waves. He literally
says I had to flatten a sine wave. When I saw the, the, the, uh, sine wave move, it, it is like,
it came into focus, this thing that I was doing in my head. That's why I, that's why I reached out
because again, like for me, a lot of this was, okay, I have all this information. I'm not a, you know,
I'm not a physicist. I'm not a, most of this stuff, but I'd have to imagine it's connected
because, um, Puhari, the way this machine worked as well, had something to do with specific
sine waves. Very, very specific, you know, he was always talking about sine waves. And so I just,
I can't imagine that that wasn't some sort of early interpretation of, of what, what he was
talking about. And you have this machine that you like, where you like, you're matching tones and
stuff. I mean, that sounds exactly like. Yeah. It's all tone. It's all tones. And then the thing
with the machine is again, um, and like you said, sounding crazy, like for a long time making this
film, you know, like I had to really grapple with like that a lot because I knew what I was hearing
and, and sort of not so much researching as a lot of stuff we got were like tapes of these experiments.
So it's not just like, I'm reading a report, you're hearing it. So I'm hearing, you know,
these channeling sessions, I'm hearing these experiments, he's doing an electron and, you know,
you can just tell something's going on, something strange. And so you're right. I mean, I think like
if that was happening in 60, 61, 62, I mean, I don't know. And this gets transitions into the
Uri Geller stuff, which I believe is very much involved in that same sort of research. Um, but
how's that? Yeah. Well, I think, um, it's my belief that, uh, Geller was, was sort of like a,
a mind control Guinea pig in a way. Uh, there's a lot of context that would, that would prove that that
was what his sort of role was in this whole story. Well, he, um, so basically Puharic, uh, in the 60s,
we had Intellectron. And the thing is too, with this device, he invented the TD 100, it was called,
which was called transdermal 100. But, um, again, this was supposed to be this breakthrough,
you know, medical device where, where people who are deaf can, can hear, you know, the, the think
about what we could do with this, but it just goes like, again, he never talks about it. No,
no one in his family. Oh yeah. I wonder whatever happened to that. Like you would think that
with such an amazing discovery, like something would have come of it. Or it was just like, went,
went dark, basically probably around 68. Um, he never talks about it again, only way later in his life.
He never, ever talks about it. Of course we learned he was using it with the space kids years later
that nobody knew about that. But, um, so he's the, he's coming off the tail end of all the
Intellectron stuff, right? Right. When he meets Geller, like literally it was 1970 is when he first
hears about Geller goes to Israel. Intellectron is still happening then. I mean, from what I
understand, like it was still very much, you know, an operating company. So he's going to Israel
to meet Uri Geller while he's still very much involved in the research of essentially sending
messages to people. And he gets to Israel, he discovers Uri Geller. I mean, I think a lot of
people know this story, but, you know, Geller was, was allegedly this very, uh, amazing psychic guy
who could bend, bend spoons with his mind and read people's minds and do all sorts of things like
that. He could like, uh, hover his hand over a watch and the, and it would, uh, the hands would
move and, and all these kinds of things. And so do you believe he could actually do those things or
do you think that was stage magic or, um, all I can say about that is he did bend a spoon for us when
we did the interview and I don't know how he did it. Whoa. So that's all I can say. It could have been a
trick. And you, uh, but I can't to this day figure out how he did it. You know, the easy debunks on
things like that. Yeah. Yeah. Okay. Yeah. Yeah. So all I can say is like, yeah, it could have been
a trick, but it was definitely kind of strange and cool and he did do it. But, um, he, so Buharic,
you know, again, the story goes, Buharic was kind of smitten with, with Geller and oh my God,
this guy's, you know, an amazing psychic. I'm in, I'm interested in psychic phenomena. I want to study him.
Um, so he brings him back, but what people don't really know, uh, unless they read Buharic's book
on, on Uri Geller, which is kind of like a rare book to, to come across, but he, uh, has this whole
episode in Israel before he even brings him back to the United States where he basically hypnotizes
Geller and, you know, the nine come through. Really? And all of a sudden after however many years,
you know, 53 from when Dr. Vinod did it to, to 71. And guess what happens? Uh, he starts channeling
the nine, Uri Geller. And so Buharic is, you know, shot up, apparently shocked. And, you know,
I can't believe this is happening. You know, there's all these tape recordings we have of,
of this, uh, going down and that kind of kickstarts again. The whole nine thing comes back into the
picture through, through Uri Geller. And all of a sudden they're like back, you know, and he's
channeling them, channeling them, and he's communicating with them. But it's very strange
because Buharic, as I just said, was still very much involved in the Intellectron company, which
as we know, was experimenting with being able to send voices, send thoughts, uh, to people.
And so one could assume that Uri Geller was a, you know, experiment in that way when the nine
just so happened to reappear all those years later. And it's also strange because I think a lot of
people know, like Geller has claimed his involvement with Mossad and his Israeli intelligence and all
these things. There's reason to believe Buharic may have been a double agent for Israel. In fact,
he says, he's, he says it really tape, but he kind of says it in a jokey way. And so I had always
just stuck to me like, okay, is this a joke? Have you found any connections between him? Uh,
yeah. Yeah. What, what were the connections besides Uri Geller, obviously? Um, well, he,
so we did tons of like FOIA requests, trying to, trying to find stuff on him and like basically
got nothing. But the only thing we were able to get was this big chunk of FBI documents,
which was basically monitoring all of his movements in Israel, literally page after page.
Uh, he just got here, he's leaving, he picked this bag up. He did, you know, in the exact years,
he's, um, he's going there to see Geller so that that there's that. And then, um, multiple people who
knew him, who never really said anything until much later in their lives, um, told me that he,
he was Mossad. Again, I, there's, I don't have a document or something that, that, that proves this.
Um, and then Puharich also mentions in a, uh, letter he was writing to, uh, there's a good friend
of his, this woman who kind of helped him with bookkeeping and stuff. And she was like his closest
confidant. And he would write these letters to her all the time. It was very clear that they were
close. You know, he spoke with her very differently than other people, but he, um, basically admitted
to being part of a Israeli U S, um, mind can, you know, mind control program that was happening at
Aberdeen proving grounds, which isn't, you know, is an R is an army base. And I read that and, you know,
again, what, what do you make of it? It's either true or for some reason he's making it up. I don't
know why. It's fascinating. So, so he wrote that. And then in this tape, um, he, he kind of jokingly
says, Oh, I'm a, I'm a, I'm a double agent, uh, for, for the Israelis. And, and he also was always
there, you know, that's the other thing. Like, yes, he went to, to, to investigate Geller, but you
know, he was even through the eighties, like well after him and Geller kind of parted ways,
he's always going there. Um, on a lot of the channeling tapes that are happening in the seventies
with the space kids, he's, he's referring by name to Israeli generals. This one guy, uh,
Aharon Yariv, who was, I think the head of, uh, army intelligence, very, you can look him up. I mean,
he was constantly, can, should we, uh, give this information to Yariv, always referring to him
and other people, um, high up there. So a lot of red flags, nothing, again, no concrete,
you know, document or something, but, uh, it's strange. And I don't know. I mean, again,
that's something like after all this time, I'm still thinking, okay, what, what was really going
on there? You know, fascinating, man. What do you think when, when he goes to Israel initially to
see Geller in 1971 and he, uh, Geller's kind of channeling the nine again, is it like the nine
are somehow like he has a protocol to like summon these specific nine extraterrestrial beings? Is it
this cynical hypnotic technique that he's doing where he's implanting this idea of nine extraterrestrial
beings or what do you think that is? Is he, is he calling in something that exists in reality,
these nine, you know, entities, or is he creating those entities synthetically?
First of all, just to quickly mention, like this, this idea that Buharach is very, um, there's always
two stories, right? So when he went to Israel for the first time in some lecture, uh, we have,
he said, Oh, you know, there was this parapsychology foundation and they wanted me to go. So they
scraped some money together and I, they, I was able to get a plane ticket and I went to,
I went to Tel Aviv and then that's how I got there. Right. And then Geller himself said, Oh yeah,
no, he, he was sent by the CIA like directly. He, he was consulting for CIA. That's why he came.
And then someone else, uh, close to Buharach said, Oh yeah, like that, he was CIA. That's why he went.
But in this lecture, in fact, twice in two separate lectures, Buharach, when he, he kind of tells the
story to an audience, you know, and he says, Oh yeah, they just, you know, bought me a ticket,
this foundation. So, you know, again, a little thought in my mind where I'm like, okay, who's,
who's telling the truth? You know, I think it's obvious, but, um, right.
But with the nine, I mean, so yeah, it, it all did come from, from, uh, hypnosis. That was the
protocol. It was a very, you know, your typical countdown from a certain number. Um, once you get
there, you know, you're in a state where they can come through. And I do think again, like I mentioned
earlier, kind of having to accept some of these darker parts of the story. Like I do think, uh,
to some extent, like he was implanting this idea because you can, you can, I mean, you can hear
it. I mean, again, this isn't like speculation, like on the tapes, you can very much hear him
saying, you know, is, is it the, not, you know, the, the type of like leading questions. I think
that a lot of people say, Oh, you know, you can't trust a hypnosis if they're doing this. And it was,
it was, it was that it was very leading questions. And are you sure it's not the nine and,
oh, actually, yeah, you're right. It is. And that kind of thing. But what's so confusing
is there's, there's a lot of other sessions he did where it was like, not like that at
all, the complete opposite, you know, not leading at all.
Mm. And the nine would still come through.
Yeah.
So that's interesting.
Yeah. And that always goes back to the crux of Fuharich of like, okay, what, what was he?
Yes. He believed in this stuff, but yes, he was also involved in very, by his own
own and minutes, you know, involved in, in MK ultra and all these things. So it's like, what.
Yeah.
Believer master manipulator. I mean, I, I usually, clearly he was manipulative somewhat.
I usually get to the end of these questions thinking it's like a yes. And like an improv or
whatever. It's, it's usually not like one neat solution kind of explains everything away.
Yeah.
You know, one neat solution that would explain everything away would be, you could think of
the Archimedes lever of reality itself and it's mind control. Right. Like that would explain like
aliens reverse engineer, like so many things. Um, but then you, you get into like the facts and
the facts are just weirder than you think often. And it's, it's like, well, I actually think there
might be these other beings that come in and certain cases, he's not asking leading questions,
but it's a, it's, it's fascinating. He also, he isolates specific, um, extra low frequency
waves that he thinks are particularly powerful as far as implanting thoughts. Is that right?
Yeah. There's, uh, and again, this was interesting because his, uh, research into, you know, ELF,
extremely low frequency, you know, that was much later, like late seventies, eighties,
he was very involved in that. But I figured out like, once again, like this origin point of the
round table foundation, like he was researching this stuff back then, like this very specific,
extremely low frequency that can, he figured out like penetrate the walls of a Faraday cage.
That was like the only, uh, you know, frequency that could do that. You know, they went on to use
that frequency with like submarine experiments. So that he believed was like the frequency that could
carry, you know, audio information to somebody's head. Uh, and he was very concerned that the
Soviets had similar capabilities. Yeah. I mean, there's, you know, project Pandora,
which started in, I think the sixties, which, you know, going back to intellectron,
that was right around the time this was happening, which was, you know, yeah, the same thing. The
Russians had these sort of radio frequency weapons, which, which, you know, they did. I mean,
that's all proven at that time. I mean, this is like pre Havana syndrome stuff. And so coincidentally,
you know, at intellectron, they're doing a lot of that same stuff. I do firmly believe that,
that Geller was some sort of Guinea pig for these experiments because it's, it's just too many weird
red flags around this time that he meets him. And I think, and again, I could be totally wrong,
but I think that there was just this, you know, we need to experiment on a real, you know, human
being with some of this stuff. And again, it goes back to this MK ultra, the, you know, LSD, you know,
giving LSD to unwitting people. Like at a certain point with these kinds of experiments, you need to,
you know, do it on a real person or else you're never going to know how someone in, you know,
the real world will react. And I think Geller, you know, was, was part of something like this,
because there's a lot of experiments they did where, um, there's a story for instance, where
Geller, uh, allegedly, uh, teleported. So he was walking down the street in New York city,
1973, I think he claims he's walked down the street in New York city, gets a weird feeling,
right? All of a sudden he wakes up and he's in Austin, New York, which is, you know, uh, however,
50 miles or whatever. Uh, and, and he crashes through the screen porch. There's footage,
super eight movie footage of, of Puhar filming the screen porch after this allegedly happened.
It's all smashed through. Right. And Geller allegedly winds up in Austin and he teleported
and from New York city and Puharich claims or told Geller, oh yeah, this happened. And the nine did
this basically you, since you were questioning their ability and their power, they said, well,
we're going to do something that will make you, you know, never question us again. And they did this
teleportation. Right. And the weird thing is again, like the length Puharich went to, to actually
get a look, you know, again, people don't remember this was like seventies, like get a load of film,
you know, put it in the, put it in the camera film, get the, get the film transferred and, and be like,
Hey, look, I actually filmed when you, right after you flew into the window and here it is, it's, it's
proof. So, you know, he's, he's, he's doing that, but I, I, that was just one instance of me thinking
like, oh, okay. Like this is a way to get somebody to believe that some crazy event like that really
happened. And Geller believed it. I mean, he, he talks about it. He wrote about it. And I think
later in his life, he, he, he started to question everything and he even came out with a statement
on a radio show in like 2019 saying that Puharich had experimented on him with, with mushrooms and
had experimented extensively with him, uh, uh, with, with hypnosis. But again, like that story
is crazy. And he, and I think it's like, okay, like if you can get somebody to believe that
they had been teleported and smacked, I mean, what else could you get someone to believe?
And I just think it was all part of that type of experimentation and Puharich himself way later
in his life. Like I said, when he starts to kind of reveal things, he says himself, I was involved
in a program and my boss was the guy who did all research with hypnosis and mind manipulation.
And so, you know, he, he was doing it. And I think a lot of the Geller stuff was just like, okay,
we need a Guinea pig here to, to see if some of these wild ideas work, you know?
So wild. I think there's a story too, that Geller tells around him meeting Wernher von Braun and
Wernher von Braun taking him to a safe that contained some UFO artifacts, maybe from Roswell.
Yeah. Well, Wernher von Braun again, was, um, somebody close to Buharich in the sixties
specifically. Really?
Yeah. His assistant, the same one I told you about who made the JFK comment said, yeah, he,
he talked to him, you know, all the time. So that was yet another person who was just kind of part of
his, you know, Rolodex. But yeah, I think Geller said something effective. Yeah. He showed him, um,
some photographs of, um, of yeah, something from Roswell or, or revealed facts to him.
And I think he showed a material and I think he felt like he had to tell about the connection with
the material.
Wernher von Braun takes me into his personal office. There is a safe in the office. He opens the safe.
I see a piece of metal. I've never seen such a color. Pulls it out. It's not heavy. Says,
Uri, touch this. Tell me what you feel now. I put my hand on it and I say, Wernher, this is not from
here. He says, you're right. This is a piece of a UFO that crashed on our planet.
Uh, it's over. It's like he, he knew that it was not from here or something. Like he showed it to
him and he goes, it's not from here. And he goes, how did you know? So, you know, some of the,
it's so interesting.
The other thing too, and this goes back to the, the controllers, um, book, a lot of the stories,
and again, keep in mind, this is all pre coming to the U S going to SRI. Everyone knows that stuff.
This is in, in Tel Aviv before any of that. And he, another story like this teleportation one,
they're in, um, the Sinai desert. They're driving around in, uh, in a Jeep and they're, they see a,
a UFO and Geller all of a sudden, I mean, Puharich's book on Geller is fun to read,
you know, in and of itself is cause it's like, it's just like a cool, crazy sci-fi book.
If anything, even though it's supposed to be, you know, nonfiction, but he claims that this
UFO lands Geller goes into like a trance boards. The, the UFO comes back with like a pen and said,
or something like a pen and basically said, you know, oh, these, these beings told me to keep
this. Cause this will forever be proof that I, I, uh, you know, went on this craft, but the same
thing, it's always like, oh, he's in a trance before this happens, you know, apparently.
And then it's that same idea of like, he believed it and Puharich kind of substantiated. Oh yeah.
You know, we saw it land and we saw you walk on it. And what, but then it always goes to that
question. Like why, again, you could just say, oh, well they wanted to experiment with,
can you get someone to believe in or just kind of framing it around this ET UFO thing,
but it's always like, why, why do this? You know, why, why was he doing this?
Yeah.
Uh, you know, I don't, cause again, there's no concrete proof. Oh, Geller was a guinea pig.
He was, he was a subject, like, I'm just kind of putting the pieces together, but it just seems
to me that it's like, let's take this UFO ET framework and do these kind of mind manipulation
experiments around that and see, you know, see what, what people can believe. And, uh,
you also get in a weird territory where it's like, it does again, the MK ultra thing,
just explain everything, which is like such a dark version of the truth, but it's possible.
We have to entertain that or is MK ultra actually converging on a technique that the, you know,
extraterrestrials or NHI non-human intelligence already has mastery over vis-a-vis its ability
to like manipulate human beings. Like I think of one of the most credible cases for me as a
guy named Mario Woods, um, who is, uh, at Ellsworth air force base in 1977 in South Dakota.
And he was a missile security officer and he's just like a really upright, great guy.
And he, uh, thought, you know, like this sort of like B two bomber was like kind of winking
at him in the distance. He and his, um, uh, you know, um, teammate or whatever his colleague,
Michael Johnson go in this little Jeep and they follow it, uh, they, they get there and it's this
like huge, like plasma orb that's glowing. It's red hot. And it, uh, it's the size of a Walmart is
the, the line he always says. It's sort of this crazy iconic line, you know, and, um, and, uh,
he ends up nine being transported nine miles, um, away from the base, uh, like behind a dam.
And it's like, then it's the next morning. He has no idea what happened. And all, all he,
I think had remembered was beings walking toward him saying, do not fear, do not fear.
And then he gets a hypnotic regression and he realizes that, you know, possibly he boarded a
craft. And what's really interesting is he says that after when he gets sort of, you know,
debriefed, they check his teeth. I think he said that like the guy checking him now said that there
was some sort of ambient radiation in his mouth or something from that time. It's really sort of crazy.
Um, yeah, that is the tooth thing is really strange. And there's a lot online about, um,
there's a story about a, an individual who changed his name in fact, because he didn't want to be
associated with this, but this was, um, so, so post Geller, right. So, so Geller, uh, Lee,
basically they, they kind of split up get Geller wants to, to move on. And again, way later in this
2019 interview, he, he kind of opens up and said that, yeah, I was kind of like afraid, you know,
and he, he, he really opens up, like, I didn't know what was kind of going on. And, and I was
suspicious and I just wanted to get away basically from this guy. And so he, you know, but he was
famous at that time anyways. So he leaves Buharich is, you know, trying to find another subject to
bring through the nine he claims. So this is even pre Phyllis Schlemmer is right around because Phyllis
Schlemmer was sort of the next channel that he, he discovers that, that brings through the nine.
But before Phyllis, there was this guy in Florida where Phyllis was from. She knew this guy.
He was part of a, um, a psychic class that she, she taught. And again, I've heard from a lot of
people that this woman Phyllis was like a legit psychic, you know, knowing things about people
and so forth. But there's this guy that she knew, she introduces him to Buharich. Uh, they do a bunch
of experiments. Yeah. Sure enough. He puts him, he, he hypnotizes him and he is communicating with
not the nine, but it was some other being can't remember the name, but anyways, this guy says,
you know, I got really, really weird vibes, you know, et cetera. But lo and behold, he wakes up
one day and realizes he has a, uh, metal filling that he never had. And he goes to the dentist
and says, you know, well, what's going on here? I, I didn't get this done. And they,
they looked at it and said, yeah, this was done. Um, you know, professionally, there's no question
about it. And, oh, complete side note. The guy that Buharich ran Intellectron with was a dentist
that he met in the army. So this guy discovers a, a, um, uh, a filling he never had. He completely
freaks out and, and leaves the, the group that is Buharich Phyllis. And, and it's sad. And again,
this always comes back to this, like not avoiding the, the negative stuff. Like apparently the guy
went like, you know, crazy. He, he just had like a mental breakdown. There's a couple other people in
the, the sphere of this story that this happened to, but that's like a real story and the guide,
you know, and he brought it up to Buharich and they said, oh, you know, we don't know what you're
talking about. We, this, we weren't involved with this, or I think, you know, actually,
I think what they said was, oh, you know, this was done by the, the beings, your talk,
they wanted this to happen and they, they did this somehow. And, and so it's very bizarre,
you know. But that goes back to the, I mean, what you just told me is crazy because this was
early seventies. So there might be something going on with this, this tooth thing. And,
you know, again, I think the film does a good job of this, or I hope it does is, is, you know,
I don't believe, or, and especially don't want to believe that MK Ultra is responsible
for everything and all of this stuff. Cause there's a couple of stories in Buharich's life
that, you know, do seem like legitimate sort of extraordinary encounters. For instance,
in the late eighties, Buharich lived in North Carolina and he, there's a story that a bunch
of his family was visiting, a bunch of his cousins and people who, you know, are very skeptical about
all of this stuff, skeptical of Buharich's whole world, but some psychic that, that night
or that day said later tonight, you know, I just got a message that like a UFO
is going to show itself over the house. And so we have the video, Buharich's son, Andy,
who's an awesome guy. He, he did this kind of like funny video where he interviewed like all the people
who were there at the, at this family gathering and say, you know, what do you think is going to happen?
Do you think it's going to show up? And everyone said, oh yes or no. But that night, um, multiple
people saw this huge UFO and Andy tells the story and he like, he gets emotional telling it. And he's
a, again, a totally sane guy, you know, of course his dad was Andre Buharich, but like he's, he's very
normal sane guy. And he said, yeah, of course, you know, the camera wasn't out because it was much
later in the night. And again, pre iPhone, of course, you know, you got to run in and grab
this bulky VHS camcorder. But apparently like him, that Buharich's son and two or three of the
cousins all saw this huge thing is silently hovered over. So wild.
And that, and, and his son again, very emotionally says like, that was the moment I said, okay,
like I, I believe in, in this stuff and, and I believe in, in, in things my dad did. And he just
had a very emotional reaction, uh, to that moment. So it's stories like that where I go, okay, well,
you know, Buharich isn't running some MK ultra experiment on his family, you know, decades after
all this stuff. So, so yeah, I don't want to put this idea out there that, you know, I, I think that
way. I mean, again, it's just, there's too many red flags in his story that point to his involvement,
but then there's that story where even his cousin who didn't want to be interviewed or whatever,
but I did talk to him and he was like, yeah, that happened, you know?
Well, I think there's something it's like, everybody sees the world through a perceptual
prism or container. And I'm sure with his hypnotic techniques and with MK ultra and with
implants and all these things, you can break that container and then probably intentionally
shade or manipulate what people experience. But the idea that there's nothing outside of that
perceptual prism that involves other entities between man and God, or, you know, whatever your
metaphysical beliefs are, I think also involves some sort of hubris. Like, you know, you can,
you can have both, but, um, it's, this is, I mean, this is one of the craziest interviews
I've ever done, man. This is crazy. I mean, I'm, I feel like shocked, like listening to
all of these facts. And I'm just thinking as you're talking about Puharich's son and this
UFO showing up, um, what was night? Cause I think of 1952 as the, you know, DC flyover,
Washington invasion, like maybe the most intense, uh, UFO showing in United States history, as
far as mass media covering it, people seeing things, you know, I actually recently met a
witness from 1952 and, and, and it was pretty amazing and he remembers it and stuff. He's one
of the probably last living witness. Um, yeah. But do you think that had anything to do with
the seance? Cause I think of the seance with, you know, the original channeling of the nine.
It was 52. Do you know what month? Uh, it was, it was, um, New Year's Eve.
Okay. Well, I mean, it was before then because the, so the, the, again, I don't want to engage
in any sort of, you know, selection bias here, but July, 1952 was when it was the thing showed
up. And so, but a lot of that early channeling with the nod, that was all 50, you know, 52.
Interesting. Yeah. Into 53. I mean, it could have been, and I told you like he, he wrote in his
journals about these orbs and the, one of the psychic psychics would say, you know, go outside
tonight. You're going to see an orbs. I don't, you know, well, every, every time I want to get
away from like the occult having to do with UFOs. It's like, it's just so obviously it does have
everything to do. And there's, there's even a group called the borderland society, which was
borderland. Well, which one? The borderlands research. Yeah. Yeah. Arch was very involved
in that. In fact, a lot of the recordings we have, not a lot, but some of them came from, from them.
They were really, they were, they, they had a bunch of stuff saved actually. So there's a really
amazing, like kind of nuts and bolts, UFO researcher who I think did some software stuff for
SpaceX. His name is Richard Geldreich. And he, he has uncovered like a couple of UFO either crashes
or appearances where the borderland society knew about these UFO appearances before the military
did, before the army, before the air force. So, and then you have, you know, this 1933 magenta crash,
which it seems like is getting increasingly corroborated. David Grush, Harold Malmgren,
both talk about it and Hugh Angleton and James, Jesus, Angleton were there. And, you know,
maybe there's some occult stuff going on there with the night to Malta, right? You know, who knows,
but you know, Puharich was a master Mason. He was interesting. And, um, he tells his story,
uh, in a lecture much later in his life about how he was always approached by these, you know,
what he would call kind of dark occult groups and, and societies and people trying to like
get him to join. And he, he didn't want anything to do with it and that kind of thing.
Well, Wernher von Braun was also, I believe a Freemason and he had gone through all these
weird neo-pagan rituals as part of the German space program. He was also close with Walt Disney. And I
think they made a little movie together and there's some Freemasonic symbolism there. There's
launch pad 33 in real life that he sort of created. And then, uh, my buddy, Danny Jones just
did an interview with one of the last living Apollo astronauts, Charlie Duke, and the number
one moon landing hoaxer person, Bart Cybrell. And Danny on the phone with me is like, dude,
I'm not sure that the early astronauts weren't MK ultra. And it's weird, you know, and it's like,
you have, you know, a picture of Jolly West on the set of 2001 space odyssey. You have,
you know, this. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I think I did hear about that. Yeah. Yeah. And so
that's insane. It is insane. It is insane. And, and then you have these, you know, it's like
Neil Armstrong looking like, you know, he's in a hostage video. Joe Rogan describes it like that,
you know, um, well, after he comes back from the moon. And so you have to wonder if there's some
sort of like weird, my, you know, and if Puhar, I didn't know Puharich knew Wernher von Braun.
You have one of the MK ultra architects in touch with the head of the American space parts. Weird.
Well, the other thing too, with the, the NASA connection with Puharich is again, in the sixties,
um, he was doing like a ton of like contract work for all sorts of, um, different agencies. But so
this is actually in newspaper articles we found, but they were doing like telepathy, uh, experiments
with, with astronauts and, and Puharich claims this. I've never heard it. We don't have the tape,
but he claims that they, before they went to the moon, right. They didn't know the surface of the
moon, what it would, would be like really. So they were saying, okay, how can we land a craft?
What we don't, could it be hot? Is it going to, is it cold? Is it, uh, is it a spike, whatever.
So he, he claims that they send remote viewers to the moon to get a picture of like, what it would
be like. Uh, so they would feel comfortable with like sending whatever, you know, if, if they went
to, to, to, to, to send stuff there. And he says, yeah, you know, somewhere in the NASA archives,
I'm sure there's the tapes we did where we recorded this psychic kind of remote viewing
the moon. And, and he, he, and he had the contracts of NASA. Like we don't, we have one that doesn't
say that, but he clearly, you know, worked with them. We have, we have documentation of that.
Didn't NASA also have a camp around with space children or whatever? Psychic.
Yeah. I've heard a lot about that. Um, but I don't, I don't know much about that. I mean,
I know about obviously Buharich is, we can get into that, but yeah, I've heard a lot about that,
that there in the late sixties, there was some somewhere in Florida, there was like a NASA
thing with kids. I honestly, I don't know.
I think Gordon Cooper might talk about it.
Oh dude, Gordon Cooper was very involved with Buharich. Uh, yeah. So this is one of the,
this is the guy who spent longer in the earth's orbit, you know, in space than anyone prior
to him in the late fifties. And yeah, he went to Austin and like many times. And in his book,
he writes about, um, going there, seeing experiments with the Faraday cage, seeing the space kids.
Um, yeah.
Why was he so interested? I mean, why was a NASA astronaut interested in psychic research?
Um, I don't know. I mean, well, I think Coop, Gordon Cooper, I mean, didn't he have some
UFO, uh, stories or experiences, or at least he was open to talking about that stuff.
We had some, some kind of craft flying overhead, had pretty good altitude and flying the same
kind of formation we'd fly in our fighter.
Were they planes? I mean, what?
Well, it turns out they didn't have wings. They were saucer shaped that we never could get
as high or as fast as they were. So I had to really positively identify them, but they
were metallic looking and saucer in shape.
So he was definitely like interested in this stuff. And, and, um, yeah, so he went up there.
Everyone went up there. I mean, the whole Gene Roddenberry thing is crazy.
Yeah. So the creator of Star Trek.
Yeah. So, so that's like something I read about and, you know, I thought, oh, that's interesting.
But in Puharic's archive, sure enough, is the tape that no one's ever heard of this session
that is kind of like crazy to, to, to, to be in possession of, but basically they would
do these kind of round table esque, uh, channelings where like back then these prominent people
at the time were now in mid seventies would come there, spend time there and they would
do these sessions. And Gene Roddenberry went up a lot and he makes mention on this one
tape recording that like, you know, he says like, like I've said many times in the past,
which would indicate that this wasn't the first time he was a part of like a channeling
session with them. But yeah, we have the tape where it was, um, Roddenberry Puharic and
Phyllis Schlemmer was the channel, the channeler. And, you know, she, he, he does his thing.
He, he hypnotically regresses her. Um, she goes into a trance. She starts channeling the
nine and Roddenberry is there. And it's like an hour or two hours of him asking questions about
everything. And that becomes the plot of star Trek or, well, I wouldn't say the plot cause
star Trek had started. I think it would, I think people think of deep space nine, which that came
out post these sessions and, um, that, you know, of course nine, and then there's a character in deep
space nine, who's called Vinod, just like the early nine channeler. So there's no question like
that, that's connected. And they actually wrote, uh, I have it. And, um, I don't know what will
ever come of it. It's a, it's a long story, but Gene Roddenberry wrote a script called the nine.
And it's all about his, he changed the names and locations and the whole premise is his experience
of working with Buharich and Phyllis channeling the nine. And we have an original copy of it and
it's like amazing. And from what we understand, like Roddenberry at the time was going through a
lot with like, I guess he was like drinking a lot and I don't know all the specifics, but it just like
it, you know, as, as stuff in the, in the movie industry does, it fell apart or whatever. And,
and it never happened, but, uh, he was moved enough to write a whole, you know, 130 page script
about, about his experience. And it's called the nine. So trippy. Yeah. And you have, so we should
make it maybe. Yeah. There you go. Yeah. You have a, hit Greg up if you're interested. I mean,
you also, you know, think about the star Trek, you think about the, you know, the galactic federation.
Yeah. That's mentioned in a couple of real world contexts to one of which being, um, you have
high meshed who would, you know, has won multiple, the highest, you know, national security awards in
Israel is basically the, uh, founder of their space program and their, their equivalent of space force
and was, I think head of it for decades. Yeah. And he just writes this autobiography where he talks
about, uh, the galactic federation. Yeah. And so do you think there's something like more real going
on that in, in that, like the heads of various nation state space programs are aware of here?
Perhaps. Yeah.
Does he mention anything about the nine too, or who?
Eshed? No, I know.
I thought maybe he, okay.
Not specifically. Okay.
But, um, the other weird connection to, um, Israel Puharich and everything was, uh, he was close with,
uh, Itzhak Bentov.
Oh yeah.
Who's, you know, a really interesting guy. Um, there's some videos on YouTube with him.
He's kind of like the Israeli Puharich. He, he kind of looks like him and, you know,
they have the same vibe going on, but they were, they were good friends. Uh, I don't know the
specifics of how they met. Apparently, uh, Bentov was, you know, instrumental in hooking up, uh,
Puharich with Geller. I don't know the truth to that, but, um, well, they definitely knew each
other because there's photographs of Geller, Puharich, and Bentov in an apartment in Tel Aviv
together. But, you know, Bentov is interesting because he worked for Israeli intelligence. I mean,
that's, that's a fact. And they, and Puharich was, again, like I said, going to Israel a lot at that
time. And he was always tape recording their conversations. Like him and Bentov would sit
around like you and I are right now, and they would record all their conversations, which,
you know, is not weird necessarily, but also, you know, why would you do that and then save the
cassette tapes decades later? So, you know, there's a lot of clues like that, that goes back to that
Israeli connection. And, and Bentov was one of a number of, um, scientists who were being tracked at,
you know, Puharich's house burned, burned in 1978. Um, to this day, no one really knows who did it,
but it was a proven, you know, arson job by the, the fire department. And Bentov, uh, around that time
was also being monitored. Puharich was being monitored. And there's this big, like this circle
of kind of his friends and colleagues were all claiming to be, to be monitored, be followed,
harassed, and so forth. Um, and there was some story connecting a possibility,
possible Israeli connection to this 1978 fire. Um, but yeah, that's a big, big question mark. I
mean, and Bentov died in a plane crash, I believe, sort of super mysteriously. He was, uh, friends
with a lot of the Stanford Research Institute and early psychic, you know, research pioneers
and claimed to have this kind of theory of everything. He writes a book called Stalking
the Wild Pendulum where individual consciousness is kind of a pinched node of some larger fabric of
consciousness or something. And, uh, fascinating guy. Yeah, they were close. Like I said, there's a
couple of tapes of them just like literally talking and they would just record it and they would talk
about all sorts of things, mostly, you know, their, their, uh, shared interest and in consciousness
and stuff. But, you know, then there's this other theory that Puharich could have not been a
double agent and, and, and simply just a spy and going to kind of pick off information or,
Hey, we're, we're buddies. We're into the same stuff. We should tape record our conversation.
Like he was CIA and Bentov was Mossad or something. Yeah. Yeah.
But all I know is that stuff exists and you can put it together how, how you want, but, you know,
I've told a lot of people, and again, it's not because I sort of fear for, you know, anything,
but we, we really done, maybe it's deliberate. Maybe we're not supposed to have found anything,
but we, we don't have any sort of like legitimate document or anything that really nailed. And I think
that's, what's interesting about the film and the story in general is like, you still question,
there's still research to be done into this because we don't have the definitive answer of
what's going on. We just have all this, all these strange breadcrumbs over several decades that would
point to. Well, I think the most interesting, you know, pieces of media or journalism, but get more
questions often than answers, especially if you're cutting to, you know, the deeper architectures
of reality. And, uh, I often think you should be kind of skeptical or distrust, you know, people
who are like, they're so sure it's just X or it's just Y, you know? And in this case, it's clearly this
kind of murky subject, but that, I mean, that makes it, that makes it so fascinating, right? It makes
you just want to go, go deeper. And, uh, um, I think that the sign too, of the whole Geller thing
being, like I mentioned earlier, like him being involved, maybe willingly in these kinds of
experiments, you know, but he, he, um, yeah, he, he really opened up. I mean, anyone can hear it.
Uh, I don't know. Maybe it's been taken down, but it was this radio interview from 2019 and he,
he was very open about, you know, I was, I was scared. Um, and he always uses the term like
Buharic made me believe this. He made, you know, and, and he, and he does credit Buharic says, look,
you know, I'm, I, I, I love the guy. He helped me, he helped me get to the, to America. Um, so it's
not like he's, he hates him or he speak, but he, he, he's very clear, like, you know, at that period,
like I was, I was, uh, concerned about what was going on. He mentions being pretty sure that,
uh, Buharic had slipped him the mushrooms. So, you know, um,
there's that, I mean, I, I, I don't think he's, he's making that up. No, I think it was like
all these years later, I think he wanted to come clean or about, about like what he really
experiences, the vibe that I got from. He's a wild character. He has a very flamboyant
online personality. He'll often make these videos directed at world leaders. So like Trump don't
push that button or Putin stand down or whatever, you know, I know what's going to happen. And he'll
like predict the wild things happening. And, um, well, he was doing that in the seventies.
He was like, like, again, these, this, this idea that you could use this directed thought to,
to change somebody's, uh, uh, opinion or change somebody's, uh, direction or, and he talks a lot
about doing that back then. Um, I have a friend who worked at the Princeton parapsychology lab.
And whenever I try to throw the kitchen sink of skepticism around, like he's just a stage magician
and he's, you know, I don't, I don't know how legit he is. He often said, you know, and I think
they're, they even have like, uh, uh, some papers where they studied him at Princeton. And I think
it's often again, like these people have something that's a little anomalous going on and they play it
up, you know? Yeah. I, that's really actually my, again, with everything I said prior to
him potentially being the sort of subject, but no, I, I actually firmly believe that
he was one of probably, you know, a lot of people out there who have something. And again,
it's just like, can you turn it on every time? Can you, can you perform at every instance someone
asks you? I mean, no, I'm not a slight, I mean, I don't, I don't know, but I would assume like
you can't do it a hundred percent of the time. Maybe you can do it 60% of the time.
Yeah. But I think that about him, because I've heard enough stories, um, through all these people
I've talked to and stuff who were like, yeah, he, he had something, you know, I think he liked the
idea of the showmanship and, but yeah, he definitely had something going on. Speaking of people with
gifted, you know, psychic abilities, uh, who are the space kids?
The space kids are, uh, well, there's a lot of them and we only were able to track down and
interview, um, one, two, three, five of them. But basically when Geller was kind of blowing up,
this was like mid seventies, early mid seventies. Uh, apparently the story goes that these kids all
over the world, um, specifically in the United States and the UK and in, and in China, which are
just the, the, the stories that we were able to kind of look into, but these kids would see, um,
Geller on TV and all of a sudden, like that would, uh, cause them to just spontaneously, like
do something psychic. Like they would, they would pick up a spoon and it would bend or they would,
you know, go into the room and the, the, the drawers would all, you know, poltergeist stuff.
Right. And there's a ton of newspaper articles at this time, which again, like, okay, it could have
all been a hoax, whatever, but you know, it's like parents calling in, uh, the TV station, you know,
Puharich claims like saying, what the hell is going on here? You know, my kid just did this.
My kid just bent a spoon. My kid just, you know, touched the, the, the refrigerator and
it short circuited, you know, all sorts of stuff. And apparently it was because they saw him on TV
and, and something happened, something clicked and they, their psychic abilities just kind of
like came out in that moment. It's like a contagion of psychic powers. Yeah. So that's apparently what
was happening. And so Puharich of course, you know, learns this and he's very intrigued. So he
starts to, you know, visit some of these cases of kids who were doing this. And, um, eventually I
guess is so, uh, eventually he's so convinced that, that this is real and that these kids actually have
this sort of like sudden emergence of ability that he, um, brings them. Well, again, a lot of people
have this idea. There's a lot online about how he like collected, uh, all these kids, almost like
an X-Men kind of thing, which is partially true, but mostly like he would lecture and, and, and, you
know, all over the country and Canada and places and, and people, and, and we say kids, we're talking
like teen, you know, early, apparently there were like some very young, you know, five, four or five,
six year old kids, but the ones that we're dealing with in the film are all, you know, in their early
twenties, maybe 18 youngest, but they would see him at a, at a lecture and they would, they would
approach him and say, Hey, you know, we got to talk. Like I have, I have these abilities and, and you
are obviously the guy who knows about this and I need your help basically, like they would kind of
go to him. So at that point he thought, okay, there's enough, there's enough stories and enough
of these kids coming to me that like, I should start a research program. And so that's when he
sort of collects like a large group, uh, of, of kids. I think it was like, again, online, there's all
sorts of stories, but it was really only like maybe like a dozen kids, I think, give or take,
but he, he kind of invites them to, to Ossining where he's, you know, living and, and starts
this sort of camp where basically they are just doing psychic, uh, uh, research on these
kids. And I think again, not unlike the earlier Vinod round table stuff, like a lot of conspiracy
stuff pops up at this moment too, because of the general nature of kids showing up at the house
of, uh, you know, known intelligence, uh, connected scientists, et cetera, and so forth. But, um,
basically he collected them and, um, just started this camp where they did, you know, kind of went
through the different abilities, tested them. And, and that all led to getting back to the nine
because a lot of these kids claim they had some sort of encounter or, or, you know, UFO experience.
And so Buhar said, okay, kind of like group them. Okay. All the, all the kids who've had an experience
here, you know, not. And so all the kids that had an experience, he would hypnotize them.
And allegedly the nine would come through even through these kids who most of which never knew
about, about the nine. And, and most of which were kids who like, you, you hear a lot with these
experiencers who like, they didn't want to talk about it. You know, they didn't want, you know,
fame or they, they were just like, I'm actually scared and I want to know what's going on with
myself. You know, they weren't trying to like, you know, do anything more than like,
can you help me figure out what's going on? After, after you've looked at this for 10 plus years,
do you think that the nine coming through these different experiencers, abductees, people who've
seen UFOs represent something real that's sort of, you know, non-human or extraterrestrial coming
through these people? Or do you think that these were sort of synthetically implanted or kind of
manipulated by Puharich?
I think it's, I don't want to say synthetically created. I think what was going on at this time,
and this is, we're talking 74 when this started, 73, 74. And keep in mind, this is right around the time
the SRI remote viewing stuff starts. Yeah. And keep in mind, Hal Puthoff tells us that he went to
Puharich's house in Ossining, heard all about the nine, and that Puharich was apparently communicating
with this thing called the nine. Wild. And then didn't really say much.
Has Hal Puthoff never talked about this? No. I mean, in the film he does. I gotta ask him.
But he basically just tells a story about, well, quite frankly, he was quite closed off
when it came to the subject of all this Puharich. So I don't know. I wasn't there at the interview.
Someone else did it. I mean, it was great he did it. But he basically, it was like Puharich was
more connected than anyone ever knew. And he sort of alludes to that. But he does say, yeah,
we went up to his house. There's footage of him and Targ at Ossining sitting on the front steps.
So my theory is that, and people have talked about this and it's out there, but I think that
there was this sort of, and we know for a fact that Puharich was part of the SRI program. A lot
of people Puthoff himself say, no, he wasn't. He just simply brought Geller and that was it. He
disappeared. Not true. There's a pay stub in Puharich's archives that is from SRI to Lab 9,
Puharich's lab from 73. We brought it up to Puthoff. He said, oh, I don't, who knows? It could have
just, it's whatever. It's nothing basically. But to me, that proves he was connected. Because I think
the story most people read is just like, he brought Geller, dropped him off there and was just like,
have fun basically. But I think that Puharich's house, which was now called Lab 9, which again,
like Intellectron and a couple others he had, which are no use getting into, but he just had these sort
of like front companies, which I just think it's obvious. So at this time he had Lab 9. And I think
that Lab 9 was doing SRI research, you know, on children, because essentially a lot of the tapes
are remote viewing. There's no other way to look at it. It's, okay, what's going on in this location?
Uh, what time is this, uh, such and such general going to be at this place? Uh, when should we go
here? And it was actually, speaking of Adam Curry, I think it was actually Adam who brought up this
idea that, you know, a lot of people who go into a trance or hypnosis, you know, there's, there's a
protocol, right? It's either like a pendulum or whatever it is, a countdown. And I think the nine
and, and something somehow like this, we're going to connect with the nine thing was like a way that
these, it was an in, if that makes sense for some of these kids to, to sort of want to participate.
Because again, it goes back to, if you really want to test like a kid's, a real, you know, 20 year
old person is a 20 year old, a better psychic than an 80 year old, you know, eventually you're going to
have to find a 20 year old and, and do an experiment with them. And I think what was happening was like,
if you go to a 20 year old and say, Hey, you know, especially at the time with Uri Geller being famous,
you know, whatever, star Wars, this and that. And you say, Hey, you know, do you want to
be a part of an experiment where you can communicate with these, you know, these beings and, you know,
I can put you in a safe and I can put you in this, this hypnotic state and you'll communicate with
them. Like, obviously you would say, Oh, that's okay. That's, that's interesting. That's cool.
You know, you're not going to say, Hey, do you want to come be a part of a, a covert, you know,
mind control experience. You're not going to approach it that way. So that's my theory is that
that was sort of his way. And one of the space kids whose name I don't, I won't mention. Um,
she, she basically admitted that where she said something to the effect a long time ago of like
the nine was basically just like this sandbox for us to, or some analogy like that, where the nine
is basically just like this sandbox for us to, to, to play in or something. And I, and again,
it was off. It wasn't in the interview. It was like one of those many phone calls we had. And I
always stuck with me. So I think that at that time, again, you've got same years, remote viewing
experiments are starting at SRI. You've got the connection to SRI via some sort of pay stub going
directly to lab nine. And you've got all these young kids who on the tapes are doing remote
viewing. So, but the, the question I want to push you on this is like remote viewing is used
for the U S from 72 to 95. And probably now to like actually add to our intelligence abilities
about real things, drop Russian nuclear bases, find hostages, you know, whatever. Do you think
that this council of nine were real, you know, extraterrestrial or non-human beings
communicating through these space kids, or do you think the nine was being implanted and they were
testing their ability to sort of manipulate thoughts and that was through the nine or whatever. And they
had some, some, you know, I mean, clearly they did have some abilities to do that.
The, the, the, the, the evidence would point to the ladder. I mean, that's, that's the best way I
can answer that. God, that's crazy. That's a, and that would go back. It's very deflating. I'm sure
for a lot of the UFO. Well, it is. And again, like, I don't want to come across as this like negative
skeptic person as I'm not, but again, it, it goes back to like, if you're trying to be serious and
piece together the life of this guy that spans decades, like, and, and that's what you're hearing.
Uh, you know, that's what you, that's what you have.
But what, what is, if you are saying some of the protocol to get people into this state involves,
uh, saying, Hey, you're, you're contacting the nine and whatever, it's some protocol. And it sounds
like a hypnotic technique, but then some seem super open-ended and they just seem to connect
with the nine. How do you sort of make sense of that?
Well, I don't know. And that goes back to the kind of, you know, I think, uh, Jeffrey Mishlove
brings this up of this sort of, uh, trickster element, the kind of paranormal phenomena where
like, sometimes they're, they're tricking you and sometimes it's real, sometimes it isn't.
And I think there was, you know, with Buharic, like, again, it's always that question of like,
where did he stand with? Like, is this real research that he passionately believes in? And
he's trying to come to some sort of, you know, reality of, of the ET phenomena, or was it just all
MK ultra, you know? And again, I don't think it was all MK ultra mind control stuff, but there's some
gray area there that is so hard to pin down because again, in some of these, um, sessions,
and, and this is strange is, is that on some of the sessions, you know, he'll be like, okay, here we
are with this space kid and in there, and their mom is here and she's, you know, this is like the
tape recording we're hearing. And, and on those sessions, it's like, you know, typical, okay,
the nine, um, the, you know, the world is beautiful. We need to save humanity, et cetera,
et cetera. Then there's other tapes that are like, you know, what time is the best to, to remote view
the Kremlin so we can get into that, you know? So, yeah. So I think it's, there was a way of like,
okay, I need to kind of, you know, give an example to, to maybe other people around to say,
Hey, look, this is what we're doing. Okay. See, you set in on a session. So now you know what it's
like. And then when those people aren't around, it kind of gets to the, the serious stuff is again,
what it, this is what I'm, you're hearing what I'm hearing. It's all based off that. It's not like
really my personal, um, you know, hardcore beliefs. It's just like, oh, okay, this is what
I'm hearing. Yeah. I think anyone would kind of conclude that. Yeah. But again, I think Puharic,
like, and, and this is a big part of the film and a big part of my philosophy about him and his story
is like, I think he believed, I know he believed in, in a lot of paranormal stuff, but I think he got
sort of under the thumb of the, uh, you know, intelligence world early on. And I just don't
think that he could kind of get away from that. And I think, you know, you often hear it's like
the mafia, like you don't just leave. And when you're, when you're that involved as he was, you
know, to say, Hey, I'm, I'm, I'm good, you know? And I, so I think that there was a lot of pressure on
him to do some of this negative stuff that he may have otherwise not wanted to do. And I think
that's like a big part of the film and what I wanted to kind of get across with it is there's
so much negative conspiracy stuff about him out there. I mean, there's tons of it. Have you read
the Stargate conspiracy, the book? It's really good. It's, um, it came out in the nineties and it
was the first book that really talked about a lot. Like this, this book had the story that
I told you about it, the guy in Florida who woke up with the, the tooth implant.
And then this is the first book that really exposed, basically saying everything he ever
did was intelligence involved. You, you know, he's, he's an awful person. He's an evil genius,
but, uh, you know, it's not true. And I think that I hope to get that across in the film.
And I think we do, because like a big part of that, that research, I don't think he wanted
to do. I think he, he, in a way was forced to do it, you know?
Yeah. And whatever this kind of amorphous blob, that is the UFO legacy program that is always
proverbially discussed, but, you know, usually in a very kind of high level fuzzy ways.
I think that's probably the case with a lot of these people is that they were kind of sucked
up into, in certain cases, they probably came upon really exciting scientific truths
that were converging on things that, you know, some, you know, behind the, the, the iron curtain
science, you know, uh, group in the U S you know, uh, uh, during kind of cold war secrecy era already
knew and, uh, and, and they would recruit these people and then they would probably be forced to,
you know, work on things in contexts that they weren't particularly happy about and didn't feel
idealistic about. And I'm sure that that's the case with him because I, again, like, I don't want
to, um, come, come across as someone who's trying to like put him out there because I'm not, I mean,
like I got to know his family really well. I'm like very close with them and, and they were great when I
showed them the sort of final product, which really gets into this stuff. And they were like,
you did a good job because you didn't shy away from, from that. And I think, you know,
you illustrated it well, but you know, they were even like, wow, there's so much in here.
We had no idea about, like, we literally had no idea you, you're telling us stuff that we never
even heard before. And so that just goes to show his own family was in the dark about
a lot of it, but you know, the nine again, like I just keep thinking, I think about it a lot. And
again, like the, the answer just is, I don't know, but what I've heard and what I've had access to
that came directly from his personal records would indicate that it was, it was a made up,
a made up thing. Fascinating. Well, that, I mean, that in and of itself seems a little messed up as
does, you know, slipping somebody mushrooms or, you know, telling them they've been abducted by
aliens and taken aboard a ship when they haven't, or quote unquote, teleporting them and throwing
them through a window. And you know, like these things aren't cool, you know?
No. And again, like, I think if you watch, if anyone watches footage of Puhar, it's electric,
he's the most jovial, funny night, you know, like he's not this like monster person. And that's why
I quite frankly think makes him like interesting and an interesting subject for a film, because like,
he's complicated and he, he's, he's again, I think being sucked into these things that he would
otherwise not want to do. And he, and not to ruin the end of the film, but he basically like
admits that, that he basically admits like that is what was going on with him. Yeah. Well, he warns
future researchers basically like, don't do what I did essentially is what he, he, his message is.
If you look at the Zimbardo prison experiments at Stanford or whatever, where, you know, these prison
guards start to get really self-important or Stanley Milgram's shock experiments, you know, it's a,
and then you combine that with the, you know, the, the, the power of the CIA at the time,
I'm sure you could get coerced into doing all sorts of things. And does that fully exonerate you?
Like probably not, but, uh, it's, uh, yeah, I mean, I think the, the, the, the best version,
which I think your documentary really gives is the nuanced one, which shows how somebody could get
incrementally walked into a position like that. And there's just no question, the level of, um,
you know, how, how deeply connected he was to intelligence. I mean, there's, there's a paper
trail of it. So there's just, there's no way to kind of beat around that bush. I think, again,
I've just, I've read so much online and there's a lot of speculation, but at the end of the day,
like those people don't, haven't seen the materials that, you know, we had. So.
So interesting. Were there any other experiments that they were obviously channeling? They were
using these sort of Faraday chambers. They had this machine that produced tones,
any other experiments that they were doing with the space kids specifically?
Well, here's, what's interesting is that, um, and you see in the film, like getting back to this
idea of the nine being this kind of end point, just to like get things, get things done.
Uh, in the seventies, we're talking 74 through 76, you know, Middle East war, right. Going on
and Puharich and specifically Phyllis Schlemmer, he was still working with her then, but, and, and,
and all the space kids, you know, they weren't specifically going on these trips, but they would
literally have a session, right. With the nine and they would do group sessions where it would be
like, you know, two people at Puharich and two other people, him and three other people,
him and six other people. And that would apparently like bring the message through more strongly and so
forth. But, um, in that time they're getting messages from the nine saying, you know, you need
to go to Egypt, you need to go to, you know, any, you know, Middle East area, you need to go to Russia,
you know, and all these places, which would otherwise be very difficult for, for somebody to
just go to during that period. In fact, one of the guys working with Puharich at that time, John
Whitmore, he was a British guy who got really involved. Like he even says in an interview, like
you, you, you normally could not even get into these countries at this time yet Puharich with his
psychic where we're going constantly because the nine said, you have to go here, you have to go there.
And so he kind of hints at like, well, what was that really the nine or once again, was Puharich
involved in something else that he had to be in these areas at this time, you know, under the auspices
that this was a psychic, you know, this was the nine telling them to go there. Phyllis Schlemmer
completely questions everything. And, you know, way later in her life, she did an interview. She said,
he used the TD 100 machine on me all the time. I never knew what it did. I never questioned what it
did. And so you just have to ask, like, how is it that Puharich is able to go to these places during
that time, get into very specific locations, often involving very high ranking government people.
And it's all just, oh, hey, the nine told us to come here. So we're here. And, and so a lot of
people speculate, you know, I've heard stories of, you know, Christian missionaries who were actually
spies and, you know, something like that going on. Again, it's interesting to go down that road to
think about it. Nothing we have like concretely proves that. But I just think like the more you
listen to those tapes at that time, and the more you just kind of put things together,
like it does seem like, what if that was, that was the cover and, oh, this guy is so crazy. He
actually thinks a psychic is telling him, oh, just let him go. What a, what a kook. And meanwhile,
he's, you know, doing whatever he needs to do there. Yeah. It's using the stigma of the science kind
of in your favor as a cover for something more vital that clearly was, was actually working and
functional. And he actually on these tapes gives, this goes back to like the remote viewing stuff
of like, some of the questions that they're asking are like, you know, what are, what is the code name
that, you know, the, the, the, you know, Russian guerrilla soldiers are using. So we then know
what to pick up on when we hear this code name. So then that begs the question of why would an alien,
why would an alien be like asking those types of questions if that's what you're supposed to be
doing, talking to the nine. But to go back to the, the, the, the constant contrast is like,
he really was a genuine believer because he would often go, um, to the great pyramid in the,
in the same time and do like all sorts of experiments there. Really?
And he just loved going there. Like he was obsessed with the pyramid. He's obsessed with
the history, all the, the Egyptian God, like, so, you know, that's not.
And there are nine, there are specifically nine Egyptian gods.
Exactly. So that was something he was like obsessive about. He would, he,
we have tape recordings of him meditating in the King's chamber in 76. And he did experiments with,
um, uh, one of the space kids in the pyramid and they brought through this information.
Apparently they're channeling this Egyptian God and some pretty weird information lined up
during that session. So then that goes back to like, it's almost like, okay, I gotta, I, I have to,
you know, do my job for the CIA and on my off time, I, I can go in the pyramid and,
and do, do some cool stuff I'm interested in. That's just kind of what it seems because like, again,
there's no mind manipulation, dark stuff going on there. It's, it's, it's very clearly him. Like,
I'm going to meditate in the King's chamber. Like, well, what does that have to do with, you know,
MK ultra? So I just think like, and again, this goes to like his death in the mystery book around
that, where I think like there was a situation too, where he may have been, you know, on payroll for,
you know, XYZ intelligence agencies and going to do these things, but kind of using that time to do
other things he wanted. And maybe that was, he, he shouldn't have done that. And, you know,
You think they took him out as a result? Maybe it's that.
Yeah. Yeah. I think a part of it is that he, he, cause again, he's going to Egypt,
right? Because the nine are saying, you have to go here, you have to go to this location to meditate,
this and that. But I think he's going, okay, well, I'm already in Egypt and there's the great
pyramid and I've been wanting to go in there anyways. So I'm already here. I'm going to go,
you know, but he's there maybe on, on a mission and Hey, you know, don't screw around kind of thing.
I think there was a lot of that going on. And, um, his death is completely mysterious.
What, what happened?
You can see the stairway, right? For this window where my father allegedly fell down and they found
him right at the bottom of the stairs. We don't really know, um, what killed him.
Well, so there's a couple of things. He, he was sick at the time. Um, but not, I believe not enough
that would have caused this to happen, but basically it was 95 and around this time, he was very vocal
about his life. Like he was doing these sort of lecture tours at sort of parapsychology conferences
and stuff. And he was being very open about his past. And it was one of these lectures at that time
where he said, you know, look, I'll admit it. Um, I worked for this part of the CIA. My boss was the
guy who was directly involved with all the hypnosis, mind manipulation. So who is his boss?
Uh, he doesn't name his boss, but I mean, you know what? He might actually, let me think.
He does. I have to think about it. Did you figure out? Yeah. Yeah. I know it. Trust me. It's just in
my crazy head, Puharich head, but, but I'll, I'll remember it. But, um, basically. And so he says,
yeah, that's what I did. I was, I was, uh, I was a consultant at the time. And so he opens up about a
lot of that stuff. He, he literally says, uh, I can produce in your mind, the image of, of, um, an alien
experience. Um, his assistant at the time was a woman who was on this, this tape that Dick Russell
recorded. I told you about when Puharich was in the hospital. There's a part of the tape where Dick
Russell goes outside. I think they're having a smoke or something. And he's, and he's just kind
of like, Hey, look, you know, give it to me straight. Like what's going on with this guy.
And she, she opens up too. And she says, yeah, he told me about things he's done that he, he, he's
worried for his life about saying, she says he, um, using flashing lights, using all, all tone,
all of that stuff was able to create the, the, the UFO experience that that stuff is all
created. She says, so what she was opening up about that on this tape. And so, so he
would like stage UFO is showing up as well. I think what she's, I think what she was getting
at is what we were talking about with this, this controllers, um, idea is that, yeah, like
kind of, I guess more implanting the, the, the idea that you've had an encounter or, you
know, you've been abducted or so, like he was involved basically making the point he was
involved in that kind of stuff, that kind of research. Um, and again, you know, you're
going to ask like, why, why, you know, like, why was it always like the UFO thing? But, um,
but all that was going on, like right before he died, you know, that tape was recorded less
than a year before he died. But, um, he, he was found, uh, at the bottom of the stairs,
he fell and he, he passed away. And at the time he had all these, um, he was still, and
again, this goes back to like, what did he really believe? He was still living with this
group of like women who were like psychics apparently. And he, he, they lived with him
and he was still like, you know, doing stuff with them or whatever. But, but conveniently
that day they, no one else was there at the house, uh, when they were usually always at
the house and Puharich has this like weird legal pad that he wrote like very soon before
this, this incident occurred where he, he fell down the stairs where he's basically like
outlining why he thinks he's being monitored. He names people that he believes have come
into his life who are, who are there to basically harm him and take him out. He claimed again,
this is either like the work of someone completely paranoid or somebody who's just totally telling
the truth.
Well, it's right before he fell down the stairs mysteriously.
He claimed that they, this, this, and again, it makes sense because these psychic people
would kind of like show up even to this day and be like, Hey, you know, you should study
me and this kind of thing. So he, and he was a nice guy again. So he would want, he would
let people in and he would welcome them. And so he claimed that there was a people like
that who were actually, you know, basically out to get him and that they installed this
ELF, uh, emitter in his television set. So when he would turn on the TV, he would get
hit by this, you know, ELF that would be, and he, and he was a physician, he was a medical
doctor. So he would know what was going on with his own body. And he writes in this legal
pad. Like, you know, I am, this is happening to me. I can tell he would test himself every
day.
Well, he also developed a lot of these techniques, right?
Yeah.
They're using what he developed on him, on him.
Yeah. I mean, if, again, if this were to be believed, which I quite frankly do believe
what he says in this, but he basically is this legal pad and he, it's all these events
kind of leading up to why he believes they're, they're out to get him basically. Right.
But, um, yeah, coincidentally, the day he's found, you know, there's no one at the house
and, um, right before, not right before that, but a few years before, before, um, his death,
he had been, uh, approached by the CIA to head up a ELF research, uh, department, basically.
Again, he writes this. I've, I've found some evidence to, to, to prove that this, this
probably happened, but there was apparently a department being set up just to, to study
ELF, um, you know, weapons and so forth.
Again, a lot of that was going on in the late seventies and he, he said no.
And apparently some argument ensued and he said, you know, get outta here. And, and cause
they came into his house. He's kind of recounting this in his notes. And, um, the guy that he
said came on behalf of the CIA to talk to him as a guy we know was involved in the CIA.
Who's that guy named Bob Beck, who's in the, who's in the film. Um, and he was another
Puharich type where, where he got roped into a lot of things. I think he, he wasn't necessarily
wanting to, to do, but, um, so that happened where he, he refused that and said, you know,
no, you know, get the hell out of here, et cetera. So all of that stuff was leading up to 95
and he was found dead. Coincidentally, you know, the Stargate program ends in 95.
I was gonna, I literally made that connection in my mind. Yeah.
And coincidentally, um, this guy Grinberg, Giacobo Grinberg, who, uh, there's a great film
shout out to, um, Ida, my friend, he made this great film about him. Um, in 95, uh, less than a
month after Puharich dies, he, this guy disappears, Grinberg. I mean, if you see the
film, um, the story basically, as he was involved in very similar research, basically
was able to prove a lot of this psychic stuff is real. And to this day, they don't know what
happened to him. He, that's still a missing person. Did he ever meet Puharich? Yeah. They
met when Puharich was in exile in Mexico after his house was, was burned. Uh, they were, they met in
Mexico in, in less than, um, uh, a month after Puharich was, uh, found dead. Grinberg disappeared.
So again, what do you say? It's all coincidence and you move on or you say there's something.
So bizarre. Yeah. Grinberg, the whole thing about him is like, he realized we live in a matrix and
then he had left the matrix or something like, but what's interesting about him is like, again,
it's, it's, it's literally still like an open case. Like they've never figured it out. And of course,
a lot of people say, oh, you know, he, he got sort of kidnapped by whatever government agency and
they're using him. And you know, what's crazy is, uh, on some random message board, uh, this was like
years ago, I saw a post that was somebody like, I know for a fact that Puharich never died and he
was, he was taken in by the government and he's still alive and someone I know. And the weirdest
thing is a, I was skeptical of that, but I was like years later, I remember reading that. And I,
and I spent hours and hours, days trying to find this mess, but I could not find it for the life of
me. I tried everything I could possibly do and I couldn't, I couldn't find it. Um,
so that was weird. That's super weird. Yeah. So it just got erased or something.
I get it. And, but that was the, that's like the real theory of Grinberg. Like again,
the doc is really good, but there's like actually, you know, legitimate proof that like he,
he was sort of taken by, by the government. So that's what your friend who made the movie
thinks that he was actually taken. And well, that's one of the theories that basically everyone
involved in the story, like agrees with, because everything just points to like that,
that happening. So, so all that was 95, January 95 was Buharic's death, February 95, Grinberg goes
missing. Stargate officially ends in 95. Government puts out newspaper articles all over the news,
you know, Stargate, there's nothing to it. It was all bunk. Um, so, and keep in mind,
Buharic at that time was lecturing about all of that and being honest, being open about all the
experiments he did with, you know, Stargate. So I think, um, Annie Jacobson alludes to it. Like,
I just think it was this classic, you know, he knows too much and he can't be, he can't be out there
talking and he, he's experienced too much. He knows too much and, uh, it's not good.
So I could see them seeing him as a liability late in life, you know, maybe he feels remorse
about some of the things that he did and he's speaking openly and, you know, they're probably
just trying to accelerate the research in the, in the black. Um, what, what are some of the wilder
testimonies of the space kids that you spoke to?
So basically, but the space kids like, yeah, there, there were a lot. Um, and again, the reason
the film took so long, which, you know, to give myself credit for, because a lot of people are
like, I can't believe it took you so long and this and that, but a lot of it was like just getting
people to talk because, you know, you could imagine these people like don't want to. And again,
this is what, you know, you hear a lot about this with the UFO abduction stuff. Like these,
these people like weren't looking to be in the spotlight. In fact, they didn't want to be,
it took about two years for me to basically earn the trust of these space kids who I now consider
like good, good friends, but that's what took so long. And I always thought like, in order to make
a really cool film, like you got to get these space kids, it's like stranger things in real life,
you know, like that's what would make this thing work. And so I was just like convinced
we got to get these, these people and we got, we got five of them. But again, there was like a lot
more, a few of them were like, you know, never reach out to me again. I want nothing to do with
this. So what did they say? I mean, that's why five is amazing. What, what did they say?
Well, so basically like, yeah, what I did was I, I somehow was able to track them down
just basically through like in Puharic's archives and things there. And again, on the tapes, like
he, he would say a name or he would write their name. Well, actually, in fact, in one of his
journals, he like wrote all the names of the kids at the time. So it's pretty easy to like
Google people, but yeah, a lot of the, the ones we got were, were again, after kind of talking to
them and saying, Hey, I'm, I'm, you know, trying to do like a level-headed, you know, portrayal of
Puharic. I'm not some crazy conspiracy person. Like after all that, um, yeah, they were really
open, but, um, you know, they basically talked a lot about like what it was like being at his
house at that time, which again was kind of cultish. I mean, if you want to look at it that
way, in the sense that like, other than the space, cause there was just all sorts of,
uh, Sarfati, Jack Sarfati being one of them, like him and his kind of group of physicists,
people would go up there. It was just kind of like a hub of just any, all these people
interested in this stuff would just go there and like hang out.
For people that don't know, Sarfati is a physicist who is pretty well-respected and
studied under, you know, very impressive people who, you know, were Manhattan project,
you know, pioneers. And he has a model of, of time travel and warp drive physics.
Yeah.
And he, he lives in the Bay area and he's very outspoken, loves to call people a schmuck.
He's written about, um, in the hippies saved physics, uh, by, by David Kaiser, this MIT guy.
Yeah.
And, um, so I didn't know he had any interaction with, uh, uh, Puharic. That's amazing.
Yeah. He went to his house.
Because he also, I believe Sarfati, the way he got involved in this exotic physics that
he ended up studying was he claims that as a teenager, he was in some gifted and talented
education program and he was, he gets a call from the future saying, you're going to meet
the others. You're going to be work on like building UFOs essentially, which he believes
his work touches on building UFOs.
Yeah.
And this is a guy who could keep up with, you know, any top theoretical physicist in
the world. Like he's an, he's a real physicist. He studied under Hans Bet, uh, uh, you know,
at Cornell and stuff.
Yeah.
And, um, he, uh, says he gets a call from the future and then, and then, you know, they
tell him when he's going to meet the others and then he ends up meeting Hal Puthoff like
later or whatever. And it's this weird synchronicity, you know, it's so strange. So he's
interacting with Andre Poohar.
Yeah. Well, you know, it's a crazy connection I just thought of, um, in that story. So the
Sarfati story, uh, quickly is, yeah, he, he got this call from this metallic voice, which
is what some of the, um, get what Geller claims this as well, actually, but yeah. So he gets
this called metallic voice. I was some sort of, you know, alien intelligence, but, um, I don't
know if you remember his part of the story where his, I think it was his dad or his uncle
or something was, was involved in the army or army intelligence. And one of the people
that he knew through a family member that was connected was this guy, Wilson Green. He brings
up this guy, Wilson Green. And that, uh, guy, Wilson Green was working with Buharich in the
fifties, um, at the round table doing everything they were doing there.
Yeah.
So do you, did you ever ask him point blank, Hey Jack, like, was any of your stuff, do you
think it was seeded by these sort of, you know, mind control people or.
I mean, I think like he's open about that being a possibility as far as.
He is.
Yeah. But I just remember him bringing up that name and, and, and, and Buharich's journals,
like he has one where he's kind of listing all these people. That's when I first told you
about the Townsend Brown connection.
This is insane. This is the craziest thing to tell everybody about this.
Well, in one of his journals, it was just, uh, him recounting, like he would often go
to DC for like meetings, Buharich would, and this is early fifties again, which weird that
the same year you're channeling the nine, you know, in your lab, you're going to DC to
meet with all these people, but he would just like keep very meticulous journals about what
he did, where he went, who we met. And he would just like, Hey, I met this person.
I for lunch met that person. And so, yeah, Wilson green comes to mind because he had something
to do with, um, I think it was the army psychological warfare department. And that's the same guy
Sarfati references, but in these journals, he mentions, um, meeting Townsend Brown and
spending the day with him. And it's very brief, unfortunate, actually, maybe we could do this
together as part of the page. That's like, so Warren, you can't really like read what it says,
but it's, it's kind of a, you know, a brief, uh, mention that he, he met with, with Brown
and spent the afternoon. He says something like spent the afternoon with him to discussed a lot
or something like this. I know some kid who like helped, I think it's called the Vesuvius project
and he helped decode this ancient papyri. And so if he could do that, hopefully he could get us
this, uh, you know, this transcript. That's crazy. So he met him when this was, again, I'm, I'm positive
it was 53 was that, that journal. So yeah, he was going there. Um, so yeah, that's how I found it.
And it brings up all these questions of like, were people like Wernher von Braun and Brown's ideas
somehow seeded by like MKUltra adjacent things? Like probably not. Cause you have like, you know,
Wernher von Braun goes way back to like, you know, early journey. Like he's clearly like a, you know,
a rocketry genius, like, you know, as a young kid, um, was all, was way into this, like, you know,
like in his, in his teenage years. Um, or was like, you know, if you think about like,
what would be one of the main use cases of MKUltra, it would be like keeping secret science
sort of on lock, maybe creating some sort of cult dynamics around it, wiping people's memories
when they work on really sensitive shit. Like who knows? And Townsend Brown to me, obviously I'm
very high conviction in his stuff. The audience will give me shit. Cause I talk about him all the
time, but I think he's like the godfather of American kind of, you know, in the black dark
science, like whole tech trees that come from anti-gravity or extended electrodynamics or fifth
dimensional physics, I think kind of arise from Townsend Brown. And so I wonder, I wonder what
that meeting was like. The time then was weird overall. I think what people don't realize about
the fifties is like, there's a letter between, I think it's Claude Shannon who invented information
theory was at Princeton. Information theory is the basis of all modern computation. And
William Shockley who invented the modern semiconductor, you know, Bell Labs essentially.
And, um, it was a letter and he goes, you know, my, my friend, you have to meet my friend. He's
really interesting. You know, he's into all this, you know, interesting science stuff or whatever.
And it turns out he's talking about L. Ron Hubbard. And so the point is, is like, it's this weird
time where the intersection between the types of people who'd be engaging in like bizarre seances,
ESP paranormal stuff that wasn't outside the Overton window like it is today. And so, yeah,
anyway, how would you speculate on? Do you, have you speculated on the connection between Townsend
Brown and Brown and Puharic? Nothing more than just, they were probably interested in similar,
similar things. And, and, but it's odd because he said it was in DC. So Brown was there for whatever
reason. Well, Brown was probably deep intelligence. I mean, there's a story of Townsend Brown engaging in
a UFO crash retrieval. And, um, I think it's in the late fifties and it's like, I think Hartford,
Connecticut, and this like green glowing object that seems like it's losing mass gets collected
by, uh, a professor there named Robert Brown. It then ends up at Moonwatch at Harvard, which is
connected with blue book and Robert friend and jail and Hynek have possession of this, you know,
material and Townsend Brown walks in to Harvard, flashes his credentials and takes the material.
And like that, you hear stories like that time, you have telegraphs that I think, um, or telegrams
that, uh, his daughter, um, I think has, uh, I, I know this, I think through, um, this amazing
researcher on Townsend Brown named Jan Lundquist. And I think she says that there's a telegram between
William Stevenson, who's the inspiration for James Bond, that Ian Fleming is Churchill's super spy.
He was like, uh, you know, um, coordinating with Wild Bill Donovan, the OSS. He was like as high up
as it gets when it comes to intelligence. And there's a telegram from, um, him to Josephine,
who's Townsend Brown's wife, uh, because Townsend Brown had, had flown behind enemy territory,
parachuted into, you know, uh, Nazi Germany in 45 to interrogate some scientists because he was an
expert in all this stuff. And it's this telegram is says, you know, from William Stevenson, your
husband is okay. You know, he's, he's been injured, but he's okay. And he's on his way back to the U S or
whatever. So I can give you like 50 other stories like that. Like Curtis LeMay, I mean, his daughter
said, I think on the phone with me, Linda Brown says, Curtis LeMay chases Townsend Brown down the
stairs. Cause he's so interested in his inventions and stuff. And so this guy was like as deep as it
gets when it came to the American intelligence and military elite. Um, so it would make sense
if Puharich was as well on the kind of the psychic, you know, you know, vector. And maybe if all of
this stuff is being coordinated at a higher level, then we understand. And there's some spooky science
stuff and the anti-gravity connects with the psychic stuff, you know, nuts and bolts, like they all
kind of materials, they all kind of connect at the, at the top. Those two guys seem like very central
nodes. Yeah. And I think there's a lot of similarities with what you said, uh, you know,
this idea of like flashing credentials and walking in play. I mean, there's, again, I could give you 50
examples of Puharich doing that kind of thing that I've heard. And so that, yeah. And I think like
the journals that mentioned Brown and these others, like, I don't think these were sort of meant to be
seen, you know, these were like buried in his, in his records. In fact, like in the film, you'll see
like his, his, his assistant at one point kind of mentions this idea that like, not, not, um,
not long before he passed away, like he had made mention, like these papers I have in my house need,
someone needs to take them. I don't trust giving them my children for their safety. And so I think
this is stuff that was not supposed to be, um, read, you know, or seen.
It's amazing.
Amazing.
There's a lot of other names. I researched them all. He met with Dulles. I don't, I guess I
didn't mention that.
Wild.
He, there's, he's literally again in the journal met, he's like, you know, says something like,
uh, you know, wait, it was in the waiting room for an hour and finally got in and we had, we talked
and so obviously you're up to something serious.
Yeah.
You're meeting with the third director of the CIA who, yeah. It's a while. I mean, if, yeah,
if anybody was kind of running the government behind the government, it was Dulles. So yeah.
D, um, yeah. Some of the wilder testimony.
Yeah. The space kids.
Space kids. Yeah.
So yeah, they, so they just basically recounted a lot of like, um, what they experienced, a lot
of the channeling sessions. So a wilder story is, um, uh, this, one of the space kids,
his name's Jaime. He's, um, from Mexico city, great guy. And again, he was somebody who would
never have wanted to appear in a documentary, you know, like his life was totally fine. You know,
he didn't need to talk about this, but he did because event eventually he told me like,
if you're willing to like, tell the real story, like I'll talk because he knows like I did,
there's just so much like BS stuff out there about Puharish and everything. But, um,
he told me a story about he, um, he was meditate at one time he was doing an experiment with Puharish's
assistant, this woman who's in the film. Um, they were doing an experiment. They were meditating,
uh, together and she, they were sitting in a room together, both meditating. And he says that at one
point she got up and she went over to him and she touched his forehead with her finger.
And when she did that, this big, uh, blue ball, I guess this like ball of energy as he describes it
appeared next thing he knew he came to, she was all the way across the room against the wall and he
was back up against the wall and he doesn't remember what happened. And the last thing he remembers is
that she touched his forehead, some sort of burst of blue light. She flew across the room and he
told me that. And, and, you know, and he said, look, you know, you can talk to the assistant, like
she'll, she'll corroborate this. And, and I did, and she did, and she did. And his, his theory was just like,
we, some connection, you know, must've been, been occurring. And, and what, what, what do you do with
that? Because something I learned, which was very bizarre, because this was another thing that
Buharich didn't kind of open up, uh, about until way later in his life is he, he says, and again,
this is not me or a speculation or making something up. Like he says in his own words, he invented this,
uh, prosthetic finger that would have a, uh, a chip with a certain ELF frequency that would emit
from it. So when you touch somebody's forehead with this, it would be the exact frequency that
would like knock them into the hypnotic state they needed to be in, in order to do channeling.
And so he could basically just like, I could go like this to you and you would fall into the thing.
He says that one of the, one of the kids says, yeah, I, I, I remember that. So was this instance
with Jaime and the finger or something to do with that? What was it not? I don't know, but that's one
of his stories that was really bizarre. Any UFO related stories? Um, yeah, there was a lot of, um,
there were a couple like the classic, you know, right now there's a UFO that's sort of hovering
over this session and then some claim to have witnessed that. Um, there was a few stories
like that. So that would be in the, like his protocol, like he'd be saying that or like,
they'd be like automatically channeling. That would be like, apparently the nine, you know,
saying that saying this through them. Yeah. But, um, then there was a lot of, um,
but like, if we're to get super concrete about this, like, is that him beaming the message right
now, there is a UFO, you know, above our head or is it like creating some weird protocol and then
like what happens to them happens to them. And we have no idea where that content is coming from.
Um, I don't know. Yeah. Yeah. It's strange because
a lot of these sessions are very long, like some of them are literally like two hours long,
you know, and it's, it's just, I, I hate to say like, it's, it's kind of like, you just need to
hear it to kind of like, to understand because it's, it's just, it, it really is mind boggling because
I, I constantly go from like, this is, this is a, an experiment. This has been to like, oh no,
this is like literally he's making contact with an extraterrestrial. Say you were to suspend
disbelief entirely and just take the contents of the nine at face value. How would you characterize
these nine beings in what they want for humanity? Well, it's like I said before, um, they, they speak
a lot about this idea that we have the ability of destroying ourselves, you know, and that if there's
a way they can prevent that, then they, they want to. And they talk a lot about nuclear bases and this
kind of thing that, you know, we hear a lot about now. Uh, they kind of say like, we're kind of
behind a lot of the sightings that, that are occurring on nuclear bases. Um, but then now I'm
like, you're making me think this shit's real. The re the reason, I'd love to be cynical about it,
but like the nuclear stuff has been going on since the 40s. There's this guy, Bud Clem, uh, there's
this UFO and nukes documentary. It's all based on Robert Hastings, great work in his book. It's really good.
And I made kind of a, you know, another little thing with Robert Hastings on my channel, but
you have this guy, Bud Clem, as early as 1945 in Hanford, where he's talking about these fireballs
in the sky. And they did this project twinkle, which was deleted from the air force archives.
Uh, Lincoln LaPaz, this meteorite expert, uh, at university of New Mexico is talking about green
fireballs that seem intelligently propulsed flashing that like aren't explained by anything prosaic.
Like, and just like the, the nuclear connection is so ubiquitous. And then you're telling me the
atomic energy commission gave him money. They gave him like over a million dollars.
Yeah. So like, if I were them, I'd be like, try to tap into what the hell is, you know, controlling.
Yeah. Dude, this is a crazy rabbit hole.
Yeah. Obviously. Uh, um, what was I going to say? You know, you're see now you're, now you're
entering what I've been in for like years of this constant, like, wait a second. Now I think this
because, um, there, there was a lot of, uh, well, you know, the, the classic thing where like with
disinfor UFO disinformation, they often say like some of it, you know, some real stuff is sort of
peppered into. Yeah, absolutely.
I think it was that kind of thing too, where like maybe there was real, you know, ET UFO related
research going on with some of this mind control stuff peppered in just to throw off the course.
Well, what connection did you just make when I said the atomic energy commission?
Well, what, what I was thinking was, um, there is, uh, I think I sent you something about this
guy a while ago and, uh, I, I have to say now I don't know enough. Um, so I don't want to go too
much into it, but there's a guy, his name is Oliver Reiser. He was a, um, philosophy professor
at university of Pittsburgh in the sixties and seventies. Um, and he wrote a book called cosmic
humanism, which I've only read some of, but it's basically, uh, this idea, like his whole worldview is
this idea that like everything is raw. Everything in the world is just run on frequency, tone, sound.
He thinks it was like the universe is all sound. Uh, and that's how, you know, we, that's how like
inner interstellar travel works. That's how all psychic stuff where it all comes back down to this,
you know, sound tones. Again, there's this big connection here with this tone stuff, but anyways,
Buharic knew this guy, they exchanged like dozens and dozens of letters, but this guy's theory, um,
Reiser was, you know, the ability to communicate with, you know, ET UFO is through tones, through sound.
And he was like, again, so complex. I can barely understand it, but him and Buharic would exchange
these letters that were like, you know, two masters going back and forth about this stuff,
like diagrams, charts, math. And like, you got to think like, they obviously were like
onto something. And again, this goes back for the hundredth time of like Buharic's real interest
in this stuff. But Reiser, yeah, this was his theory that the way to communicate with, you know,
non-human intelligence was essentially through tones and through sound. And so you get Buharic,
you know, doing that basically where he's using tones and sound with space kids. And can you,
while they're in a trance, there's a lot of experiments where like, I'm going to play
this certain tone. And can you kind of like connect with that tone while you're in this
hypnotic state? And can you follow that tone? Where is it bringing you? And what do you hear
now? All sorts of stuff like that. Um, so I guess what I'm getting at is maybe there was some real
research there that had to do with something that wasn't just, you know, a mind control thing.
Cause this guy Reiser was brilliant. I mean, in his obituary, Albert Einstein said he was like,
you know, a genius. Is that true? Yeah. What? Yeah. Albert Einstein said like Reiser is,
he had some quote about him being, you know, this genius. That's insane because Reiser talks about
like parapsychology and mind batter stuff. And you think of Einstein as being totally opposed to
things like that. Well, I think with Reiser, like a lot of guys, like he started doing more,
you know, quote unquote legitimate research, but he got, he got obsessed with this, again, this,
this theory of tone, sound connecting the universe. This is how everything works. And so him and Puharic
were, um, exchanging a lot of letters about like, you know, do you have the ability to, to create
such and such a tone and what, at what speed should it spin within the, you know, complex stuff,
but would lead me as a lay person to think like, okay, clearly they like, they're talking about
something serious here, you know? That's so fascinating. So, so. And then the Atomic Energy
Commission funding it. Those same years, literally the same years he's exchanging letters with Reiser.
Yeah. 63, 64. Yeah. That's when he gets the contract from Atomic Energy Commission. I mean,
it's all, there's, there's, it's a paper trail. And the 50s UFOs showing up around nuclear bases is
this ubiquitous thing. It's constant. It's all over various CIA, Air Force documents. You know,
I sort of document a lot of this stuff. Hastings documents it. It's, it was definitely a thing.
64, there's a famous case at Vandenberg Air Force Base. Oh yeah.
The guy, photo instrumentation specialist named Bob Jacobs. Um, so that's, that's fascinating.
Very interesting. So yeah, it just points back to this idea that I, I, I, you know, he, he was
genuinely interested in, in, in paranormal, you know, research and, in UFO. I mean, it's not just
like all of that was fake. Yeah. Yeah.
I just think it got muddled at some point. Yeah. And like, I, you know, maybe there's somebody
like typing out, you know, what these space kids are channeling and then it's converted
into this ELF frequency and it's transmitting to the, you know, space kids brain or whatever.
Well, you know, it's weird you say that because on a lot of the tapes, there's mention of, um,
coupling to the computer data bank is often a term that is thrown around a lot. And this idea that
there are some sort of computers involved. On which end though, because are they recording
what they're saying? No, what you, what you just said, somebody's typing something.
Whoa. Cause they often say, well, now I'm back in the, in the more cynical camp where it's
mind control. Well, they said at one point he said, um, that, you know, the referring to the
channel being that the person, you know, at some point they will become a more reliable
source of data. And there's a lot of talk about, about that. And again, like what we have are tapes
and, and tons of them and hundreds of hours. So like you just, all you can do is piece together.
Well, what did the space kids think? Do they think that they were genuinely tapping into nine,
you know, non-human entities or extraterrestrials? Or do they think that they were
tapping into like some dude on the other end? Like a lot of them probably know the history that
you know, at this point. Well, that's a great question. And I think that's really the best
way to approach it because they, they were involved firsthand. But I think, you know, to answer from
what I know is I actually discovered things about, you know, what I'm talking about with these more
sinister connections that they, they did not know. In fact, um, one of the space kids who I'm close
with, like, yeah, she, she was like, you know, shocked. I, I, I, cause again, what, what they
didn't understand, what I think a lot of people didn't understand who were involved in this project
is like information. I was getting information, like as recent as like six months ago about things
that I didn't know that were like really important to the story. Like this guy, Bob Beck, who was,
who was most certainly CIA, who was at the, at Austin-ing at the time of these exact space kids
experiments, this one of the spaces, like I never even knew, knew that, like you're telling me this
for the first time. So it's a mix between, I think, to be quite honest, I think a lot of them
want to believe that what was happening was genuine. And I think they want to remember the time they had
there as a positive time. And they want to, they don't want to go down the negative path, or they
don't maybe want to accept that the negative path may, may be, you know, the reality. And I don't,
I mean, I would probably do that. I mean, I, you know, so I think, um, some of them want to just
try to say, Hey, look, we were told, we were talking in the nine, we were committing with the
nine. We were, it was a good time. We were young, we were free, you know, et cetera. And a few of them,
um, have become more open. Like the guy from Mexico city, I told you where I think some of the
things that I told them made them say, wait a second, I didn't know that. And all of a sudden,
after all these years, they themselves are going, wait, what is that? And whose name is,
and they're starting to put pieces together that they never, they never thought about. And they're
starting to maybe think at least, okay, something else was going on. What was it? You know, we don't,
we don't know for sure, but I think they're willing to accept like some, something else was going on
back then. One of the trippiest people that interacted with Puharich who, who he probably
had plans for. And it almost seems like the subject of some, you know, kind of maniacal
experiment is Valerie Ransone. Yeah. Who is she? She, well, I wish I knew who she was. She's like
the most elusive person I've ever come across. I think she's the most elusive person in this whole
UFO history. Well, I mean, so basically what I do know is that she was, um,
she was working in the, uh, white house during the, uh, Nixon administration. And it had nothing
to do with like intelligent or maybe it did, but it had nothing to do with intelligence or anything.
It was, it was some sort of, um, uh, program to, I can't remember. It was sort of like a snap
benefits type program. It was something like this, but that's how she was, you know, involved in
government was, she was part of a, a program like that. But apparently she became very interested in
the UFO topic. Uh, she became very good friends with, um, Gordon Cooper and she claimed to be a
space kid, I guess, like she claimed to be able to like channel information. And so she somehow wound
up at Puharich's lab, lab nine and 78. And she is very, there, there's nothing there about her.
There's nothing out there about her. There's a couple of people I know about who have been trying
to track her down for years. They can't, apparently she's still alive, but she basically, um, I believe
was extremely deep in the whole UFO thing. And I think I knew a lot, we have a tape recording of,
um, this guy, Elvis star, who was very, very high up. Uh, I can't remember his exact role. He was like
maybe head of the army in the, in the sixties, some high up role in the army. But anyways, he was very,
very kind of these pictures of him with like every, you know, president during the sixties, seventies,
like there's a tape of him saying like, I met Valerie Ransone in the white house. Um, she
believes she was in touch with extraterrestrials and he kind of makes a joke. Like, what do I know?
Maybe she was, but that kind of firmly places her in that circle. Cause there's a lot of speculation
about like what's true and what's not true. But this was a very legitimate guy basically placing her.
What's, what was his role exactly? He was, um, so from what I understand is, yeah, he was like
the head of, uh, army something or other. And then he went on to become the president of like
West Virginia university, but he was a part of all these like weird science, um, uh, companies
and weird energy companies that were happening in the late seventies. Like there's this, this company
called Magnetic Energies LLC or something that Valerie had some sort of connection to. And this
guy was like consulting for that, or he was connected to a lot of like weird stuff basically.
And it was very little on him other than his more official kind of government roles. But, um, he,
he has this, cause he was writing a memoir and we found this tape where he was kind of like dictating,
um, the, what he was writing. And he says, yeah, I met her. She was in the white house a lot. Um,
she knew a lot of people, but yeah, she basically, she just claimed that she could communicate with
UFOs that were giving her advanced, um, information that she in effect had to pass on to like important
scientists. She predicted the failure of one of these rocket launches in the late seventies that
actually did occur, which I don't, I don't know. You have to look it up.
So, so, so basically she was there, but, but the kicker is like, she was also really involved
in a lot of Tesla technology research, a lot of ELF research, and a lot of people who I know who
were, um, including the space kids, uh, were like, yeah, she was like, she was connected.
She was extremely mysterious. We have no idea what was going on with her. Um,
so they remember seeing her around and then, and then, but, and she was somehow like, do you know
what role she had in the white house or no, uh, other than this guy, Elvis star, basically saying
like, I, I met her on, on numerous occasions at, you know, inside the white house, you can look it
up. I can look it up to you. I, I, I'm sorry. I don't remember, but it was some program that she
like ran in DC and as part of the Nixon administration, which again, was not like
involved in an intelligence thing, but that was her like in with, with that, that world.
And she had some NRO involvement too.
Yeah. Jacques Vallée is the only one I know who wrote about it, but he claims that he, he
spoke with her back in that late seventies time. And she was doing some sort of work for the NRO and,
um, experimenting with satellites and messages from satellites to people. And I'm telling you,
man. Yeah. I mean, I've tried to, I mean, the other film I'm doing, which is a whole other thing,
but she's really involved in that. And that's how I got into her. Cause we have a tape recording
of her. Um, that was a phone call that was recorded, but yeah, if there's like any crazy
enigma in this world that someone needs to like get to the bottom of it's, it's her.
And, uh, I don't know if they ever will. Cause I've certainly tried hard to, and apparently
she's still alive. She's still alive. Yeah. Oh, you gotta go find her, man. Well, I've,
I've, I think I, I think we kind of know where, where she is and stuff, but, but it's really just
strange. She was very involved with Gordon Cooper. And again, he had started some company
as well. That was some like advanced energy LLC or something. And so from what I understand,
she was kind of like going around and even Jacques says this, like she was just trying to create this
network of, of, you know, high up government individuals and people to kind of like start
getting interested in, in advanced technology, Tesla technology, ELF stuff. But all the while she
claimed to be, you know, a space kid and able to receive information and, and channel information.
And so trippy. Yeah. And there's a guy, a kick green. He, um, I mean, I don't even care anymore
at this point about saying stuff like this. Like he, I was talking to him for a while and he was like,
yeah, I can't be involved in anything that mentions Buhar is just too controversial.
And then he told me that he knew Valerie Ranson really well and that he was like,
I don't know much about him again. I'm not trying to cover cause I'm like nervous or anything. I
genuinely don't really know. I just know I've heard a lot about him being like a doc, like a person who
helps like abductee people who claim they're abducted and stuff. So apparently he was doing
that even back then with Valerie and he was working with her, which I don't know what that means
exactly. But he was very, I mean, there's something out there online as that's, you know, very, you
know, open where he talks about this, I think. But, um, anyways, he, I, I was like, Hey, I'm trying
to do this Valerie thing about, he was just like, yeah, no, uh, and like, basically like, don't talk
me again. And anything revolving that name, I can't be associated with. And every single person
I've talked to who knew Valerie or had same reaction. Yeah. I'm literally like, I wouldn't
go there. You should just kind of stop now. And I've gotten all that stuff. So like, what's
going on? What do you think? Do you have it? Well, so for, first of all, a little context
for the audience, Kit Green, um, deeply involved. He's a CIA psychiatrist and doctor.
I knew that, but after all that stuff, I don't really know like what his, he's, he's deeply
involved in like, I think the, whatever CIA files around biological interactions from,
you know, people interacting with UFOs that was given to, um, Gary Nolan in the like mid
2010s. I think that was, I think given by Kit Green and Kit Green analyzed them alongside
Gary Nolan, but he's like a long time guy who kind of pops up in UFO lore, kind of akin
to, uh, how put off, but really seems to be as deep as anybody specifically on kind of
the, uh, psychological kind of, you know, um, you know, neuroscientific dimension of,
of this whole thing. So what, what do you, do you speculate as to what Valerie?
Well, yeah, I have a couple of things, but yeah, the Kit Green thing, again, I'm not,
I did talk to him, I'm not trying to throw him under the bus. I just think he, like, it's
just another example of someone who's like, Oh, her. Yeah. I can't be involved. Like you're
better off, like not going there kind of thing. So as a couple of speculations firstly, and
this came from someone, um, uh, named Bruce Erickson, who's this kind of like new age researcher
guy who, um, I, I know who's really cool, but, uh, he knew her, he knew Valerie really
well. And he, um, painted her in the same light as like, you know, she always happened to
be there whenever something was going on. She always happened to travel with no, no
issues, no money issues. She was always anywhere she needed to be. But, um, he speculates that
she was sort of, um, like a spy and, and the, and the type that would maybe sleep with, with
somebody for information. And a lot of reasons that these men in particular don't want to
talk about her is, you know, I don't need to say it. Maybe something happened now they're
married. They don't want to go there. Maybe that's why it's this very standoffish thing,
which I can get that, but that was his theory. Um, because apparently she was really good.
I mean, there's one photograph that I know literally one that exists of her. That's not
true. There's one online and there's one that I have in the Puharach archives of her
at lab nine. Um, and you know, yeah, she was very good looking. So that was this one theory
is that she was kind of like getting information, um, on behalf of who, I don't know, but this,
you know, you hear about that, uh, happening, you know, sleep to that kind of thing. So that
was what this guy said who knew her. Well, that was his theory. But, um, the other theory
is that she, um, was again with the same idea of being an attractive woman was able to lure
in, uh, individuals to help with funding for certain projects and Hey, I'm a part of this
thing. You should be a part of this thing. Cause again, she was always on these boards of these
sort of weird energy companies and things like that. But, um, the really weird thing is, I don't
know if you've seen it. There's, there's allegedly an interview of her on YouTube. So you, you probably
know this YouTube account, eyes on cinema. Oh yeah. So, so anyways on there, this one day,
this was not even that long. It was like a year ago, this video pops up and it says,
Valerie Ransone, like describes her UFO, um, experience. You can go, anyone can go right
now and look it up. And I was like, holy, holy shit. Like that's her. I've never seen, again,
there's one picture and I'm like, Oh my, this is crazy. Right? So in the interview, it's really
bizarre. She tells us really weird. And the thing is it checks out of what we know from her.
And most of the information is from the forbidden science books, Jacques Vallée stuff. And, you
know, she says, I was going to school in Northern Illinois in this interview. Uh, she says she
moved to Houston. We know Jacques met her in Houston. Uh, the point is everyone I know who
knew Valerie, I said, Oh, this is great. A video exists of her now sent it to them. Hey,
look, here's Valerie. Like, can you believe this? Every, no, that's not her. Nope. That's
definitely not her. I knew her. That's not her. And I said, well, that doesn't make sense.
Cause like everything she says in the video checks out to what we definitely know. Nope.
Not her, not one person. And even this, do you think they were like, they just, again,
didn't want to, I don't know, but it's just, it's so goes back. She's so, she's the biggest
enigma in this whole world. Every single one of them. Nope. Oh man. What, you know, anyone
who thinks that's her as an idiot. And, but everything she says checks out. And in the
video, she tells this crazy story about how she had a UFO experience when she was a kid
in college and her friends saw it. And then after that, she continued to have bizarre, um,
sightings of UFO sightings happened to her in her life many times. And then some guy, you got
to see the video. She says this guy, um, shows up one day to her job and is like, Hey, you
know, I want to take you. I can't remember exactly what she says, but basically this very
mysterious guy shows up, they go out to lunch and he's like, you know, I know that you've
had these UFO experience and he, and he spouts all this stuff about her that no one would otherwise
ever know, like stuff about her family. I know you've had, you had this UFO experience
at this time in this location. So she's shocked, right? So then she says she gets into the car
with this guy because he's driving her home or something. And he gets a tape cassette, puts
it in the car and the tape cassette starts. And it's a voice, a metallic voice basically
saying, you know, I am an A, I'm an ET and I'm here on earth on like a humanitarian mission.
And I, we want you to work with us. You, you're going to be the first, uh, test human to work
with us. And, you know, do you, do you accept this position? And, and then she, she, the
guy parks and she gets out or whatever. And, and she starts to question, okay, what, what's
going on here? Like, was this real? Was this guy trying to like recruit? It's, it's, that's
her story. And, and then after that is when all this stuff happens of her getting involved
with Puhar. Oh, this was like early seventies. She claims this happens. And all this stuff
that we know about is, you know, late 76 and 77, 70. So that's her like origin story, but
apparently it's not her according to everyone who knew her. Oh, that's not her. That's the,
not the right woman. That's not even what she looks like. So on the tape recording we
have, it's, which is a recorded phone conversation, the voice on that, which is most definitely
her sounds it's, it's her on this video. It sounds just sounds the same. It sounds like
that voice. So it's probably her. Yeah. It's so weird. So that's a rabbit hole in and of
itself. But, but basically, yeah, she spent like a good amount of time at lab nine. Um,
and she brought Gordon Cooper there and then she disappeared and everyone who knew her was like,
yeah, I have no idea what happened to her or they're just straight up. Don't want to talk about
her. Uh, I don't know. It's really bizarre. She wrote some book. That's basically all this
like channeled information that she got. Have you read it? Uh, no, I I've, I've skimmed it,
but I think you used to be able to buy it on some odd website, which is now down, but, um,
it's very, very strange. And, um, when I was trying to get in contact with her,
I weirdly, this is a crazy story. I got in, I, this, this guy got in touch with me completely out
of the blue. And this has happened a few times throughout the making of this where like someone
is like, Hey, I heard you got, you have Buharic's archives. I'm really interested in him. And
what do you have? And we should, we should talk and, and that kind of thing. This one guy weirdly
right around the time of trying to, um, try to track down Valerie, he reaches out to me
and he's like, same thing. Hey, I know I'm a, I'm a researcher and I heard your name about Buharic and
this and that. And he's like, you know, have you heard of Valerie Ransone? I said, yeah. He goes,
would you want to talk to her? Cause I'm actually in contact with her. And I'm like, yeah, sure.
And, and so he forwards me an email, which is allegedly from Valerie, which is like,
you know, Hey, uh, you know, let's talk and this and that. And, and one thing led to another,
and this guy just completely ghost disappears. Right. Never heard from him again.
Um, I look him up on Facebook and again, I may, maybe I'm crazy and this stuff has gotten to my
head, but his Facebook looks like the, the, the, the quintessential I'm making a fake Facebook
account. This isn't me kind of thing. Sure. And that, you know, again, I'm very level head that
it really like spooked me out. And then years later, year, this was, we're talking probably
tooth, uh, probably like 2016, 17. I'm talking like, you know, not that long ago, like 2021,
20, he reaches back out to me and is like, Hey, you know, what's going on with the film? And is
there any way I can see it? And did you ever talk to Valerie? If you want, I can try to get,
and I just never responded to the guy again. It was really strange. Wow. And I tried the email
that he had that he claimed was Valerie's. Of course it like, you know, weird. But, well,
what happened when you emailed? Oh, no, nothing. Okay. It wasn't, it didn't kick back, but I just
never, you know, I never got anything back ever. Yeah. But you think you've located her. Yes. And
you're going to try to interview her. That's amazing. Yeah. Well, I hope you do, man. That would be
incredible. Yeah. I mean, there's a lot to get in with, into it with her, but that's,
that's the gist of it. And then just the fact alone that Kit Green was involved with her
back in the late seventies is really strange. So strange. Yeah. And early eighties. Yeah.
This is crazy. It's so, it's like, there's a woman in the Nixon white house who's claimed she's
channeling aliens and also happens to be on the board of all these sort of, you know, spooky science
outfits that seem to stem from exotic Tesla, you know, uh, uh, extra low frequency technology.
It's really wild. And what I can say for, for, again, for a fact is like in the late seventies,
there really was like so much, um, unknown about this potential, like radio frequency weapons. And
it's on YouTube. There's a whole CNN special, which came out a little later. I think it was like 83,
but it was kind of detailing all the research that had gone into like, you know, those, those types
of weapons and, um, you know, radio towers that can beam a certain frequency that can agitate people
and et cetera. So that was kind of like the wild West in the late seventies there of like, I think
people trying to figure out what this is, what can be done with it. And he was just like in, in the
middle of that. And, um, you know, there was a lot of people running around researching that at the
time. And I think there was also a lot of research happening of, um, you know, what's the potential
of this stuff, what's possible with it. Um, so, and Valerie was again, interested in that
and was involved in, in that. So it's so wild. Um, what are the implications for all of this
on modern UFO disclosure, which seems to usually emphasize kind of aerospace contractors, secret,
you know, nuts and bolts, weapons, technology, faster than light travel, that sort of thing.
What are the implications of the stuff you're looking into for, for that? I think it's,
I honestly, I, I think it's more of the same that we talked about earlier. I think there's some,
there's some truth peppered into a lot of, you know, false going on. And I think that that still
happens, you know, I think that's still going on. So, you know, I think the implications are,
it's just still difficult to navigate what's, what's real and what is not real, you know?
And I think it takes people, you know, like you and, and others who are like really seriously
interested in looking into this stuff and talking to people to, to kind of like keep going with it,
you know?
Yeah. Well, this is a, I mean, if they're, you know, it's a big puzzle that we're putting
together. This is a huge piece that I think is missing for a lot of people, you know, prior to
your movie. So I really hope people go check it out. I think it's going to be, you know, make,
make a lot of waves and update a lot of people's understanding of this whole topic. And I loved
it. I thought it was really well made. How can people go find it?
Uh, well, it's going to be for purchase, um, on, you know, iTunes and YouTube and that
kind of thing. Yeah. We're going to do kind of like this, uh, release now with, um, age
of disclosure. Okay. We're going to do like a, you know, you can purchase it for a certain
amount of bundle situation. Yeah. Okay, cool. But there's some interest in, in, um, some
streaming stuff. So any, anything big that, uh, I didn't touch on that I should have
that. Honestly, like, yeah, probably. But I mean, you're, you got your gift that keeps
on giving, man. It's crazy. Oh, um, the one thing I was going to mention is, um, this
is again, an example of something like very recently, like Bobby Ray Inman. Yeah. I know
a lot of people are talking about right now. I called him cause, because he was, uh, head
of, uh, Naval Intelligence, I think during this exact time, um, that Puharj is doing a lot
of space kids stuff, like late seventies into the early eighties and a lot of ELF
stuff. And I just, just called him straight up. And I introduced myself. How'd you get
his number? I found his number online. What? Yeah. I kid you not. It was one of those classic
white pages sites where it was like a bunch of different numbers. And I'm like, none of
these are ever going to work. And I was like, hello. And it was him. It was one of them.
Oh my God. And he was pretty nice, but I just straight up was like, Hey, have you ever
heard, you know, the name Andre at Puharj, do you know, Bob Beck? Cause those are the
two working at that time, um, with the space kids. And he was like, no, I've never, never
heard the name. And he was really nice. And he was just like, if you come across anything
more concrete, you can call me back. And, and, um, but I just figured, huh, maybe he, you
know, something. Cause we know, we know Naval Intelligence at one point, uh, was like a big
funder of Puharj, not, not only back in the fifties, but going into, um, the early eighties
as well. But anyways, he didn't. That's what Harold Malmgren always said. He said the, the
deepest, you know, kind of core was the ONI office of Naval Intelligence. They really knew
the most about this stuff. Yeah. He, he, Puharj was in with them very early on and he continued.
In fact, there was a, um, scientist working with Puharj at the, this time, Elizabeth Rauscher.
Hmm. She passed away, but they got like this huge grant from the, the ONI. And I was like,
you know, looking everywhere to try to find dog. Like she has a huge archive at Berkeley
of all of her research. And I, I had someone go there and look and we couldn't find anything,
but, but, um, you know, they, they were working with a lot of people then. Um, but yeah, Inman,
uh, didn't come up with anything. So yeah.
Well, he might have reasons to withhold information as well. He was the, I think, uh, uh, deputy director
of the CIA and the director of the NSA at the same time, I believe.
Yeah. Something like that. Um, oh, the other thing. Yeah. The last thing I'll say is, uh,
not unlike Valerie, one of the, uh, space kids who we did an interview cause we couldn't find her,
but she's on a lot of these tapes. So it was this woman named Sharon. So, um, you know, Sharon with
two Rs and like Valerie, you know, huge question mark. Everyone who knew her then was like, she was
this very legitimate, real psychic Puharich. Apparently we'd bring her around, show her off
to people in government and academics and just say like, look what she can do. She can channel
all this advanced information. He was always working with her. There's pictures of her
and she just disappeared. And everyone who knew her back then was like, you know, it would be
amazing if you found her because she, they're convinced that she was pulled into a, you know,
stranger things, Montauk project type project where like she was the real deal and she was sort
of pulled into a project like that. That's why she's just kind of like wiped off the face of the
earth. There's nothing about her anywhere. Again, I went to the great lengths to try to locate her
nothing. Does this people don't want to like Valerie. They don't want to talk about her when you
bring her up. So that was another example of like, okay, maybe there's some reality here because
it's just so bizarre. And like multiple space kids were like, yeah, I knew her well. And I wish
we could find her. Like she was a friend of mine and she disappeared.
Just like she was, the whole program was a feeder maybe into something deeper.
Yeah. There's a lot of conspiracy stuff like that out there, but people think that his,
yeah, Puharich's lab was, was that. So.
Do you, does this add to your conviction? You know, I think even the makers of stranger things
say that, uh, it's based off of, you know, the Montauk experiments. And I think it's pretty well
established that there were some experiments in Montauk Long Island. Does this add to your
conviction that, I don't know, you hear all these things around gifted and talented education,
you know, uh, kids who do, who have psi abilities being taken into secret national labs facilities,
often associated with the Atomic Energy Commission or federally funded research and development
centers like Battelle Memorial Institute and others. And, um, you know, they're, they're told
to like, you know, how do you interact with this exotic piece of metal or, uh, you know, pick a card
or, you know, things like that. Does this add to your conviction that this was happening in sort of a
widespread way?
Yeah. Oh yeah. Puharich himself. Um, again, if you choose to believe, you know, what he says,
he, he openly says, I helped locate these kids. He, he talks about it. I mean, he says like,
I was the person who would say, you know, yeah, this, you know, this one checks out and they would
move on to wherever they would move on to. Um, he talks about helping other countries with this,
the UK. He said he traveled to the UK and help them locate children with psi abilities. So
it's all that, it's all that gray area, you know?
Yeah. And you, you have to ask why this stuff is coming back into vogue. Like you have the
telepathy tapes top the podcast charts in the entire country. And part of me is thinks it's a
beautiful, amazing thing. And obviously I, in my opinion, I think, I don't think it's all
a psyop. I think that some of these autistic nonverbal children are actually, they do have
really amazing abilities. It's unfortunate that some of them, like this woman that went on Danny
Jones, um, I think are actually faking things as the mother of one of the kids. And she clearly
was peaking past this blind fold, which is, it's just so sad. And what a poor representation
of, you know, again, what I think is an underlying real phenomena, but does it, does it make you
ask questions around why is all of this stuff coming back into vogue? It feels like if you
were to take an index of aliens, psi and psychedelics, um, and you were to, you were to, you know,
invest, like say it's like a, you know, synthetic derivatives, like an ETF or something. If you were
to invest in this in the late sixties, early seventies, you'd like lose a lot of money into
today. But now if you were to invest in these things five years ago or something, it's just
feels like they're all taking off. Like it feels like the trend is like, and are you cynical about
that? Is, is there, is there, I mean, maybe even to take that ETF analogy further, are there
financial or corporate interests behind the repopularization of some of these things?
Cause a part of me is extremely idealistic about them coming out because I do think it
touches on kind of deeper architectures and nature of reality. And then there's another
part of me where I'm like, it's gotta be coming out now cause of some military industrial complex
reason or something.
I don't know. I mean, I think, I certainly think this film is going to help, you know,
put some pieces together about the history of all this stuff. And I think the fact that
it's coming out now is interesting because of all this, you know, this resurgence of interest
in it. But, um, I know what you mean. I don't know. Like I talked to a kid who claimed he was
part of the gate program and I won't say his name, but now, now he's very vocal online about
his involvement in that and what he did. And he wanted to talk to me because it was so similar
to the stuff, the space kids did that he read about, but I don't know what's, I don't know
what to believe, you know, with that. So it's just, I don't know. I'm in the same, I'm in the
same boat as you. I don't know what, what the motives may be, but I think that Puharic was
certainly extremely important in this whole world. And the fact that there's never really
been something like on him that's out there is, um, exciting for me, obviously. So yeah,
I think it'll, I think it'll raise some eyebrows.
I think so too. Raise some eyebrows, maybe ruffle some feathers, but you know, you know, you're
on the right path if you do that. But, um, Greg, this is an honor, man. This is a lot of fun.
One of my, honestly, like I love information dense podcasts, especially ones that are
uncorrelated from other, you know, I love the, the stories, you know, I love, I saw a thing and
I was in the bed and I wasn't, you know, they put a chip in me like that's, it's fascinating,
but you, it's always hard to sense make after that. Like, how does this fit into some coherent
tapestry of what's actually happening? I love this interview because you just, to me, again,
you know, you, you added this big puzzle piece, uh, that seems to be missing as far as this whole
story. And obviously it begets, uh, you know, a hundred more questions, but, um, I really hope
everybody checks out the movie and, uh, thank you for being here. Thank you, man. I appreciate it.
Awesome. Yeah.
Head to AmericanAlchemyMerch.com to grab official American Alchemy merch and support the show
directly. And while you're there, the Cowboy UFO T is a fan favorite. We always keep in stock
along with the atomic age design. Thank you all so much for following and supporting the show.
Have a great day.