There we see a wreck, and there we see something in there.
And then this thing popping up on the screen.
My next guest is a world-famous treasure hunter.
You heard that right.
His name is Dennis Asperg.
And this Swedish sensation is a real-life superhero
out of a different era.
I'm a curious guy.
I've always been interested in finding things
that nobody else has found.
But on June 19th, 2011,
his life's mission would change forever.
From unearthing human treasure
to unraveling the nature of reality itself.
That's when he came upon what you might call an underwater UFO,
or what's now known as a USO,
an unidentified submersible object in the very remote Baltic Sea.
It's something that makes our instrument go wild sometimes.
It's on the ocean floor right now.
So me, my crew, and Ammar Kandil from Yes Theory
went to go see it.
Sitting 90 meters below the surface,
60 meters wide,
this is one of the weirdest objects
ever detected by humans in the ocean.
Period.
Yeah, it's round,
and then we have these corridors.
You have angles, 90 degrees angles.
When you say corridors, like...
Yeah, you have a corridor,
and you have walls, flat walls.
Wow.
Dennis has now confirmed
that it is not attached to the seabed floor,
so it's not a natural geological formation.
I have never seen anything like that before,
not have my colleagues either.
Electromagnetic anomalies are rampant around it.
It breaks down GPS, subsea rovers, drones.
And then when we have used the Aero-V,
the Aero-V stops working.
Really?
Yep.
You lost GPS?
You were close to the...
To the object?
Yeah.
Oh, my God.
We have video of smoke
coming out of the water above the object,
as if it's fuming or emitting gas.
And then you see, like, it's from this hole,
this milk is going...
Uh-huh.
...and on.
Like it was...
Something is moving.
Yes, breathing.
Breathing.
Yeah.
Almost like a biological organism or something.
But it doesn't stop there.
It was literally struck by lightning,
an occurrence often considered a high watermark
for its unlikeliness.
We also have video of NATO ships
encircling this object
and tracking Dennis' Ocean X crew
in the middle of the Baltic Sea.
We had a meeting at the headquarter in Stockholm.
I said to one of the people there,
have you been there?
Have you dive on it?
And he just looked at me,
no, no, no, no.
We have not been there.
But I'm filming you.
I have filmed you.
So I know you have been there.
Nothing.
He don't say anything.
Whoa.
You'll get to see the full extent
of what we found at the end of this video.
Whether this is an ancient sacred temple,
a crashed unidentified flying object,
or an unidentified submersible object,
whatever this thing is,
it's definitively weird.
And like the object under the mesa at Skinwalker Ranch,
it seems to have a life of its own.
So without further ado,
sit back, relax,
and prepare to take a deep dive into the abyss
with this week's amazing Swedish alchemist,
Dennis Asperg.
So we're 60 kilometers out at sea,
kind of the epicenter between Finland and Sweden.
We're right above the spot,
right above the Baltic Sea anomaly.
And it just feels like we're in the middle of the ocean,
to be honest.
It doesn't feel any different than anywhere else.
One of our videographers, Phillip,
unfortunately threw up.
I think I'm the only person
who hasn't taken the seasickness medication,
which is probably pretty stupid.
Now we're sending the ROV down,
the remote-operated vehicle,
and we can see what it sees,
although visibility will be low,
so you can only see maybe max,
maybe a foot in front of it.
And then we're also going to be doing some sonar scanning
and try to get a better understanding
of the 3D structure
that we're looking at with the Baltic Sea anomalies.
And how deep is the object?
90 meters.
Yeah.
It's a very unconventional career that you have.
When did you start to get into treasure hunting
and exploring all of these unknown things in the ocean?
Exploring and have been interesting in history
and all that thing,
have been since I was a kid.
Something I grew up with with my parents
because they were also interesting in that area
to find out things and search for things
that nobody else have found.
So it's a natural thing.
I have, you know, grown up in a family
that works, not works,
but have an interest in that field.
So...
Was your father an explorer?
No, he was a diver,
but he had an other job also,
but he was a diver also.
Okay.
Yeah.
And did you grow up, you know,
reading about explorers?
Yeah, that was the...
Yeah, yeah, of course.
Reading history books, of course,
and fictions also,
and going into these things
with the treasures and shipwrecks
that have disappeared with interesting cargo.
So that has been interesting for me
and, you know,
that has always been the interest for me.
What was the first shipwreck
you went looking for?
When I really go into commercial diving
and in that area was for...
I mean, it must be 15, 20, 20 years ago.
And it was together with Peter Lindberg,
my friend,
and we did exploration in the Baltic Sea
and we found wrecks with liquor,
cognac and wine
and different type of things.
Booth ships.
That's the money.
That's...
The booze are still valuable.
Yeah, of course.
Of course.
And it's still drinkable and...
Yeah, some bottles are still drinkable.
We found also one of the oldest wine in the world
from 1600.
Wow.
Drinkable.
Oh my God.
And cognac on its way to this Russian Tsar.
Drinkable.
And we have tried it also, Peter and I,
and it was very strong.
Unbelievable.
Yeah.
What's some of the more interesting shipwrecks
that you found,
or maybe one in particular
that you remember that has a story attached to it?
Except the Baltic Sea anomaly.
We're building up to that.
Wow.
It's many, I must say.
But one very interesting wreck we found
was 2015.
We found the Russian Tsar's submarine, SOM.
Wow.
Yeah, built in US, 1904.
Oh my God.
And the Russian Tsar bought it
and used it in the war against Japan.
Uh-huh.
And it was out on a mission
in the Swedish water.
Should not be in the Swedish water.
Uh-huh.
It was.
And it was a collision
between a Swedish cargo ship
and this submarine.
So the periscope went off
and 18-man down to the bottom.
How do you,
what sensors do you use
to locate an object?
Uh, it's very easy.
It's a side-scan sonar.
It's a sonar that looks down
to the image you get.
Okay.
Of it.
Uh, so,
and then we use ROV
and of course we have dive on it also.
What's ROV?
A remote operating robot,
you know, underwater.
A little sub-seedule.
Yeah, exactly.
Okay.
So that we have used
and after that,
we did dives on it also
to really identify it
and see if it was that submarine
we have,
we thought it was.
So interesting.
And so when you find
these shipwrecks,
you know,
uh,
with cognac and wine
and that sort of thing,
is this your business?
Do you then go out
and sell that on the open market?
Oh, I wish.
I wish.
Do you know?
Or do you have financiers?
No, we have,
as you know,
we have the situation here
as we have in other countries
in the whole world
with the pandemic
and the virus
and also the,
the war
and lots of things
are going on.
So it has not been easy.
Uh,
so we tried to sell this,
uh,
wine and cognac
and things on the market
and the interest was zero.
Mm.
Now,
nobody was interested.
No way.
No.
That's why you said
you drank it.
Yeah,
I drank it myself.
at home now
instead.
No,
uh,
no,
no.
So it has been very difficult
because we have spent
lots of time
and money on this project
because we believe
this can,
this can finance
our other projects.
Yeah.
But the interest
has been weak,
very weak
when it's come to that.
Interesting.
Yeah.
So do you ever,
are you ever able to sell
or make a business
out of,
you know,
some of the stuff you find
or is it mostly
just for passion
or for history?
No, no.
I mean,
in that case,
when it's talking
about the bottles
of champagne
and cognac
and wine
and things like that,
of course,
we have it
and hopefully
we're going to sell it
in the future.
Yeah.
But I don't,
you know,
I won't have
lots of money for it.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So, but that is something
I don't think about
so much now.
Should invite myself
over for a drink.
You can get the drink,
of course.
Tell us about
the Baltic Sea anomaly.
The Baltic Sea anomaly,
yeah.
What is it?
Wow, good question.
The Baltic Sea anomaly,
okay,
it begins like this.
We were out
on a mission,
this time to find
a wreck,
special wreck
with champagne on it.
We were out
for almost a week
and then we have
problems with the boat
that began to leak
and we almost sunk
with the boat.
So it was very scary
but we managed
to come to a harbor
in Finland
to repair the boat
and we had been out
for one week then.
And then we decided
to go out
to a new area
and search there
with the Sidescan Zona
to see if we find
this special wreck.
We were out
and we searched
in a new area.
We were quite tired,
I must say,
after one week
and then we had
all the problems
with the boat,
the leaking and so on.
So we were tired
and disappointed.
We have not found
the wreck yet.
But now we're going
to search in a new area
and hopefully
we're going to find it.
It was nighttime,
I think it's one or two
at night.
Me and Peter
and our friend
Floris,
we are sitting
in front of the screen
and we have
the Sidescan Zona
in the water
and there we see
a wreck
something in there.
And then this thing
popping up on the screen.
This huge thing.
I mean,
we're talking about
60 meter in diameter
and it's round
and you have this track
at the bottom.
so I remember
Peter laughing
and oh Dennis,
you know,
he's a UFO
and I was like,
what?
Then we begin
really to look at it
and it was
so odd
and nobody else
have seen anything
like that before.
Anything like that.
And round potholes
you can see,
of course,
mines and things
from the
Second World War.
But in this case
we're talking about
the big thing
60 meter in diameter.
So it's 3,000 square meters.
Round thing
in the middle
of the ocean.
3,000 square meters.
Yeah.
So huge.
Yeah, it's huge.
Wow.
Yeah.
And nobody had ever
seen anything like it.
And it was round?
It was like a circular?
Yes, round.
And then we have
these corridors.
You have angles,
90 degrees angles
and so on.
So it looked like
an artificial structure.
Yeah, it looks like that.
We went home then
after we had done this
with the side scan sonar
and we go deeper
into looking at
this data we have on it
and Peter and I
were sitting in front
of a computer
measuring, you know,
that, okay,
what is possible?
Can it be that
or construction
from the military time
or from the world war
and so on?
I know it cannot be
any things like that.
And then we talked
to friends
in the same area
as we are
in US,
Australia
and Europe
and showed them
the pictures
and they said,
no, we have never
seen anything like that.
What have you found?
Where did you find this?
No, no, no, no.
We don't say anything
about that.
So then
after one week
or something
we don't get
any help.
I decide
or we decide
to go out public
with it
because I want
to have somebody
can say what it is
because we
we have experience
of course
when it's come
to exploring
and shipwrecks
and we have
never seen anything
but perhaps
somebody have seen
something like that.
So I talked
to a journalist
here in Stockholm
Expressen
as a big newspaper
and I went there
with my laptop
and showed them
the data
and they,
you know,
they were very surprised
about that.
And then I
explained for them
the purpose
we were out there
we were searching
for that and that wreck
and then we found
this instead.
So they were
oh wow
and then
they're sending up
me to the office
and I talked
to the manager
or chief there
and then
I understand
that they are
interested to public
and they go out
with this information
and I said
okay do it
hopefully
we find somebody
that can
help us
with this
because we don't
know
we don't know
and we have
friends that
don't even know
about it.
So
that was the start
of something
crazy.
Yeah
it was
because I was never
in the spotlight
before
and
in one
I mean
the first week
was in the Swedish
news
and then Scandinavian
and then after that
week after
it was international
news
and my phone
is ringing
all the time
day and night
and I turn
it off
sometimes
because I was
so tired
so I talk
about the same
thing
like over
and over
with all the
journalists
and I say
the same thing
I find something
I don't know
what it is
but it's odd
it's strange
it's unique
we have never
seen anything
like that.
As you know
on American Alchemy
we cover a lot
of technology
that goes beyond
human limits
this is about
technology that
helps the body
catch up
and feel good
I'm talking about
the iRestore LED
face mask
a red light therapy
system that uses
clinical grade
wavelengths
to boost
skin cell
energy production
the same exact
principle used
in the top
recovery clinics
and bio-optimization
labs in the world
I've been using it
most nights
10 minutes
while I'm reading
prepping for a show
or decompressing
it's completely
hands-free
comfortable
and engineered
to deliver
consistent light
intensity
across the face
not that uneven
scatter
most cheaper
masks use
it feels like
your face
is taking
a warm bath
what it's doing
is called
photobiomodulation
stimulating mitochondria
to repair tissue
reduce inflammation
and improve circulation
you actually feel
the calm
and rejuvenation
after a session
I've tested
a few of these
this one really
stands out
for the build quality
it feels like
it was built
in a high precision
lab
and it's not
just a cheap
beauty gadget
so if you're into
real evidence-based
recovery tech
this belongs
in your setup
head to
iristore.com
and use code
jessie25
for an exclusive
discount
again
iristore.com
code
jessie25
red light therapy
has really been
a game changer
for me
so I hope you love it
and the size
and the size is odd
and the right angle
how many right angle
you know
no it's plenty of them
it's a big object
and then you have
corridors with angles
and you have also
holes in it
a hole with like
two meters in diameter
with a frame around it
and also
when you say corridors
like
yeah
you have a corridor
and you have walls
flat walls
wow
totally flat
it's like almost like
and then you have
90 degrees angles
like that
yeah yeah yeah
so
I don't think
I'm not sure
that's what we try
to figure out now
can the nature
create this
I don't know
but it's so odd
and so strange
doesn't look like coral
or any sort of rock
that you would see
on the seafloor
and you must be
familiar as somebody
who has probably
traversed a lot of the world
and looked at the ocean floor
for a lot of your life
yeah
and I'm sure a lot of the people
working with you
at the time as well
yeah
so it's
no it's
very very strange
and
not only that
it looks odd
and strange
we have been out there
a couple of times
and every time
we have been out there
we have problems
with our equipment
what just happened
to the boat
you lost it
you lost GPS
you were very close
to the object
oh my god
like what happened
the radar
showing
things that should not
are not there
so one time
we are there
and the radar
is working properly
but then
something popping up
on the radar
and
I remember
Peter said to me
that Dennis
look at the screen
and I look
what
okay
and I go out
and
we are alone here
but
should be something
150 meters from us
nothing there
and then
another position
how big are the objects
showing up on the radar
no no you cannot see
how big it is
on the radar
okay
but you see
something
some object
yeah
and then when we have
used the arrow V
the arrow V
stops working
really
yep
and when we have dive
on it
the camera stops working
the light stops working
so there must be
some sort of electromagnetic
probably
and the GPS function
is not working
properly either
really
so there's maybe
magnetic anomalies
as well
where
yeah
that's what I think
every time we are there
even
now
in June
when we were out
we have the same problem
equipment malfunction
every time
yes
you gotta go down
in a Faraday cage
or something
yeah
so that was
very strange
also
that we have
these problems
and we were out
again now
this June
and
with another ship
Stockholm University's
own ship
with their own equipment
not mine equipment
yeah
that's perfect
and it's
much better equipment
that I have
sure
that's old things
but
so
we were out
and I remember
I talked to the crew
and also Tomas
the captain on board
and mentioned for him
all the experience
we have out there
with all the
equipment
stopped working
and all the stuff
you know
GPS and so on
and then
we were quite close
and Tomas
said to me
okay
let's start then
we begin
with a multi-beam
so we get the 3D
image of the object
yeah
perfect weather
good conditions
for everything
and then we go
over the object
and Tomas
said to me
Dennis
we have problems
with the GPS function
and I look at him
are you joking with me
no Dennis
we have problems
with it
with the GPS
do you used to
have problems
with it
nope
what happened
with the GPS
it's not working
lost connection
totally
really
yep
and then we go
over it
and go back
and
the same thing
again
wow
yeah
so interferes
with radio signals
changes compasses
yep
messes with the
subsea drone
and rover
so there's
there's some
sort of electromagnetic
thing going on
down there
and you said
you know
what the color
is now
what's the color
now Stefan
was one of the
divers down there
and he brushed
off the sediment
of it
and it's dark
black
dark gray
almost black
interesting
so he touched it
yeah of course
and when he touched it
he tried to take
samples also
did not manage that
either
too hard
yeah
interesting
and when he touched
it did he feel
anything
or notice anything
that I don't
no he did not
mention anything
about that
but he said
it's very odd
and he had never
seen anything
like that before
and then one
thing I remember
when he's coming up
he said to me
that the temperature
usually
at that
depth
is around
four to five
degrees
celsius
yeah
now it's most
almost zero
that you know
is not possible
interesting
so almost zero
degrees
almost freezing
so it's alarming
in his equipment
yeah yeah yeah
so he must have
been very cold
and then he go to a hole
like 20 centimeters
in diameter
and when you're down
there you have the sediment
and you get like milky
the waters get milky
as you understand
yeah yeah yeah
yeah dusty
and then you see
like it's from this hole
this milk is go in
and out
and in
like it was
something is moving
yes breathing
breathing
yeah
almost like a biological
organism or something
yeah
wow
but it was hard
yeah
too hard to get a sample
from
yeah it cannot
perhaps if you drill
the core drilling
or something
but there's
there's a hole
where
sand is coming in
and out
yeah
that's so fascinating
if all these anomalies
that you've experienced
yeah
do they increase
when you get closer
to the object
so i guess
the way you would
instantiate that
it would be like
if you had
the rov
or if you had
maybe a compass
and you were getting
closer
does it get
more intense
the closer you get
the anomalies get
more intense
the closer
yeah
we have problems
with the equipment
the closer we get
and it's a clear rate
of acceleration
or increase
of the
oh wow
so it really feels
like it's a source
I forgot something
it's important
2019 we were out
and
I know
we were out
in Finland
I did
diving work there
and
we had some friends
there that we have
done
expeditions
with before
and
I remember
the laugh
you know
Finnish guys
Dennis
you're yuking
you know
you don't believe
in that
it's a stone
you have found
they said to me
yeah of course
perhaps it's a stone
but still
it's unique
you have not
seen anything
no that's right
Dennis
so next
next time
we're going out
can you come along
then with your
equipment
okay okay
he said
and then after
a couple of months
I said to them
that we're gonna
go out now
on a mission
you want to come
along
with your
equipment
your ROV
and everything
so
they come to
Sweden
and
go out
with the ship
and
Peter and I
are just
you know
checking what they're
doing
their equipment
and coming to
the spot
and
they
go down
with the ROV
and he's sitting
there
and the first
thing
when he's coming
down there
is
okay
dude
this is
strange
this must be
man-made
this is
constructed
and I just
what
what did I
hear
and I look
at Peter
and he said
yeah
so
so even
the skeptics
when you bring
them to see
it firsthand
they understand
directly
it was something
for sure
that we have
found
something
that is
odd
and
yeah
and you must
be familiar
given that you
have an interest
in UFOs
with the fact
that you have
electromagnetic
anomalies
occurring
in many UFO
sightings
and cases
even
close encounters
of the third
kind
you see
the main
character
with this
you know
big sort
of
almost like
sunburn
because
they're basically
experienced
this sort
like basically
a redshift
of you know
electromagnetic
light
and you know
Travis Walton
is another good
example where
he's in Arizona
with his friends
he gets out
of the truck
he touches
the UFO
and he gets
almost kind
of zapped
because of
the electromagnetic
activity
there's
geomagnetic
anomalies
where a lot
of UFOs
show up
so places
like Skinwalker
Ranch
or Mount
Sengun Mori
in Japan
next to the
Fukushima Prefecture
their nuclear
civilian grid
you always
have these
geomagnetic
anomalies
Hesselden
you have
you know
magnetic
anomalies
as well
so that
is a common
theme
in UFOs
yeah
I remember
what he said
also
when he was
done with
the ROV
this Finnish
guy
and he said
it looks
like a
power line
it's
something
very
like a
power line
we don't
have any
power lines
there
nothing
looked like
a power line
no but
you know
the
with the
instrument
they're using
on the
ROV
was
something
that is
putting out
energy
of some kind
wow
it is
it looks
very strange
it might
it might be
a cloud
of methane
that it's
a methane
seep
from the
bottom
I don't know
how
close we
can go
but
we have seen
this
growing now
for a while
it's
lots
of
things
and
even
weather
phenomena
like
thunder
and lots
of things
just on the
spot
really
yeah
that's
fascinating
I forgot
lots of
things
when I'm
talking
to you
but
lots of
things
have
happened
out
there
thunder
on
the
spot
and
like
nowhere
else
yeah
exactly
and
like
the
does
lightning
hit
the
water
yeah
really
so
it's
like
a
conductor
or
something
it's
true
oh my god
we have
filmed that
also
you've
filmed
that
oh
this is
amazing
the most
exciting
thing
ever
so
now
all
the
things
together
that
you know
you cannot
let it
go
you must
that's
why I
have
fight for
this
for so
long
time
I mean
if you
just
list
the
anomalies
you have
biological
material
in a
dead
right angle
corners
you have
an object
that's
180 meters
so it's
very big
you have
it's hard
you see
that's
detached
from the
seafloor
you have
electromagnetic
anomalies
that it's
causing
then you
have
thunder
conducting
hitting it
I think
that's
extremely
and then
you have
a team
of people
who have
been diving
for
each
for decades
all
having
tons of
data points
and they've
never seen
anything
like it
so I think
that's
very worthy
of investigation
and so
some people
might be wondering
because you
described it
as a round
object
but it also
had right angles
and right angle
corners and stuff
how does that
work exactly
it's not a flat
disc
as many
perhaps
things
it's a quite
rough surface
around it
and then you
have these
corridors
and angles
so
and it's
not round
in the corners
it's rough
it's
perhaps
it's broken
okay
have been there
for a while
so the circumference
is 180 meters
but if you look
at from upside
it's round
but still
it's
there's some
jagged
right angles
and stuff
and right angles
in a way
where it's not
just
a little sliver
or whatever
it's like
longer right angles
that apply
artificial construction
yes
fascinating man
yeah
it is
for sure
have you
seen
all the
remote
viewers
that have
done
all the
things
about
Baltic Sea
remote
no
have they
yeah
when we were
in Sweden
I called
Joseph McClonegal
and Angela Ford
and they helped
us with this
retreat
so we should
do it
I don't have
reception
right
we don't
have any
connection
I was gonna
say
I could
easily
call them
well what
do they
say
what do
the remote
viewers say
that is
constructive
and it's
some have
said it
made of
gold
really
yeah
it's
some kind
of energy
source
really
yeah
energy source
for what
I don't know
so which remote
viewers say
this
there are lots
of it
I have
I can send
you the link
oh yeah
please
I'm gonna
write it
but the cool
thing is also
when the
Finnish guy
our colleague
from Finland
was here
he mentioned
okay
this is man
made
this must
be constructed
and I
and it looks
like it's
a high voltage
thing
and I
just
high voltage
so that's
like a
something that
put out
high voltage
like a power
who said
that
the Finnish
guy
wow
and I have
it on tape
also
that's
amazing
I have it on
tape
we have
film
and everything
really
yeah
oh my god
and
the meteor
that happened
the day
after
we went
home
yeah
that's
crazy
what's
the story
there
oh
you know
I did
not see
it
but
it was
on the
news
that
happened
on earth
yeah
like
one or two
times per year
a meteor
impacts earth
one or two
times per year
yeah
and the day
and so
so you
went out
here
I was here
exactly
on the way
home
on my way
the day
after
what year
were you
here
oh
just
in june
oh
okay
yeah
so
it was
in the news
that the big
meteor
are over
Åland
and over
here
wow
or perhaps
they're going
down
and was it
like
pretty much
in the center
of the baltic
sea
yeah
whoa
crazy
right after
you went
and there
was
was no
sonic boom
or there
was a sonic
yeah
it was
there was
a sonic
boom
yeah
whoa
lots
of witnesses
to that
crazy
yeah
for sure
so
some sort
of energy
you know
there's
a guy
named
Christopher Dunn
yeah
he thinks
that the
pyramid
is an
energy
generator
yeah
I heard
so I wonder
perhaps
it's a connection
I don't know
yeah
never know
but we will
find out
I can't wait
and so
how do you
get to the
bottom of
something like
this
like what
do you
what steps
do you even
take to
figure out
what this
is
yeah
you know
I'm a
explorer
and a treasure
hunter
I'm quite good
at that
when it's come
to find
things
and when
it's come
to this
with
find out
what this
is
you know
that's why
I have
this
geolog
and
people
from the
university
that helps
me
and they
have opened
the doors
for me
and I have
one person
that I must
you know
she's
wonderful
and that's
Beatrice Villarelle
that's the person
that opened
the doors
for me
before that
I mean
for 15 years
I have tried
to get
attention
people get
interesting in this
and I have been
at places
and I talked
about that
and they say
oh Dennis
it's very interesting
but you know
I don't want
to get involved
in this
you know
the stamp
UFO
and things
like that
my company
but it's interesting
I follow you
but nothing else
and then I met
Beatrice
two years ago
I think
and
because I have
always been
since 96
and of course
when we found
the Baltic Sea
interesting
in Europe
UAPs
and
and then
I've
you know
met Beatrice
for the first time
and
and we find
each other there
and we have
the same interest
to find out
what's going on
around us
because I'm
already convinced
100% convinced
so
and I'm
you know
I'm a doer
I do it
I'm working for it
and I don't give up
and it's the same thing
with Beatrice
we're working together
now
she opened the doors
she had the keys
so the scientists
we are working with
now are
very excited
and have been
out there now
with us
so we're gonna go
out again
because it's unique
they have never seen
anything like that
either
so
wow
that's great
and these are guys
with experience
of underwater objects
and ocean objects
and that sort of thing
they all say
they've never seen
anything like this
exactly
and
you made a video
recently
that went kind of
viral on Twitter
where you say
you know
I've seen some
really amazing things
with the Baltic Sea anomaly
you know
we're gonna talk
about this soon
is there anything
you can speak to
about that
like what you found
in this last trip
because you just
went out there
right
I was out there
it's so interesting
that we must go out
again
with a scientist
because I
I trust them
because I have no experience
when it's come to that
so if they're saying
Dennis
this is
this is interesting
we have not seen
anything like that
we must go out again
and take more measurements
and you test that
and that and that
with different
type of instruments
and so on
when they are saying that
I get
as you know
I'm always on the hunt
for things
that help me stay
sharp
focused
and full of energy
while I'm diving
into life's mysteries
and making this show happen
and I've got to say
mud water
has completely
transformed my mornings
back in the day
I used to struggle
with that post-coffee crash
and let's not even get
into the caffeine jitters
mud water gave me
the smooth
steady energy
I was missing
it's packed
with functional mushrooms
like lion's mane
chaga
and reishi
plus turmeric
and cacao
all working together
to keep me
focused
calm
and grounded
honestly
it's like coffee
went on a yoga retreat
and came back zen
what I love most
is that it's not just
about replacing coffee
it's a whole new ritual
it's a simple
nourishing way
to start the day
and I actually
look forward to it
every morning
every ingredient
is USDA
certified organic
vegan
non-gmo
and there's
zero sugar
it's energy
that doesn't mess
with your sleep
or make you
question your life
choices at 3am
ready to make
the switch
to cleaner energy
head to mudwater.com
that's mudwtr.com
and grab your
starter kit today
right now
our listeners
get an exclusive
deal up to
43% off
your entire order
plus free shipping
and a free
rechargeable frother
when you use
code jessie
that's right
up to 43%
off with
code jessie
at mudwtr.com
after your purchase
they'll ask you
how you found them
please show your
support and let
them know we
sent you
keep your energy
natural and
refreshing all year
long with mudwater
because life's too
short for anything
less than clean
delicious energy
did you pick up
anything in this
last trip or
detect anything
new that was
exciting
not pick up
anything we
have new data
okay
that's what I
can say
okay
and anything
about the new
data
or it's
I'm a little
careful to go
out with the
new data now
it looks like
it's separated
from the bottom
that's what I
can say
separated from
the bottom
that's amazing
it's not a
geological formation
I don't know
it looks
sounds like
it's not
I must be a
little careful
that
but yeah
it's
I don't know
so fascinating
and so
what's the next
step
after this
it's more
testing
or
yeah
of course
it's lots
of things
we must do
it's of course
to go out
again and take
core samples
not from the
object as I
understand it
because that's
quite difficult
so but
if we succeed
this time
to get
more data
that are
very interesting
of course
we must go
out again
and take
core samples
but that
equipment is
quite expensive
so core sample
take from the
object
from the
so this would
be like
drilling into
it
yeah
and that's
not easy
sure
yeah
and it costs
lots of money
so
but I hope
it's so interesting
that we do
a core drilling
yeah
has anybody
thought to
stick their
hand in the
hole
that's breathing
in this
believe me
yeah many
and even I
but you haven't
done it
no no no
we have not
done it
I mean
it's a risk
we don't know
that's a risk
for sure
but as
Beatrice and
I have talked
we have talked
about that
perhaps we're
going to use
the ROV
the smaller
ROV
to go in
yeah we have
this big hole
yeah
like two meters
in diameter
yeah
I mean the ROVs
cost lots of money
but perhaps
it's worth
does the ROV
have like
night vision
can it correct
for it
it must be dark
down there
no you don't
see anything
really
even if you
have the
you must have
a sonar on it
okay so you put
the sonar
on the
yeah I have
the sonar
on the ROV
so I see
everything around
it
and it's
a side scan
sonar
so you end
up with
the 2D
no no
it's not
a side scan
sonar
side scan
is something
you have
between
behind your
boat
or ship
okay
when you try
to find
anything
then you have
a blue
you sonar
on the
ROV
okay
there you can
see
a front
like a picture
in the front
of you
okay
there you have
no visibility
there you can
see anyway
it's like a radar
okay it's like
radar
interesting
so you basically
get the structural
formation
yeah of course
you can see
small details also
but you can't
see optical right
you don't see
an image
no it depends
if you're lucky
you can see
perhaps a 30
or 50 centimeters
in front of you
okay
a little bit
yeah
it's difficult
that is fascinating
yeah it is
so interesting
when you started
to talk
to the press
about this
even back
you know
years ago
yeah
why do you think
like military
or aerospace
or I don't know
anybody
didn't want to
check it out
themselves
like authorities
they did
how do you know
they were lurking
around in the waters
when we were there
really
yeah
how do you know
I filmed it
they were authorities
were they Swedish
they were NATO
it's for French
and German
American British
ships
around us
really
yep
and then also
a Swedish
coast corvette
go quite close
to us
suddenly we saw
in the distance
that this
must be
some kind of
navy ship
heading
directly on us
turn out
to be a navy
ship
and actually
a Swedish one
and it
shouldn't be
lurking around
in those waters
they just stopped
and were laying there
and we were going
in a search pattern
and they were
in our way
and we called up
on the radio
and said
we have divers
in the water
please move
and they did
but still
they were there
it's crazy
yeah and then
we have airplanes
so
how many
did you film
six seven ships
wow
big ships
yeah
interesting
so you think
they were there
for you
it was not
it's not normal
to see them all
no no no no
it's not normal
I don't know
I mean
but how many
other dives
have you done
where you're looking
for cognac
and wine
where you've seen
six or seven
ships from various
different NATO countries
not many I must say
but when we dive
on the submarine
we found
of course
we have
the Navy
and the Coast Guard
was there
and boarding us
and you know
want to investigate
what we are doing
and so on
and it was
so that sounds
like a similar thing
because it's a
national
it's of interest
to the government
in this case
the Russian government
and in this case
it's of interest
to NATO
and many governments
probably
yeah yeah
of course
and then
when we were home
they got the call
from the Swedish
let's say
it's like FBI
in Sweden
and they want me there
directly
come over here
we want to talk to you
so I did
and it was about
the submarine
we have found
and what people
I'm talking to
and they want to
know every detail
everything about it
the Russian people
I'm talking about
I talk with
and so on
so it's
yeah
but every time
we have been out
on the Baltic Sea
except now
this time
nobody
interesting
why do you think
that is?
the ship we're using
owned by the government
the Swedish government
ah
so they get the data
no matter what
I don't know
probably
interesting
maybe
maybe somebody on board
is
working on their behalf
I hope not
anyways
yeah
the Swedish FBI
did they contact you
about the Baltic Sea anomaly
too?
no no
when it's come to
the Baltic Sea anomaly
we had a meeting
at the headquarter
military headquarter
in Stockholm
and
I remember
I said to
one of the people
there
in this group
I said
you should know
I mean
you have been out there
and lurking around
and laying there
and watching us
so
what do you know
about the whole
have you been there
have you dive on it
and he just look at me
no no no
we have not been there
but I'm filming you
I have filmed you
so I know
you have been there
nothing
he don't say anything
whoa
so
they have been there
and
probably dive there
also
they probably dive down
of course
but they might also
not know
what's down there
they might know
no no no
of course
they have dived there
but do you think
would they know
what it is
do you think
they've classified
the object
or
classified it
in terms of
they know
what they're looking at
or
I mean
that's crazy
if they have not done that
I mean
but still
you know
the crazy thing
is also
it's not on
international
it's on international
water
but it's also
on Finnish
international
economic zone
it's not on Swedish
water
Finnish economic zone
so it's a little
strange
that the Swedish
military ship
are there
and also
other ships
but you know
it's
I don't know
but they have been there
and probably
dive on it
or use ROV
and investigate
it themselves
but when we
were at the
headquarter
and talked to
Grandes
said that
we know
nothing about it
we have had
no ships there
and
I filmed it
you filmed it
you have evidence
when you went
to the military
headquarters
was it explicitly
a meeting
around the Baltic Sea
anomaly
and they called
you in
so
okay
they definitely
had an interest
at least
of course
they were interested
yeah
but then they acted
like they knew
nothing
they had never
gone out there
and we show
all the data
all the information
from them
and for them
and yeah
is it a Russian
drone?
I see a chip
on it
yeah
you see a chip
well you're a long
way from home
my friend
what's the greatest
ontological shock
that you've experienced
around the Baltic Sea
anomaly
oh shit
there's so many
but the
I mean the first
time we saw it
the first time
we saw it
yeah
that was the experience
because we have never
seen anything like that
before
yeah
so we were very confused
and of course
I mean
curious about what it can be
and then after that
we have done our
things down there
and Péfan had been down
as a diver
and explained for me
what happened down there
and what he had experienced
with the temperature
and all the angles
and walls
and holes
and things like that
so when you see it
yourself
or photos
or film
then you begin
to understand
this must be
in some way
constructed
have any skeptics
come to you
and said
I think it's a rock
have any insight
yeah
of course
all of them
and what do you say
to them
perhaps you're right
I'm not sure
the only thing
I can say
I have no experience
when it's come to that
I have never seen
anything like that
before
not my colleagues
either
so nobody
have seen
things like
60 meter in diameter
that was the first
thing we did
to send it over
to the friends
and people
that we know
are working
with the same
things that we do
and when they
saw the picture
of course
they were curious
and wondered
where have we found
this
found this
as I mentioned
without the
the Baltic Sea
do you have
a top theory
as to what it is
it can be
something that
is constructed
on the spot
can be
long time ago
perhaps before
the ice age
I don't know
and that's why
I have never
give up
when it's come to this
because I want to know
even if it's
rock
but
very strange
rock
I must say
with all the angles
and holes
and it's a round
object
it's also
separated
from the bottom
it's separated
how do you know
that it's separated
sub-button profiling
have we done
so we can see
the layers
wow
amazing
that's really
incredible
that it's definitely
separated from
so it is an object
it's not a geological
formation
it looks
the data
say that
that's amazing
what's it called
sub-sub-sub-button profiling
sub-bottom profiling
and do you know
how that tech works
yeah it's like a radar
you go down to the ground
and you see all the layers
wow
and the sediment
so we know
it's attached
to the
seabed
but it's not
it's not a part
of a mountain
or something
it's not a geological
formation
not part of the earth
the data say it
that's pretty amazing
so it's an object
that's why it's important
so important
that we do
in this investigation
continue with it
yes
with different methods
because it's
it's of course
interesting
that's how it
at least
that's how it felt
for me
I was
having a
a hard time
melting it
I had a hard time
I was talking
to my friend
Dennis
who's sitting there
I just spoke
to your colleague
that you mentioned
Beatrice Villareal
who is amazing
and discovered
all sorts of
very cool things
in her own right
she talked about
the importance
of having a hypothesis
and having an idea
of what you might
be looking at
so you can test
against that hypothesis
I mean
I've seen some
astronomers suggesting
that you should
just look
without any hypothesis
and do like
classify things
like you're
classifying butterflies
I think you're
not going to
find anything
well obviously
because you have
no hypothesis
you don't target
your experiment
yes
and you're going
to invest
years into that
and you might
have a great
catalog of things
but I'm not
interested in the
catalog
I don't know
really what to
think about that
it's something
for sure
and if it is
a UAP
or a crashed UFO
it should be cool
if you have found
that
of course
but at the same
time with all
the data we have
now
it cannot be
a volcano
even if it's
can be a volcano
but when I've
talked to scientists
and I look at it
now
it's not a volcano
no no
it should not be
like that
then
is it a metri
or an asteroid
or a metriite
or something
no it should not
be that
then you have
this and this
and this
okay
why can't it
be an asteroid
or something
then you have
a crater
right
yeah
and no crater
here
no no
it's standing up
as if it's an
artificial structure
on the seafloor
yeah it's laying on the bottom
and how big is it again
60 meter in diameter
60 meter
60 meters
yeah that's big
it's very big
yeah
that's so interesting
so
let's find out
instead
so your two
top hypotheses
are that
it's either a ufo
maybe something
we're not alone
from space
yeah
or you think
maybe it's
an artificial structure
that was built
before the younger
driest period
maybe when
you know
there was probably
flooding
there was flooding
we know
meltwater pulse 1b
in 9600 bc
yeah
before that
you know
you had
water levels
were different
yeah
and maybe this was
on land
and it was built
at that time
can be like that
yeah
something is built
there
either one
is very interesting
it's fascinating
yeah it is
and you're
reasonably confident
that they're
it's detached
the object
is not part
of
a big stone
or something
yeah
now as we can see
it now
the data we have
from the last
mission
or where we're at
it looks like
it's separated
from the bottom
on the data
but you know
we're gonna go out
again and do it
one more time
that's how we
must do it
did the diver
that you mentioned
before who
I think it was
Stefan
Stefan Hågerborn
he touched it
did he say
it felt like
anything
no not really
he was surprised
it was dark
under it
it was gray
like
gray
when he
the sand
and then
it took that away
and it was dark
almost black
gray black
did he say
it looks natural
or artificial
no nothing
about that
he didn't say
he didn't mention
anything about it
interesting
did he mention
feeling anything
being around it
like oh my god
yeah
yeah yeah yeah
he have
he have never
ever
and this is
he have been
diving for a long
long time
he is well known
in Sweden
when it's come
to diving
how many years
has he been diving
since he was
a young guy
okay
but anyway
he is
how old is he now
same age
okay
wow
so
and then
so 40 years
probably
yeah
probably more
but
still
you know
he said to me
that
when he was up
because he was
um
I saw him
in his face
he was
very
uh
confused
or
you know
sit in his face
and
and I was
of course
curious
what have you seen
and
and he said to me
Dennis
I you know
I have dived a lot
and I have never
ever seen
anything like this
wow
that was probably
the most important dive
I've ever done
in my life
and I've done maybe
six thousand dives
in my life
I would dive for an expert
to tell me what I've seen
wow
yeah
and then he explained for me
about the hole
he explained about the temperature
and he was brushing off
the sand
the sediment
it was dark under it
and
he tried to take samples
from it
it was too hard
so he takes samples
that lose samples
on it instead
like lose stones
uh-huh
and where did those stones
have you tested those
yeah
we had tested in Israel
and
are those stones
did they come back
normal or
uh
they found
minerals
of course
and
not
nothing that really sticks out
and basalt
uh
volcanic stones
they found
but at the same time
when I've
talked to
the people
the scientists
they say
you will never find
any
any basalt
in the Baltic Sea
because you don't have
any volcano
but then
they said that
probably
if you have found it
it's coming
at the ice
you know
the end of the ice age
it's a melting period
coming from
the atlanta
uh
atlant
and uh
be in the Baltic
but I
I don't know
interesting
yeah
so it's almost like
uh
when you look at
an ice core sample
yeah
and you can kind of
uh
see what carbon levels
were
in the sediment layer
of the ice
or something
this might be a record
that it was
an ancient structure
that was built
from a long time ago
the fact that there's
even basalt there
yeah
is that kind of
what you're
that's a very
interesting test
we're gonna do
a core drilling
not at the object
but around the object
now
and even it's
this track
and see if we
see any layers
ah
smart
so that's important
to see how
I mean
how long
I've been there
have you brought
a Geiger counter
down or
measured
menu active
no but this time
we're gonna do
you will
yeah
it's amazing
this is so fascinating
what do you
do you want this
to be a contribution
to humanity
or what
what do you want
for this
the truth
yeah
that's the only thing
and even if it's a rock
a big rock
I want it to come out
because I want to do
like check
I have done this now
I can go further
with my other projects
are there any other rocks
with corridors
no
and right angle
not only that
as I mentioned
with corridors
and holes
and things
I forgot one thing
very important
I have a
like a triangle
like this
with a hole in it
a triangle
with a hole
how big is a triangle
like 15
centimeters
20 centimeters
like that
whoa
with a hole in it
yeah the hole
like a perfect
round circle
yeah
almost as if it was like
laser cut
or something
perfect
on the
object
any writing
I assume not
no inscription
you know
as I mentioned
we were lucky
when we found this
on a film
but you know
it's a big object
and visibility
down there
as I said
it's very
you know
it's pitch black
yeah
and it's difficult
to see things
wow
but we saw that
and probably
we will find more
next time
we're coming out
that's so fascinating
before the Baltic Sea
anomaly
were you interested
in UFOs at all
did you have any
interest in
unidentified flying
objects
space
aliens
anything like that
okay
let's go back
in time
then
I have
talked about
this before
and I can do
it again
because that
it was
that was something
that changed
my life
totally
back in 1996
I live outside
of Stockholm
not far from here
very close
to a military
installation
and I was
an entrepreneur
explorer
entrepreneur
I had my
businesses
and doing
lots of
things
I was
a daddy
to two
boys
and I have
a wife
and a good
life
perfect life
and the only
thing when it's
come to UAPs
and UFO
I saw
Star Wars
ETs
and aliens
that was
the only thing
no interest
and when it's come to
I did not think
about it
I was busy
in my world
so
anyway
that thing
that changed
my mind
totally
was
in the summer
in the early summer
I lay in my bed
in the apartment
not far
from this
military installation
I have a big window
in front of me
I wake up
3.30
something
in the morning
usually I sleep
a long time
you know
I used the time
for sleeping
at that time
of course
I'm working a lot
but this morning
I wake up
of some reason
I still today
don't understand
really
I have thought
about it
of course
but
I wake up
lay in my bed
for 10 minutes
and I decide
to go up
and drink water
in the kitchen
so I'm sitting
in the bed
I have a big window
in front of me
and outside the window
I have this military
installation
for one
it's called
in Swedish
down
so I'm sitting
there
in my bed
and look
out of the window
and see something
that should not be there
and it's taken me
a couple of seconds
to really understand
that I have something
in front of me
that should not be there
should not be there
what is it
yeah good question
and then I'm
getting frustrated
you know
when you see something
that not fit
you know
it should not be there
that
I get to use
I begin to use
my F words
and try to get
my wife's attention
because she's sleeping
behind me
I want her to see
that also
because it's something
so you're making
a little scene
yeah yeah of course
and then
stand up
and turn around
and look at her
to what
you know
and she look at me
scared
because I mean
that's not Dennis
I'm a quite cool guy
and this in the
early morning
so
then I turn around
and look again
out to the window
and it's still there
it's still there
and
then I begin
to understand
this is something
very very
odd and strange
I have in front of me
and then
the thing happens
that when you see it
like this
it looks like a hot dog
and it's brown
it's yellow
and the sunlight
is reflecting on it
and then it's going
like this
and it's dark under it
and then I see
it's round
before I don't see it
around
then I see it round
and then after
one second
one and a half second
it's
wow
so what shape is it
it's round
but if you see it
like this
you don't see it
as round
but when it do
like this
it's round
interesting
yeah
so you just saw it
it looked like a flat plane
because you were looking
at it from the side
like a hot dog
or a cigar
or something
some sort of long line
yeah
which is a common
people's tic-tac
cigars
and then it turns
and you saw
that it was round
yeah
and then it popped off
and how long
did you see it for
14-15 seconds
how far away
from you
standing in front
of the window
one and a half
kilometers
one to one and a half
wow
so it must have been
a pretty big object
it was a big
it was not
as I mentioned
to many people
it's not what
it was not a bird
shit on the window
yeah
not a bird
or
it was something
very very strange
it's amazing
that you woke up
at that time
yeah
was it around
the military installation
was over the military installation
interesting
yeah
and does the military installation
house any sort of
nuclear stuff
I guess there's no nuclear
in Sweden
or
there's nuclear energy
there's fun craft
and stuff
no no no
plutonium
and lots of other things
the nuclear things
they work with there
because I did my investigation
because I was
you know
wow
I have seen something
now I must figure out
what it is
I must try to find out
if I can find any information
regarding this
what I have seen
if anybody else
have seen it
so local papers
at that time
we had Alta Vista
you know
and modem
you put your phone
and
and then you call
no broadband
internet service provider
modem
so it was
a local paper
military sites
and also my friend
in the military
I talked to
nobody
nobody have seen it
or heard anything about it
so
then
I contacted
UFO Sverige
UFO Sweden
you haven't talked
to one of the
guys
I think
Klaus Svahn
yeah
so this is like
the official
civilian investigation
investigation
and UFO
so I
I mailed them
but I did not get
any receive
anything back
so that was
a shock
for me
and that was
something that changed
my belief
totally
before that
nothing at all
so
I remember
when I saw
this thing
I
I got my
I got her
attention
but she
did not come up
and saw it
anyway
it's flowing
over my
house
and then
I run over
the bed
over her
to come to
the other side
and I'm standing
there like
what
where is it
and I see
don't see anything
and then
she's coming
what's wrong
I don't know
I have seen
something
and then after that
my two kids
are coming
papa papa
what's wrong
and I'm
this morning
we're sitting
eating breakfast
and I try to
in my best way
to explain for them
what I have seen
and later that day
we go down
to this area
it's a protected area
it's a military installation
so we cannot go in
but anyway
I go there
because I have reference
I saw that
there was one part of it
and that was
how big is it
and then I begin to
okay
must be like
six
seven hundred meters
in diameter
so we're talking
about the big thing
wow
so
yeah
that's what happened
to me in 96
that's amazing
and you looked into it
and you realized
that the military
installation
that site
does like
plutonium enrichment
yeah
and that seems
to be
a huge pattern
as I'm sure
after a while
I did
begin to understand
that's the reason
perhaps
they are there
yeah
other plutonium
enrichment sites
in the US
Savannah River site
South Carolina
or Hanford Washington
there are a lot
of UFO sightings
over both
in fact
one of the earliest
sightings
was over Hanford
plutonium site
in 1945
this pilot
named Bud Clem
so it's
it's a very common
thing
wow
that's amazing
yeah
that was something
that
begin
I mean
there were
there was
that was the time
that I began
to think
about
okay
we are not alone
something
are here
so you started
to get interested
yeah
very
did you start
to read
about
the topic
yeah
of course
I tried to find out
if somebody else
have found
seen anything
like that
yeah
look at pictures
and
because we did not
have YouTube
and things
at that time
in 96
but
then I saw
pictures
and no
no
nothing like that
I really tried
my best
to find out
if somebody
have to take
a picture
of it
or something
fascinating
yeah
I saw
two UFOs
in 2020
and then I just
became obsessed
and I had
like a
kind of a prestigious
job in finance
or whatever
and I was like
all I can spend
time on is this
and so I
yeah
that changed
your life
totally then
definitely
changed my life
yeah
our experience
as you know
I have experienced
lots of other people
I've talked to
that have experienced
they have changed
their life
totally
yeah
and not only
their life
only their family's life
because you get
you'll be another person
yes
yeah
it opens you up
spiritually too
and I think
I think I was nihilistic
before
and I didn't believe
in higher things
you know
me too
I was like
totally focused
on my
you know
myself
and my family
and my carrier
my business
and everything
that I'm doing
and then
that happened
that
really changed me
yeah
that's beautiful
the meaning
of life
we need to think about
who are we
who are them
why are they here
and so on
you know
that's why
it's so important
for me
and I know
for you
and lots of other people
too
yes
you cannot
just leave you back
or just walk
away
no you can't walk away
you cannot do that
because
you have it
your whole life
in you
yes
maybe the way
that
the beings
are speaking to us
is through the discoveries
you know
it's like their language
yeah
perhaps they don't want
to just give it on
they want us to find it
I think that's right
it's every
every story
is like that
you know
King Arthur
anything
it's always
you have to search
what do you say
to the people
who say
oh well
Dennis was already
interested in UFOs
and you know
he's just
biased
because he already
had this in his mind
when he saw this object
yeah
as I mentioned
that changed my life
and I am an explorer
I have been an explorer
since I was a kid
really
I'm a curious guy
I've always been interested
in finding things
that nobody else has found
and of course
make money on it
so I can pay my bills
and do new
you know
expeditions
and things like that
so
and then we found
this thing
and they can't believe
what they
I mean
it's my
it's my life
I have always been
like that
and
yes
sorry
if they
feel like that
but
this is my reality
this is something
I have gone through
and I found something
for sure
that is very interesting
and I'm open with it
everything I do
I'm open with it
it's the same thing
with shipwrecks
I'm doing that
because
I know lots of people
as I was
and when I was a kid
I was curious
I look at
TV
and things
and books
and I know
lots of people
around the world
are very curious
about treasures
you know
I'm a treasure hunter
and
then I found
this thing
and the same thing
there
I'm open with it
and then I have
seen something
that convinced me
so
I'm open
I've always been
like that
say you
take a core sample
you bring a Geiger counter
you observe much more
the next time
your next visit
and you
actually get
conclusive proof
that this is an anomalous object
not from Earth
what next?
Talk about it
show the whole world
about the truth
about it
that's how I work
and that's how
we together
Beatrice and I work
we want to be open
with everything
we
even if it's
a stone
or a comet
whatever it is
I must be open
with it
Are you familiar
with the history
in Scandinavia
of specifically
waterborne UFOs
or UFOs
that hit the water
specifically
the ghost rocket
anomalies
in the 40s
for example
never landed
on land
or crashed
they always
hit the water
in lakes
and stuff
Yeah
you know
since I was
out with information
in 96
then
I found it
but 96
I was not out
with the information
but since 2011
I have received
I mean
so much mails
from people
around the world
and even here
in Sweden
they're talking about
they have seen cigars
they have
you know
crashed in the water
in forest
and things like that
and they want to
talk to me
and you know
lots of people
have contacted me
and I wish
I can clone myself
and you know
do
it's so many people
Yes
So
You know who
Matthew Brown is?
Yeah
So he's this
recent whistleblower
you know
UAP whistleblower
recent UFO whistleblower
in the US
and he encountered
this immaculate
constellation document
within the government
and it talks about
trans medium objects
UFOs going in
and out of the water
Yeah
But he also
he talked about
in his interview
with Jeremy Corbell
and George Knapp
the idea that
some of these UFOs
are made to purpose
so they're built
in order to serve
specific functionalities
Sometimes these might be
you know
made to purpose
so
you know
if they're
only making it
for a specific
use case scenario
they'll design
it to
excel in that
mission
and
this is
getting into
very speculative
territory
but there's a
UFO whistleblower
on 4chan
you know
it's one of these
kind of dark
internet forums
or whatever
and
he said he was
sick
and you know
he didn't have
much time left
and it was time
for him to
reveal the truth
and he says
that
basically
these UFOs
are built to spec
they're made
for specific purposes
and they're on
the ocean floor
and so I wonder
if this was an
object with
all of these
you know
kind of intricate
corridors and holes
and 90 degree
corners
that was maybe
built to spec
for some specific
purpose
and then
maybe it served
its purpose
and it was disposed
of or you know
who knows
I don't know
but that will
hopefully we will
find out
when it's come to this
and since 2011
I received lots
of mails
and even letters
on paper
that the story
about things
that have crashed
down in the water
and even
former officers
in the Navy
that have contacted me
that are very
scared to go out
with it
but they want
to tell me
the story
about they have
seen things
like that
in the water
yeah
there's even
in the US
there's a guy
named John Pina Craven
he wrote a book
called The Silent War
and they talk
about all sorts
of covert operations
in the US
and finding things
on the seafloor
and there are rumors
that the Glowmore Explorer
for Hughes Corporation
was maybe you know
subsea
to find sort of
objects like this
so I think
there's a long history
of crash retrievals
you know
in the ocean
and it's fascinating
and then I don't know
if you wanted to like
touch on the
like the Baikal
Baikal Lake
do you know the story
of like
Soviet divers
going down
to like
look for something
and they get petrog
like they meet
these tall
tall humans
I don't know
maybe it's
interesting
when was that?
in the 80s tomb
82?
yeah
because it's a big story
in the UFO war
of just like
these soldiers
like got petrified
where was that
in the lake
or
yeah Lake Baikal
there's also
there's another story
somewhere in Hawaii
this guy
David Noble White Crow
because he's
an Indian guy
yeah
he was a UFO witness
but then he was
stationed somewhere
with this guy
who apparently
dove on
an object
in Hawaii
and
the idea
was maybe
it was related
to the
Starfish Prime
test series
so the Marshall Islands
you know
atomic tests
or whatever
where UFO material
supposedly came out
of the sky
you know
I interviewed a guy
Harold Malmgren
who basically
on his deathbed
said that he
held in his hands
UFO material
from
that came out
of the plume
of a blast
from Operation
Bluegill Triple Prime
and it was given
to him
by Jeff Bezos
maternal grandfather
Lawrence Preston Geis
at Sandia National Labs
in Kirtland Air Force Base
in New Mexico
amazing
and so
anyway
so this guy
David Noble White Crow
was stationed
with this other guy
he said that
he dove down
and
saw some sort of object
but that it was
almost
alive
and it was
I think Dolan
might talk about this
as well
Richard Dolan
so the object
itself was like
breathing
and it was organic
and he didn't know
why he was
this kind of
you know
in intelligence circles
often they say
go find a thing
and you don't know
what you're looking for
and so he
apparently looked
at the object
when he was
down there
and
it really shocked him
he became
it was ontologically
completely shocking
he was
like
what am I seeing
and it was because
it looked organic
and it was like
breathing
so
and then I think
about the hole
with the sand
yeah but you're saying
something very interesting
because when we did
the samples there
from
we take from
not from the object
but from
that laying on
the object
it was
organic
burned
material
wow
yeah
organic
burned
yeah
whoa
so like
but you know
I'm not a specialist
in that area
but it was
it was that
so it was like
charred
like
no
something
at high temperature
very high temperature
and it's like basalt
as you know
and then when it's
cooling down
the layers on it
when you're scrapping it
and take the test
what's biologic
how'd you know
the science
I mean
it was biological
yeah they tested
it contained DNA
and stuff
no that I don't know
okay but it was
biologic
when you say biological
plant or animal
can be I don't know
some sort of tissue
or something
yeah I don't know
it's fascinating
nothing
it's dead sea
dead sea
so no
but this had
biological material
yeah
so normally
you would never find
biological material
in this area
no no no
the fishes
that's fascinating
yeah
not out there
in the middle
of the baltic sea
but nothing we can say
that's more descriptive
than biological material
or
no
not a specific animal
or specific
no
wow
so
but hopefully
this time
when we go out
we're going to take
more samples
core drilling
as I mentioned for you
but we're going to take
hopefully we can take
something from the
object
but if not
we take new samples
from different spots
around it
and even on it
and do our
investigation
and you know
look at it
amazing
well godspeed man
I'm very excited
to see what you find
I think it's very cool
what you're doing
and
do you think
I mean
do you believe
that you'll succeed
in figuring out
what this object is
yeah
you do
100%
even if it's
a stone
or
volcano
whatever it is
we will find out
I don't give up
we
must
have an answer
now
to what it is
but it has been
a tough time
15 years
and grey hairs
and
struggling with this
to convince people
to get into this
and now
we have the right people
involved in this project
and
I'm so glad for that
but it has been
a tough time
with threats
and people
that want to hurt me
or my family
and so
it has been tough also
I'm sorry
in many ways
any specific threats
that you can talk about
not really
but
you know
you get mails
and
like threatening me
and my kids
and
lots of things like that
horrible
to
make me
to stop
or
yeah
they literally say
stop looking
for the Baltic Sea anomaly
we know
what your kids are
what kindergarten
they are at
now we're talking
about my youngest kids
now they are
teenagers
and
but
at that time
they work in the
we're in the kindergarten
and school
and
and they said
that we know
about your son there
and daughter there
and that
when I was
what the
you know
Jesus
and
be careful about
that
blah blah blah
I still have
the mails left
you know
you do
yeah
and
lots of it
and then
people that
think
I'm opening the door
to hell
really
yeah
like you're opening
a gateway to hell
gateway to hell
so I'm the
gonna blame me
on
you know
so it was tough
and then to
if you have a wife
you know
family
and
I must be open
with everything
if there's fret
fretting me
and my family
yeah
I must be open
well being public
is the best
yeah
and that was
very tough
for them
to
accept that
and
and they did
not really
accept it
and it was
tough for me
I mean
Dennis what have you
done
don't put this
put us
in this situation
you know
and
was
tough
but
they have
you know
supported me
and
this
because
it's important
they know
that's important
for me
and
now
we are here
and
we are out
again
and hopefully
we have
answered
this year
what we have
found
and
but
even if
it's
a stone
or whatever
it is
I will
continue
to work
in
in this
area
to find out
are we alone
or
and
we are not alone
but
who are they
coming from
what's the purpose
and so on
so that
that is something
very important
for me
well
I think
if the people
mailing you
didn't think
it was real
they wouldn't be
so vociferous
and aggressive
in everything
they're saying
it's
implying an insecurity
that they actually
think the thing
is real
if they think
they thought
that you were
obsessed with
a volcanic rock
for 15 years
they wouldn't
be threatening
anything
no no no
we all
on the
the crew
everybody
on the ship
and also
as I mentioned
the Finnish guys
and
we have been
out there
and it's the reason
we are going out
many times
I've been out there
not for a stone
I mean
we have seen
something that have
you know
make us
confused
do you
plan to document
what you find
throughout
so that you can
I think it's important
maybe for
just
as a defense
for yourself
to show
the process
as you're
finding things
so nobody
can kind of
deny
that you
because you
have
you know
evidence
that you're
doing it
as you're
yeah
we of course
we have a plan
for that
and
we have
filmed
when we were out
last time
we did a little
filming
of course
we don't have
any film crew
with us
or any
production company
because I have
been a little
you know
we do it
ourselves
now in the
beginning
but
we have
changed our
mind
little now
we must be
think about
perhaps to
connect a team
with or get in
contact with a team
that can film us
and document
everything
because I think
lots of things
are going to happen
when we are out
now
this time
and hopefully
later
that's what I hope
for
and it's good
to have on film
also
well
we're available
yeah
you all right
you see anything
not yet
now with the
drone
we were
flying on the
hovering on the
surface
yeah
we saw some
rear lines
some cracks
yeah
and something
I would say
looked like rust
brownish color
like rust
like metal
I looked really
like it
was my first
intuition
so like
it was
a little bit
like old
metal
rust
keeping
off
the door
in all
the
standards
but just
running
theory
why would
there be
metal
question
oh
now you see
quality of that
oh yeah
it's like a wall
that's the picture
you take
you took
when you dive
for the first
time
with your
RV
so this is
higher resolution
yeah
because the range
is smaller
so you
don't
and it shows
it's even
straighter
than
how long
is that
super straight
part
it must be at least
30 meters
at least
60 meters
the whole thing
so what are the chances
of that
it's crazy
yeah I don't know
my dream is that one day we can have one of these objects in a museum so a kid can like
exactly can can look at it and be inspired and understand and understand that the potential of possibility that exists in the universe for me that was the pyramid when I was a kid yeah I grew up half an hour away from it so I know the impact of having seen something
can can look at it and be inspired and understand and understand the and understand the potential of possibility that exists in the universe for me that was the pyramid when I was a kid yeah I grew up half an hour away from it so I know the impact of having seen something that almost doesn't feel like it belongs to this reality and like
ever since I think I said that on camera during the grudge yeah you know the grudge documentary just like that's why I'm in a fort cool because I hope that our work and every interview that we do can can push people to
Yeah. That's why it's so important for us in this, you know,
what we are doing, it's that we work together.
That we really, instead of, oh, no, he's doing that,
you know what I mean. Lots of people in different groups,
and then, you know, I don't want to speak to them.
I think the phenomena doesn't open itself up to you
unless you have that orientation of, like, loving and humanity.
It'll reject you.
Something perhaps I forgot to mention or was about 96,
you know, go back to 96, I was parents, I had two young guys,
I was occupied with all my businesses and exploring and so on.
Something I thought about later, perhaps a couple of weeks,
a month after that incident, was a feeling I had.
A feeling that usually I don't wake up so early.
At that time, I was a young daddy, you know, and blah, blah, blah.
And I used my time to sleep.
When I had the chance to sleep, I sleep.
Don't go up 4 o'clock, 3.30 in the night, no way.
I did not, as now, I'm an old guy.
I don't go up and pee, you know.
That's what I'm doing, not at that time.
But I wake up of some reason, of some reason, I don't understand today.
And perhaps, perhaps, there was that feeling I had in some way,
and I begin to think about it later, after a couple of weeks, that perhaps it was some
plan for me to wake up and see it, because I had the feeling after it, not in the situation.
Then I was angry and pissed off, because I did not understand what I'm seeing.
But after a week or two weeks, I begin to, how come?
And I talked to my wife at that time, you know?
How come?
And she, no, Dennis, I don't know.
You used to sleep a long time, but this time I wake up.
It was something.
I cannot put my finger on it, but something.
Do you know what a time loop is?
Or a closed time-like curve in physics?
No.
It's two connected points in time that couldn't exist without one another.
They're entangled. And so a classic story is Carl Jung, you know, the Swiss psychologist.
He was a contemporary of Freud. He had a patient, and this patient was very kind of
materialist, reductionist, just believed in the physical world, was very rational.
Yeah.
And she had a dream that she was gifted this golden scarab beetle.
Mm-hmm.
And it was this very important thing in her dream.
She comes in, she talks to Carl Jung, who's her, you know, psychologist,
and she says that, I don't know, I was given this scarab beetle.
It was very strange, I don't know, but she's very skeptical.
And as she's telling the story, a scarab beetle comes down the windowsill
and lands right in the office. And so he ends up giving it to her.
Mm-hmm.
And then she gets so emotional and starts crying, and it opens her up to a realm of
all sorts of possibilities as to how time and space work, and that there's far more beyond,
you know, just our material existence and plane that we see. But the point is,
if she hadn't noticed the dream, and she wasn't looking out for the scarab beetle,
then the dream itself wouldn't have been this self-fulfilling prophecy.
Yeah.
And he wouldn't have gifted it to her, and the whole thing wouldn't have happened.
And so there are two points connected in space and time. And so, um, I think that could be
what's happening with you right now, where, and it's a lot of people, you know,
I think the almost dirty little secret of UFO research is people always try to say,
oh, I'm this very impartial observer, and I haven't been affected by this on a core personal level.
And then you get a little deeper, you have drinks with the person, and they're like,
okay, I saw something five years ago, and I know it's real, so now I'm looking for it.
And I have a similar, I've seen stuff, and it was right at the start of doing this show,
and it really has impacted my own desire to, you know, substantiate what I saw more.
And so I do believe what you just said.
Yeah, I saw what I saw, and then I decided to be quiet about it. As I mentioned, I tried to see
if I can find any information in local papers, in the military sites, and so on. And I did not
find anything. And I decided to be totally quiet about it. The only people that had known about it
was my family, my closest friends. But then on the cruising with the ship, because they were
curious about the Baltic Sea anomaly, one young guy coming to me, Dennis, have you seen anything?
I mean, the UFOs. And I just, no, I should not talk about that.
And then, okay, let's do it. I say it.
That was the first time I mentioned it for a public or for a person.
And then who knows if you would have been as persistent to spend
almost 15 years looking for this object, if you hadn't had prior evidence in your own life
that there's something else out there? Maybe you would have overlooked it.
Maybe you would have said, ah, it's probably a prosaic thing.
Why would I spend so much time on this thing? So it's interesting. Even a scientist as reputable
as Gary Nolan at Stanford, it's similar where he kind of started to uncover experiences he had had
in his childhood when he got into the subject professionally later in life. So I think it's
impossible to completely separate the observer and the observed. And I think it's always honorable when
anybody admits what's driving them is, you know, often a personal experience.
There's no way to decouple those two things.
Yeah. Oh, interesting. Interesting.
Very interesting. Yeah.
Well, the journey continues. Let's find out what it is.
Yeah. Okay, great. Thank you. Thank you.
Yeah, you're a curious guy and that's good. I'm a curious guy and that's so important for me to
continue. Still, I'm alive. I'm healthy and I'm okay. But you never know. Someday you just get sick
and you don't have the energy to continue. But still, I'm… You're great now, man.
I want to do it. Yeah. Continue to find the answer without the military or the governments.
Yes, I agree. Yeah, that's important for me. Yeah.
No, for humanity, for the world. For the future, for my kids, grandkids and so on.
Oh, I think you will. I think you, uh, you have the right energy towards it, so…
I'll do my best. I want to go dodge down there.
Alchemist, did you enjoy that? Well, here's the thing. That episode was just the tip of the iceberg.
If you want the full picture, head over to the American Alchemy magazine we just
launched on Substack. That's where we deep dive into all sorts of crazy topics that we don't have
time to fit into every video, with weekly articles exploring all of the strange, forgotten, and
conspiratorial corners of space, history, and high weirdness. So join up today at our free or paid
tiers on Substack. I am including the full link in the description of this video.
Uhm,
you
and
go