There was an age in which the gods were dwelling on earth among men.
And those beings came from somewhere.
The human species was originally created, designed, intended to be a member of the divine family.
This is an archetypal myth that cuts across a lot of regions and cultures.
It's universal.
So we have these watchers that came down.
They were extraterrestrial.
They mated with man.
They created Nephilim.
And then we have evidence that a lot of this actually holds astronomical weight in the ancient world.
There are ruins of an ancient civilization on the planet Mars, specifically in the region of Sidonia.
And this, what's so fascinating about this, is that the ancients believed that the gods descended from Mars.
We can understand the modern phenomenon in light of the Book of Enoch.
Hearing about the Book of Enoch, and it sounds a lot like Prometheus, where you have titans who try to give mankind sacred knowledge.
So these were very, very intelligent beings, probably in possession of what I would describe as advanced aerospace technology.
I, myself, have seen a UFO right above my car.
And this thing just descended and just hovered there like I was supposed to see it.
That is some top secret.
Speaking of evidence of Nephilim and this whole narrative, you're one of the few people who has gone deep on this phenomena of giants.
The story that has since become known as the Kandahar Giant.
This is where it begins.
He was a cargo pilot, and he would describe these missions as classified.
And one day he's flying in there.
They said, this never happened.
No pictures.
Don't ever talk about it.
He sees a forklift bringing over an air cargo pilot, and there's something on it.
And he said the first thing that hit him was the odor, like B.O. and death.
The hair of this being was red.
The skin was pale.
He said it had six fingers on each hand and six toes on each foot.
And he said this thing was solid as a rock.
So you can imagine, let's say it was 12 feet tall.
The whole thing weighed 1,100 pounds.
That's pretty crazy.
Yeah.
How is this possible?
Nothing too emotional about that.
As you know, we have a new starship.
Of course, we have a healthcare center on board.
Ask what my new favorite product in it is?
Some billionaires are rejuvenating in underground light pods.
I'm doing my own version in my living room.
This mask is like a med bed for your face.
It's lightweight, super convenient, cordless, and runs red, blue, and infrared light therapy
all at once.
The same type of technology NASA studied for skin healing in space.
It's safe for your eyes too, so you don't have to sit there like a statue.
You can live your life.
I wear it when I'm reading, meal prepping, or investigating life's mysteries without
feeling like I'm staring into the sun.
10 minutes of light and my skin looks and feels so good.
Finding red light therapy was a revelation for me.
I've definitely had a few late nights reading about magnetic pull shifts.
But with this mask, I look like I actually slept.
Did I?
That's debatable.
It's warm, wireless, convenient, and makes your skin feel super soft.
And iRestore is kicking off their spring savings with some very big discounts.
Right now, you can get the Elite Plus Illumina Face Mask bundle at an exclusive deal when you
use code JESSE at iRestore.com.
That's JESSE, J-E-S-S-E, at iRestore.com.
Please support our show and tell them we sent you.
I don't know exactly what AG1 is doing in my body, but I do know that my microtubules are
online.
I'm not saying I can feel the force, but my chakras have definitely auto-aligned.
In fact, I used to think I had 7 chakras, just like everybody else.
And then I drink AG1.
Now, I have 50.
Just kidding.
But I did used to wake up feeling stiff and groggy like my brain's on airplane mode, and
then I started one habit.
One scoop in 8 ounces of water.
It's a multivitamin, a prebiotic, a probiotic, and with its adaptogens, it's the only green
powder I'd ever bring to a skiff.
Shout out Chris Ramsey.
I take this in the morning, and it's the easiest upgrade I've ever made.
My favorite flavor is berry, but honestly, they're all good.
AG1 has over 50,000 verified 5-star reviews and comes with a 90-day money-back guarantee.
Go to drinkag1.com slash alchemy to get their best offer, and get 3 free AG1 travel packs,
plus free vitamin D3 plus K2, and AG1's welcome kit with your first AG1 subscription order.
That's drinkag1.com slash alchemy.
Again, that's drinkag1.com slash alchemy.
We're linking that in the description.
Thank you so much to AG1 for sponsoring today's episode.
I'm here with Timothy Albarino, and I could not be more excited to speak with you.
I have been just going through all your stuff, all your podcasts, your book, your amazing
book called Birthright, which is really awesome because I think people in this space, it's
always an anecdotal story that's really crazy and interesting.
You have a lot of those anecdotal stories.
I want to talk to you about the Peruvian face peelers.
I want to talk to you about the giants of Kandahar, all of these amazing things that you cover.
You're this kind of modern, larger-than-life adventurer.
But you also are, I think, a really impressive kind of philosopher and sensemaker, and you
do such a great job in this book Birthright, which I recommend people get, in reconciling
the whole kind of alien, you know, NHI phenomena, which is now kind of all the rage with kind of
the modern disclosure movement, but with ancient traditions, and with the Bible and Plato and
the Book of Enoch, which is where I kind of want to start this conversation. So I appreciate what
you're doing. I think it's really cool. What does the Book of Enoch hold in terms of relevance for
our life and our world today?
Enoch provides the foundation for Hebrew cosmology as it pertains to the antediluvian world. So you
cannot separate what I call the Enochian narrative or the Enochic tradition. You cannot separate that
out from the biblical narrative. It is fundamental to how the ancient Hebrews viewed the antediluvian
world, the world before the flood. And not only is it the ancient Hebraic view, it's the view of our
antescendants across the board. The ancient Egyptians, the Mesopotamians, the Greeks, the Romans, they all
viewed the antediluvian world in a particular way. Namely, that it was a time of great learning. It's a time when
the fundamentals of civilization were imparted to mankind from extraterrestrial entities.
And in the pagan world, and pagan just means everybody but the Hebrews, in the pagan world,
this was known as the Golden Age or Zephtephi to the ancient Egyptians. And it was a time when the
demigods commingled with mankind, literally. They procreated with human women. They progenerated
a race of hybrid demigods in the earth. In many accounts, these demigods were giants,
such as in the biblical account and the ancient Mesopotamian account, the Epic of Gilgamesh.
Gilgamesh himself was a giant. And so these traditions are ubiquitous across the earth.
And this is how civilization began in the minds of our antescendants. Again, whether it be the Hebrew
account, the Judeo-Christian account, or the pagan accounts. Now, among the Jews, there was no greater
prophet and scribe, and these are important terms, prophet and scribe, than Enoch. Enoch was the greatest
pre-flood patriarch. He was revered above all others. And the Bible says very little about Enoch.
It says that he walked with God for 365 years, and then God took him.
And that's pretty much all the Bible says of Enoch. And there's a couple of references in the New
Testament. But it always was strange to me as I was a teenager, thinking and reading the scant
information provided in the biblical text concerning Enoch, who clearly was the greatest pre-flood
patriarch. The Bible has much to say about its other prophets and scribes. The Bible says a whole lot
about Moses. It says a whole lot about Elijah. It says a whole lot about Noah. It says almost nothing
about Enoch. And it occurred to me when I was probably, I think I was 16 years old. I just had
gotten my driver's license, and my father was a pastor. So I grew up in a very, very good home.
I had a very, very good upbringing. My dad was an excellent father and pastor. And I had a wonderful
mother. My mother died when I was 14. But I remember when I was 16 years old, I drove to
Borders. That's the one that went out of business, right? Borders?
Yeah, Borders bookstore.
I drove to a Borders bookstore. And I remember I was perusing the aisles, just sort of wanted to
buy a book. And I was particularly interested in the pseudepigrapha.
Yeah. And I pulled this pseudepigrapha off the shelf. It was this big, you know, ancient-looking
book that they had there in Borders. And I was most interested in the Book of Enoch. I'd heard
about the Book of Enoch, and I didn't really know what it was. And so I remember pulling it off the
shelf and sitting down on a bench in Borders and opening it up and sort of skimming through the
Book of Enoch. I was instantly captivated. And I bought it, and I took it home. And that sort of
began my fascination with the antediluvian world. Because what the Book of Enoch does is it provides,
as I said earlier, it provides the foundation of Hebrew cosmology in regard to the antediluvian
world. And I remember reading, when I was a teenager, reading the verses in Genesis 6,
those enigmatic verses inscribed in Genesis 6 about the sons of God who saw the daughters of men,
that they were beautiful. And they came down, and they took wives of all whom they chose.
And they copulated with these women and progenerated a race of giants in the earth
called the Nephilim. But that was it. Just this little footnote. It is a bizarre digression in the
Genesis narrative. And this precedes the flood. The next chapter is the flood. And then you get to
the New Testament, and you see Peter referencing the angels who sinned, and as a result, are chained
in the gloomy abyss, Tartarus. Jude takes verbatim from the Book of Enoch. He copies and pastes into his
epistle a few verses straight out of 1 Enoch. And it's the same sort of—it comes from the Book of
the Watchers. And the Book of the Watchers in 1 Enoch is the story of the descent of these beings,
of these heavenly beings, these celestial beings. And you realize when you read the Book of Enoch that
the reference in Genesis 6 is an abridged version. It's just an abridged—it's a cliff note,
basically, of a story that was clearly already well-known by the audience. So, the author of
Genesis, when he inserts into Genesis 6, again, this bizarre digression of the Genesis narrative
about these heavenly beings, the sons of God who descend and commingle with the daughters of men
and copulate with them, the reason he doesn't expand on that story is because it was already
well-known from oral tradition, but I also think from written tradition, namely the Book of Enoch,
or some version of the Book of Enoch. So, the story was already so well-known to the audience that the
writer of Genesis, whether it was Moses or someone else, didn't need to retrace the details of this
story. It was so well-known. It was so essential to the fabric of their cosmology. And indeed,
the Book of Enoch lays out this story. So, what does it say? The Book of Enoch says that
in the days of Jared, who was the sixth from Adam, Jared was the father of Enoch,
that these heavenly beings, which the Book of Enoch denominates as watchers, and the watcher
denomination is not exclusive to extra-biblical texts. It's in the Bible. It's in the book of
Daniel. That these beings called the watchers, 200 of them, decided that they were going to descend
to the earth, or maybe they were already on the earth, but that they were going to—they wanted to
take wives from the daughters of men. They wanted to wed the maidens, the daughters of Adam,
because they were beautiful. And they wanted to procreate with them. And they wanted to essentially
to make families, to sire offspring. And these watchers knew, these 200 watchers knew that this
was a grave transgression. And so, before they did this thing, they bound themselves on the summit
of Mount Hermon. According to the Book of Enoch, they descended on the summit of Mount Hermon.
And they bound themselves by an oath of mutual imprecations. In other words,
we're all in this together, and we're all going to suffer the consequences, whatever befall.
So, they bind themselves with an oath. And that's why, to this day,
Mount Hermon is known as the Mountain of Oath. And so, after binding themselves by an oath of
mutual imprecations, they descend into the plains. They choose for themselves wives. And then,
they make a transaction. I believe with the fathers of these maidens, a dowry of sorts is paid.
And they provide, the fathers provide their daughter's hand in marriage, the maidens.
And the watchers, in turn, as a dowry, remember, this is a very patriarchal society in the pre-flood
world, the fathers give their daughter's hand away. It's not like today where, you know,
it's mutual agreement, let's get married. In the antediluvian world and even in the ancient
post-diluvian world, and still is the case in some parts of the earth, the father gives the
daughter's hand in marriage in exchange for something, a dowry. And so, the watchers received
the daughter's hands in marriage from the fathers. And they, in turn, gave the fathers
information, knowledge, forbidden knowledge. Book of Enoch says they gave them the knowledge that
they were, that the men were striving to learn. And this, I think this was technological knowledge,
what we would call today scientific knowledge. And then the watchers,
just as it says in Genesis 6, they copulate with their wives who conceive and give birth
to a race of giants called the Nephilim. And then what results is men are corrupted by the
forbidden knowledge of the watchers. The giants grow to an enormous size and ultimately begin to
consume all of the acquisitions of the land so that men can no longer sustain their appetites. So,
human beings were basically subjugated to these, to this hybrid race of giants. And they were
spending all of their time and energy feeding them. And when they could no longer satisfy their
enormous appetites, the giants began to devour mankind. And it's at this point that men begin
to cry out to God. And the court of heaven hears the appeal of mankind. And God dispatches some
angels to the earth. He causes the, he binds the watchers. But by the way, I should say,
this is, nobody knows the duration of time from when the watchers descended the days of Jared
to the flood of Noah. At the very least, you're looking at hundreds of years, if not thousands of
years of this going on on planet earth. And then, so the watchers are dispatched. I mean,
the angels are dispatched to the earth. They bind the watchers. But before the watchers are
incarcerated in the abyss, they're forced to watch the destruction of their beloved sons,
of the giants, who are enticed, who are incited to war with one another. So, you have this
fratricidal war that takes place among the giants. And I describe this as the empire of the gods,
because it's not like, you know, big dumb giants from Disney movies when we were growing up,
you know, bashing each other over the head with clubs. These were exceptionally intelligent beings.
Their fathers, the book of Enoch says, taught them and their wives. They instructed them
in their knowledge. So, these, they were receiving the instruction of their fathers. So, these were very,
very intelligent beings, probably in possession of what I would describe as advanced
technology, maybe even advanced aerospace technology, which I do believe existed in
the antediluvian world. I think that's how the watchers got to the summit of Mount Hermon,
by the way, at the helms of advanced aerospace vehicles, what we would describe today as UFOs.
And so, to close out this story, the watchers, rather the giants go to war with each other.
I believe this is a technological war. And then, the flood ensues, the great flood. And the flood was
intended to cleanse the earth of the abominable seed of the watchers, and to reset mankind.
So, that's an encapsulation, a summarization of what the first section of the book of Watchers
describes, rather the book of Enoch, called the book of Watchers.
It's a great summary. If I were a biblical scholar, would I have any points around the book of Enoch to
say that it's, oh, it's just apocryphal, and it's not connected to the Bible? And what would you say to
those points?
Well, nearly all scholars agree that the book of Enoch provides the cosmological substrate
for the ancient Hebrews. There's no doubt about that. I mean, the story is referenced indirectly
in the Old Testament, obviously, Genesis 6, and in other portions, but also in the New Testament.
In fact, when you get to the New Testament, you find Jesus of Nazareth using a title, a very specific
title, the title he preferred, more than any other. It's a messianic title, but it doesn't come from the
Old Testament. It comes exclusively from the book of Enoch. And that title is the Son of Man. Now, there are
several titles that Jesus could have employed when referencing himself, messianic titles. And he did
use various titles, the Son of God, for example, which he was. But he uses the Son of Man the most,
and there is no reference. That is a proper title, the Son of Man. So, the only reference in the Old
Testament that scholars will go to is a reference in the book of Daniel, where Daniel sees one like
a Son of Man. But that is a descriptor. That is saying, like, I saw one who looked like a human
being, like an offspring of Adam. It's not a proper title. The proper title, the Son of Man, comes from
1 Enoch, specifically from the second section of 1 Enoch, which is called the parables. And the parables
are the oracles of Enoch. And the oracles of Enoch pertain primarily to the Son of Man and were
fulfilled, clearly fulfilled in Jesus of Nazareth. Now, there is some dispute in regard to when the
parables were authored or compiled. The book of Enoch, first of all, the book of Enoch is a compilation
of texts with several authors. And the various sections of Enoch were probably written at different
time, different periods of time. The oldest section, namely the Book of the Watchers, containing
the Enochian tale, the Watchers, that was written at least circa 300 BC. But I think that the oral
tradition at least is way older. I think it began with Enoch. And in fact, the Hebrews believed
that Enoch was the inventor of writing, that he was the first to write. And remember, Enoch
was revered as a prophet and a scribe. So he prophesied and he wrote. And tradition says
that those writings were delivered ultimately to Noah and preserved through the flood. So
is it possible that portions of 1 Enoch actually originate thousands of years ago, maybe the very
first writing ever conceived by the human species was written by the hand of Enoch. And that's
why people, the contention here is mostly from the secular world, that the Bible is, all of
the stories in the Bible are just copies of the more ancient Mesopotamian texts. Well, sure,
but what if the foundation for those stories goes all the way back to Enoch? Then everybody's
copying Enoch. And everybody has a version of what Enoch wrote. And it's very possible in my mind that
the Hebrews have the most faithful rendition of what was, of the oral traditions and of, in fact,
of the written compositions that came from the antediluvian world, which far predate the ancient
Mesopotamians. And Enoch was related to Noah, is that right?
Yes. Yes. I believe Enoch was his great, great grandfather. Enoch was the father of Methuselah,
who was the father of Lamech, who was the father of Noah.
Interesting. And yeah, in the Old Testament, you have, then Methuselah, a lot of these guys lived
for very long periods as well, which I think caused you to ask all sorts of interesting questions.
900 plus years.
That's right. Yeah. It's so fascinating. How, how was it found? How was the book of Enoch discovered?
The book of Enoch was preserved by the Ethiopians. And had the Ethiopians not preserved the book of
Enoch, we would not have it to this day. Because it was clearly expunged from the scriptoriums
of the Middle East and the West. There was controversy, a lot of controversy in the early
church age over the book of Enoch. Some of the early church fathers wanted to incorporate it into the
canon. So there was a debate, an ongoing debate that what, what cannot be denied is that the book
of Enoch was, is that the early church was conversant with what we call first Enoch today.
Now, there was clearly a different manuscript in circulation because some of the early church
fathers cite the book of Enoch and they're citing portions of, of, of the book of Enoch, which we
don't have today in what we call first Enoch, but then they also cite portions, which we do.
So some of these early church fathers referenced the book of Enoch as scripture. In fact, around the
4th century AD, the Tawahedo Orthodox Christians and the Beta Israel Jew, Jewish community in Ethiopia
incorporated the book of Enoch into their canon. That's why they preserved it. So to this day,
if you visit Ethiopia and you visit a synagogue or you visit an Orthodox church, among the scriptures
that we have in, in, in our canon in the West, you'll find the, the book of Enoch and, and some
other apocryphal works as well. They revered the book of Enoch and so they preserved it. So, um, but as I
said, the early church was undoubtedly, undoubtedly conversant with portions of what we call today
first Enoch. And, and what I was going to say before was you have the book of Enoch attested in
the old and new Testament. And when you read the parables, the oracles of Enoch, which are primarily,
um, prophecies pertaining to the Messiah, to the Christ, again, fulfilled in Jesus of Nazareth,
clearly, you realize that the writers of the New Testament derived much of their
eschatology and Christology, their theology regarding the Messiah directly from the oracles of Enoch.
And in fact, there are citations throughout the New Testament that are not found in the Old Testament
references, indirect references that are only to be found in the book of Enoch. So, um, it's, so scholars
will say, you know, it's divided, the scholarly community, there's lots of difference, difference
in opinions there in regard to the book of Enoch. They all will concede that, that the earliest portions
of Enoch are, are, are, were, were compiled around 300 BC. Some scholars will say that the, that the
parables, again, containing those messianic prophecies, were compiled some, sometime around 100 AD.
Um, there's a lot of debate about that, but because, precisely because it's apparent that the authors of
the New Testament are, are, are deriving so much of the theology from the parables of Enoch. Um, and so
it's, it's, it's, it's hard for some scholars to, to believe that these, that these prophecies, which are
so astonishingly accurate, uh, fulfilled, clearly fulfilled, as I keep saying in Jesus of Nazareth,
that those could have been written before the advent of Christ. I believe they were. I believe that the
oracles of Enoch are ancient, that, that first Enoch, um, that the earliest portions of first Enoch,
namely the book of the Watchers, and the oracles of Enoch were written by his hand.
That's what, or some version of them, you know, carried through the flood in the form of oral
tradition at the very least, and then someone later compiled them.
Yeah. Is there, uh, some sort of control mandate or something? If you think of the Council of Nicaea
and, you know, creating the modern canon. Yeah, I think so. Is there a reason to specifically get
rid of the book of Enoch because it's sort of subversive or irreverent in some way? Yes, because
the prevailing view became, especially because of, um, uh, Augustine, or Augustine, I always forget how to
pronounce his name, uh, the saint, uh, because he was a, he was a proponent. He was a, he was a proponent
of what's called, um, the non-supernatural view of Genesis 6. The supernatural view of Genesis 6 is
that the sons of God were the angels of heaven. Clearly this is the case because in the Septuagint,
which is a Greek translation of the, of the Old Testament, which was in circulation during the time
of Christ. And, and certainly during the early church, um, this is the, the, this was the manuscript
that, um, the non-Jewish converts were reading was the Septuagint of the Old Testament, right? So it's a,
it's a translation of the Tanakh, the Hebrew Old Testament into Greek. And in the Septuagint,
when you read Genesis 6, it doesn't say the sons of God, it says the angels of God. So that's
definitive. These are not human beings. These are celestial beings. And this was the
prevailing view, um, until probably the second century AD when the Jews, the Jewish community,
um, they, uh, they preferred the non-supernatural rending, rendering of that, of that verse. And,
and what they did was, uh, they said that the sons of God in Genesis 6, that, that copulated with
the daughters of Adam, that these were noble men from the line of Seth and, or the, the Sethites is
what they call it. It's called the Sethite theory. And these were not heavenly beings. These were just
men. And the church adopted that position. They followed suit and they adopted that position, um,
primarily because of St. Augustine. And, and so that became the prevailing view. And it is the
prevailing view to this day, although the tides are turning more and more people are realizing that
that's preposterous based on the, based on, by the way, the story of Enoch, uh, the, the Enochian tale
is attested, not just in Enoch, but in several Dead Sea Scroll manuscripts,
including the book of Giants, uh, the book of Jubilees, the Genesis Apocryphon and others,
all, all of these. And, and, and, and there's no question that, um, that the supernatural view
of Genesis 6 was the prevailing view during the second temple period. No question whatsoever.
And then you combine that with the Zeptepe, with the Greek gods, with like all of these other
kind of myths across disparate cultures, all involving sort of demigod, like little G gods,
and then some sort of flood. And it's like, okay, this, maybe we should stop treating this
just as myth and start treating it as history, Plato and so on. And all, you know, you, you,
it's just a, you know, kind of ubiquitous, you know, the difference is, this is kind of what makes
the Hebrew account unique. The difference is those other cultures, they viewed the antediluvian world
through a laudatory prism. In other words, they viewed it as this wonderful time of peace and
prosperity, of the sharing of knowledge from the gods to mankind. If the gods, as I said earlier,
were establishing, um, the, the, the foundations of civilization, of learning, of science, were
imparting them to mankind. And that the world that existed in the antediluvian world was in every
way vastly superior to, to their own civilizations, to their post-flood, post-cataclysmic
civilizations, post-cataclysm civilizations. That they, they, when they look back into the past,
very, this is antithetical to the way we look back into the past. So when we, as moderns, when we
look back into the past, we see this, you know, the timeline of history, right? We are, in our minds,
we're the pinnacle of civilization right now. We're the pinnacle of learning, scientific learning.
We're the smartest human beings ever to exist on planet earth. Everybody that preceded, preceded us
was, was inferior to us, intellectually speaking. And, and there's this, this gradual retrograde of
civilization as you go backwards on the timeline of history. So you start from superior modern man,
and then you, you, you progress backward through history and people are getting dumber and dumber
and dumber and dumber until you get into the Neolithic and you've got cavemen, right? You've
got these, just these, these Neolithic dummies, basically, you know, one step removed from,
from chimpanzees. That's not how the ancients viewed the past. Quite the opposite.
The way that our antescendants viewed the antediluvian world was that they were like
children trying to recover some vestige of the knowledge of the glory of the magnificence
of their antescendants that existed in the world before the cataclysm. They, when they went backward
in time, it wasn't a gradual decrease in the knowledge and sophistication of civilization, but
rather the, the civilizations that preceded them in the antediluvian world were vastly superior to
them.
Speaking of which, you said something amazing earlier. You said, you think that that time
period, those sort of demigod creatures used advanced aerospace vehicles. And, you know, I think of
the Vimana as just kind of the, you know, proverbial example of this. Do you have, is there any other
evidence that they actually had kind of technological, you know, aerial vehicles? Obviously, we have to
go to texts and that sort of thing.
You have to go to texts, yeah. So, I don't know of any archaeological evidence.
Sure.
Of course, you have anecdotal, you have anecdotal accounts like Bob Lazar.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Who said that, you know, among the craft that he saw in the hangars at the S4 facility, he was told
that one of them had been retrieved from an archaeological site.
That's right.
It was very ancient. Not the one he worked on, not the sports model, but a different one
had been allegedly, and he didn't know if this was true or not, but allegedly it had
been recovered from an ancient burial site, an archaeological dig. So, yeah, I don't have
any problem with that. You know, when you look back into the, again, this is a period of time
that the ancients described as the golden age. And what I was illustrating earlier was
that in the mind of the pagan cultures, this was the pinnacle of mankind, of civilization,
and it was a time of peace and prosperity. But from the Hebraic perception, this was a
dystopian nightmare. This was a time of great oppression, the empire of the gods, when essentially
the watchers were governing the earth by proxy behind the thrones of their hybrid giant offspring
who were devouring mankind, who were oppressing mankind. It was a time of unparalleled bloodshed
and sorcery and all manner of transgression against the king of heaven. That's the difference.
So, from the pagan worldview, the gods were like our Promethean benefactors. They stole fire from
the gods and gave it to mankind. But from the Hebraic perspective, these watchers were evil.
They were, these were malevolent beings and their intention was to deceive mankind and that mankind
was corrupted by the knowledge that was given to them, the forbidden secrets, as the book of Enoch has
it, and that all of this activity led to the flood, to the destruction of the world. So, that's a very
different view of the antediluvian age from the Hebraic perspective.
Do you think this book is not just this kind of, you know, past thing about, you know, kind of
metaphysics pre, you know, flood? And do you think it holds relevance today? Where are the watchers
today?
Yes, it does. So, to your first question, according to the book of Enoch and the Bible in the New
Testament, according to Peter, according to Jude, the watchers are currently chained up in, Peter
calls it Tartarus, the abyss, in the gloomy darkness. And this is directly from the book
of Enoch. So, when the angels were dispatched to bind the watchers, remember, the watchers
were first forced to watch the destruction of their beloved sons in this fratricidal civil
war, which, again, I think was technological. And then they were in prison. They were incarcerated.
And they're still incarcerated to this day. And according to the book of Enoch, they're going to
be incarcerated until the end of the age, when the age is fully consummated. That's what the book of
Enoch says. And until the day of judgment. So, until the very end. Now, there's some
biblical commentators, some colleagues of mine, who believe that the watchers are going to be
released at the end of the age, and that they're going to create a lot of havoc that you see
unfolding in the earth in the book of Revelation. I don't know. I personally think that the book of
Enoch is pretty explicit, that the watchers are going to be chained until the day of judgment,
which would mean all the way to the very end when the great judge returns to the earth. By the way,
I should probably—this is a little bit of a digression, but here's another illustration,
another attestation of the book of Enoch in the New Testament. Jesus was in the land of Gadara
with his disciples, and he was approached by a man, a man who the Bible describes, or two men,
depending on which gospel you're reading, who's described as the Gadarene demoniac,
because he was full of a legion of demons. You'll recall this story. So Jesus disembarks on the
shore of Gadara. This demon-possessed man, who has a legion of demons inside of him, comes running up
to Jesus and throws himself at his feet. And he declares, we know who you are, you son of God.
And then he says, why have you come to torment us before the appointed time?
And that always puzzled me when I was growing up as a teenager reading that. What do you mean
before the appointed time? What does that mean? They recognized that Jesus was that son of man,
from the oracles of Enoch, the son of God, and that there was an appointed time of judgment for
them. So why were they freaking out? Because they recognized two things. They recognized
that Jesus was the great judge. He was the judge who was going to judge them at the appointed time.
And the second thing they recognized was it wasn't time yet, but here's the judge. What are you doing
here? It's not time yet. You're early. Now, where does that come from? It doesn't come from the Old
Testament. It comes from the book of Enoch. Because when the giants destroy themselves in this
fratricidal war, they're cursed. God puts a curse on them because they're not fully of their celestial
fathers, the watchers, and they're not fully of their human mothers. So they're unsanctioned
sentient beings. And so they're cursed. When they die and their spirits depart from their bodies,
their spirits are now going to be forced to wander the earth as disembodied vagabond wraiths.
But the curse is this. They're going to have all of the desires of the flesh. They're going to be
hungry, thirsty, presumably have all of the sexual impulses of the flesh, but without corporeal bodies
through which to satiate these desires, to satisfy them. That's the curse. And you'll probably recall
that this was the Mayan curse in the curse of the Mayan gold in Pirates of the Caribbean. Remember?
That's the Nephilimic curse in the Pirates of the Caribbean. Barbossa and his crew were,
they were deathless, basically. They couldn't die, but neither could they enjoy anything while they
were alive perpetually. And remember, Barbossa wanted to bite into the apple and it was revealed,
I forget in the story, I think on a full moon or whatever, that they were like these wraiths
and they couldn't enjoy anything. And so they desperately wanted to break the curse. That was
the premise of the story. And that's exactly the situation of the spirits of dead giants. And this is
where you get the origin of demons in the New Testament and in the Old Testament. Demons,
according to ancient Hebrew cosmology, are the disembodied spirits of dead giants that persist
in the world. These evil spirits. That's like the definition. That's the definition. And in the
book of Enoch, the judgment that comes against the giants is you will be called evil spirits in the
earth or unclean spirits in the earth. And you will wander the earth. You'll be hungry, you'll be
thirsty, but you won't be able to satisfy the desires of your flesh because you won't have any
flesh. And so what do these beings do? What do these disembodied spirits do? They seek to inhabit
human flesh. They possess human beings in order to attempt to satiate these desires. That's why they
inhabit the body. So fast forward to the New Testament and you have Jesus of Nazareth encountering,
and his disciples encountering people who are demon possessed and they recognize who he is.
And he tells them to be quiet in a couple of occasions because they say, we know who you are,
you son of God. Right? And so now fast forwarding to the Gadarene demoniac who's inhabited by a
legion of demons. Oh, and I actually skipped the most imperative point here. Going back to the book of
Enoch, part of the curse was, this was going to be your lot. This was going to be your curse to the
spirits of the dead giants until the great judge appears to judge the living and the dead until the
day of judgment. And then they will be judged with finality and cast into the, into the, uh,
like a fire. And, and, and so the, the, the legion of demons recognizes that Jesus is the great judge
from the oracles of Enoch. And, and, and as I said before, knows that the time has not yet come
for their final judgment that comes directly from the book of Enoch. So it's just another illustration of
how the, the themes, the Enochic traditions and themes are woven through the old and new
Testament. And that's a digression, um, from what we're talking about. No, it's fascinating. And
a, a burning question I have is you have this conversation around UFO disclosure to alien
beings or, you know, non-human intelligence. You have, uh, Congresswoman Anna Paulina Luna going on
Joe Rogan and saying, you know, read the book of Enoch. That somehow is important for
this whole story. Like imagine a world in which if Enoch was left in the Bible and people were
like, wait, what happened? Okay. So if you read it, it talks about the fall of angels, um, thus
creating really the precursor of civilization that led to the first flood. Um, I think that when you
even go into potentially the technology that was given to mankind by these angels, it talks about the
hidden, um, beliefs and, and there is an astronomy, et cetera, metal workings, all of it. If you have
this information pertaining to UAPs, whatever might they might be, the origins. I mean, if you have a
understanding of what Enoch was talking about, kind of makes sense.
So what does this clearly, you know, not so apocryphal, actually probably core text in the book of
Enoch and the Nephilim and the Watchers, what does that have to do with modern kind of alien UFO
disclosure? Well, um, so generally speaking, what do you have in the book of Enoch and in Genesis 6
are extraterrestrial beings descending to the earth? And why do you think that? Well, because they are
by nature extraterrestrial. This is a, this is one of the things that I, I talked about in my book
Birthright. Um, so I think the word extraterrestrial is a very, uh, useful word. It's a very useful term
because extraterrestrial simply means a being whose provenance is not planet earth. So a being whose
origin is not the earth, that's an extraterrestrial. And of course, we're contextualizing this term
within the context of sentient beings. I'm not talking about amoebas here or something like that
or bacteria, although those would also be considered extraterrestrial, extraterrestrial bacteria.
Should we find bacteria on Mars, those would be defined as extraterrestrial bacteria, right?
Because they're not from the earth, even if they're very similar to bacteria on earth. Well,
they're extraterrestrial because they're not from the earth. So it's a very accurate term,
very useful term. Now, um, opponents of mine will say, wait, that's not a biblical term. Well,
I would like to highlight that neither is the term fallen angels, a biblical term, right? And a lot of
people think it is. It's not, you'll never, you will not find fallen angels in the Bible. It doesn't
exist. Now the concept is biblical. The concept of a quote unquote fallen angel is very biblical.
These, a fallen angel are defected sons of God. They are apostate sons of God. They're angelic
beings who defected from the kingdom and now are in opposition to God. We all understand that. That's
what fallen angel means. In the same way, the word extraterrestrial doesn't show up in the biblical
text or extra biblical text. They didn't use that terminology back then. But the concept is accurate,
is biblically accurate in that you have beings who are clearly not from planet earth,
whose provenance is not planet earth. And in, and indeed whose origin is preexistent to mankind,
they preexist us. This is clear, especially in the book of Job, where we read that the morning stars
sang together and the sons of God shouted for joy as the foundations of the earth were being laid,
or depending on how you view that as the earth was being renewed, previous to the creation of
mankind. So here you have sentient extraterrestrial beings. By definition, there's, they're not on the
earth. They're observing the creation or the reformation of the earth, depending on your theological
worldview. And they are celebrating it. They're shouting for joy. And the designation morning
star and sons of God, morning stars and sons of God is very important because morning stars,
the Bible uses the stars as a metaphor for angelic beings, for celestial beings. So a morning star,
what that designates are beings who were created early on, who are preexistent. You know, they're
the first beings to appear. In other words, the stars you see in the morning, it's like those are
the morning stars. These are the beings who appear at the beginning of creation, the first sentient
beings. So I think they're very old. And furthermore, they're called sons of God, which is very important
because that's a designation. That's a familial designation. These aren't just whatever sentient
beings. These are sons of God. These are members of the family. This becomes very important in the
biblical text. And this is something that I articulate in Birthright, is that Adam was created
to be a son of God, using that same familial language, and that we, through Christ, become
the sons of God, according to Jesus of Nazareth, being, by the way, sons of the resurrection.
So there's a family dynamic here. The Bible uses these familial terms because there's a family.
There's a divine family. And when you read the genealogy of Jesus of Nazareth, you know,
it traces Jesus through Joseph or through Mary, depending on which genealogy you're reading,
back through David, back through Abraham, back into the pre-flood world, through Enoch,
and all the way back to Adam. And when you get to Adam, it says, Adam, the son of God.
So what the Bible is signaling here is that Adam, the human species, was originally created,
designed, intended to be a member of the divine family. And so this ties into the gospel of Christ
later on because you understand when Jesus shows up on the scene, I hope you don't mind me digressing
into a bit of theology here. When Jesus shows up on the scene, he makes it abundantly clear that his
mission is to bring back the prodigal sons back into the family of God, that he gives us power to
become the sons of God. So, in other words, that's really the message of the gospel, that you were once
members of this family. You were once members of the divine family in Adam. And that was the
intention. Mankind was, in my estimation, created for two purposes. Number one, to commune with the
creator, with the maker, and with the other, with his, with who I describe in Birthright as his elder
siblings, these other sentient beings, the other sons of God who pre-exist mankind, to fellowship in
the family of God. That's the primary purpose. And then secondarily, to govern the earth, to govern
planet earth. These theological threads become very, very important when you get to the discussions that
are currently happening about extraterrestrials and how we ought to view that coming from a Christian
perspective, at least. And so, the whole point of the gospel is to return the sons and daughters back to the
family of God, illustrated, by the way, in the parable of the prodigal son. So, you have these
sons of God who pre-exist mankind. They're not, clearly, they're not human, and they're not from
planet earth. They are, therefore, by definition, extraterrestrial. The celestial beings, they're
extraterrestrial. Now, you can quibble over whether or not they come from a literal extraterrestrial
world, like a different planet in the universe, or they come from some kind of a spiritual world,
like a different, I guess, dimension, or you could just say they're interdimensional beings that come
from a different dimension. It doesn't matter which of these you choose. You're still talking about
beings whose origin, whose provenance is not planet earth. They are, therefore, unequivocally
extraterrestrial. So, this describes the beings who descended in the days of Jared, according to the
book of Enoch in Genesis 6. These beings came from some extraterrestrial realm. Again, whether you
think it's an interdimensional realm, like Anna Paulina Luna, whatever, it doesn't really matter.
And this lines up, by the way, with Sumerian myth. You have the Anunnaki.
Definitely.
Lines up with Greek myths, where you have these titans, and they're the sons of God. And,
you know, I'm hearing about the book of Enoch, and it sounds a lot like Prometheus, by the way,
where you have this sort of rebel faction of titans who try to give mankind sacred knowledge,
and then are, you know, in his case, I think he's chained up to a rock, and, you know, vulture has to-
That's right.
He picks at his liver, like, constantly. And so, this is an archetypal myth that cuts across
a lot of regions and cultures.
It's universal.
Yeah.
It's universal. The universal testimony of our antecedents is that there was an age previous
to a great flood or a great cataclysm in which the gods were dwelling on earth among men,
and parting their knowledge, establishing civilization, the benchmark, the trademarks of
civilization, and that those beings came from somewhere. And specifically, this is, by the
way, what the late researcher extraordinaire David Flynn unfolds in his book Cydonia, which
was the most, as I was telling you earlier, the book Cydonia, that's the most consequential
book I've ever read in my entire life.
You got me a copy. I really appreciate it.
Yeah.
It looks amazing.
It's, and his daughter, Ticey, who I'm friends with, I'm very good friends with his twin brother,
Mark, who's brilliant in his own right, author himself, and his daughter, Ticey, and his son,
Alexander. And I'm so excited that Ticey, because it was basically out of print for a long time.
There was a couple of places you could find it, but it was extreme. That book was, that book
before Flynn's daughter reprinted it, it was going for $2,000 and $3,000 online. And then
she reprinted it. Now you can get it for like $25 on Amazon. But Flynn really unpacks a lot
of this in that book. And it really, that provided sort of the substrate for my book, Birthright.
Right. And, and what Flynn proves, I would say definitively, is that not only did the ancients
believe that the gods descended to the earth in the antediluvian world in the, during the golden
age, but that they came from somewhere very specific. They came from a planet in our solar
system.
Which planet?
Well, there's, it's which planets. Primarily, there's, there's a planet that, that Flynn talks
about, which is, which is, you know, sort of in, in, in, in popular culture, it's referred
to as Krypton. That's where you get the, the Superman mythology from. But the ancients also
had a Krypton in mind, a destroyed planet, a destroyed realm from which the gods descended, or a
destroyed, destroyed realms, more specifically. And one of these planets, Flynn believed, and
I, and I believe this as well, I write it in Birthright, is actually named in the biblical
text, cryptically.
It's called Rahab.
Wow.
And that this planet, there was a, there was this conflict that erupted in the cosmos long
before the creation of mankind. Because in Flynn's view, and I completely concur, our solar
system was inhabited by a non-human extraterrestrial race of angelic beings. So Flynn viewed this
very much, not as sort of like an interdimensional thing, but literally the planets were inhabited.
That's why on the cover of that book there, you have the ruined, the ruined structures on
Mars. And I believe, of course, most of us are familiar with the Cydonia region of Mars,
the alleged face on Mars. And Richard Hoagland was instrumental in publicizing this back in the
90s. And in fact, Richard Hoagland did a series of conferences with David Flynn, and sometimes they
were accompanied by the late Michael Heiser, the scholar. And they really, as I said, really
publicized the idea that there are ruins on the planet Mars. Ruins of an ancient advanced
civilization. Of course, you have the remote viewer, McDonagall.
Yeah, Joe McMonagall.
McMonagall, who recently, I believe he was on Sean Ryan's show.
He was tasked by the CIA to remote view Mars a million years ago and described giant beings.
That's right.
And ruins. And ruins, yeah.
And ruins, eight to 12 feet tall beings and pyramid structures. By the way, I think on
Cydonia, you do have some pyramid-like structures.
The DNM pyramid, which is a massive, massive pyramid.
It's remarkable. And then you also have this guy-
Allegedly.
Allegedly. You have this guy, John Brandenburg as well, who's a PhD physics who worked at
Lawrence Livermore in Sandia. And he believes that Argon-40 and Xenon-129 exist in excess
of what you would ever see just based on kind of natural decay. And this is proof of a nuclear
cataclysm that occurred on Mars.
And apparently he got called by Carl Sagan when he started to talk about this publicly.
And Carl Sagan was like, John, why are you making such a fuss about all this stuff or something
like that?
And you know what? I mean, so Hoagland and Flynn were talking about this back in the 90s and early
2000s. And then NASA, you know, NASA released some, the early photographs that it looked like a face
on Mars. It looked like a pyramid. And then they released new higher resolution photographs,
which seemed to debunk the whole thing, right? No, actually it doesn't look like a face and it's
not really this. I personally, I have no proof of this. Okay. I'm just spitballing, but I personally
think that the images from the first mission of the surface of Mars were correct, were accurate.
And that NASA released those second higher resolution images to sort of quell the firestorm
that had erupted. And I am extremely persuaded that there are ruins that dwarf anything on planet
Earth. The ruins of an ancient civilization on the planet Mars, specifically in the region of
Cydonia. And this, what's so fascinating about this is that the ancients believed that the gods
descended from Mars and from this other planet that was destroyed. It's sort of, and this is, again,
sounds very complex. It is. And Flynn lays it out. I mean, you read Cydonia and it's like,
to me, there's no question that the ancients believed that the gods descended from Mars and
from Rahab. And as I said before, I believe that the destruction of Rahab, which is always associated
with the wrath of God, this pre-Adamic conflict that erupted in our solar system, and this faction,
this defected faction of angelic beings who went to war with the King of Heaven. And it's associated
with the dragon. And the dragon becomes a moniker for Satan in the Bible, which neither dragon nor
Satan are his actual names, nor Lucifer, by the way. That's a misnomer from the Vulgate,
from Jerome's Vulgate. But there's this character in the Old and New Testament, the Bible, who's never
actually named. He's much like Voldemort from the Harry Potter series. It's he who should not be
named, right? He's never actually named. But he's the great opponent of the King of Heaven and of the
purposes of God. And one of his, I think, one of his primary monikers is the dragon or the serpent.
And so the destruction of Rahab, and Flynn goes through this in Cydonia, I go through this in
Birthright. There are multiple verses in the Old Testament that seem to suggest that God shattered
a planet, that he shattered Rahab like a vessel of clay. He pierced the dragon and shattered Rahab.
Are there any of those verses that come to mind? And then what's the evidence that it's Mars
specifically?
Well, the shattered planet isn't Mars. The shattered planet is Rahab.
Okay.
So the idea is that the asteroid field, the asteroid belt between Mars and Jupiter,
that that is the residue of a planet that exploded. And the contention, the popular contention,
is that there's not enough debris. It can't be a planet. There's not enough debris. But
recent papers have been published, peer-reviewed papers. I read a couple of them, one at least,
in which a very good case is made. And I wish I could cite the paper here, but I can't. I don't
remember what it is.
We'll pull it out.
That there is enough debris because much of the debris, if a planet exploded,
much of the physical debris would have, A, been vaporized, and B, shot off into space.
So you would have the planet explode. Much of the debris is just getting
jettisoned into deep space. And only a very small fraction of it would get caught up in the
gravitational pull of the sun and would form ultimately the asteroid belt between Mars and
Jupiter. Now, I'm not an astrophysicist, okay? So I'm way out of my depth talking about this kind
of stuff. But the ancients believe, you can track it, that there was a planet that was destroyed.
And this is one of the places that the gods came from. Now, it connects to Mars. Because Mars was
destroyed partly because in the wake of the destruction of this planet, which again, I also
believe is attested in the biblical narrative. There's a few verses, and I have them in my book,
Birthright, the exact verses, but there are some verses in the Psalms and elsewhere,
which position the earth as a spectator to this cosmic destruction that causes the mountains
to melt like wax. And so you can imagine if there was a massive planet between Mars and Jupiter,
assuming that the planets today are in the same orbits as they used to be, because there's a
possibility that such an explosion could have pushed, you know, could have moved things around. But
that planet implodes. I mean, we can't even imagine the destructive force that that would
have unleashed. I mean, there's no explosion, except for like a supernova that we can think of
that would be that powerful. But when that planet exploded, it rained down fire. Shards of Rahab
bombarded the surface of Mars, bombarded the surfaces of the other planets in the solar system,
bombarded the surface of the earth, and absolutely reduced everything to rubble, eviscerated whatever
civilizations were inhabiting those planets. But also, previous to the destruction of Rahab,
I believe, again, in the biblical narrative, you can trace the thread of a cosmic pre-Adamic war
that erupted in the heavens among this angelic civilization, and possibly other things as
well. And it was between what the Bible describes as the king, the king of heaven, who vanquished
the dragon, who pierced the dragon, who crushed the dragon's head and shattered Rahab like a vessel
of clay. And that in that process, in this conflict, the civilization on Mars was eviscerated. In other
they were first engaged in this conflict, technological conflict, with, again, who the Bible describes
as the king of heaven, who is revealed to be the son of God, a kinetic war. And then after that,
you know, or in the midst of that conflict, Rahab explodes. God destroys it. And then that's like,
that's the final blow to this rebel faction. So this would be, the idea here is a rebellious faction
of quote-unquote fallen angels are going to war with the king of heaven, kinetic war in the cosmos,
indeed in our solar system, before the creation of Adam. So this is a pre-Adamic race of intelligent
beings, clearly extraterrestrial, especially if their habitation is on Mars and Rahab and elsewhere in the
cosmos, which I believe it was. And I don't think it's even controversial on kind of conventional
astronomical circles to say that Mars had a biosphere at one point. I mean, there are water
caverns all throughout Mars. I believe also in the 90s, there was ALH 84001, this meteor that was found
that Bill Clinton made a speech on and said they found, you know, polycyclic hydrocarbons or whatever
in the meteor. And I think they sort of backtracked that, like they backtracked on the, you know,
the Viking missions. By the way, I've heard that the JPL guy who was in charge of the Viking missions
also swears by there being sort of, you know, evidence of life on Mars or something in his
sort of secret life. So it's all very interesting.
What's even more interesting is that Elon Musk is determined to put men on Mars.
Occupy Mars.
And what people don't realize, again, I'm going to reference Cydonia. This is what Flynn traces in
his book, is that the objective to put a man on Mars is an ancient aspiration. It is in fact one of
the primary objectives of the mystery schools.
Really?
Yes. To make contact with this, to recover the lost knowledge of the gods on Mars.
On Mars specifically.
Like mystery schools, like the Brotherhood of the Serpent and the Freemasons.
Mystery schools going all the way back to, I believe they go back to Cain on, obviously,
that's just a conjecture of mine. But certainly, unequivocally, the mystery schools are perpetuated
primarily through the Phoenicians. And the Phoenicians really are the, you might, aside
from the antediluvian mystery schools, if they existed, the Phoenicians are certainly
the primary post-Diluvian keepers of knowledge from the antediluvian world. I mean, the Phoenicians
were the great masons of the ancient world and navigators.
Seafaring people.
They circumnavigated Africa, for sure. I think they crossed the Atlantic. I think they
were mining copper in the Great Lakes. I know that's very controversial. I think that
the reason why you find red-haired giants, the remains of red-haired giants in the Mounds
of America back in the 18 and early 1900s, is because they came over the sea with the Phoenicians.
The Phoenicians had a cult of giant worship.
All kind of evidence of giants among the Phoenicians. And the Phoenicians are like, they were essentially
a secret society.
Wow. Fascinating.
And they, I mean, who did Solomon contract with to build the temple?
Phoenicians?
The Phoenicians. Hiram of Tyre. And Hiram of Tyre, his artificer, the Hiram of Tyre, the king,
and Hiram of Tyre, his premier artificer. That's who built the temple, Solomon's temple.
They were the master masons. They built the fleets for Egypt, for ancient Egypt.
And so, and the mystery schools have this aspiration, because I think of the Temple
of Solomon as part of the mystery school aspiration and interest as well. But they have this sort
of through line around getting to Mars? I didn't know that.
Yes. Yes. So again, one of the primary aspirations of the mystery schools is to recover the lost
knowledge of the gods from Mars. Now, is our aspiration, is Elon Musk's aspiration to go to
Mars associated with this? Or just part of that impetus, this sort of undercurrent for the mystery
schools? Is there a hidden hand directing us back to Mars? I would say so. And I think when we go there
soon, probably in our lifetime, we are going to find evidence of an ancient civilization,
extraterrestrial civilization on Mars. And I have a feeling that it's going to be announced rather
soon, perhaps even by President Trump, that there's microbial life on Mars, or was. That we
have evidence of... I mean, NASA's sort of already beginning to prime that pump. So I think what's
going to come first is the announcement that, hey, there was life on Mars. We have evidence of
microbial life on Mars. And that's the preamble. That would be a good... To the big one.
Little soft disclosure, exactly. Yeah, exactly. Test the water, see what happens there. So I think,
okay, so we have, let's establish a baseline. So we have these watchers that came down,
they were extraterrestrial, they mated with man, they created Nephilim, of which we are kind of the
descendants, the Nephilim were banished. They were made to be kind of these disincarnate kind of
wandering spirits, demonic spirits. And then we have all this interesting evidence that a lot of
this actually holds astronomical weight in the ancient world. What does all of this have to do
with modern, you know, we think about UFOs flying around and alien abductions. And is there anything
that we think of, you know, metaphysically back then with those stories that still apply to today?
Because I think my biggest question is like, you have UFOs back then, and you have sacred knowledge
back then. The sacred knowledge gets lost in the flood. And now, you know, circa 2026,
you have Trump tweeting about UFOs. We're all talking about all this stuff.
Yep. And then you have this alleged group of evangelical Christians who are being talked
about all the time now.
The Collins elite.
Collins elite, the so-called Collins elite. Yeah. It's all very interesting.
Yeah. So do you think the flying vehicles of today, because you're kind of, you could be
considered a modern UFOlogist. You research a lot of these phenomena today. You know, if the
watchers are chained up somewhere, but some of that knowledge made its way to mankind,
where, what are these aerial vehicles that we're seeing?
So that's actually a great point. So these 200 watchers that descended to the earth within
the biblical context, these were a separate group from the other beings, the other angelic
beings who the Bible describes in many ways, but in one passage is the devil and his angels,
right? So the Satan figure was here before the watchers descended to the earth. Satan was here
with his quote unquote fallen angels. I'm not a big fan of that term, but people understand when
I use it what I mean. So these apostate rebel sons of God, angelic beings are here on the earth
and they have not been chained up. They've been here. They were here before us. Um, and
this is a remnant of that. Let's put it into the star Wars terms, a rebel Alliance, except in this
case, they're the bad guys who were fighting against the kingdom of heaven that we talked about
earlier when Rahab exploded in the, in the, the civilization on Mars and all that. They came from
there. So we're not even that we're not even referencing the watchers in that context. The
watchers came afterward. The watchers came in the days, descended in the days of Jared. So
humankind was already populating the earth. That's when the watchers descended, but, but you know,
the dragon, the devil and his angels, Satan and, and, and his, uh, uh, and his consort, his,
his cohort, they came to the earth or were cast down to the earth a long time ago after that cosmic
battle. So they were here before Adam, they were here before the watchers. They're a separate
group. Um, these are, these are, these are heavenly beings, right? Um, probably the same kind of
beings as the watchers. And by the way, there's a misconception and this really is, is propagated in
the West. And this, this has to do more with a cultural perception than any sort of a biblical
fact is, is the idea that, that quote unquote fallen angels are these ugly, grotesque, demonic
looking beings, like they're, you know, like they look reptilian or something, or they have horns and
whatever. There's no indication that that's true anywhere. That's not a, that's certainly not a
biblical concept. That's a Western traditional concept because we ascribe, we, we, we ascribe their
qualities, their, the attributes that they're cunning and they're deceptive and they're evil,
you know, that these are malevolent beings. And so we portray them. Traditionally, the church has
portrayed them in cultural, in culture as these ugly beings, right? Who embody these attributes.
But, but I believe that these, in fact, biblically speaking, Satan is described as, as the most
beautiful being. He's the, he was, he was, he was the sum of perfection and, and, and, and he was
absolutely beautiful. And so quite the opposite of the Western tradition. And I think that goes for
Satan and, and the other angelic beings who defected with him from the kingdom and, and are now in
opposition of the King of heaven. And they're, at least in part here on earth, and again, have been
long before Adam, at least from my theological perspective and many others as well. But, but
from my theological perspective, they've been here a long time. So let's differentiate between the
watchers who descended in the days of Jared and who the Bible designates as the devil and his angels,
the dragon and the other, the other apostate princes, because that's what they are. These were
princes in the kingdom of heaven. Okay. So what I'm trying to describe here is a kingdom, a real
kingdom, not an imaginary kingdom, not a spiritual kingdom, not a interdimensional kingdom, because
these are all, there may be, you know, interdimensional aspects and things like that, but I'm trying to
get people to disassociate the kingdom of heaven with sort of the fairy tale stuff and think of it
instead as a practical functioning kingdom. And, and that the, the, the, those who've defected from
that kingdom before the creation of Adam, in other words, angelic beings who defected from that
kingdom are still here with us today and perhaps elsewhere. Um, and, uh, and that those beings,
according to the Bible are still active in the world. And so, so from my point of view, these beings
are, they, they, they, they, they are very comely. They look, we look like them, these angelic beings,
which is, which is, which is apparent in the, in the biblical narrative. Every time human beings
encounter angels in the narrative. And when I, I'm stressing narrative because you have the narrative
of the Bible and then you have the prophetic content. The prophetic content is a world of symbolism.
This is, you know, when, when, when the prophets are having these visionary experiences,
they're either a, in a trance or B dreaming. They never go anywhere. They're in a trance or
they're dreaming. So just like in a dreamscape, everything you encounter in a dreamscape in as
much as it means anything is symbolic. So this is a world of symbolism and communication, the world of
the, what I'm calling the prophetic, right? So set that aside. And, and, but the narrative,
what I refer to as the narrative, the biblical narrative is the actual story. I'll give you an
example. Abraham encounters angelic beings in the narrative, not in a vision, not in a trance.
In the actual narrative of the story, Abraham encounters a group of angelic beings and he
has dinner with them. He sups with them. He interacts with them just like we interact with
each other. And they look like us. They look human. They're not human, but they look human.
So his nephew Lot encounters angelic beings who come to extract him and his family before the
destruction of Sodom. And what does he do with these beings? He eats with them. He has dinner with
them. And then they escort him out of the city and the city is destroyed. So what I'm trying to
establish here is, is that these beings that we describe, again, I'm coming from a Christian
perspective, the beings that we describe, that we call angels in the Bible, we have a false
perception of what these beings are, what they look like and what they do. And that perception comes
from tradition. It's, it's, it's not extracted from the biblical narrative. It rather, it comes from
church tradition and just Western tradition in general. And in the Western tradition, of course,
we're all familiar with the depiction of cherubim in the Catholic church in Roman Catholicism,
which depicts them as, as little chubby toddlers, basically with little wings, is absurd. That's
absurd. That's not what cherubim are. That's not how they're described in the Bible. And even the way
they're described in the Bible is symbolic. So, because that's within the, that's within that
visionary context. But angels, whenever they're in the, whenever they're actually interacting with
mankind in the narrative, they look very much like we do and they don't have wings. Angels do not have
wings. And in fact, there are these vehicles that are described in the Bible, and I'm not talking
about Ezekiel's wheel. Because Ezekiel's wheel, we're going to relegate that to the trance visionary
stuff, the dreamscape stuff, because that's what that was. It's symbolic. So, I don't think Ezekiel's
wheel is a, is a UFO. However, in the narrative, you have these other vehicles that are called the
chariots of God, or the chariots of Israel, or the chariots of fire. They're described variously,
but the same thing. And these are, it's very ambiguous, but these are clearly some kind of
vehicle of conveyance. And, you know, I'm old enough to know that horses don't fly.
And, you know, the Bible doesn't oblige me to believe that horses fly. Because when you think
of a chariot, obviously, a chariot is the most advanced vehicle of conveyance in the mind of the
Iron Age rider, right? There's nothing that's more advanced than a chariot. That's it. I mean,
that's, that's like the Ferrari of their time. So, chariot is pulled by horses. So, if you're
trying to describe a vehicle that is advanced, you might describe it as a chariot, a chariot of fire,
or a chariot of God, or a chariot of Israel. And so, I do believe that these beings, these angelic
beings, A, as I said earlier, they look like us. Why do they look like us, by the way? It's something
I mentioned earlier. Because they're our siblings. They're the older siblings. They're the sons of God
that pre-exist us. Then Adam's created to be a son of God. So, it's a family. Clearly, it's a family.
And we were supposed to be part of it. So, and we were part of it in the beginning. But we've been
sundered from the family, divorced from the family of God. This is a great tragedy of our story.
We were sundered from the family, subjected to, subjected to decay and degeneration. And, but the
good news is, and this is what the good news, what I alluded to earlier, is that there's a way back in
through Christ. He brings us back and restores us back into the family of sons. So, these other sons
of God, the morning stars, remember that we're singing together, and the sons of God shouting for
joy before mankind was created, that because we're members of the same family, we bear the same image.
We look similar to one another. And I would go further than that. I would say, based on everything
we've discussed here from the book of Enoch in Genesis 6, we're so alike that we're genetically
compatible. We can copulate. We can procreate. That's exactly what we're doing in the book of
Enoch. That's exactly what's happening in Genesis 6. The sons of God are procreating with human women.
So, I just, I just choose the path of least resistance here. It's because they're genetically
compatible. And one thing I didn't mention when we're talking about those sons of God was that
the impetus, what I call the first cause of the watcher's defection, was lust. They lusted,
the book of Enoch says. And this is what the Genesis 6 implies. They lusted after the daughters of men.
They were sexually attracted to human women. Well, I mean, we can extrapolate then that they have
the male machinery, right? Because if you're just some wraith or you're just some spiritual being,
how do you lust? How are you consumed with lust after the female form? And then furthermore,
how do you copulate with a woman and procreate? And so, again, I just take the path of least resistance.
I add up all of these data points from the biblical narrative, and I conclude that we are the younger
sibling. They're the older sibling. I call them the elder race in my book. By the way, that's a wink
and a nod to J.R.R. Tolkien. Remember the Eldar? Yes.
In the Lord of the Rings and the Silmalarian were the elves, were the high elves, who were somewhat
related to humans and could certainly copulate with them. But that's not exactly from where I derive
the idea. I derive it from the biblical text, that we are the younger sibling. So, why am I building?
I'm building this structure here so that I can begin to build on top of it. So, what I'm trying
to depict here is that there's a faction of beings, perhaps one of many, that pre-exist us.
They look like us. Rather, we look like them. They're more magnificent than we are.
And King David said in the Psalms that mankind was created to be a little lower than the heavenly
beings. Okay? So, these are those heavenly beings. We were members of the same family. That's why we
literally look like each other. We bear the image of our Father. And who's the express image,
according to the Scriptures, the express image and likeness of the Father? The Son of God. So,
basically, we look like the Son of God, who's the preeminent Son. And so, we are genetically
compatible. We can copulate. And so, I'm depicting a class of beings, angels, who are technologically
advanced, who use, utilize technology, dare I say flying saucers, who have knowledge that is much
older than any knowledge on earth, much more advanced, who come from a kingdom the Bible
describes as the kingdom of heaven, a literal kingdom with a king and a council and courts and
courtiers and couriers and armies. You know, the most common name for Yahweh in the Old Testament is
Lord of Hosts. That means Lord of Armies. So, you have angelic armies. And when I was a kid, I always
thought, how do you have supernatural armies? How do they do battle? And because I was thinking of it
as supernatural, which means above and beyond nature. And I've since changed my view. And I believe
there is precisely one supernatural being in the universe, and that is the Father, God, Supreme.
Everything else, everybody else is subjected to the laws of nature, equally so. So, you have this
functional kingdom from which these beings come. Now, so, you have this faction of beings,
the angelic faction, the sons of God, the morning stars. These are all the same. I'm using those terms
analogously for these beings. And we look like them. They use technology. They speak a language.
And then you have a group of them that defected. Those are the, quote, unquote, fallen angels. That's
the group that defects from the kingdom. Those are the beings who are in opposition to the king of
heaven on earth, opposition to his kingdom, opposition to mankind, corrupting, always seeking
to corrupt and cause mankind to become disaffected with the kingdom of heaven and to sin against God
and to reap the repercussions, which is what they were doing with Israel. And these beings are here.
So, those beings speak the same language as the unfaithful, fallen angelic beings speak the same
language as the faithful ones. They look the same. They use the same technology. So, again, what I'm
doing here is I'm creating this structure upon which, coming from a Christian perspective, to be able to
understand the phenomenon without reverting to supernaturalism.
What do you think they want to do with humanity now? Do they have intentions for us?
Oh, yeah. There's no question about it. I mean, from a biblical perspective, the enemies of God,
first and foremost, are in opposition to everything that God desires. And almost their job is to lead
mankind astray into apostasy, to cause mankind to transgress and to destroy us, and by doing so,
to do injury to God. That's part of what they do. They're also—this is all building. This is all
crescendoing. This is the crescendo of my book, Birthright. The culmination is—
Armageddon. And Armageddon is so often interpreted as a war with Israel. But if you really pay attention,
Armageddon is a war with the Son of God returning to the earth. And I believe that's a kinetic war.
So, I think that literally these fallen sons of God, these apostate sons of God are slowly
building—eventually, they're going to be building an army. They're amassing the technology. They're
building an army. They're leading humanity into a post-human condition. And the objective is to usurp
dominion of the earth and resist the Son of God returning to the earth. Now, I understand that, you know,
that's a very theological position. So, your viewers who aren't coming from a biblical perspective may think
that that's absolutely absurd. However, from a biblical perspective, that's absolutely accurate.
So, yes, there's a conflict coming. And all of this is mounting towards that conflict,
that ultimate conflict between good and evil. And so, those beings are at work in the earth.
They've been here for a very long time. So, let me make this really practical for people.
And then I'll shut up. Let me make this really practical.
No, I love it.
So, you know, I'm—you're probably aware—I'm a person who is completely, utterly convinced
of the nuts and bolts reality of the UFO phenomenon. Because I myself have seen a UFO right above my car,
40 feet above my car. You know, a UFO. I think it was an ARV. But nevertheless—
Where was this?
Brook Park, Ohio.
Whoa.
Is that near Wright-Patterson?
No, it's near the John Glenn NASA Research Center and also—well, yeah, the NASA Center there.
So, you think it was possibly human reverse-engineered or—
So, I'll digress into this really quick because this does sort of illustrate the point I was about
to make. So, this was during a time—this was probably, my God, I don't know, 14 years ago. I
don't know. I always probably say a different number because I'm really bad with numbers and dates
and stuff. It was before—I currently live in Montana. It was before I moved to Montana. I was
living in Brooklyn, Ohio, where I was born. I was born in Brooklyn, Ohio. And I had just returned,
you know, a year or two previous to that from Peru. I lived in Peru for about 10 years. And I was living
in Cleveland and not far from my brother-in-law. And he and I would always work out in his basement.
And we'd always lift weights in his basement. And I would say, more often than not, the topic of
conversation was UFO stuff. And we were deep into Lazar and just kind of kicking around what the
reverse-engineered technology would look like and, you know, all of that sort of stuff. Talking about
gray aliens, talking about sort of all the ufological lore. That was more often than not the topic of
conversation. And he's an inventor. And so he liked to think about, like, you know, maybe what some of
the anti-gravitics look like and stuff like that. And so one day, probably was the topic of conversation
this evening. We were working out in his basement. And he wanted to run over to the suburb of Brook
Park, Ohio, which is, that's where I actually grew up, was in Brook Park, Ohio. And so we hopped in
my car. And this was probably, we were trying to get there before it closed. I think it closed at
nine o'clock. This was in February. Really, it was really cold outside. And it was really windy this
particular night, like really, really windy. And we jumped in my car and we drove over to Brook Park
and we went to the Brook Park Strip Mall, the Brookgate. It was called Brookgate Strip Mall.
I don't know if it's still there to this day, but I used to ride my bike around there. I'm very
familiar with this area. And then, you know, not far from there is the airport in the John Glenn
Center, the NASA Center. And there's also a, um, um, a, um, reserve, um, what do you call it? The
Army Reserve or whatever it's called, um, base close by. Air Force Base or Army Base, okay.
Yeah. And, um, uh, National Guard. National Guard. National Guard. And so we're, we're,
it's dark outside. It's probably 830 or so. And we're, we're, we're pulling up to the
Brook Park, Brookgate shopping, uh, strip mall. And there's this light and we got to go through
the light. Then you go into the parking lot and we're stopped at the light and we're, we're both
kind of just, we're just talking. He, I remember he was talking to me about some invention he had
related to like a toothbrush. I can't remember that. And, um, and as he's talking, we're, we're,
we're just kind of looking ahead and we see this thing, this craft hovering above the corner store
and it's got really bright lights. And we immediately thought it was a, a training exercise
from the National Guard. That's what we thought. Oh, look at that. There's a helicopter. It's a
training exercise. Like it was big. I thought it was like a Chinook or something or like a Blackhawk.
And, and, and we were just sort of, um, you know, uh, amazed that they're, they're hovering
that low over the building. It was probably only 30 feet above the building. And so we rolled our
windows down because we thought we were going to hear the telltale sound of blades whipping
through the air. Nothing. And we were close enough. We should have heard it. And we, and it was windy
granted. And we looked at each other like, uh-oh. So I go through the light. There's hardly anybody in
the parking lot. Cause it's almost, everything's almost closing, right? We're rushing to get to
the store, probably 845 by now, pull into the parking lot. And I don't even like park. I just
throw my vehicle into park because this craft that was hovering above the corner store, it lifts up in
the air and effortlessly glides right over my car, but it wasn't directly above. It was in front so
that it, it like positioned itself so I could get a full view of it through my windshield. So it was in
front, but above. And then it descended to about 40 feet. And it was immediately apparent to me and
my brother-in-law that this was not National Guard. This was not, this was not anything
conventional. Um, it, it was reminiscent of the F-117 Nighthawk fighter. It had sort of that angular
body armor, a little bit of that. And it was like a grayish green, dark color. Although it was hard to
tell because it was nighttime, it had really bright triangular lights. I remember two, my brother-in-law
remembers one, but triangles, lights, white. And then it had a series of, I think, green and blue
lights around the perimeter, the bottom. And it, it didn't have wings. It had little stubby protrusions
in the place of wings. And it was kind of shaped like a diamond. And, um, and it, it, it was,
it didn't really have sharp angles. It was very smooth. Um, there was no visible windshield or
anything like that. No markings. There was no propulsionary systems, propulsion system to speak
of, no engines, no propellers. Um, nothing like that at all. Again, it just had little stubby
protrusions in the place of wings. It was not aerodynamic is what I'm trying to say. And, and we
rolled our windows down to listen to hear if it, if there's any noise of an engine, nothing
completely silent. All we heard was the wind. The wind was so strong that it was rocking my car
like this. Um, it's rock, the gusts of winds are rocking my little Kia Sportage, I think is what
I had at the time. And, and this thing just, like I said, descended and just hovered there like I was
supposed to see it. And we're just staring at this thing. I remember saying, the only thing I could
say was Tony, that is some top secret. And then we're just staring at this and, and, and then
suddenly like, I'm thinking, I don't, I have a flip phone at the time. He has a smartphone. I'm
thinking, get a picture, get a video, get video of this thing. So I said, Tony, your phone,
your phone. And he like, like he's coming out of a trance and he starts, you know, looking for his
phone in his pocket. He finds his phone, pulls it out, drops it on the ground. So he, he bends over
to pick up his phone, right. To get a, to get a picture or footage. And as he's bending over, I mean,
we probably were staring at this thing for at least 30 seconds, which is a long time, maybe even a minute
or two. I don't remember. We had a long look at this thing. And as he's fidgeting on the ground to find
his phone, the craft lifts up into the air again, it is so windy. And I failed to mention the craft
is completely unaffected by the wind completely as if it's in its own atmospheric bubble lifts up
into the air. And then it begins to turn effortlessly. And by the time he gets his phone up, it's moving
away and it's just gliding away. And we jump out of the car and it is, I just remember jumping out of
the car getting blasted in the face with ice cold wind. And by the time he got his phone up,
it was descending over the horizon, like over behind the houses toward the glass. I'd rather
toward the NASA, um, John Glenn center, by the way, right in that direction.
Whoa.
No, I, again, it had no insignia, no air force insignia. It was not a helicopter. It was the
size of a Chinook or a Black Hawk helicopter, no insignia, no propellers, no noise, no propulsion
system, no windshield. Was it a drone? I don't know. Whatever it was, it was not using conventional
technology. That's for sure. You know, I mean, you know, when a Harrier jet takes off, if there's
vehicles below it, it like blows them out of the way. Right. Um, this thing, nothing. So I don't know
why, but I sort of concluded that I was looking at, you know, what, what people call ARVs, alien,
um, reproduction vehicle. I, I don't know why I can't, I can't say, I don't know why, but I got
the distinct sensation that, that, that this was ours. This was, this was, but, but that the technology
was exotic. I don't know. That was just a feeling, which doesn't mean much, but that's what I saw.
Wow. And, and that was it for me. Okay. So everything that I had been learning about in
the realm of ufology, right. Was suddenly concretized in that moment. Now that doesn't
mean that everything's true, but it means the phenomenon is real. 100%. We've got advanced
technology. Now, whether we, you know, took some divergent path from Nikola Tesla and built it
ourselves or whether we derived some of this technology from crash retrievals, which is what
I believe. In fact, I would say, I know that to be true at this point in my life. Um, the phenomenon
is real. The technology is real. People are in possession of it and are utilizing it, are deploying
it. Um, and that really, like I said, it concretized the whole thing in my mind way back then.
And so moving forward from that position, it, it wasn't, you know, I, I wasn't struggling and choking
on aspects of ufology like a lot of people do because they've never seen anything. I was able to
just have this baseline understanding that, yeah, something's there's some aspect of this is, is
absolutely real. Do you think this biblical fallen angel idea accounts for all of the
phenomena that we see? Okay. That's a very good question. So this loops us right back into what
I was saying, which was that I established that I believe that the, the good guys and the bad guys
look the same. We look like them. They come from an advanced ancient civilization that pre-exists us,
biblically speaking. And some of them are loyal to the King of heaven and some of them are in
opposition to him. So you have the quote unquote good angels and fallen angels, right? Loyal sons
of God, disloyal sons of God. Um, and they're both operating, I believe with the same technology.
So like I said earlier, you know, we'd established that the watchers are a separate group from,
I believe they're the same species, so to speak, but they're a separate group.
So when the watchers descended to Mount Hermon, I believe that they were at the helms of advanced
aerospace vehicles. I believe that the technology of this civilization is exceedingly advanced. So
some of what we see out there is for a lack of a better term, angelic technology. That's the way
that I would describe it. Now, some of that technology is being piloted by good guys and some of that
technology is being piloted by bad guys, but the technology itself, you cannot ascribe motive to
a piece of hardware. You can't say that that piece of hardware, you know, flying saucers is no more
good or evil than, than, than my truck.
So you would say as below, so above they're good and bad people and they're good and bad.
Just like on earth. Yeah. There's, there's factions of human beings and some, some of us do good and
some of us do evil, but we're the same species and we use the same technology.
So this is interesting because it's almost, uh, you know, we've heard people like Jacques
Vallée talk about connecting the modern phenomena with sort of biblical elements. Uh, and then you
also have people like Hal Puthoff, who actually lives out here in Austin, who wrote an interesting
paper about the Silurian hypothesis, these, these ultra terrestrials.
Yes. So survivors of an ancient cataclysm and you're sort of combining them.
Well, I'm, I'm going, so, so that's the first, that's just a component of the phenomenon.
Okay. Do I believe that describes a totality? No.
Okay. It does not describe the totality of the phenomenon.
I'm glad you're saying that. Cause I, I agree. I think it's every time we try to.
Yes. No, I don't believe that describes a totality of the phenomenon. I think that's an,
that's a, that's an aspect of the phenomenon. These beings we call angels in the biblical
narrative. Angel, by the way, is just a occupational descriptor in the Bible. It just means messenger
and envoy, one who is sent. It doesn't give us any insight into the nature of those beings.
And, and often they're kind of terrifyingly violent.
We just, well, the, the, the, the, the, the bad ones are certainly.
Yeah. Or even, I mean, it depends on where, like in, uh, the old Testament, sometimes they're
violent, but it's sort of in this moralistic Sodom and Gomorrah. Exactly.
They eviscerated Sodom and Gomorrah. How did they do that?
I don't know. Lasers. Maybe there was a saucer hovering above that thing.
Yep. So, um, so, you know, people, this is very difficult and it was difficult for me
in the beginning to sort of retool my mind. Um, yeah, but you know what, uh, to challenge
the audience, you know, anybody who's like, we're talking about stuff that's serious now
and that the government's talking about, but in the past, all of this is extreme, it's
extremely speculative and you have to, if you have these ancient traditions that are
all triangulating towards a common truth and you have, you know, eons. I mean, literally,
I think Jacques Vallée is kind of a, this really important kind of godfather of modern UFO research.
I agree.
If you read Wonders in the Sky, you read Passport to Magonia, you have to take this trans-historical,
trans-cultural idea. This isn't just post-Roswell nuclear age American stuff happening.
That's right. This is where I like to draw delineations here. So what I've described is
one faction, one aspect of the phenomenon, but I don't think that that describes the totality
of the phenomenon. And what I mean by this is if I know, because I'm so convinced of the
biblical narrative, right, I know that that faction exists, this angelic faction, and that
they're in the game. They're major players in the game here. But also, being a eager ufologist for
all these years, I know that gray aliens exist. And I know I say that definitively, but I think
the evidence is overwhelming. And the reason why I say the evidence is overwhelming, primarily,
it's not because of the whistleblowers and all of the crash retrieval stuff, Leonard Stringfield,
all the stuff he compiled, although all of that is compelling. What pushes me over the edge is
alien abduction. That's what pushes me over the edge in regard to gray aliens. So I have too many
friends and associates who've seen them and have touched them and have been taken by them.
So, um, so. Yeah. The amount of people out there who have been taken, uh, have implants with,
you know, the implants of isotope ratios that don't occur on earth. That's right. Roger Lear
was literally like extracting them from bodies. Many. Many. And then. Andy, Andy captured one of the
best, and I don't know what you think about it, but one of the best UFO videos I've ever seen.
Oh, I've never seen this. Oh, you haven't? You have to have seen this one. Maybe. I think it was
in, was it in Lebanon? I can't remember the details. And it's like, uh, it looks like a craft
and you can see grays inside of it. Oh yeah. And I don't, people say that that's been debunked and
other people say it hasn't been debunked, but, um. I didn't know that was his video. Yeah. Roger
Lear captured that. Wow. Isn't that weird? That's wild. Here's the guy pulling implants out of
people. Yeah. Captures that video. So now whether or not that video has actually been debunked,
I don't think so. Um, I think it's one of the most compelling videos I've ever seen. Certainly.
Is it, is it Lebanon or is it Turkey? Or Turkey. Turkey. Yeah. Somewhere in there. Somewhere in
that area. Yeah. I don't, I don't remember where it is. They're looking over the ocean. No,
it's an amazing video. Yes. And, and, and I mean, it looks like these big bulbous headed gray aliens
in there. And nobody's ever conclusively debunked it as with a lot of imagery. Yes. You have the
negatives and nobody can conclusively say it's fake. That's right. Long before the age of AI. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. So I
don't know, but that's, that Roger Lear was, was awesome. And yeah, implants are, are so
overlooked. I mean, it's like, by the way, this is oftentimes my conversation with some
of the congressional people I interact with. Like you want evidence? Yeah. There's a lot
of people walking around with, with exotic material, technological material in their
bodies. Yeah. And, and I don't, there's, there's no question about it. I mean, uh, this is,
the aspect of ufology where you can mine the most physical material evidence is the
abduction stuff. Yeah. It's so strange. You know, I, I interviewed Whitley Strieber and
you could say what you want about some of his stories or his book or his writing
background, whatever. I felt an implant in his ear and I don't think he's putting it
in his own ear or behind the ear. Yeah. And all he's doing that for show. Yeah. It's
right here. It's at the top of his ear and it's so strange. And then I just did a show
with my buddy, Chris Ramsey runs this great podcast called the area 52. We had
this guy come up on stage and he had an experience when he was a child and he has
something very similar in his ear and he could put a magnet externally on it and
it'll stick there. It's so strange. Most people who have implants, most of them are
generally located somewhere in the head. Although people have had them all over
Roger Lair extracted implants from knees and whatever. And you know, my, my
colleague and good friend, Ellie Marsulli worked with Lair and, and was there when
they extracted some of these implants and, and they would describe, he would
describe to me how some of these implants were evasive. Yeah. They move and they
don't cause, they're not rejected by the body. Yeah. They don't cause swelling. They,
they migrate around the body, but often, and many abductees have ejected them
unintentionally from their nasal cavity. Um, you know, they'll have a bloody nose and
they eject an implant. Yeah. A little BB will come out. A little BB will come
out and they're, they're shaped variously. Like some of them are look like tiny
little pills, oblong, some of them around, whatever. Um, and I think Lair
concluded that they're, that they, they had some sort of nanotechnology in, in
them. Yep. Some very, very sophisticated technology. And it's like, that's
physical evidence. It is physical evidence. That's physical evidence. And
not only that, and I know we're, we're diving into alien abduction, but not
only that, cause let me, before I dive into alien abduction, let me just wrap up
what I say real quick. So I said that the angelic stuff doesn't account for the,
the, the totality of the phenomenon. Yeah. Because, you know, I look at the gray
alien faction again, I'm very, very persuaded that that faction is real. And,
and you have the, the little grays, you know, people think are automatons of some
kind, maybe artificial intelligence or something. Um, I like to think of them as
cybernetic drones, uh, clones, cybernetic clones. And, and they're, to me, from my
perspective, they seem to be clearly created by the insectulins. You know, what
Dr. David Jacobs describes as insectulins, the mantid beings. In my estimation, that's
the biological species, the organic species, and they're making the little
grays. And there's not just little grays. I mean, there's, there's big grays too. I
mean, from, you know, from ufological lore, at least. And, but the little ones are the
ones that come to retrieve the abductees. So that's a faction. And so when I say
these things, I'm, and I talk about angelic beings, people conflate the two. Like
they think I'm saying that the grays are the angelic beings. I am not. I just want
to make that clear. What do we think the grays are? So I don't know. Um, I have no
idea what gray aliens are, but, or where they come from, you know, are they
crypto terrestrial? Are they, by the way, you, you mentioned something really
interesting, the antediluvian hypothesis that maybe some people from like an
Atlantean civilization escaped and maybe went off planet or under the earth. And
then now they're, they, they have this advanced technology that they developed
a long time ago and they're still here. Right. I love that idea. I don't know if
it's true, but I think I find it intriguing. I find it intriguing. Now, one thing I
think we can say about the grays definitively is that wherever they come
from, they have bases here now. So let's say there was a forward operation of
grays that came years ago. Well, they established bases a long time ago, just like
we would, if we were, were coming, by the way, for a hostile purpose, we would come
and we would establish a forward operating base and, and in anticipation for more of
us coming later. Right. And so those forward operating bases would be, would be
established in, in, in the areas that, that human beings would least look for
them or, or be able to discover them, which would be at the bottom of our oceans
underground bases. And, and certainly at this point in time, I'm, I would say that
it's, it's much more, uh, it's much more likely to be true than not. Let's put it in
very generous terms that these bases exist specifically the grays and maybe, maybe
there's mobile bases, you know, the 4chan stuff that I've seen of, uh, mobile
construction units. That's right. And they're creating these craft to spec, which I think
is again, wildly intriguing. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Cause it seems to comport to a lot of
the data. The, the, then the other stuff about how the grays excrete, you know, they
excrete waste out of their skin. Yeah. They smell like ammonia and sulfur. That's why
people say, oh, it's, and, and, you know, people, sometimes Christians say, well, they
smell like sulfur. So therefore they're from hell. Right. It's like, whoa, whoa. They
smell like ammonia and sulfur. Yeah. Which is, which is like, you know, urine coming out
of your skin. Right. That's what that would smell like. Right. If you're excreting
your waste or your skin, that's, you know, you would expect it to smell like ammonia
and then like that sulfuric smell. I could imagine that, um, if you're dealing with
beings that are excreting waste of their skin, they don't have sexual organs. Um, they
don't appear to have tongues or, or they might have palates in their mouth, but they
don't appear to have teeth. Um, their organs appear to be different from ours. Um, but
they are clearly physical beings because they, they crash and die. And, you know, I've got
a friend who, um, I've got a friend who, uh, is an abductee and, and she actually, in
one of her experiences, she actually grabbed one by the neck and squeezed it before she
passed out in one of her abduction episodes. And she said it felt leathery, like a snake,
like, you know, like the skin of a snake, cold, clammy, leathery. Wow. And so, you know,
the, the, the popular idea today is that some people don't think that these are actually
sentient beings, that they're just sort of meat suits either for artificial, artificial
intelligence or in the Christian community, it's very popular to say they're meat suits
for demon, demonic spirits. Um, I don't subscribe to that theory myself, but I think, as I said,
I would describe them as cybernetic drones. And the reason why I would describe them that
way, I know we're like diving into gray. I don't know if you want to talk about this.
I love it. Yeah, of course.
But the reason why I would describe them that way is because they do appear to have,
according to abductees, they do appear to have personalities, vague personalities,
but personalities nonetheless. Why do I say that? Because in the abduction material,
you find abductees who can recognize the grays or they can perceive their age. Like this one's older,
this one's female, that one's male, even though they don't have sexual organs. Um, there, there's
sort of a personality that they're picking up on, even though the grays are very robotic
and dispassionate, stoic.
Do you have any sense? Cause I know you've looked at David Jacobs, Carla Turner, John Mack,
all these amazing Bud Hopkins, who's really kind of the greatest compiler of all this stuff. Um,
do you come out of looking at that research with any sort of idea as to the intentions of these
beings or you do?
Yes. I, I think that. So, um, Bud Hopkins was just sort of documenting the phenomenon,
you know, as an objective observer, maybe subjective sometimes. He did get very,
very enraptured in the lives of the abductees. Um, but brilliant, brilliant researcher. Um, I'm going
to, I'm going to separate out John Mack, quite tons of respect for love John Mack, but John Mack was
much more, uh, psychologically involved in the phenomenon. Like, you know, kind of just sort
of trying to parse it from a psychological aspect. He was on the fence about it being
the physical, but, but nevertheless, he laid a lot of groundwork and him and Bud, some of the,
I don't know if you can still find these. Have you ever seen the interactions, the, the, the,
the dialogues between Bud Hopkins and John Mack? I don't think I have. Yeah. Really fascinating.
I know they were childhood friends. Both men were just complete gentlemen. Yeah. Both of them were
extremely intelligent guys. Both of them very objective. Um, so they're never arguing. They're
just having dialogue and it was some of the awesome, some awesome UFO content that's, that's
not seen very often anymore. You could probably still find it on YouTube. Just, I have a ton of
respect for both those guys. So Bud, Bud Hopkins was kind of documenting the, the physical,
the, the physical reality of the, of the, uh, abduction experience, missing time, you know,
the, the, the table procedures, all that kind of stuff. Then, then enter Carla Turner, who was
herself a student of Bud, Bud Hopkins from Afarsh, um, and Barbara Barthalek, who she interacted with,
another great, uh, abduction researcher. And what, what made Turner unique was that she was an
abductee and her family. So now she is writing from the, the, um, from the perspective of being
an abductee and her family was subjected, subjected to both alien abduction and my labs, military
abduction. And Carla Turner stuff is so fascinating. Um, I love Carla Turner. She died, obviously,
very aggressive cancer. I believe Hopkins died of cancer too, if I'm not mistaken. Barbara Barthalek,
if I recall, died in a very, but died in a car accident. Um, John Mack was hit by a car. John Mack
was hit by a car. And if I recall, another guy named John Mack was hit by a car in the same day,
right? In, in England or something like that. Very strange circumstances. Weird. And then, you know,
uh, David Jacobs is still alive. Yeah. I think has dementia. I think so. Yeah. Um, and so Carla
Turner was, was, what's the, the lesson here is don't study alien abduction. Yeah. You know, think about
that. I mean, Turner said that, um, she would say that she would be in her book. She wrote,
she wrote the book, um, um, taken. She wrote the book into the fringe, which was a story about her
family. And then of course, masquerade of angels, which documents the story of Ted Rice, who's still
alive. And, and Turner was so fascinating because she was so, so, um, unflinchingly objective. Even
though her life was being affected by this, she would say, we don't know where they're from and
we cannot believe anything they tell us. Here's what we know. We know they take us against our will.
We know that they force us to carry babies. We know that they take sperm and eggs. We know that
they subject us to all kinds of invasive procedures. So she was very, very, she was not like
trying to put her own spin on it. Um, which I really appreciated about Carla. I, I, I, I,
we really lost a, a, an amazing researcher in Carla Turner when she died. Um, and the new,
you know, all these new people coming to ufology, they don't, they don't, they don't read Turner.
They don't read Hopkins, you know? So, but what I was gonna say about Turner was, um, she really
highlighted, uh, a couple of things, the capabilities of these beings. She referred to what, something
she described as virtual reality scenarios, VRSs, that these beings were, were in possession
of technology that allowed them to fabricate virtual reality experiences so that an abductee
can be seeing and hearing things and in this complete virtual environment. And you could
have other people around them and they're not seeing the same thing. So it's like a hijacking
of human perception.
It's literally Descartes' demon.
Yes. So you could, they have the ability to hijack, I think both through telepathic powers
and through technology, the implants. So, and, and, and external technology that's directed
toward the abductee. So Turner's first, like the first thing she would stress or one of the
main things in her books and in her lectures was you cannot believe these beings. You can't,
you can't believe anything they're showing you. You can't even trust your own experiences
when you're with them because they control your perception 100%. You are under their control.
That's the, that's one of the main things she would stress.
I think that's a very healthy starting point as to how to think about all this stuff.
It is a very healthy starting point. So all these people established, like with alien abduction,
John Mack and, and David Jacobs, and all of this really culminates in David Jacobs. Like David
Jacobs, I feel like pulls all the pieces together, puts them together, um, from a very objective,
uh, um, from a very objective perspective. Uh, he of course being, was a tenured professor of history
at, at Temple University. So he was approaching it as a historian and all of these people, you know,
between them, they, they interviewed thousands of abductees, thousands. And some of it was hypnotic
regression. And some of it was like with David Jacobs, he didn't practice hypnotic regression.
He just did what he called relaxation techniques. And, and so all of them would, one of the things
that you realize is that this phenomenon, alien abduction, their starting point, just like you said,
is deception. That's how, that's the starting point of this phenomenon. Deception. The program is covert.
The grays don't tell, they don't communicate to you what the program is about. And you throw in the,
the virtual reality scenarios that they generate. And, and that's not to say that the abduction
experience is virtual reality. No, it's a hundred percent physical. You're literally taken from the
point of abduction and brought onto an alien vessel and subjected to all the procedures that are typical
of the, of the, of the abduction episode, but they have the power to completely hijack, hijack your
perception. And in addition to that, they implant false memories. So they, they implant screen memories
so that the real memories have to be retrieved behind that screen. So when you're dealing with
beings who can do those things, you can't trust anything that they say or that you think happened.
That's why. It reminds me of like the jinn in Islam or like these sort of trickster supernatural
beings that implant false, literally false memories. And you, you think certainly like,
I think in, in the jinn's case, they would like change certain verses of the Quran or whatever.
And that was, you know, it was like, yeah, it's sort of that typical trickery that's associated
with demons. However, um, I'm, I'm, I love Jacques Vallée. Um, but I would disagree that as it,
and so did Dr. David Jacobs, by the way, I, and I would guess Turner probably would have disagreed
with this as well. Although I don't know that for sure. Jacobs definitely that, that the alien
abduction phenomenon has anything to do with fairies and gnomes and sky people. I disagree. I
agree with Jacobs. I would say this is a completely different phenomenon. Now, does that mean that
there weren't saucers and hot and technology? No, no, it doesn't. I think that, that, that,
that sort of technology did exist in the antediluvian past. I'm just saying there's a different faction
in play right now, or at least another faction in play, this specific faction, the gray aliens.
It's interesting because I remember I had, and I don't, I think I said this in my book,
I had personally come to the conclusion after consuming all of this abduction material from,
from, from these excellent researchers, the old school guys and gals. I remember concluding
that it appears to me that the abduction phenomenon must have begun somewhere around the mid to late
1800s. That was my conclusion. And I remember, um, and I drew that conclusion based on the fact that
it seems that this phenomenon, the recollections of this phenomenon only go back to the mid 1800s,
early 1900s. Um, and I remember I was at the gym working out with, with my air, with my headphones
on listening to David Jacobs, listened to one of his lectures. And he said in his lecture that he
and Bud Hopkins, because they were colleagues and, and, and did a lot of work together, that he and
Bud Hopkins had concluded that the abduction, that the abduction phenomenon began in the mid to late
1800s and that it is not older than that. And I was just astounded. Like that's, that's precisely
what I thought. And I've still think that to this day, I believe that the abduction phenomenon began,
let's call it the turn of the century, maybe late 1800s, early 19th century. And this is in a very
interesting period of time because what most people don't realize about the turn of the century,
the 19th century is that there is a corresponding phenomenon happening all around the world,
especially the United States and in the West, generally speaking, it was the phenomenon of
spiritualism. I was, uh, when I wrote my book birthright, I was, um, resourcing articles, uh, from
the 18, late 1800s, early 1900s, all about this. I mean, some of these are all about this phenomenon
of spiritualism, this wave of spiritualism. And, and some of these articles said, one of these articles
in particular said that it was, it was as common at the, at the height of this thing for an American
to get up on a Sunday morning and go to a seance as it was to go to church. And so when I say
spiritualism, I'm talking about, you know, basically what the Bible describes as divination.
Um, it's the seances. These are, uh, all kinds of sort of, um, uh, psychic, um, acquiring of a
medium. Yeah. Mediumship. Mediumship. It was happening in the white house. Um, it was, it was
extremely common. This was when you had the, yeah, go ahead. I was just going to say that the
parapsychology started then the society for psychical research in the UK started then you had
William James and, uh, those sisters, what were their names? If they can make tables levitate
and stuff like that. I forget to sit those sisters. And, and you have, and then of course
you had, uh, theosophy, um, as well. Bingo. Right in the middle of it. Salons looking at,
you know, have with all this occult history and these, you know, this alternative history
involving root races and hyperboreans and Atlanteans and that sort of thing.
Right in the middle of it. The theosophical society is established.
Exactly.
With Helena, with Helena Blavatsky. And, um, so you have this, this spiritualism rampant
in the West, the United States and Europe. And then suddenly at the same time, you have
the mystery airship phenomenon. Literally same time. These things, these things coalesce.
That's fascinating.
The, the, the, the, the movement of spiritualism and the, the, the airship phenomenon. Now
I would say a good portion, I remember talking to, uh, uh, Richard Dolan about this, that a good
portion of the mystery airship phenomenon is just hyperbolic is, is newspapers, periodicals
at the time, just trying to one up each other. Right. With sensational stories. So even, even
considering that, that, that much of it was that, you still have incidents nestled inside
of this mystery airship phenomenon that are very credible, witnessed by many, many people
and that correspond to the modern UFO phenomenon. Silvery objects flying in the sky. You know,
I think a lot of the, the, the propellers and the balloons and all that kind of stuff that
people say they saw in the mystery airships was confabulation. Remember, nobody's flying
yet. Nobody's flying yet.
It's pretty right brothers.
But you know what you have out there? Jules Verne. So you have the steampunk stuff in
the minds of the observers. And so I think in many of these cases, nobody can understand,
like you take a piece of metal and throw it up in the sky and you can't envision how this
thing can just stay up there. Right. It falls to the ground. So see that little shiny thing
way up there. It must have balloons. It must have propellers. I think a lot of people confabulated,
you know, the, the, they, they sort of overlaid the, the steampunk stuff.
Just like chariots in the Bible.
Just like chariots. Precisely right. So, but I think that, you know, when you, when you,
when you, um, when you distill the credible real, uh, sightings and you, and you, you know,
you take all the cream off the top of all of the hyperbole and sensationalism, you're
left with a phenomenon that is very much like what we have today. Very much like what we
have today in terms of the metallic objects, the saucers, the cigar shaped craft, you know,
darting around in the sky, moving at impossible speeds. And this corresponds with the, the,
so you have, so you have spiritualism, mystery airship, alien abduction, coalescing at the same
time. And this gets us into some very bizarre territory because I think that, yeah, this gets
a little theological, but I think that to some extent we invited the phenomenon, not, not the
totality of it. I'm just talking about a sliver, the gray alien faction. Okay. And this is what people
get confused with when I'm, when I'm, when I'm talking, they sort of jumble everything I'm saying
and, and, and, and not you, but a lot of people in my audience. So I've separated out the angelic
faction. Okay. That were here long before we were right. They were here long before we were. So
they've been flying around here forever. I mean, since before human beings were, were even created,
biblically speaking, that faction is out here there. We've already thrown them out into the ether. Now
we're narrowing down on this other one called gray aliens, which I would say is a separate faction,
a separate thing. Now people, you know, from, from my community, Christians, there's some very
interesting ideas out there. Some people think that the gray aliens were manufactured by that group.
I don't know. I mean, I don't know. I guess anything's possible. Some people think that the
gray aliens are meat suits for demons. There's all kinds of ideas floating around there, right?
Some people think the gray aliens, that faction are the watchers, whatever. There's a lot of ideas.
But what I'm trying to do here is I'm, I've took that, the sons of God, I've separated them out. Now
we're focused on gray aliens. I think that the gray aliens arrived. I don't believe they're from here.
I think they came here. Okay. They arrived to the earth. Maybe there were some forward groups that
were here just sort of preparing, but the abduction phenomenon began as far as I can tell. And in, in,
in, in, in, in accord with Hopkins and, and Jacobs, the, the abduction phenomenon began in the mid,
mid to 18, 1800s. And I think that it had something to do. The gray's arrival had something to do
with the phenomenon of spiritualism. There's a coalescing of these two things happening. And
maybe we were broadcasting something. Maybe we were, again, theologically speaking,
maybe we were permitting something to happen through divination. Just speculating here. But,
but I don't think it's coincidental that these two things dovetail.
No. And it's really interesting, you know, you hear about this magenta crash,
you know, 1933 in Italy and, you know, it's being spoken about in very official circle. Like,
this is what David Grush came out with talking about. He wasn't talking about, you know, Roswell or
any of the kind of proverbial archetypal American crashes. And then I interviewed this guy, uh, Harold
Malmgren, who was this, you know, advisor to JFK, LBJ, Nixon, and Ford. And he's talking about
how James Jesus Angleton, who's this longtime CIA counterintel guy who discusses UFOs a lot and
is probably responsible for the MJ-12 docs getting leaked. And it, you know, makes you think that
maybe part of that's passage material, trying to catch Soviet spies at the time, because that was
what he was obsessed with. But he was stationed in Magenta, Italy with his father, Hugh Angleton.
And Malmgren is 89 when I'm interviewing him. And he is just obsessing over this idea that
the Knights of Malta have something to do with this crash. And, you know, they're obviously this,
uh, military arm of the Vatican, but they also have kind of, you know, headquarters at the Vatican.
Yeah, exactly. And they have, uh, esoteric roots, you know, they're, they're really the, um, heirs
to the hospitaliers, which are the kind of medic arm to the Templars. And then you hear things like
the Cosmo club, you know, had to do with UFO crashes. This is this like elite, like DC society,
which was doing kind of a cult stuff. And this guy, dark journalist talks a lot about this stuff,
but I've heard it in circles, in UFO whistleblower circles as well. And so there is something here.
And I think we're looking at the remnants of the mystery schools.
Yeah. Okay. Yeah.
And so the mystery schools are to the average person.
So the mystery schools are secret bodies, secret fraternities whose objective it is to preserve
and recover knowledge from the antediluvian world. The knowledge that was given to mankind by the gods.
That's what the, that's the objective of the mystery school is. And that's why they go back to at
least the Phoenicians, you know, the Freemasons, they trace their origins back to, well, really back
to Tubal Cain and Cain, the first builders of cities. But, but even more specifically, one of their
primary figureheads is Hiram Abiff, right? We referenced him earlier, who's the, uh, the, who was the
great artificer of, of the Phoenicians at the time. I believe he was, he was part Jewish and, uh, part
Phoenician. And so these mystery schools, the, the information that they keep, that they preserve
on the surface, it looks metaphysical on the surface. It looks mythic like the Freemasons,
right? All of their, um, all of their, you know, when you see there's some video leaked recently of,
of a Freemasonic, right? And it just looks like a bunch of adults playing dress up, right? Um,
and it is at this point in time, that's primarily what free, the, the, the Freemasonic lodges are.
It's a good old boys club where they dress up and act out things they don't understand. But the,
the play acting is a, is a mode of preservation of knowledge. So the mystery schools preserve
knowledge in their rights and in their myth, their, their various mythologies. In fact,
that's what mythologies do. Um, if you were to talk to the ancient sages, for example,
and this becomes apparent when you read material that's available from some of these ancient sages
from Egypt and from Mesopotamia and so forth, the, the myth is, is a capsule. It's, it is designed to
encase, to preserve, like a pill. It's, it's, it's designed to preserve and to transmit through time
functional information, knowledge, not metaphysical for the most part, but,
but knowledge that pertains to what we would call the sciences today. And many of the myths
pertain directly to astrology and actually more accurately astronomy. So many of the myths are
astronomical. The, the information that's encoded is, is astronomical. And a lot of it pertains to
what we call today, the Zodiac procession of the procession of the equinoxes and cyclic cataclysm.
And, and, and these are things that were very important to the ancients. But in addition to
that, um, there's information and knowledge that has been preserved from the antediluvian world.
And without digressing into the whole, um, history of, of, of some of these myths, like the Osiris,
the Osiris myth, um, they, they illustrate that the knowledge that's being preserved is from the
antediluvian world. And, uh, uh, by way of illustration, you know, Osiris, according to
legend was, uh, the story, the, the myth of Osiris, um, you'll recall that he died and his body was
divided up. I can't remember how many pieces. Yeah. That's a very important, uh, part of the story.
I think it was 13 pieces, but that story begins by his twin brother, Set, who's like the evil
version of him, um, builds his coffin. He has this coffin built because Set wants to, uh, usurp
Osiris' throne, get rid of him. And Iris, of course, is, uh, Osiris is of course married to
his sister wife, uh, Isis. And, and so Set has this sumptuous coffin built and he throws a party
and he says in the party, I've, I've, I've got this challenge. I've got this beautiful coffin
and whoever fits into it the best, most perfectly gets to keep it. Right. But he already made the
proportions to fit his brother Osiris perfectly. So when Osiris gets into the coffin, Set has him
sealed inside. Okay. First idea here. Osiris, a god from Zeptepe, the antediluvian world is sealed
inside of a coffin. Then, um, Set has the coffin thrown into the Nile. So here's Osiris inside of
the coffin, who's obviously going to die. He's thrown into the Nile in the coffin.
And the coffin floats on the Nile. So what we have essentially here is an arc floating on the
water with a body of knowledge inside of it from the antediluvian world. Right. Osiris represents
that body of knowledge and it's floating on the water, comes out of the mouth of the, of the, um,
Nile. Guess where it makes its way to? Byblos, which is a Phoenician city. It goes to Byblos.
It gets, uh, beached on the shore and it gets entangled in the roots of an, uh, in the branches
of an acacia tree. Acacia trees are very important in the, a very important symbol in, in the mystery
schools and in Freemasonry. It gets encased in this acacia tree and so much so that, that you can't
see it anymore. It just becomes part of the trunk. Now, uh, Isis decides to go on the quest to try and
find her husband's body. So she's going through the lands looking for her husband's body. Isis
represents the objective of the mystery school. Isis embodies the adepts of the mysteries. Her job is
to go and find and recover the body of Osiris. Looking for the hermetic knowledge. For the lost
knowledge. So she goes and she finally makes her way to Byblos and the king of that land,
Melikandor, I think was his name. It just occurred to me, um, had, had taken that tree. He was, he saw
that tree and he thought it was beautiful and he had it cut down. He had taken it and incorporated
it into his palace as a pillar. Well, that's interesting. That's conveying that some of the
knowledge is incorporated into the architecture of some of these palaces and temples and so forth,
right? The geometry now is part of the symbolism and some of the messaging. Cause remember inside of
that pillar is the coffin containing the body of Osiris. So Isis looks for, uh, she gets to
Byblos looking for her husband's body and she, she, she's able to divine that the body of Osiris is
inside of the pillar. She has it cut, cut out, takes it back to Egypt. Where was the pre-flood
knowledge condensed two places? Among the Phoenicians and among the ancient Egyptians.
So the knowledge is, goes to the Phoenicians after the flood and then from the Phoenicians to
the Egyptians, right? You're tracing the idea here through the story. So Isis has the body of Osiris,
but Set gets ahold of it again. But this time he wants to make sure it's not found again. So he chops
it up, I think in 13 pieces. That's a, that's a detail I should know. I'm pretty sure it's 13,
maybe 14. I want to say 14 pieces. I don't remember. We forgive you. You can, yeah, you'll
forgive me for that, but it's, it's chopped. The number is important. I just can't recall. Like I
told you, I'm really bad with numbers. So the body's been chopped up. You're not bad with general
memory. It's chopped up into pieces and those pieces are distributed all over the place. Cause Set
wants to make sure this is never found again. He takes the phallus, you know, chops off his phallus
and, and it's thrown into the Nile and either some stories say it's swallowed by a crock. Others say a
big fish. So the phallus is like gone, right? And so I, Isis, what does she do? She embarks on another
mission to recover the various pieces of this knowledge that had been scattered abroad.
And she starts to recover the body of Osiris, which represents the body of antediluvian knowledge,
a knowledge that was given to mankind by the gods. She begins to assemble it, but she can't find the
final piece, which is the phallus because it was eaten. So what does she do? She fabricates one.
She makes a golden, she makes an artificial phallus so that she can copulate with Osiris.
She, she resurrects him. She puts all the pieces together. She resurrects him momentarily
with the artificial phallus. She copulates with him and becomes impregnated by him so that now she's
conceiving the offspring of Osiris, which is Osiris who's going to be reborn. And that child is named
Horus. And so this, this story communicates the objective, the modus operandi of the, of the mystery
school. It is to recover the lost knowledge of the gods, reassemble it and resurrect their empire.
Literally bring them back. And that may sound crazy and spooky and metaphysical to everybody,
but I'm telling you that's what they want to do. I told you earlier that they, that one of the
primary objectives in order to do this is to go to Mars and get some of the, recover some of the
knowledge. So they want to bring the gods back and they actually believe that the gods are real.
What's so interesting is, so this guy, Neil McCaslin, do you know that name?
He's trending on Twitter right now. And I don't know when this comes out, but hopefully he's found
by the time this comes out, because this is a guy who's a general.
He went missing. Yeah.
At Wright-Patt and I believe ran the lab that essentially, you know, foreign material exploitation
ended up with the Roswell pieces, if you believe the lore. And he was Tom DeLonge's source for a lot
of his sort of stuff with secret machines and to the stars Academy. Was known as this very kind of
wise guy who literally, I mean, he was a AFRL, like ran air force acquisition. So like in conventional
circles is like an impressive guy. And apparently he would talk a lot about Greek mythology.
And so you have to, and then you hear things like Diana Pasolka, who talks to this NASA mission
controller, Tim Taylor, and she talks about people in the quote unquote secret space program or even
conventional space program, rocketry, you know, paying homage to the sponsors with second century
Latin. And then you look at all the names of all of the missions in NASA.
All of the place, all of the locales that they land their stuff on.
Yeah.
It's all, it's all, um, from the, the, the, the pantheon of, of, of the Greeks and, and
the ancient Egyptians and the Mesopotamians.
Yeah. It's fascinating. It's almost as if they sort of secretly believe, they secretly believe
that those sort of little G gods or the like, you know, the Greek gods or, you know, whatever,
whatever your tradition is, the, the, you know, uh, fallen angels are like more vital in some sense
than the big G God or something. And they're sort of like, you know, communing with them.
That's where all of this is headed. I believe that's what I write in birthright is the culmination
of this. We were talking about this off camera. So what we're headed for here is the formulation
of a new religion. And I've been saying this since 2020, we are headed for the formulation of a
new religion. See, everybody thought that, that the neo atheism that was on the rise back in, uh,
the, the, the, the 20 teens was kind of just going to sweep over the Western world and basically
eradicate religion. And actually the opposite is happening now. People are becoming more religious.
Yep.
And, and, and, and, you know, there's a lot of people who are, who are becoming Christians now,
but then also a lot of people who are just adopting other kinds of, or becoming spiritual,
generally speaking. And then you have also now a religion of technology that the elites are,
are, are obsessed with, right? The Silicon Valley religion that, you know, I think it was, uh,
uh, Ray Kurzweil when they, when they asked him, do you believe in God? Not yet. In other words,
in other words, we're going to create God, artificial intelligence. This is a religion of the,
of, of the technology.
And you have Noah Yuval Harari writing that Homo Deus. That's like, that's our next incarnation.
It's just like when man becomes like God or something.
In, in 100 to, what does he say? 100 to 120 years from now, there will be no more human beings
left on planet earth. And what he means is that the human species is going to evolve.
This is directed evolution, right? So we're going to direct the, the, the evolutionary ascent of our
species using technology. This is the first time we've ever been able to do this. We are now building
the tools that are going to give us the capability to modify the human biology wholesale and, and
integrate cybernetics, artificial intelligence. And then also something most people don't realize
is coming is the genetic revolution. Um, artificial wombs, designer babies, all coming along with
robotics, advanced robotics and everything else. Uh, some of it's here, right? Artificial womb
technology I think is here. We, we, it's just, you know, some of these things that there's a moral
gray area that, that there's some legislating that has to be done in some of these, um, barriers that
have to be surmounted before this stuff hits the commercial market. But the point is that what I see
is a convergence of two things happening. I see that a new religion being formulated and it's going to
combine the convergence of these two ideas. One is a very ancient idea. This is at the core of the
mystery schools. It's called apotheosis. And apotheosis is the deification of man, man becoming
like the gods. That's what apotheosis is. The second, the second component is theism, a belief in the
gods. So the religion of the future in my estimation is this, the gods of old actually
exist and we shall become like them. That is the religion of the future. And what do I mean by the
gods? They're going to show up in UFOs. The gods are coming. And I think this is going to be a
component of our going to Mars. Uh-huh. Uh, I think there's going to be a revelation of Mars
that's going to happen in our lifetime. Uh, what we talked about before that there's, there was in
fact an ancient extra, extraterrestrial civilization on Mars and that the gods of the ancients were
actually extraterrestrial beings. Of course, the claim will be also that Yahweh was one of these
extraterrestrial beings. And then furthermore, culminating by the way, I'll remind you in,
from my point of view, culminating in Armageddon. So the idea is going to be, and this is by the way,
going full circle back to the beginning of the story where Eve is being tempted by the serpent
in Eden. And what does the serpent say to her? If you eat of this fruit, you will not surely die.
You will be become like the gods. So it's going full circle back to the beginning. So you're going to
have a scenario in which, again, from my, in my estimation, from my perspective, in which it
becomes apparent that the gods of yore were, were these real extraterrestrial beings and the god of
the Hebrews is one of those. And he happens to be the tyrant. And so the gods are going to lead
humanity into a kinetic war. And it really, it's post-humanity. I know this sounds crazy, but I do
build, and I'm not, I don't keep referencing birthright just to promote it, but really I do
build a, it sounds crazy, but you can build a logical progression to this reality. And part of
this reality is what I call the post-human apocalypse. And what I mean by post-human apocalypse is
precisely what Harari says, that in the future, the majority of the populace on planet earth will be
post-human, will no longer be homo sapien sapien. In other words, will no longer be the offspring of
Adam and Eve, biblically speaking. They're going to forfeit the, they're going to forfeit the body of
Adam, so to speak, and with it the birthright of Adam, which is dominion of the earth, in favor of this,
this Faustian bargain, in favor of life extension, in favor of living forever. And there's indications
in the biblical text that this is in fact going to happen. I mean, in the book of Revelation,
you have a group of people who are, when everything is coming apart in the book of Revelation,
when basically the judgment of God is befalling on earth, you have a group of people who cannot die
and who are calling for the rocks to fall on them and crush them because they can't die.
Very interesting. I mean, you can imagine a scenario, maybe not that far down the road in
which we perfected nanotechnology. We've, we're, we're upgrading, we're up, maybe, I don't know if
this is possible. We're uploading our consciousness into artificial bodies, maybe nanotech bodies,
maybe robotic, whatever, combination of all these technologies. See the culmination
of these technologies, make no mistake about it. The culmination of the technologies is to,
is to redesign human biology. It is, it is to create Homo Deus. It is to create, to build
the ubermetsch. It is, it is, it is, that's the, um, Friedrich Nietzsche. That is the, the impulse
of evolution. Friedrich Nietzsche, obviously the, the, the famed philosopher, Friedrich Nietzsche
was a proponent of evolution, but he didn't like evolution by natural selection. Why? Because
Darwinism, evolution by natural selection, has no purpose, right? It's purposeless, it's blind.
Nietzsche didn't believe evolution was blind. He believed that evolution had a purpose and the
purpose of evolution was to bring forth the ubermetsch, the Superman, the superhuman in the earth.
That's what, I mean, it feels like post-World War II, eugenics just went underground and you see,
I don't know, all this stuff coming out with the Epstein files and it's weird, man. It's, it's, it is
enmeshed with the occult. Yeah, it feels enmeshed with the occult. It feels very transhumanist. I think
the transhumanism stuff can be tricky. Like there are things like IVF, for example, or things that are
like, you know, it's probably pretty positive, you know, like modern medicine is good on the whole.
Gene therapy. Gene therapy would be awesome. Gene therapy, you're taking, so, you know, our genomes
are, are, we have a, what's called a mutational load in our genome, which means that we're copies
of copies of copies of copies of copies. And every time you make those copies, you get, you get errors
in the code, right? Some geneticists believe we're headed for error catastrophe, by the way, which means
we can't reproduce anymore. That's, that's a thing that's believed quietly by population
geneticists, by the way. We're going to become reproductively inviolable, enter artificial
wombs. So, so the idea is that you get to a point where you're reproductively, reproductively
inviolable because your genome has broken down to such an extent that, that you're dying,
you're dying of all kinds. We have tons and tons of genetic diseases. Um, but I'm digressing into
this. I'm sorry. I cut you off. No, I mean, so that's, it's clear to me that all of that is
happening. And even the thought process of, Hey, this is healing versus this is extending our brains
and, you know, turning us into some post-human thing. That thought process is not occurring among
elite circles or whatever. It's this reflexive desire for, uh, self-deification for everlasting
life, you know, all that. That's right. And then you said something else very interesting. You said
that will coincide with the gods themselves returning. So there'll also be this theological
element to this. So is in your prediction, cause I think the, I think the prediction around elites
doing transhumanist, you know, self-deification, I think that's safe. The other prediction of,
you know, the return of these beings in UFOs, would you put a lot of weight in that? Do you
believe that that will happen in our lifetime? Oh, in our lifetime? Probably. Yeah. Yeah. I, I,
I, I suspect, and by the way, to complete my thought, which I, I rambled on that I was going to tell
you, I was going to agree with you that there are certain technologies that I'm totally for gene
therapy. The reason why I said that was because the human genome is so, um, so full of error and
mutation that you have what we know to be the correct code here. And if somebody's got a mutated
gene, it leads to cancer, at least all kinds of sickle cell anemia. So if you go over here and you
take that human gene, the right code, and you plug it in to the equation, it, it cures the disease,
right? So I'm all for that. I just want to make that clear. I'm not like a Luddite. I think you
could take a gene therapy, human to human. The problem is when you're starting to either grab
code, snippets of code that aren't human, cross species genetics, or you're creating new code
and you're modifying the genome in ways that are not natural to the, to the genome that are not
indigenous to the human genome. So just to draw that line, um, that delineation as it pertains to
these technologies. But yeah, I believe that the, you know, at some point, so here's what I see,
of course I could be completely wrong. Okay. This is just rank speculation here. Um, I think that
we're headed for a disaster, um, twofold disaster. I think that we are headed for a natural, uh,
cataclysm because we're due for one. The hour is now for cataclysm based on the Zodiac. And we
could talk about that later based on the precession of the equinox and all of that. We are transitioning
from one aeon into another. Okay. And when that happens, that's, that's called a suntelia last for
a thousand years. And within those thousand years, cataclysm befalls like clockwork. Um, going back and
referencing what we're talking about, the priests of Sais, explaining all of this to Solon of Athens.
That's a component over here. Cataclysm is coming, but in conjunction with the cataclysm is you have
the activity of gray aliens, which we were mentioning before. The grays appear to be, uh,
engineering a human alien hybrid species that is indistinguishable from us, but is not us.
A species that for all intents and purposes looks just like us, but they retain the telepathic
capabilities of the grays. They can control us in other words. And one of the most frightening things
about, uh, one of the most alarming things about Jacob's final book, walking among us is
he documents the latest thing that the, that the abductees were telling him from their abduction
episodes in that he called this personal project hybrids. Are you familiar with that? The personal
project hybrid. So he described this as personal project hybrids because the grays have been trying
to perfect a hybrid. And, and this progression is evident in the, in the abduction material,
because in the beginning people were encountering, abductees were encountering hybrids that were very
imperfect. Their heads were too big. Their hair was scraggly. Their eyes were too big. They kind of
look human, but they look too much like the grays. They were too short. Um, and as the years progressed,
so did the program and you were getting more refined hybrids that looked more and more like us until,
until, until lately, or at least when, when, uh, Jacobs published his book, was it 2016, somewhere around
there? Um, he was reporting these, these advanced human alien hybrids that he described, he calls
hubrids. And they're so advanced that, as I said before, they're indistinguishable from us, but they
retain the telepathic capabilities of the grays. And they are completely loyal. Their, their allegiances to
the grays, not to human beings. And, and so these advanced human alien hybrids would be assigned,
according to Jacobs, would be assigned to certain female abductees. So you get these male hybrids.
They're, they're assigned to female abductees. These, these Jacobs called personal project hybrids
because the female abductee, they would have to, they would have to, um, tutor the hybrid and teach
them about life on earth, teach them how to do mundane things, how to go into a grocery store and
buy groceries without looking like a freak, how to just be out in public, how to drive a car, what a
refrigerator is, what a TV is, just the most basic things. And what's really frightening, I should use
the word, word alarming. What's really alarming is that these, these hubrids, according to Jacobs,
are psychopaths. Like these are like, uh, superhuman villains. They, they, they, they abuse these women
sexually, but also verbally. They completely manipulate and control them. They're very violent.
They beat them in certain cases. These are really, really evil people, these hybrids,
according to the accounts from the, from the, uh, abductees. They're very abusive, or at least
some of them. And so it makes you wonder like, what is the end game here? Well, David Jacobs said
that the end game of the abduction program was planetary acquisition by stealth. So they integrate
themselves into us. It's the opposite of the Borg from, from Star Trek, right? The Star Trek and Star
Trek, the Borg, assimilate other factions into themselves. Well, the Greys integrate themselves
into our civilization. And it's a conquest by stealth. And so I think that elements of
the United States government are aware of this. And I think, and certainly if you, referencing Carla
Turner's work, one thing that Carla was always talking about was the fact that some of these abductees
were being, would be abducted by gray aliens. And then when they were turned, were turned
to their homes, the military would show up and, and, and then they would, they would endure
a my lab, a military abduction, which was oftentimes much more violent. And the military, according
to Turner and her husband got abducted, by the way, Turner's husband was abducted by elements
of the military. They think they were brought on to air force bases in some cases, sometimes
underground bases. And they were interviewed and, um, interviewed's a nice way to say
it. Um, they were, what's the word, uh, interrogated, interrogated. Thank you. They were interrogated
in regard to what was happening on the alien vessel. What were the Greys doing? They were
trying to figure out what the Greys were doing and they're trying to use the abductees to, to
get insight into what the Greys were doing. And because I think there's, there's panic had ensued
by that time. I don't know what you think about this. I personally am persuaded that the Greys
a contract was real, that it actually happened.
So this is this Eisenhower agreement that essentially in exchange for, you know, some tactical advantage,
maybe some help with, you know, warfare or whatever, uh, they would, we would let the aliens
do sort of medical experiments across, you know, the United States population.
To abduct our citizenry.
So I don't know, but I also, if you look at the data, it seems like abduction sort of
ramped up around that time, like mid century. So it's, it's very interesting.
They did. Uh, and this is what, um, what I, I think the, some of these researchers would,
would, uh, have concluded was that yes, there was a, an increase in abductions and the, and
the abduction phenomenon is exponential because it's, it's hereditary. So if you know Eisenhower's
granddaughter is an abductee and is like all over this issue, which is really interesting.
Laura, exactly.
So, um, alien abduction is hereditary. And so if you're, if your parents were abductees or
one of your parents, then you're, you're, you're also an abductee. It's hereditary. I found
no exception to that rule. Now, the reason why I'm so, uh, runs in families.
Yes. It's, it's definitely hereditary. So the reason why I'm so, uh, interested in this
phenomenon is because I interact with a lot of abductees. They come to me and they tell
me their stories. And of course, I'm always aware of the fact that, you know, you got screen
memories in there, you got VR, you know, uh, VRS scenarios and so forth. And you sort of
have to navigate circumvent some of that, but basically, and they're coming to me all
the time. I'll probably get another wave of them after this interview. And they're all
telling the same story still. Maybe there's some variation in there that I haven't picked
up on, but from what I've seen, it's all, it's the same thing is they're being abducted
and they're being integrated into this breeding program. Forcibly the men are having the sperm
taken, the women are, are having, um, ova taken. And then there's some sort of an in
vitro fertilization with some exotic component. Then that's, that's reinserted into the woman's
womb or, or, or an extra uteral womb, even if the woman doesn't have a womb, you know,
uh, she had a, uh, hysterectomy. Is that what it's called? They take the womb out and then
the grays create an artificial womb. And, and these women, they carry these babies, these hybrid
fetuses, um, for about three months, right before they really start to show. And then
they're, they're, they're abducted and the, and the fetuses are taken out and put in gestation
tanks. This is the ongoing procedure. This is what's happening. And it's still happening.
I know there's a narrative out there that alien abduction isn't happening anymore. Not as far
as I can tell. I have a friend, by the way, who, who I've known him for years and I've always
suspected that he and his kids were abductees. Why'd you suspect that?
Because of various experiences and dreams, dreams, things like that. Um, uh, things that
were indicative of alien abduction. And I never really, I think I've asked him in the past
if he thought he was an abductee and he never thought he was. But the other day, this, this
last spring, uh, I was in my office working and he happened to be at my house and, and
he came in and my office, we're talking for a second. And then he's walking out and he
stopped and he said, he turned around and he said, I forgot to tell you, they came and
got me.
Whoa.
And I was like, what do you mean? Who's they? Who came and got you? He said, the grays,
they came and got me.
Whoa.
Cool. And, and then he walked up to me, pulled up his sleeve. He said, look, and he
had the typical that, I don't know if you've ever seen this, the Delta.
Yeah.
Formation.
Little dots.
The dots, the Delta formation, that a lot of abductees.
Triangle, yeah.
Yeah. And it, and it had been a couple of weeks and it was fading, but it was
clearly there. He said, he said, I had this wild experience at night. He was like, I was
sort of out of it and all this weird stuff. And I woke up with that. And he's like, I, they
came and got me.
And it was just like a punch in my face. Like, you know, I'm constantly being
reminded that this thing is real and it's ongoing. And we were talking about the
implants earlier too. I think all abductees are implanted by the way. And so anyway, so
that's happening. And if, and if Jacobs is correct, and I think he is, that the
objective is planetary acquisition, that they're integrating these human alien
hybrids indistinguishable from us into human society, right? What's the end game
there? Who knows? To direct civilization in a particular way and elements of our
government know about it, then that is a clear and present danger. I mean, that is,
it's like a sci-fi movie. It's like a, it's, it's like a scenario that's, that's, um, it's
ultra red alert. The human species is being usurped from within, right? And so why do I
bring that up? Remember I talked about the natural catastrophe that's coming, the
cataclysm, cyclic. We're due. We're within the, we're in a Suntelia right now. And we
can talk about that more if you want later, how we know that, but we're in a Suntelia.
Cataclysm is going to befall. Now that's a thousand year window. So we don't know when
exactly, but we're within the window. And then you have gray aliens doing what they're
doing simultaneously. So what do I think is going to happen? I think somebody is going
to show us to show up to deliver us. Interesting. From either one of these or both of them.
Whoa. And that that group will be received as the gods returning to the earth, that these
are the gods. Perhaps they'll say that they created us. They spliced our genome with Bigfoot
or something, or some hominid, some ancient hominid and, and that they provided some of
their own genetic material. And they've been sort of guiding us through our evolution, all
of these centuries, all of these millennia. And in your view, that should be viewed as
a deception. From my point of view, this would be the group that the, that the Bible
identifies as, as the man of sin. Yep. The Antichrist, basically presenting himself
as the savior in place of Christ. Jesus was one of us, or I am Jesus, that sort of a thing.
And showing up to, to, uh, to deceive humanity. Of course, that's a very, uh, specific point
of view. It's a point of view coming from a biblical perspective. But I think, my God,
I mean, the trajectory is certainly headed that way. And so in that, in that, what happens
then is humanity is, is, is, and by the way, in the, in the book of Revelation, this figurehead,
the beast is what the revelation calls him, right? This figurehead, uh, the beast consolidates
power on earth, governmental power on earth. And then he leads mankind into worship of the dragon.
That's what happens. He leads mankind into worship of the dragon. And so I think that the narrative
that's coming is that these beings are going to show up. Wouldn't be surprised if they look like
Nordics. Contrast that with the greys. You know, here's the clear enemy who's, we have no defense,
by the way, against this enemy. They're far more advanced than we are. They're integrating
themselves into our populace. We have a natural disaster on the horizon. These beings show us to
show up to deliver mankind from, from these disasters. They will be received as our extraterrestrial
saviors, our progenitors, our Promethean benefactors. And then, according to my perspective,
they will lead humanity, post-humanity really, lead humanity into the final stages of a post-human
transformation. And then they will take the armies of earth and, and their faction to go to literally
go to war with the King of heaven, returning to the earth. That's called Armageddon. Now, again,
I know that that may sound plausible to Christians and it may sound utterly ridiculous to people who
aren't Christians and people with different persuasions, but there is definitely a biblical
case for what I just laid out. Yeah. Fascinating. Speaking of evidence of Nephilim and this whole
narrative, you're one of the few people I know who has gone deep on this phenomena of giants and giant
bones and, and mythology around giants. But I think maybe most interestingly is you've encountered,
uh, personnel in the air force who have fought giants in Kandahar in Afghanistan in the mid 2000s. Is
that correct? Yeah. I, this, so this begins for me, this begins with, with Steve Quayle. I used to work
with Steve Quayle, who's an author and, and really his area of research, his primary area of research was
biblical giants. And I was working with Steve in Montana and we created a, uh, we created a production
company called Gen Six Productions and we were making a film series at the time called True Legends, which
was focused primarily on giants, right? And looking for evidence of giants and so forth. And in the midst of
this, uh, Steve was contacted by a, uh, an elderly woman who told him that her son had a story that he needed
to hear, but her son did not want to come forward because he was still active duty. And she said,
you need to, you, my son has a story. You need to hear it. And she, ultimately, she was able to
convince her son to come to, to tell Steve the story. So he got in contact with Steve. I believe
they went on coast to coast AM with George and Ori. That's the first time they, that, that this
individual story was heard. And then subsequent to that, uh, he, we, we, we wanted to put him in our film,
in our documentary series. And so we flew him out to Bozeman, Montana, and we interviewed him,
Steve and I, he showed us his CV, his credentials. He was active duty. He was, he was a, um, a C-130
pilot, cargo pilot. And, um, and he told us a bunch of stuff about his background. He was a fascinating guy.
Uh, and, uh, just a lot of, um, confirming data and just really demonstrating to us that he was
what we said he was. And then we interviewed him, but he did, he wanted to be interviewed in silhouette.
Like he knew that, you know, his voice is already out there and people, he understood people are
going to be able to put the pieces together and figure out who he was if they wanted to. But
just, just to maybe add a little layer of, of making a little bit more difficult, he wanted to be filmed
in silhouette. So we filmed him in silhouette and he told us, uh, the story that has since become
known as the Kandahar giant. It's grown into a mythology on the internet, right? But this is
where it begins. Um, so he was a, as I said, he was a C-130 pilot and he would fly missions into,
into Bagram airfield in Afghanistan. And he would describe these missions as, as,
classified. And he would always often be called in to pick up high valued assets. And he said,
usually these were like Taliban guys. Um, and so this was routine for him. And one day he's flying
in there. He said in 2005, he was flying a routine mission into Bagram airfield. He lands on the tarmac.
And I've been getting this detail wrong for those who've been hearing me say this. Um, I've been saying
he, he, he disembarked from the plane and walked over to the hangar. That's not true. I double
checked the other day. Uh, he, he disembarks, he, he de-planes with his crew and they're met on the
tarmac by individuals he describes as the babysitters. And he thinks that these are air
force intelligence or army intelligence, something like that. And they told him right away, he said,
I've never been met on the tarmac like this. I always go over to the hangar and get my cargo.
And they said, this never happened. No pictures. Don't ever talk about it.
And as they're standing there, as he's standing with the babysitters, he sees a, a, um, a, um,
forklift bringing over a crate, a huge crate, one of the, an, an, an air pallet, um,
an air cargo pallet, which are, you know, I think they're 14 feet. I think I got that right. No,
no, no, not 14. There's, there's, they're nine feet long. Somebody will correct me. They're nine
feet long by something. Seven by nine, I think is what they're, they're larger than like the
pallets at home Depot and they're heavier. You know, there there's dunnage under them and they're
heavy. And so it's a nine foot long pallet and there's something on it. And it's whatever's on it
is covered with a tarp. And he said, the first thing that hit him was the odor. It was this
pungent odor of like BO and death. And it was, he said, it was like, unlike anything he's ever
encountered. And then as they put this thing down on the ground so it can be weighed and loaded into
the aircraft, he realized that, that the tarp wasn't covering the whole thing, that parts of
this thing were hanging out. And it was apparent that it was a really, really big dude in his words.
And, but it was not a normal person because it was in the fetal position and it was, it was hanging
off the pallet in the fetal position, nine foot long pallet, hanging off the pallet. Part of its head
was, you could see part of its head, you could see its hands and its feet hanging off the pallet and
they weren't covered by the tarp. And he said that the hair of this being was red. The skin was pale,
white. He said it had six fingers on each hand and six toes on each foot. And the feet were wrapped in
a very primitive canvas type wrapping. And he said he and the guys that were standing around the body
were actually taking their boots and putting it up to the foot. And he said it was, you know,
twice as big as every, twice, three times bigger than everybody's boot. I mean, the feet were enormous.
They're all putting their feet up to the foot. And, and he said this thing was solid as a rock. He
would, he was, they were all kind of tapping it on the top. And he said it was like a brick. I mean,
this thing was just like solid muscle. He said it could have been some rigor mortis or whatever,
but, but I mean, it was apparent from what you could see of this dude that he was, he was a
brick house. So. How tall? So the pallet was nine feet long and he's in the fetal position. So they
estimated his size at 10 to 12 feet tall. Wow. They weighed the giant. They weighed this being
because they had to weigh it. The load master had to weigh it before they put it on the C-130. He weighed
the whole thing weighed. I think they told me, and I could be wrong, but I think it was 1500 pounds.
And then when you subtract all the dunnage and the pallet and whatever else, I know that the final
weight was 1100 pounds. The final weight was 1100. And then he told me for sure. He said that the
weight was, this thing weighed 1100 pounds. And so you can imagine, let's say it was 12 feet tall,
1100 pounds. So, uh, I mean, I mean, this thing weighs more than like a Kodiak bear. I mean,
it's a massive, massive guy. And then, you know, he was asking about the body, like,
where'd you, where'd you guys get this thing? And they told him that they had heard, they didn't
know, they didn't at first had knowledge. They heard that a group of guys got lost somewhere
out in Afghanistan, that this, this, this group was out there, this, these military guys were
out there doing something, recon or something like that. And they, they weren't reporting back
in. So they sent out another group to look for him. Another team went out to look for that,
that first team. And when that second team found them, they found them either at the mouth of a
cave or in a cave. I can't remember where, but it was in the vicinity of a cave and they were all dead.
And, and this gigantic humanoid was eating on one of them and it, and, and they were able to kill it.
They were able to take it down. So it killed the whole first team. That's what he heard. Now,
again, that's, that's what those guys had heard, had heard. So maybe that was just a rumor.
But either way, the, the giant was airlifted from the Kandahar region and, and deposited at
Bagram to be picked up by the pilot. And so he loaded the giant onto the aircraft and then they,
they transferred it to Qatar, a base in Qatar. And that's where his, that's where his interaction
with this being ends.
So he was part of the transport of the body.
Yes. And he said, he told me he heard through the grapevine. He said, I don't know if this is
true, but I heard through the grapevine that the giant ended up at Wright-Patterson. He said,
I don't know if it's true, but that's what I heard.
And he was sure that the being was dead while he was transferred.
Dead. Yeah. It was definitely dead. Was it shot?
Yes. They, they, they, yeah, they, they filled it full of ammunition. So, I mean, the thing that it,
and from what I, he said that it was, it was, it took a lot of firepower to take him down.
Jesus. Did he sound kind of traumatized as he's telling you?
No, no, no. He sounded very fascinated. Like this crazy thing happened. Here's what happened.
Yeah.
He wasn't traumatized because he didn't, you know, he wasn't involved in the interaction with the
giant when it was alive and he didn't know if the story of it eating on guys was true.
Sure.
So that's just what they had heard. So he's like, I can't confirm that, but this is what
they told me.
Still, even seeing the thing, it's like, fuck, that's pretty crazy.
Yeah.
Since conducting that interview with, with the pilot in subsequent years, I've been able to
confirm that story by several sources or have that story confirmed by several sources. And,
and I have to be very careful because I want to protect these guys. Um, and I should say before
I get into that, that my, my colleague who I referenced earlier, L.A. Marsulli, he had a guy
come to him and this is important because this was confirmation of the story that we had heard
from our pilot. L.A. Marsulli had a guy come to him, a different guy. I think it was a special ops
guy from the, I don't remember what, what branch, but, but he told L.A. Marsulli a very similar story
about the Kandahar giant. We don't know if it was the same giant or if it was a different one,
but in, but in that story, they said it was 2003 as opposed to 2005. Maybe our pilot remembered the
date wrong. I don't know. Or maybe they were remembering the date wrong, but in their story,
very, very similar, a team went, a team went missing. Another team was dispatched to find it.
They encountered this giant in a cave. And in that story, the giant skewered one of the guys
with a spear. And, but, but apart from that, all the details are pretty much the same.
Uh, so we don't know L.A. and our, L.A. and I don't know if, if it's the same story or if these
are two separate stories. Sure. So. Well, if there's one giant out there. Well, well,
after, after L.A. told that story publicly, he put it in a film and after he went public
with it, our pilot got, got ahold of us again. He, he contacted Steve Quayle and he told Steve.
And then he told me subsequently that, that he knows that the, the other story is true because
he purposely withheld certain details from the story so that if somebody comes forward trying
to add additional information, he could vet whether or not they're telling the truth.
And he said, that guy's telling the truth. Whoa. So that was kind of a confirmation from our guy that
L.A. Marsouli's guy was telling the truth. Now, apart from that, I've interacted with a handful of people,
some soldiers, others, officers that have confirmed to me that A, that story is true. And B,
there are even wilder stories and there are more giants out there than just one, obviously.
Um, and, and then also that this is one of the, that this is, this, this topic is one of the most
highly classified, dangerous topics to broach.
Why do you think it's so dangerous? Like my, I almost suspect it's more dangerous than UFOs and
crash retrievals because it's confirmation somewhat, maybe of an origin story of humankind. Like it
really breaks Darwin. Unless you come up with some other reason as to why these giants exist,
evolution of primitive to progress apes to mankind is kind of broken by this, like where the giants
come from. There are some difficulties for evolution by natural selection, but not too
many. I mean, they could just say that this was a divergent homo sapien species that branched off of
whatever. So they could just add another branch of the tree, so to speak. Totally. Other people think
that the reason why this is such a touchy subject and apparently very highly classified, the existence
of giants, both in a, in an ancient context and in a contemporary context is because it affirms the
biblical narrative. And although that's true, I don't think that's it either because it doesn't
just affirm the biblical narrative, like we were saying earlier, it affirms the ubiquitous testimony
of our antecedents from the ancient world in general. I mean, everybody had mythologies of giants. The
Egyptians, they had the Mesopotamians, they had the Greeks, the Romans, the Polynesians, everybody,
the Inca, the Aztec, everybody. It would explain a lot of this megalithic architecture.
Yeah. Well, potentially, yeah. The North American Indians had legends of giants. Six-fingered red-haired
giants, by the way. Yeah. You've done some great videos on that. Yeah. I mean, the giants were being
unearthed by the Smithsonian Institution in the mountains of America. Right during that time,
we were talking about the spiritualism and, and, uh, and, and the, uh, the, the, um, airship
phenomenon, the mystery airship phenomenon, right in that time, we're unearthing the bones of giants
out from the mounds, from within the mounds, the Indian mounds. So why hide, if you're the
Smithsonian, you're the Air Force, why hide this stuff? So I've been, I have my own theory here and
it may or may not be true, but I have a feeling that really what's behind this, what's behind the
secrecy is the occult. Because if you know anything about the legends of giants, you'll
find out really quickly that there was a cult of giants in the ancient world, especially among
the Canaanites, but not exclusive to the Canaanites. And there were some things that
were known about the giants. For example, it was known that the giants, in some cases,
it was believed that they could be resurrected. In other cases, it was, it was believed that,
and almost universally, actually, that the spirits of the giants could be contacted. Remember I said
in the book of Enoch that when this, when the giants were killed, that their spirits departed
their bodies and that they persisted in the world as vagabond wraiths, right? So those, so those are the
demons of the New Testament. And, and so those spirits are in the world and occult practitioners
believe that they can make contact with those spirits, either to harness their power or to
extract information from them, to attempt to control them, uh, or maybe, maybe because they're
looking for, to possess themselves or other people. I don't know. I don't know. But there's
definitely, in the ancient context, there was a cult of giants. And in fact, uh,
in, in, in the areas where biblically speaking, we know there were giants and then archaeologically
speaking, I would say, we know there were giants such as the Island of Sardinia. You have, and also
Menorca, the Island of Menorca and Spain, you have a lot of, in fact, all over much of the world,
you have dolmens. You have dolmens, which are these sort of freestanding large stones,
megalithic stones. Oftentimes they're shaped like, um, um, almost like a little house,
you know, with like three walls and a big slab of stone on top, various configurations of dolmens.
Some of them are quite large, many of them megalithic. Um, and I believe that the dolmens
are associated with the giants, not just because they're large stones, but they're associated with
the cult of giants. And this, this is, this is what I would describe as, as Canaanite or Canaanitic
sorcery, more specifically, Canaanite necromancy, because necromancy is the, it's, it is the,
let's call it the dark art of trying to contact the dead or resurrect the dead. Uh, and this is
definitely, this was definitely a belief in Canaan among the Canaanites. We know because there are
Ugaritic texts that have been discovered that have, uh, that have summoning rights that are summoning
dead Nephilim. In other words, it's like a, it's like a, uh, an attempt to resurrect, either resurrect
dead Nephilim, re-embody them or contact their spirits. It's a good golem or something. Yeah.
Like the myth. Right. And, and, and, but before I forget, there's a little bit of a,
there's a little bit of a crossover here with the Epstein stuff that you mentioned earlier,
because it's apparent that the, some of the elite, some of our ruling elite are obsessed with,
with Baal. And Baal was a Canaanite deity, right? And so you have this Canaanitish cult
that's still being perpetuated among the elite. And part of that Canaanitish cult, at least in ancient
Canaanitish cult, was the cult of giants. So if you go to the island of Sardinia today, for example,
you will find many, many megalithic structures that are still standing. Those are called, uh,
nurage towers. And they're, they're circular stone towers and they're, they're pretty impressive,
although they're crude. This is, this is Cyclopean architecture, which is large stones fit
together without the use of any binding agent like mortar. And at the top of these towers,
some of them were over a hundred feet tall. And there were over 30,000 of these things
on the island of Sardinia, over 30,000. At the top of some of these towers were megalithic
basalt stones that were cut. So you, you do have some, some more of the monumental architecture
incorporated into the top of the towers, whereas the rest of the towers, pretty crude.
But big stones, nevertheless, in the Cyclopean style, but associated with these towers are
what are called the tombs of the giants. To this day, they're called the tombs of the
giants on the island of Sardinia. I visited, I've been to Sardinia a few times and I visited
many of the, both the towers and the tombs. And the tombs are configured in the shape of
a womb. Now, I used to think that it was bull's head because of Molech and Baal, and it was
clearly a Canaanitish, the, the, the ancient culture that this, that they attribute these
towers and these tombs to is called the Neuragic people, the Neuragic culture. But the Neuragic
culture, it's clear we're Canaanitish for sure. That's, that culture was Canaanitish.
Their iconography, their, they, we know that the, at the very least, we know that the Phoenicians
inhabited that island for some time. And the Phoenicians were descended from the Canaanites
and had continued on many of their rights, including, according to the Romans, they sacrificed
their children to Molech. And that's part of the reason, ostensibly, why they, why the Romans
detested them. I didn't know that. So the, so these practices, the sacrifice of children
was practiced widely by the Canaanites and, and also by the Phoenicians. The, the Canaanites,
the, the, the Greeks called the Canaanites Phoenicians. And, and so you had the, that
specifically the inhabitants of, of Tyre, Sidon, and Byblos were Phoenician and they were
Canaanites. So, but then there were other Canaanite tribes, right? And in the Old Testament,
among these Canaanites were literal, were literal tribes of giants, clans of giants,
mostly inhabiting the high country. And these are the giants that Joshua encountered during the
conquest. So I think my, and I'm going to get back to the occult thing here. I think that Joshua
drove out a lot of the giants that weren't killed in the conquest. They went, they went over the
Mediterranean, across the Mediterranean, and many of them reestablished themselves on the island of
Sardinia. That's my guess. That's just a conjecture of mine.
Are the tombs extremely large there or?
Yes. And I'll get to get back to the tombs in a sec, in a second. So this migration,
this forced migration, this eviction of giants out of the promised land documented in the biblical
text, is evidenced in the fact that there was a, I forget who recorded this, one of the Greek
historians, that there was in Tunisia, there was a column that had an inscription and the inscription
read, we are the Canaanites who fled before the face of Joshua, the son of Nun.
Whoa. And so the Canaanites obviously were evicted from the land of Canaan. And I think they coalesced
on the island of Sardinia. And so now you have massive megalithic towers and you have massive
megalithic tombs. Again, to this day, known as the tombs of the giants. And initially, as I said, I thought
that the- Are the tombs for like a 10 foot plus body or?
Okay. So I'll describe the tomb and then I'll, and then we'll talk about a controversy regarding
them and, and, and, and, and how large they are. So the tombs are shaped, generally speaking, like a
bull's head, right? Like, like the Chicago bulls logo, generally speaking, shaped like a bull's head.
So I had thought initially that because this is a Canaanitish culture, that these, these tombs are
shaped in the bull's head, which is a very iconic figure among the Canaanites. Sometimes
representing Molech or, or Baal, right? And, and so I had assumed that, that this was the
configuration. I was wrong. The tombs are actually shaped like wombs. They're shaped like a uterus,
which is, if you look at it, like if you pull it up on, on, on Google images, it's shaped like,
it looks like a bull's head kind of. So it's got like the two arms and then this curved portion on
the bottom. And that's how all the tombs are shaped in Sardinia. Now there's two types of
tombs. One of them has a trilithon entry, a trilithon doorway, which means it's like megalithic
stones that are stacked like a, basically like a, like a doorway, right? And then the other
configuration is a large megalithic stone that's like a stele with a, with a little doggy door in it,
the bottom, just like a little door that you and I couldn't fit through. But a young person could,
like a 12 year old or something like 13 year old could, could squeeze into the hole.
So there, as I keep saying, I'm not inventing the word tomb of the giants. That's what they're
called since time immemorial. They were called the tombs of the giants. And the locals believe that
giants were buried in them, in the vicinity of them, or more importantly, beneath them.
So the contention is by armchair archeologists that
the bodies of giants can't fit in the tombs. Well, first of all, that wasn't the purpose of
the tomb. The purpose wasn't to put the body inside. I'll explain that in a minute. But even
if it were, I went to Sardinia with a tape measure and yes, you can fit the bodies of giants in those
tombs. So even if that was the purpose, you could fit a 10 foot tall dude in there. And I'm estimating
a guy that's, you know, three times my width, like laying on the ground, just imagining somebody
three times my width, you know, two, three times my height. Yes, you can.
And the locals think that the giants were buried there. There is mythology local.
They're associated with the tombs. So I learned when I was in Sardinia that the tombs actually
were, are configured the way that they're configured with the, in the shape of a womb
with the door, one with the trilithon door that you and I could get into, but we'd have to stoop
down. Right. But the other one, the little door, we could, we couldn't squeeze into it. I learned
that those tombs, it's known to the archeological community, were configured in such a way so that
they could accommodate what's called the rite of incubation or a rite of incubation. What is the
rite of incubation? It was a, it was a rite of passage ceremony. So when young people were adults
and back then the ancient world, I mean, you were an adult when you were like 12 years old, right? 12,
13, 14 years old, you're, you're, you're being initiated into adulthood, getting married at 14,
15, 16 in the ancient world. Right. So, uh, they were, they were, they were the rite of incubation
is a rite of passage in which the young person would squeeze into the, either that little doggy door
in the stele, the one configuration, or they would be sealed in with a door with a stone into the other
configuration. Both of them shaped in the, both of them configured in the shape of a womb. So what you
have is a gallery inside the tomb and both of them, it's, it's a quite a large gallery. And
in, in, in, in the, uh, in the tomb with the trilithon doorway, you can stand up and walk around.
They're very large inside. Um, and there's a little bench built into it and you could see where maybe
you could put some candles or whatever. And the idea was that the young person as part of this rite
passage would incubate in the tomb in order to commune and to absorb the power, the prowess
of the mighty one buried beneath the tomb. Whoa. Right. So this is like, you can think of this as a,
maybe like a resurrection tomb. Somehow were you communicating with the beings,
the dead giants, their spirits come. Remember the mythology of the ancient world, not just the Jews
was that the spirits of dead giants persisted in the world as demons. So you could commune with
their, if you have their bodies, maybe you can commune with their, reach out to their spirits,
commune with them and be inhabited by them or just gain information. So that imagine, you know,
the Gadarene demoniac that we talked about earlier was so, um, was so energized, demonically energized
that he, that they would chain him up in the tombs because he would scream. He was wild. He was a
feral and he was so demonically energized that he would break the chains. So you're talking about
superhuman strength. That's pretty useful if you're like a warrior society, right? You want to field some
berserkers, some demon possessed berserkers. That's a very useful technology, so to speak.
A field on an ancient battlefield, these demonized berserkers. That's one possibility that they were
trying to, to become, um, to become infused, inhabited by demonic spirits, but, but also maybe
just to commune with the, with the mighty ones who had, who had died and gone before them, but that's,
they were incubating and they were sealed in there for a period of time.
It's wild. Have we-
It gets wilder.
Keep going. How does it get wilder?
Do you remember, um, the WikiLeaks emails?
Yeah, of course.
Remember there was allegedly an email that was a correspondence with Hillary Clinton
where she was inquiring about the resurrection tomb and body of Gilgamesh.
That's right. And Gilgamesh was a giant.
Yes. So-
Oh, this is so weird.
It connects back to the occult stuff. So what do I think is behind the coverup of giants?
I think the occult is behind the coverup of giants. The Epstein type ball worshiping cult
who are literally attempting to either demonize themselves or others or make contact with these
spirits of dead giants, harness them, gather information from them. If they come, if the
antediluvian world was technologically advanced, there's a lot of information, practical, functional
information that you could gain by interacting with these ancient beings.
Yes. Do- Have we ever found giant bones?
Okay. So that gets- that's a- that's a whole conversation in and of itself. So on the island
of Sardinia, again, I was there three times and I interviewed a lot of people.
Yeah.
And I put all this in a film. It was in a- one of those true legends documentaries that
I mentioned earlier that I- I produced with Steve Quayle. Um, I interviewed dozens of people
in Sardinia who, who had dug up the bones of giants themselves with their hands.
Whoa.
And no, the common contention here is that these were the bones of giant sloths and mastodons
and other megafauna. But the problem is that the reason why the Sardinians at that time,
we're talking about the thirties or forties, you know, fifties, sixties, back in that era.
Yeah. The reason why, and these were all elderly people I talked to, the reason why they were
actively looking for, or if they were plowing in their field, they would, you know, they'd have
a horse drawn plow at the time. Plowing the field, they, they, they kick up a large,
some skeletal remains, right? Of a large, let's say forearm and hand, fingers. The reason why they
would, they would be excited about this is because oftentimes, more often than not, they would find
jewelry associated with the remains, rings on the fingers, necklaces, different pieces of jewelry
that were just jumbled in with the bones or sometimes still on them. And, and I heard this
from a lot of people in Sardinia, the elderly people who still remember it. And I interviewed a
couple of gentlemen who excavated at the site called Anastasia, at the, at the church of Anastasia,
it's a Catholic, little Catholic church. And the church was planted on top of a, of a, of a
neurologic archeological site. And they decided to do an excavation of the site. And these individuals
excavated, I'm probably going to get the dates wrong here. I want to say one of them excavated from
like 78 to 79. And then the other one excavated from like 80 to 81 in that range, right? They both
excavated at the same site and they both, I interviewed them separately and they both told
me the same story. They were hired by the municipality to go in, to go to the grounds of
the church of Anastasia and start to remove systematically, take apart the ruins and remove
the artifacts. And both of them, the, the, uh, the procedure was all of the artifacts that came
out of the site went into the church. They put tables, they set up tables in the church.
I went to the church of Santa Anastasia and it's just this little chapel and they put tables,
they set tables up inside the church. And then they would take the artifacts, all kinds of artifacts,
gold and silver and all kinds of artifacts and goblets and plates and jewelry and the bones of giants.
Would come out of the site and they would put them in the, in the church. They found entire
skeletons of giants, entire skeletons, both of them independently. And I could give you just a ton
of examples here, but I remember one, there's a couple of examples that jump out. Uh, in one day of
working, one of these gentlemen found three, they found three skeletons of a giant, you know,
they, they, they reassembled it. They, they, they, they, they, uh, extracted the pieces and parts
and then they re, they reassembled it in the, they were told to, to, to lay out the bones next to the
church as opposed to in, usually everything went inside the church. But in this particular occasion,
he laid out three skeletal remains of giants and he said, so the procedure was, I know I'm
sort of tying this in a, in a, in a confusing knot here, but the procedure was the artifacts go in
the church and then overnight somebody came to take them all away. And then when they would come
back in the morning, everything's gone and they would just, that was how they proceeded. But on this
occasion, this guy was told to lay these bodies out in the, next to the church in the yard. So he
laid them out, three bodies. They were at least nine feet tall each. Next day they were gone.
And another occasion. Who takes these? Well, that individual told me that he knows
that, that, uh, some of those artifacts were, were recovered, were, um, uh, were retrieved by
certain individuals who were associated with the University of Cageti, the capital city in Sardini
is called Cageti. The University of Cageti, he knows that there was some certain professors or
somebody associated. He told me the name who, who communicated with him.
About what to do with some of these artifacts, including the bodies of giants.
You contact that professor?
Uh, I couldn't find him. So then the other individual, the other individual, um, he, he
told me there's dozens of stories from both of these guys. He told me that he was excavating
one day and he had his wife with him and they found a skull that was so big. And he said the
vertebrae was still attached to part of it because these were very well preserved. When I say
skeletal remains, I'm not talking about bleach bones. I'm talking about like bodies that are
really well preserved. Not, not like, not exactly like mummies, but like some of them have sinew.
Some of them still have like, they're not just skeletons. And he said this, this, he, he unearthed
this gigantic skull. It was so large that he and his wife had to carry it together and they brought
it into the church. Then he said there was another day he was, I'm just skipping over a bunch of other
ones, by the way, but he said he was excavating and at the site and, and they were excavating a new,
a, one of those towers, one of those Nuragia towers. And he, uh, they, they unsealed a chamber.
Like it was, it was almost like hermetically sealed because what it looks like had happened to
these towers is they were suddenly submerged. They were suddenly covered in earth, almost like
a tidal wave had swept across the Island and deposited all of this, all of this soil over
the towers and buried them. And in fact, that's true because, um, I saw, I saw, so keep in mind,
some of these towers are very tall. Some of them were up to a hundred feet, but they've since
crumbled. Right. But they're still pretty tall. And if you look at the towers before they were
discovered, they just look like hills. They just look like hills of dirt. Right. And then they dig
into them and that's one of these towers and they're all over the place still out there all
over the place. What does anybody have photos or video of the bones or? So no. So we'll keep in
mind, this is back in the late seventies, early eighties. Yeah. And they were told not to take any
pictures and never to talk about it again, two individuals. How many of these witnesses came out
in your documentary? Well, this particular case too, but of other cases, dozens. Okay. Wow.
And so they unsealed this one, this, this tower that was buried. Remember it, let's say this thing
is buried suddenly, right? Let's say you've got somebody living inside of this thing. Tidal wave
hits, carries a mountain of, of soot, dirt, deposits it suddenly over one of these towers,
hermetically sealed. Yeah. Whatever's in this thing is sealed inside, right?
And going to be well preserved. So, um, he, they opened up one of these chambers and he said,
he walked, they walked into the chamber with flashlights and there was a giant seated at a
table and he was dead and he was just slumped over. And, and he, they said that at the time,
everything was gigantic. He said the table was gigantic. There was a gigantic plate and goblet
on the table and the plate still had like oysters on it. What? Yeah. And the giant had been eating
oysters and he was a giant goblet on the table and probably nine, 10, 11 feet tall, maybe 12 feet
tall. I just somewhere in that range is most of these giants are in that range between how,
between nine and 12 feet tall. Wouldn't the flesh have decayed by that?
I think it did start to decay immediately as soon as they, like it started to crumble.
So it was like somehow concealed from oxygen. It was hermetically sealed.
The thing was just buried suddenly probably.
Shit.
So at least this is what they said, you know, this is what they're telling me. So, um,
and I didn't pay these guys or anything like that.
Yeah.
It was nothing like that. So they, they, they took the body of this giant,
they carried it out together and laid it in the church.
Wow.
It was very, very well preserved. And then they took the goblet and the plate and,
I mean, they found all, they found earrings. They found all kinds of things, jewelry,
all kinds of stuff at this one site in Santa Anastasia in Sardinia. Apart from that,
I interviewed lots of other people who found the remains of giants all over the place in the
countryside.
Wow.
One guy said that, um.
Do you think we'll get concrete evidence of this in our life?
I don't know. I don't know. This one guy said.
Because if this is this prevalent, I would expect that. And I would hope.
That we do.
Well, like I said, I think the occult's at the center of this thing, so I'm not sure.
Right. Um, but.
But it's the same thing with the UFO stuff where it's like, it always disappears,
always slips through your fingers.
Are these bale worshiping pedophiles ever going to go to jail?
Right. Yeah.
So.
Yeah. Yeah. No one apparently visited the island.
Yeah. Exactly.
Everyone was on the emails, but no one actually.
Right. So if I see a bunch of pedos go to jail,
then I'll have more hope that we're going to learn the truth about giants.
Yeah.
So just to give you one more illustration here,
I talked to a guy who was 101 years old when I interviewed him.
Wow.
He was still very spry, very, uh, spunky, funny guy.
It's a blues on there, right? There's a, like, centenarians.
Yes. This is, this, this, this is some of the longest lived people in the world,
you know, in Sardinia.
So he told us.
Maybe it's the giant DNA.
Maybe it is. Well, they actually,
they say some of them that they were descended from giants.
Wow.
And, and on the island of Sardinia, you do have an unusual, uh,
pot, uh, portion of the population with red hair.
Hmm.
Uh, so.
Which seems to be a trademark of, of these Nephilimic tribes.
So.
And, and didn't, uh, Canaan literally had red hair, I believe, right?
Who?
Was it, uh, or maybe it was, uh, Esau had red hair.
Esau.
Okay.
Esau was like a hairy ape.
Yeah, exactly.
Red hairy ape.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So, um.
And that's not related to this.
It is kind of.
Kind of.
So, okay.
But just to give you another illustration here.
Yeah.
I talked to this guy, 101 years old.
Can't remember his name.
It just came into my head and then, and then departed.
But it was a lot of fun talking to him.
And of course I had a translator with me, Anna Tuveri.
So, Anna, if you're watching, shout out to Anna Tuveri.
Shout out, Anna.
She was born in Rome, a native Italian speaker.
Actually, I believe some of her family was from Sardinia.
Oh, wow.
And so she was with me as my translator.
And we interviewed this gentleman and he, uh, he told us some wild stories.
One of the stories he told me was one time he was working in a field when he was a young man.
So this was, I mean, he's 101 years old.
I don't know what, what year that would have been.
He told us, I can't remember.
Uh, I think it was like 1920s, 1930s, something like that.
And, and he's working in this field because this, the owner of the field wanted to plant a vineyard.
So they were tilling, getting ready to plant a vineyard.
And this field was in the vicinity of one of those towers, right?
One of those Nuragi towers.
And they're plowing.
And as there's a bunch of guys out there and they're, they're, they're tearing up the soil.
And suddenly they start unearthing the, the remains of gigantic people.
And he said, they were all starting to shout to each other and a big commotion because they were all sort of simultaneously starting to unearth like this graveyard.
And he said, all of the bodies were positioned like this, two by two in a cross configuration.
So like that, all the bodies.
And there were dozens of them.
And he said they were gigantic.
So when people say that in Sardinia, they mean nine, 10, 11, 12 feet.
And they were clearly humans that had been buried their intention.
This is a graveyard.
And as they're digging this up, the owner of the field says, stop, stop, stop.
I got to call this in.
Got to call the coroner or whatever.
And so he made a phone call to whoever, the university, I don't know who he called.
And then he came back and he said, everybody has to vacate this area.
We all have to leave.
He said, I've been told they're going to come get the remains.
They want us out of here.
So we have to go.
Well, this gentleman I was interviewing, he's very funny.
He said, he said, well, I really needed the money and I wanted to make this guy pay me a day's wage, not a half a day's wage.
So I stayed.
He said, my plan was to just stay and work and then say, hey, I just stayed.
I worked the whole day.
So he get a day's wage.
And, but what happened was as he's in the midst of working by himself now, right?
He said, these vans pulled up, a bunch of vans pulled up and people started, these people started getting out of the vans with equipment.
And he hid, he went and hid himself like in the bushes or something.
And he watched them come out of the vans, take pictures of all of the, the, the remains that were in a cross configuration, gather up all the remains, load them into the vans.
Then he said, they went into the tower and they were examining the tower, taking pictures of the tower.
And he said, there was like this, in that tower, there was like, um, some kind of like a passageway that went down and maybe was obstructed.
They sealed it up.
I think he said they, they put some stuff and then cemented over it.
And then they left.
So strange.
I mean, these are the kinds of stories I heard one after another.
And don't you also have a story of being at a function, you see this kind of high up air force officer and you mentioned the Kandahar 2003 or 2005 kind of giant and, you know, confrontation.
And then it was his wife says, like, he's not supposed to talk about this.
I don't want to, I got to be really careful with that story because that, that I don't want to get that guy in trouble.
But yeah, let's just put it this way.
Let's only be very vague.
I've had interactions.
Yeah.
With people.
Where we could talk about like UFOs on the ground basis and they'll whisper, you know, and tell you a little bit of what they know.
But when you bring up giants, one of them literally went like this to me.
And pointed to his phone.
What?
That's crazy.
And, um, and, and then I had a friend of mine who, uh, I told him, I told him some of these stories.
Right.
And, um, he said, uh, he said that he was with a friend of his who happened to be.
And I got to be careful here too, but he was with, let's, let me be very vague.
Uh, he was with, I don't want to get anybody in trouble.
Sure.
I talk a lot and I got to make sure I'm, I'm not saying things that I can't.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
You don't want to burn any sources.
So, um, he was with this individual who's associated with the government, somebody from the government.
And they're just having a casual conversation.
He said, uh, uh, they're really good friends having this casual conversation.
And, and he had just been with me, this guy, the, the, the, the, my, my friend who's talking to his government buddy.
He had just been with me and I've, we're talking like we're talking right now.
We were talking like we're talking right now.
And, and, and, and he, cause he was like, whoa, that's crazy.
I can't believe that.
I was like, well, listen, man, bring it up.
See what happens.
Bring this topic up to people who you think might know something.
Watch what happens.
So he did.
He brought it up with this individual.
And he said, he asked him, he said, Hey, do you know anything about like this Tandahar giant thing?
And he said, this person who's his friend just totally switched.
Yeah.
And said, well, I'm trying to think what he told him.
He said something like, um, what the hell are you getting yourself into?
What are you, what are you getting, what are you getting yourself into?
You need to be careful.
Whoa.
Like just turn, just, just casual fun conversation just turned into like this very serious warning.
I don't know what you're getting yourself into, but you need to be careful.
Is what he was saying.
Then he called me and he told me, dude, I, he said, he said, man, I didn't know what to think after you talked to me, but man, I, I brought this up.
And just like you said, he changed on a dime and warned me.
So, you know, I have a lot of little anecdotal things like that.
And people accuse me all the time of, you know, the trust me, bro stuff.
I get it.
Look, these are stories.
Okay.
Well, you know, I'll, I'll hit you with the story of mine, which is before we even met.
And, you know, maybe I was vaguely aware of your work, but this was years ago.
I had a friend who's kind of, uh, you know, prominent and like, or semi-prominent on like Twitter and like tech circles and stuff.
He's like not into any of this, like ancient civilization, UFO stuff.
Really?
I mean, like maybe is somewhat partial to it now, but like, is, you know, has been dragged into it by the fact that the narrative has changed so much in the last five, six years.
And, uh, we're at like a conference or something.
And he's telling me about, uh, his buddy who is special forces.
And he's like, you got it.
You know, um, you come to New York, get dinner with me and, uh, this guy, uh, he's special forces.
And he claims to have, or his troop or whatever is, you know, um, the core he was with claims to have fought this giant in, in, in the caves of Afghanistan.
And so this was like totally independent of anything having to do with you.
And, uh, and so I have to do that.
Cause honestly, at the time I was like, that's insane.
What is this?
I was like, I mean, I was at the time, you know, UFO stuff was so still like kind of interesting.
Integrating in my mind.
And I was like, this is, this is really crazy.
Like what the hell?
But, uh, so another independent source.
Yeah.
And I don't know.
I'm pretty sure I could be wrong about this, but I'm pretty sure that I saw something that looked like an official, like press release from the Pentagon saying the Kandahar giant story is not true.
Like, oh, that's funny.
They commented.
Yeah.
It seems like they've gone, uh, they've, they've explicitly wanted the public to know that this story isn't true.
So again, why all the secrecy?
Like what's the big deal?
So giants existed, you know, we know that giants existed in America, the native Americans had the, had the legends of the red hair giants.
And the, as I said earlier, their bones were being discovered on record in the Smithsonian institution's own annual reports.
You have, you have evidence of, of very unusual skeletal remains, many of which were very large, uh, which, which were, were the remains of giants.
And where did those go?
Yeah.
Where did those go?
You have, you have, uh, Abraham Lincoln, who's waxing poetically about Niagara Falls in a speech in which he says, the eyes of that ancient species of giants whose bones fill the mounds of America.
Have gazed upon Niagara as ours do now.
That's wild.
Abraham Lincoln.
So is he referencing something, something that nobody would understand what he's saying?
Of course not.
He's referencing something that everybody knew to be true.
The, the bones of that ancient species of giants who's, who's, or the eyes of that ancient species of giants whose bones fill the mounds of America.
So, uh, it's, it is bizarre.
It is bizarre when you can talk to guys about UFOs all day long, you know, government types, but they won't say a thing about giants.
Yeah.
Not only will they not say a thing, they freak out, they get visibly, you know, concerned.
Yep.
It's so strange.
Again, I would, I would say that there's something, uh, if I can use the term Epstein-ish, Epsteinian, Epsteinian.
Epsteinian.
About this whole thing with the giants and the ball and the, in the, in the occult.
Well, yeah, that's the, I mean, you, one of the deeper thread on the Epstein stuff, it's like, why is he showing up in email saying, I killed ponds from ponds and Fleischman, like cold fusion, which is clean, limitless energy.
He's saying he, you know, Robert Maxwell, Ghislaine's, you know, uh, super spy father who was, you know.
Buried on the Mount of Olives, I believe.
Interesting.
Well, there you go.
Yeah, MI6, Mossad, uh, you know, all these, basically like helped invent peer review, scientific peer review, was also in charge of Nazi tech transfer, which is really, I think, an important fact.
And then you have Epstein telling Bannon in an interview that he moved Zora Ranch to where it was, or he moved to Zora Ranch because it was near retiring Los Alamos physicists.
And then he's, he's showing up and he says he's killing cold fusion and he's obsessed with anti-gravity.
So you end up like with the bones of the giants or with UFOs or with all of these things, because you ended with really like this weird, like there's almost like a cult of science, like, like, uh, uh, cause there's so much circumstantial evidence.
There's so much, and then there's very little concrete evidence in the way of like really good high res photography.
And then there's always some muddling of the good, you know, when there is good evidence, we talked about photographs that have negatives.
We talked about videos, talked about implants.
We've talked about material, like there are all these things, but there's always the muddying of the water.
So you get into this really weird ontological territory where there is literally a faction, uh, on earth that wants to hide, uh, breakthrough technology and wants to hide breakthroughs as far as our own ancient discovery, you know, like understanding our past and wants to keep us in this state of amnesia.
Are these the adepts of the mystery schools?
Maybe, maybe.
I don't know.
I don't know the answer.
I don't know, but there's a lot of weird symbology on Epstein's.
It's not coincidental that, that ball comes up Canaanite.
I mean, the, the, the, the Canaanite God, the, as I said, the coverup of giants, uh, crossover with the UFO stuff.
And you throw into the mix that just the, the rank occultist like Elis to Crowley and Jack Parsons and.
Right.
And, and Crowley's another guy who had an alien being sort of seemed to show up.
Yeah.
The lamb thing.
Lamb thing.
Yeah.
He conjured.
And yeah.
So there's a lot of crossover here.
Yeah.
Is the, is any of that?
Cause like, you know, I, mostly I associate the occult with like left hand path pursuit of power via paranormal channels in a way that is a Faustian bargain and kind of blows up in your face if you do it.
But maybe it confers power for a temporary period of time.
And then I also think of like the founding fathers of America all being Freemasons and like, I'm interested in the Templar.
I think they're interesting.
You know, I don't think this is all like, I often find myself caught between the people who are like, it's all demonic.
And then these other people who are like, you know, uh, obsessed with it for very dark, bad reasons.
I'm sure that within, within some of these, like, for example, Freemasons is a great example.
Uh, most Freemasons, certainly ones that I know.
Yeah.
Are just good old boys.
They don't know nothing about anything really.
That's, I mean, now if you're a Freemason, you don't know shit.
Yeah.
So maybe back then, I'm sure it was much more intense.
You know, I think Francis Bacon, who was, who was, who was the author of the colonization scheme.
Ah, I didn't know that.
Yeah.
And, um.
He knew some stuff.
He was.
He read like the new Atlantis.
He was, uh, I think he was a Rosicrucian.
Yeah.
And I think he was a, a, uh, acolyte of John Dee.
Right.
The, the famous magician at Elizabeth's, Elizabeth's court, who was definitely a Rosicrucian.
So I think that, yeah, you definitely have a cult activity.
You have, you have certain acolytes in the occult who are very serious and who know things
and who have, uh, very devious, dark aims.
Then you have other people who were involved for other reasons.
Mm.
Um, fraternities.
You know, it was popular to be a member of some kind of fraternity back then because,
you know, you didn't have cell phones and internet.
And so if you're going to, if you're going to network with people, you did it in, in a
fraternity a lot of times, or you did it in like a church.
And some people think that Jesus himself was part of that.
So there's a Martin Luther King Jr.
Actually wrote a book or sorry, an essay called the pagan continuity hypothesis.
And then you have people like Brian Morescu who writes, you know, the immortality key and
Elaine Pagels as Princeton religious studies professor.
And a lot of these people sort of hint at the idea that the last supper was itself a mystery
ritual that had some, you know, continuity between the Eleusinian mystery rituals and
whatever he underwent.
I have no idea if that's true.
I personally would reject any notion that Jesus was, uh, was a mystery, mystery school
adept or went to India to learn from the, from the gurus or whatever.
You know, there's lots of things people say, but.
But do you think he had secret teachings?
I think he was, I would say that Jesus is exactly who he claimed to be.
He was the Messiah, the son of God.
That's what I would say.
Um, and that, uh, he differed from all of these other masters and gurus in that, uh, he was
endowed by the Holy spirit to do what he did.
And he rose from the grave, which, which distinguishes Jesus of Nazareth from everyone else.
Uh, so I would say as a Christian, I believe that Jesus was the Messiah, the son of God.
But all this stuff around him have, you know, you needing to have ears to hear and having
disciples and stuff.
Okay.
Initiates of something.
It is very interesting that Jesus.
So here you have, according to the authors of the new Testament, Jesus is, he's the son of
God and he is, he is the creator that it's, um, a Colossians one.
15 through 17, which reads he, the son of God, Jesus, he is the image of the invisible
God, the firstborn overall creation provide him.
All things were created that are in heaven and that are on earth, visible and invisible,
whether thrones or dominions or principalities or powers, all things were created through
him and for him and in him, all things consist.
In fact, I missed the other part.
And he is before all things and in him, all things consist.
So, uh, that is a very unique, I mean, this, the, the, the person of Christ to the, to
the apostles was not just a great teacher.
He was, he's the singularity.
All things were created through him and for him.
And he is before all things and in him, all things consist.
And this was the, this is what the apostles believed about Christ.
And, and, and Jesus, so here you have the, the author of creation who is walking among
men and he could have taught us about anything.
He could have instructed us in the, in, in electromagnetism, electricity.
I mean, you know, the, the, the Jews were, were, were under the dominion of the Romans.
Jesus could have conferred information to them, uh, upgraded their, their, their military
technology, right?
Giving them information, electricity and so forth that would have allowed them to easily
dominate, not just the Romans, but the entire world, right?
He could have instantly upgraded their, their, their civilization.
He didn't do that in contrast to those gods who descended in the days of Jared, Jesus spoke
in parables and he taught the people like they were little kids.
And, and he, he, what, what he, his message was about the kingdom of heaven and, and everything
that he did was a demonstration that he was precisely who he said he was, namely the son
of God.
And so I look at that and it's remarkable to me because the message of Christ was,
was, was, was the, the gospel of Christ is about, as I referred to earlier, is about
redeeming the sons and daughters of Adam and reconciling them back to the father.
That's why the cross of Christ brings reconciliation so that we can go back into the family.
That's what he was about.
He could have taught all, all manner of secret knowledge.
And instead he taught us about the kingdom of heaven and about his father and, and the
way to go back, uh, to be reconciled to the father, which was through him.
So I separate Christ from all of these other, you know, I don't believe that, that Jesus was
a mystery school adept.
But I think that in fact, his message was in direct contradiction to the, the knowledge
of the watchers, to the knowledge of the gods that was delivered to mankind.
The people that like to lump him in with the mystery schools also say he hung out with the
Essenes or whatever at the time.
All of this is, of course, conjecture.
Yeah, of course.
Um, you know, we know that, uh, Jesus, that they fled to Egypt and he was in Egypt for
a while and they came back and that, that Jesus was growing up with his parents, arguing
with the teachers of the law and the synagogue and so forth.
So, um, yeah, I would ascribe to, uh, rather I would not, I don't personally subscribe to
any of those alternative ideas about Christ.
Um, I believe Jesus is precisely who he said he was.
And do you think, you know, with respect to, you know, this idea of the watchers and the
Nephilim, he's of a totally different variety.
He is just the, the son of God.
Yes.
So, yes, you know, so much of what, what was happening in, in the life and ministry of
Jesus of Nazareth was really kind of undoing what had been done the, the, by the watchers
and, and, and reclaiming, uh, and, and, and reestablishing the kingdom of God.
And so there's a, there's a great book called Reversing Hermann by the late scholar, Michael
Heiser.
He also wrote a great, another great book called, um, The Unseen Realm, which is a, which is a
really, really, I think, uh, critical scholarly, uh, dissertation on the life and ministry of
Jesus as it relates to the things we were talking about earlier on, the watchers and
everything that they had done.
Heiser also really corroborates the Nephilim ideas, like a real historical thing.
Yes.
And he's a guy who sort of throws, pours cold water on the Zachariah Sitchin kind of.
Yeah.
He had a website called Sitchin is Wrong.
Exactly.
I think it was SitchinisWrong.com in which he, he demonstrates how a lot of Sitchin's
interpretations of the cylinder seals were, were not very good.
So another point in favor of giants is a biblical scholar who's pretty serious in debunking other
people who are, you know, considered more quacky or whatever seems to corroborate the
giants.
Yeah.
I mean, Heiser would have affirmed and did that the, the, the Enochian tale that we talked
about earlier, that that idea, the idea of the gods, the watchers descending to the earth
and copulating with human wind and progenerating that hybrid race of giants, that that formed
the, the, the, the substrate of human, uh, rather of Hebrew cosmology, that that was part
and parcel to the historical narrative of, of the Hebrews when they look back into the
antediluvian world.
Um, there's a lot of other scholars too, who acknowledge that most scholars acknowledge
that for sure today.
So it's, um, but what I was saying earlier was, you know, to kind of circle back to the
beginning, we were talking about sort of this, this larger biblical context into which you
can accommodate the UFO phenomenon, reminding us of, um, uh, Anna Paulina's words, you know,
look at the book of Enoch if you want to understand the phenomenon.
She references that in the context of interdimensional beings.
I don't know whether or not these were inter, interdimensional.
I don't even know what interdimensional really means.
That's hilarious when people say, oh, it's interdimensional, or they say, oh, it's spiritual.
It's like, and then you ask them one follow-up question.
It means nothing.
It means, it means movie reference.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Or it means it's a, their political polemic on what it is.
So often if somebody says it's spiritual, they're kind of saying it's demonic.
Yes.
And you hear this with certain Christian podcasters, some of whom I'm a huge fan of, but they'll
say, they'll use this line.
They'll say, I think it's spiritual.
I think it's kind of dark.
And then they won't like, they won't touch it.
And it's like, okay, fine.
But like, what is an angel?
What is a demon?
Precisely.
Like we should try to investigate this.
Exactly.
So if you're going to invoke, if you're going to invoke interdimensionality, for example,
as you, I'm sure, well know, there isn't like one theory in physics that describes extra
dimensions.
There's a suite of theories.
Yeah.
And they're not the same.
You know, you have like multiverse, which is a, you know, different universes with different
physical properties.
Right.
So in the multiverse, you have just this endless, infinite, infinite function never
collapses.
Yeah.
Like the bubbles in a, in a, in a, in a glass of bear constantly, you knew universes being
created and each universe and multiverse has different physical properties.
And the reason why multiverse came into existence is because physicists, I think, finally realized
that you can't get around a creator, like an intelligent creator of the universe.
And so the, the, to circumvent that idea, they, they created the multiverse theory, which
is just like random, spontaneous universes are going, are being created all the time
because our universe is finally tuned.
Clearly our universe is finally tuned.
I mean, it is precisely tuned.
And if any one of the, any one of the, these constituents of our universe was not exactly
the way it is, you couldn't have life.
Yeah.
The anthropic principle.
The anthrop, the anthropic principle.
So the universe is clearly finally tuned for life.
And that points very clearly to a creator and a purpose for the universe.
And so to circumvent that, you just make it so the, the universe just happens to have
these qualities because universes are being, there's a multitude of universe, of universes
being created all the time.
There's an infinite number of universes.
And so it's just like rolling the dice and we happen to live in the one that just the
Goldilocks universe where everything is so finely tuned.
That was a circumvention of the reality that the universe had a beginning and it was finally
tuned so that I could support life and be the way it is.
And so multiverse is each one of these universes and multiverse has different physical properties.
Right.
And so what you see, like there's multiverse and then there's string theory, super string
theory, which super string theory posits that there's 11, there's 11 dimensions, right?
And there's different aspects of string theory that posit more, but there's at least 11 dimensions.
But, but those are like inaccessible dimensions.
Those are like, um, subatomic dimensions.
And, and those dimensions don't give you access to another universe like multiverse.
They just open, it opens up another facet of this universe, right?
And then you have the hyperspatial theory of the universe, which is actually, um, quite
similar to that.
You have the, um, alternative worlds theory.
These are all different scientific theories.
So what people do is they, they just say interdimensional and they invoke them all like a hodgepodge.
And what they're doing is they're invoking a Marvel movie.
Yeah.
So, and this is why when people say, well, I think it's interdimensional, just like you.
My follow-up question is, what does that mean?
Where are they coming from?
Yeah.
Right.
Because you can have, let's say a portal open up in the sky and saucers fly out of it.
Like what my friends saw, my, my friends saw this actually happen.
And then a portal closes, right?
And when a portal was open, he could see a different atmosphere on the other side inside
of the portal.
Well, okay.
So let's assume that story is true.
And if we analyze this, we can say, okay, this is a portal.
What's on the other side?
Is it a different universe?
Is it like some sort of different multiverse or is it a different part of planet earth or
is it a different planet?
Right.
And, and then, so it doesn't mean what I'm trying to say is just because you see a portal open up in
the sky and flying saucers come out of it, does it mean that those saucers are interdimensional
or are by nature interdimensional?
It doesn't, it doesn't follow that those are interdimensional beings.
In fact, there are, it's just as likely, if not more likely that what you're witnessing
is what's called an Einstein Rosen bridge.
And it's connecting two parts of either somewhere on the earth or in the known universe or in
our universe rather.
And so what you're getting is vehicles that are coming from some other part of the universe
or some other part of the earth or the inner earth or something like that.
It doesn't, it doesn't necessarily lend itself to interdimensionality.
And I think there's a lot of confusion there.
I really do.
And I'm not against interdimensionality.
I just don't think it, no, and nobody really can define it properly.
Yeah, I agree.
No, it's a, they're, they, when they say interdimensional, they just mean it's not extraterrestrial.
Exactly.
It's not based on any sort of physics or anything.
So let me ask you, I wanted to ask you what, so based on all of your research, everybody
you've interviewed, everything you know about this phenomenon, what do you think is the
most likely, I know you're probably not going to want to commit to anything, but what do
you think is the most likely explanation based on all the crash retrieval material, based
on the clear nuts and bolts physicality of at least part of this phenomenon?
Yes.
Based on all of the testimonies that you've heard personally?
I struggle.
I can, I can give you like very viable local theories around anti-gravity and propulsion,
and then maybe even an interesting sort of physics theory as to like who the beings are,
where they're from.
I think there are multiple phenomena at play.
So here's, here's our, would be my sort of more multifaceted, very speculative, weakly held
answer there.
I think there is some antediluvian remnants that are, that have survived some sort of
cataclysm and exist in underwater bases, specifically oceans.
Which faction are you referencing here?
When you think about that, who are you thinking about?
It could be, I mean, you're now kind of updating my thought process on this maybe being, you know,
fallen angels, I don't know.
But are you seeing in your head like Nordics?
Are you seeing gray aliens?
Oh, I see.
As far as like the actual-
Are you envisioning when you, yeah, the survivors looking-
What the beings look like?
I don't know.
I don't know what, I mean, it's tricky.
Okay, so would you agree, based on your, based on your research, that the three factions
that are commonly cited are real?
Nordics, reptilians, and grays.
The grays, including the insect and the mantis beings, the gray aliens.
I think they're all real.
And then where it gets so confusing is like you have cases like Travis Walton where they're
working together in conjunction.
Yes, and other cases like that in the abduction material.
There you go.
So if I had to guess, I think usually in the abductions, like the tall grays are overseeing
the small grays.
And then the Nordics are sort of, they seem like even higher on the pecking order.
And so the Nordics somehow seem like really, I don't know, somehow important as far as how
the hierarchy works.
And then mantids also feel above just the grays.
I don't know how the Nordics and the mantids would relate to each other, but yeah, what
would you?
Well, it's very intriguing.
I think it's apparent that the mantids, the insectillins, as Jacobs denominates them,
are clearly in charge of the grays.
Like they are definitely in charge of the little grays.
Um, so they're managing the abduction program, I would say, at least on some level, maybe
there's somebody above them, right?
Yeah.
But they're definitely managing like the procedures and the grays.
That seems to be apparent to me.
Um, here's an interesting anecdote.
So in, in Carla Turner's book, um, Taken, she features the abduction stories of a number
of women.
And one of these ladies, after being abducted by Grace, was abducted, suffered a, endured
a my lab abduction.
She was taken forcibly from her house by military personnel.
She's brought onto a base.
And it was a very violent episode.
And she remembers seeing, I hope I'm getting this right.
She remembers seeing Nordics on the base and she had an interaction with one, like she was
laying in a bed.
Sometimes they were like the, the, the, the scientists and the human scientists were extracting
the, the, the implants and stuff and interrogating her and trying to figure out what the grays
were doing.
It was always about trying to figure out what the grays were doing.
But then she had this, there's this weird story with one of these women where there
was a Nordic.
She was interacting with a Nordic on one of these bases and she asked the Nordic if they
were involved with the grays.
And the reply of the Nordic was by degrees.
That was his reply.
What does that mean?
I don't know.
But I, so, and this is interesting.
You're bringing this up because this would also be my mental model on the sort of these
covert space initiatives of involving, you know, legacy reverse engineering programs is
that we're actually working in conjunction with the beings themselves.
And that story you just told is one of a variety of, of the beings being on these bases.
And if you think about, it's so strange.
It's like you have MK ultra, you have exotic propulsion, you have free energy, you have
all these things where it seems like there's a confluence or convergence of like, um, just
human science initiatives.
And then the, the people at the forefront of all those initiatives start to communicate
with aliens or get into weird alien, like the, the inventors of the radio.
So Tesla and Marconi claimed alien communication.
Puharich, who was like the pioneer of MK ultra was Herman Oborth was saying that rocketry
was inspired, was, you know, Von Braun was inspired by the beings and Oborth gives a
whole lecture on UFOs.
So you have people who are pioneers of the science, specifically science, which is the
forefront of human knowledge.
And so again, going back to the kind of fallen angel, the rebel angel, which gives the knowledge
to them so that these people who are at the front of all of those things seem to be interfacing
Thomas Townsend Brown.
You could think of his anti-gravity stuff as an explanation away from the extraterrestrial
hypothesis.
And then you get into his, the details of his life and he's had, you know, literally close
encounters of the third kind.
He says he's communicating with space brothers.
And so that's as, you know, as deep as you go, it's, it's like the three body problem.
It's this Chinese science fiction novel where they, the interface between the people who
are stealing fire from the gods, you know, these Promethean, you know, figures, these kind
of Oppenheimer style figures, they seem to be interfacing with these beings most.
And so that seems significant.
And then the nuclear thing seems significant because the nuclear thing is kind of the Archimedes
lever, both for cataclysm, but also nuclear is, if you take Feynman's like the room at
the bottom thing, you know, the fact that we're splitting an atom, um, seems somehow really
important for our root access to reality itself.
There's probably an ambient, I mean, there is the Schumann resonance ambient electromagnetic
radiation that helps life grow.
And so like interfering with that, they would obviously, you know, interfere with us interfering
with that.
And so there are all these things that I, you know, I have, feel like I have a good grasp
of there.
And then on the, I don't know how the beings and how they work together.
And then which, you know, it's like when people, um, commune with God and do these sort of
Kabbalistic protocols of which CE5 is a variation and I'm not the biggest Greer fan, but like,
you know, I do think there's actually something to the phenomenon.
Somebody's making contact with something, yeah.
Somebody's making contact with something.
And I don't know if that's, that's probably not the same thing as what's showing up at
our nuclear site.
Is that the same thing as what's showing up, you know, under the oceans?
Like all of these might be different things.
I don't know.
Have you, have you had discussions with any of the psionic assets?
Oh yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So I've talked to some of those guys and, um, I wondered with the psionic stuff, I wondered
if there was a connection between these psionic assets and alien abduction.
And the reason why I wonder that is because one thing that seems apparent is abductees are,
are continually interlaced with the, uh, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the,
phenomenon.
In other words, the grays know their thoughts, even from a distance.
And a good illustration of this is there's been women who, uh, have had a, a, a, you
know, I've had a zygote implanted.
It's grown into a fetus in their womb and they realize that they're pregnant.
They go to their gynecologist.
They realize that they're pregnant.
You know, what's crazy is that sometimes these women are virgins and, um, but the, the
pregnancy is confirmed and, and they contemplate an abortion, just contemplate an abortion or
they're talking on the phone to somebody about it.
The grays come and get the fetus.
They come and get it.
And so the woman will go in for the abortion and they'll do the ultrasound or whatever before
gone.
You know, this is the missing fetus syndrome gone.
Why?
Because the grays took it because they didn't want the, they didn't want the fetus to be
retrieved by the doctor or aborted.
So they came and got it.
They reabducted her and they took it out.
So, um, and there's other such stories that I think indicate that perhaps through the implants,
but also because the grays are, are potently telepathic, that there's, there's a, there's
a connection established between the gray and the abductee.
So if you are, this is just my theory.
And by the way, I, I posited this theory to some of the psionics guys said, so if you are
an abductee and you, you're signaling something, you're broadcasting, maybe because, you know,
you're implanted or just telepathically, whatever, brainwaves, you're broadcasting something.
This is the way I like to think of this.
I have a friend who, uh, was a rancher in all in Australia and it was, you know, always
really hot and he had all his cattle out there.
So he didn't ever really want to get up.
He'd sit there in his tighty whities and on his computer and he didn't want to get up
and go see if there was a problem with his cows.
He'd hear like, he'd hear some commotion out there and he, and he could see him on video.
And so rather than getting up and going out there, he would, he had a drone.
He just put his drone up in the air and he'd fly his drone over there and kind of check
out what's going on.
Did one of them get bit by a snake or something?
Right.
So he didn't have to get up and go out there.
I almost wonder if that's what's going on with some of these psionic people.
They're broadcasting something and then an automated response shows up.
Like orbs often will show up, uh, or sometimes craft, sometimes they can get the craft to
land.
Uh, I almost wonder is because they're intrinsically interlaced with the phenomenon, if it's almost
like just sending out a broadcast and the automated response comes kind of just like the drone
checking on the cattle.
No, that would make sense.
It really would.
Because if you look at like, you know, Skywatcher, which seemed like this.
Jake Barber.
Yeah, exactly.
Almost externalization of what was happening on the inside and maybe it got botched somewhat
and I don't know what ended up happening with it.
But it was that you had this mechanical dog whistle and then you had this human dog whistle.
And so I do think it was this thing where you could predictably, and then you, you hear
other stories of the reverse engineering program involving like the only way to fly the craft
is with your mind.
With your mind.
So that seems significant as well.
Yeah.
There's definitely a mind machine interface involved.
Um, I think that's clear.
I don't know what you think about Lazar's testimony.
I personally believe it's true.
I do too.
Um, I, I think it, I believe it's true.
And then I also think they were, you know, they were messing with him and probably maybe
trying to get certain things out and then it went ran amok.
And the initial briefing that he got, I'm not sure how much of that was true.
Yeah.
Oh yeah, exactly.
There's a lot of passage material.
The UFO Bible, I think he called it.
Yeah.
Or whatever it was, the material that they had him read before he began to work in the
project.
Yeah.
That to me seems like, like maybe some manipulation to try and, you know, I don't
know.
Definitely was some.
Throw some confusion into the mix because they don't ever want any of these guys putting
too many of the pieces together.
Yep.
They just want them to be laser focused on one aspect of it.
And you want to give them uniquely false details.
So if there is a leak, you know.
Precisely right.
You know.
Yeah.
So you always got, and Lazar actually, he, he thinks that that is.
He says that.
A possibility.
So I actually asked some of these psionic guys and, well, I proposed this idea to them.
And they were very receptive to it.
In fact, I was told, we know for a fact that some of our assets are abductees.
So there's no question that that's.
Yeah.
A component of this.
That's wild.
And they actually conceded that, yeah, that might be why.
Yeah.
These people can kind of summon UFOs is because they're already interlaced with the phenomenon.
Yep.
And you're broadcasting and there's just an automated response.
You know, I hate to put it in such crude terms, but, you know, we're the cattle and the
drones show up.
Right.
And so I think there's something to that, but.
Well, is there, is there, but, or, I mean, that's the somewhat negative framing.
What if, you know, the Enoch goes up and, you know, or walks with God and you have, you know,
Ezekiel, maybe it's a dream like thing, but like he sort of walks with God.
There are people who believe in this sort of Kabbalistic story and they'll say Jesus in the book
of Acts going up on the cloud is an example of this and maybe they're taking liberties
and you can, you know, correct them if they're wrong.
But like, what if the craft showing up is like to commune with or take them somewhere
and show them something beautiful and then they come back down?
Well, I mean, okay, let me give you an example here and I got to go back to, and I'm going
to give you two examples.
First one is a positive encounter.
Okay.
So I have a good friend of mine and he's gone publicly, he's gone public with this.
So I'll just say his name, his name is Gary Stearman, a wonderful man, older gentleman.
And he's a, he's a, a great Bible teacher, uh, just really, really knowledgeable.
He's dedicated his life to it.
He's in his eighties now, just a phenomenal Bible teacher and a really good friend of mine.
And he told me a story one time that threw me for a loop years ago.
And this sort of got me, it sort of dislodged me from, from a, the sort of the traditional
position where you're not really thinking about UFOs in a biblical context.
This sort of, this is, as I like to say, it rearranged the theological furniture in my
brain a little bit.
He had an encounter and I'm going to get some of these details wrong, but, um, Gary's told
this story several times, including at a, uh, one of our conferences, true legend conferences
years ago.
So, but he was, I don't remember the, the, the, the, the year and, and, and, and he comes
from a family, the Stearman family, they, they're an air, an aircraft family and members of the
Stearman family have worked with Lockheed Martin and various, they've been in the programs.
Let's just say that.
And so that was the environment that Gary grew up in.
And, and so he was, he was, I'm going to try and get the details right here.
He was delivering an aircraft, um, a prop plane.
I think he was flying from, I want to say Lubbock, Texas to Dallas, I think.
I don't remember.
Um, and he was delivering this plane.
And so, uh, at the time he just wanted to be a pilot.
He wanted to just do what his family did.
And he was on this routine business, uh, situation where he's delivering this aircraft
and he gets up in the air and he's flying and he's a young guy in this context and he's
flying along.
And then suddenly the, the electrical components went out on his craft and he realized he's
in trouble, right?
He's, he's electrical components went out of his craft and he knows he's in trouble.
So I think, I forget what he did to try and manage the situation, but he knew he could,
he could have a real problem here.
And, um, I think what he was going to do is try and turn off the electrical components
and then turn them back on when he was coming closer.
So he had to land.
I don't remember, but he was in trouble and I think he was flying a Cessna.
And as he's flying along with this problem, serious problem, he looks off, I think he looks
off his left wing and he sees this shiny object flying out there in the distance.
I think he said like a mile away.
I hope I'm not butchering this story.
I'm getting the fundamentals right, but I hope I'm not butchering the details.
He sees this shiny object flying a mile away.
He thought it's just another aircraft out there.
And then, um, at, at some point he hears a voice, he hears a voice that said, and he said
it was comical.
The voice said, if you look to your left, you'll see a UFO.
And it was like, he said it was like a tour guide voice.
It was comical.
And he looks to the left again and this craft now is right close to him.
And it's a walnut shaped craft.
He got a good long look at it.
It's right off of his left wing and, and it's flying perpendicular to him.
Um, and, and it's, it's, it's just this, he said it was just this beautiful shining craft.
Just, it was just, just the way he describes it.
It had these colors emanating off of it.
And it was just the silver, you know, the typical silver craft, no rivets, no seams, you
know, the typical UFO.
And, and, and he said that, um, he, he, he couldn't see the beings inside of it, but
he felt them like he had this, he felt like this intense fraternity, like this fraternal
affection is, I think the way that he describes it, like this fraternal affection, like, like
these beings were familiar with him and were there to look out, look out for him.
Um, and, and, and that craft stayed with him and guided, like basically, um, it accompanied
him for the rest of the flight until he got to the airport and then it just hovered up
there and he landed successfully.
Now, the crazy thing is he gained, I think he gained like three hours.
Whoa.
Because he was in close proximity with this craft and he ended up arriving really late
and he didn't have the fuel for the amount of time that he was up in the air.
He didn't have the fuel and the people he was delivering the aircraft who were freaking
out on him.
And in addition, they, the, he told them there was a problem with the aircraft.
So they, they took the aircraft to the mechanic to take a look at it.
And the next day, Gary came back and was talking to the mechanic and I don't remember
what the issue was, but he should have been dead.
Like this, this, this, whatever the issue was, the mechanic said, I don't know how you
landed this. You don't, you don't land a plane like this. He should have been dead.
So, so Gary, and here's a really important facet of this story.
So when Gary took off that day in the Cessna, his trajectory on his life, in his life was
to be a pilot. By the time he landed, he knew unequivocally that he was supposed to be a
Bible teacher.
Hmm. Whoa.
So the encounter with this craft completely changed the trajectory of his life. And he
became, he, he devoted himself, uh, to learning and teaching the Bible because, because of
that encounter. So I asked Gary, well, what do you think was in that craft? Who do you
think was in that craft? Because they obviously saved his life and his answer angels were in
that craft. So, but that's a true stories. And Gary is a wonderful man. And, uh, as I
said before, excellent Bible teacher and that, that, that encounter changed his life forever.
So, um, that's why it's established in the beginning that, you know, you can't just label,
there's no, you, you, if you try and be overly simplistic with this phenomenon, you're going
to get it wrong.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's highly complex. And I always tell people embrace the complexity. If you're trying to
squeeze it into one thing, you're going to be wrong. Uh, because the universe is vast
for one thing. Um, if you're coming from a Christian perspective, you, you cannot hope
to constrain the mind of the maker that you don't even comprehend. In other words, you,
you can't say that, that God's only created X, Y, Z, and that's it. We have no idea what's
out there. We have no idea. And I don't do that. I don't restrain the mind of a being
that I cannot hope to comprehend that the mind being the maker himself. So I think that
you have a few things happening out there. You have, as I said, the beginning, you have
some of the, what we see are the, the non-human good guys, the, the, the, the faction that the
Bible describes as angels. Some of them are, are from the same faction, but the bad guys,
the, the ones that we would describe today as quote unquote fallen angels. And then you
have a host of other things in the game that maybe we have no idea what the heck they are
or where they come from.
And then the, the weirdest part of the whole phenomenon is it's often feels like it mirrors
somebody's internal state. So when they do these sort of, you know, um, sigh, you know,
attempts to call the craft, uh, I hate to use the word summoning cause that inherently sounds
kind of dark. Uh, it feels like the emotions that get amplified. It's almost like in a psychedelic
trip where if you go in with a lot of ego, you have a lot of like pain and hardship kind
of excavated and you're humbled. Like it feels like that you, you, you are. Yeah. I, the way
that these guys have described it to me is there's, there's, it's, it's actually in some
cases it's unbearable. Right. And they have to be severed. Like they can't take it. They
have, that's why there's, you know, I think, um, well, I think a lot of the legacy program,
a lot of these guys have sundowners syndrome and they literally lose their minds.
That's right. Yeah. It's, it's unbearable. So they have to be, you have to be careful
because guys can go crazy if they're, if they're, they establish a connection and whatever's
happening there is so intense that it's almost like sticking your finger in an electrical
socket, you know, at some point you're going to get fried and that they have to cut themselves
off or somebody has to sort of remove them from that state. Um, and it can be extremely
traumatizing. I know that because the guys have told me themselves, it can be extremely
traumatizing because you're, you're interfacing with number one, something we don't understand.
I think that's the first, that's how we started off this conversation. Uh, we're
interfacing with something we can't control. Yeah. We don't understand that's much smarter
than we are and probably way older. That's the baseline interaction. Those are the, those,
that's the, our baseline scenario when we interact with this stuff. So if you're, if you're
interacting, let's say psychically, psionically with this, with this phenomenon, you may, cause
they can, they can control the craft sometimes and not all these craft have anybody, have
anything inside of them. You know, some of these things are just like, uh, you know, drone for
lack of a better word. And, and because the, the mechanism is a mind machine interface, they can
actually control some of this, grab, grab hold of it, so to speak. And sometimes there's, they'll
grab hold of something and somebody else shows up to break that connection. Right. And when that
somebody else shows up, there's like this intense personality that's introduced into that
scenario. Like another intelligence is suddenly introduced in that scenario and it's overpowering.
It's, it's overpowering because their capabilities are much stronger than ours. We're like toddlers.
I always warn people, like when you interact with this stuff, it's equivalent. I think it's
an accurate analogy. It's like a two-year-old interacting with a nuclear physicist.
Right. Right. That's what it's like. We're the two-year-old. We can kind of communicate. We can,
you know, say we're hungry, we're thirsty, whatever, but we're never, ever going to outsmart
these people. Yep. We're always going to be manipulated by them. For sure. So we're always
at a disadvantage. And this is why there's a prohibition of contact in the biblical, in, in,
in the Bible. That's why divination, there's a prohibition against divination because divination
is essentially seeking information from other, let's just be very broad in our terminology here,
from other non-human intelligences aside from Yahweh, aside from God.
So how do you reconcile, because you're clearly very Christian, but you also have an intense interest
in this. So how do you reconcile your almost, you know, you think of this whole thing, it's like
this forbidden truth, you know, and it's like this, this kind of constant desire for that
with, uh, you know, your adherence to the Bible and Jesus.
Well, it's a, I wouldn't say it's forbidden. The truth of it, I wouldn't say is forbidden. I would
say that, um, I would say that it's important for Christians to have a, a very well-developed,
um, paradigm that can accommodate things without, without busting it, shattering it into a million
pieces. So an, an elastic paradigm. So the way that I approach this is I come at this entire thing
from a Christocentric perspective. So what I mean by that is traditionally, the, the traditional
Christian worldview is anthropocentric, which I call the anthropocentric perspective and birthright.
Right. And in the, from the anthropocentric perspective, and when I say traditional, I
mean the traditional Protestant, Catholic, Orthodox view, mankind is at the center of all
things. We are at the center of all things. And, and, and the earth is at the center of
all things, not necessarily the center of the universe, but like the center of everything
happening. I mean, not, not the center of the, the solar system, um, in that sense, even
though that's the way that, you know, they used to think in, uh, centuries ago, I mean,
like in terms of conceptually speaking, mankind is at the center of everything. And if you think
of it like as a, as a wheel, like a, a wagon wheel, you have the hub and then you have the
spokes from the anthropocentric perspective, mankind is the hub and everything that's happening.
The universe is revolving around him. He is the center of attention in all things. And, and
that's sort of traditionally been the view and that's, people have a hard time then
contemplating, could there be other extraterrestrial intelligences? Well, how can that be? How does
that fit into this, our, our wagon wheel here with mankind at the center and everything focusing
on mankind? Well, I don't have, that's not my perspective. In fact, I would say that's not
the biblical perspective. The biblical perspective is an anthropocentric, a rather a
Christocentric perspective of the universe. So you remove mankind from the center of that
wheel, from the hub, and you place Christ at the center, right? And you make us one of the spokes
of that wheel. Now everything revolves around him, the son of God, that Colossians 1, 15 through 17,
that I cited earlier, that, that he, he is the center of all things. All things were created
through him and for him. And he is before all things and in him, all things consist. That's the,
that's the Christocentric perspective. So he's the main character. He's the primary protagonist.
We are ancillary characters in his story. Everything with the universe itself was created for him.
So once you, once you sort of disassociate that, you disassociate the universe, the purpose of the
universe from mankind. That's an important thing. You disassociate the purpose of the universe
from mankind. We're not the purpose of the universe anymore. Christ is the purpose of the
universe. It's his story. It's his universe. Everything revolves around him. Then that opens
up a much larger, more, much more extensive cosmology because he's now at the center of this
thing. I'm a spoke in that wheel, right? Along with how many other, who knows what, we know that the
sons of God exist. We other non-human, which we went through earlier, pre-exist us. They're,
they're, they are preeminent in regard to their nature. We, mankind was created to be a little
lower than the heavenly beings. So we have non-human intelligence already in the game,
biblically speaking. They're part of the story, but the story doesn't revolve around them and it
doesn't revolve around us. It revolves around the central figure, the son, the son of God who sits at
the center of this entire thing. So when you do that, you can comfortably begin to accommodate
things into a biblical worldview and it doesn't matter anymore. Like it doesn't change, for example,
the gospel of Christ at all. If it turns out that there are, let's say, let's say that gray aliens
are from Zeta Reticuli. That doesn't do violence to my theological perspective at all. Christ is still
at the center of the universe. The gospel of Christ is still true. And people often raise the contention,
well, wait a minute, if you can, if you have extraterrestrials, doesn't that mean therefore
that Jesus would have had to go and die for all the different, uh, alien factions on the different
planets or that they all had to have their own version of Jesus? The Bible already answers that
question. And the answer is no, because it says he did not help the angels. And what that means
that the context is he didn't provide, he didn't do what he did for mankind. He didn't provide a way
of reconciliation for the angels like he did for us. And the angels are non-human intelligence who
are already in the game. These are already extraterrestrial beings. They're already in
the picture, biblically speaking. So just adding some more intelligent beings into that equation doesn't
change anything, biblically speaking.
Have you ever read C.S. Lewis's Space Trilogy?
No. And everyone is shocked when I say that.
I'm shocked.
You know, I, I grew up on the Chronicles of Narnia when I was a kid, when I was in grade school
and, um, elementary school. I grew up, I mean, I just devoured the Chronicles of Narnia. I just
read through the whole seven books and then start over at the beginning, read through them again.
And, and I never cared about, I never wanted to read the space stuff.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
But everybody always tells me, man, you got to read the, the Space Trilogy.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Well, cause I think of him as another, uh, Christian thinker who's,
you know, very, um, very impressive, like a really amazing thinker.
Very philosophical.
Very philosophical. And, uh, but then also has this cosmology and writes about this sort
of, you know, space war and it's very interesting.
Yeah.
So I feel like I'm, uh, I'm in accord with C.S. Lewis, even though I've never read any
of this.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. Okay. Uh, this is probably sacrilegious after the last 30 minutes of
conversation we just had about religion, but I need to hear this story about the Peruvian
face peelers because it's so gnarly.
Back in 2023, in the summer of 2023, specifically in the month of June and July, there were,
there were these series of videos that hit social media and just went viral. And they
featured, uh, some indigenous people out in the Peruvian Amazon who were encountering this
phenomenon. And there was something terrifying happening to them. And they were running around
at night, screaming, yelling, discharging their firearms into the jungle. And, and then in
interviews, these individuals, these various villages, but particularly this, particularly
at the center of this was this village called San Antonio de Pintuyaco. And individuals in
these videos were being interviewed and they were saying that they were being attacked by
aliens. Some said aliens, others said pelacadas, which, which translates to face peelers.
And, um, obviously something very traumatic was happening. It wasn't just happening in San
Antonio de Pintuyaco. It was happening in other villages as well. Multiple villages were being
affected. Uh, there were reports of people who were being recovered, bodies, cadavers that were
being recovered without their faces or faces partially surgically removed. And it just spread like
wildfire on social media. And it turns out that, you know, I lived in Peru for 10 years and, uh,
I cut my teeth in the Amazon. I speak the particular dialect they speak out there. They speak Spanish,
but they speak, uh, a dialect of Spanish that they call charapa, which it mixes in some Quechuan
words. And, um, that's, that's the kind of Spanish it's, it's kind of like hillbilly Spanish,
actually. So, um, and it was happening in an area of the, of the Peruvian Amazon that I'm quite
familiar with roughly in the region of Alto Nanai was a lot of this was unfolding. So people were
contacting me and I was, I was watching all of this happen on, on, uh, social media. I made a
couple of videos about it with my friend, Doug Thornton, and we were talking about the phenomenon,
just sort of tracking it. And people were sending me emails and tagging me on social media, begging
me to go to Peru. But luckily for me, I didn't have my passport at the time. I had sent my passport
away to renew it. And it sort of gave me an out cause I really didn't feel like going. Cause I
had to, I was actually, uh, had planned a trip with my son, my oldest son to Guatemala. And I didn't,
I was not going to sacrifice that trip with my son. So, um, I didn't really want to travel before
that. And, and I, I honestly didn't just didn't want to go and people were begging me to go. You
need to go up there. Nobody was going. I kept waiting for somebody to go. Nobody was going. Um,
there were some interviews with some of the, uh, villagers in the city of Iquitos, but nobody
went to the village except two, uh, provincial policemen with a Navy escort. They went to the
village because the villagers were begging the Navy to come protect them. They were begging the Navy.
They were making these videos where they're all holding signs that say, we're under attack.
Please help us. Uh, they were begging the Navy. These people were clearly not just from San Antonio
Pinto Iaco, various villages in the region, right? Alto Nanay, generally speaking. And so these
policemen went there, um, and did a, what I describe as a piss poor investigation. And they
interviewed some of the people, some of the villagers, they interviewed a 15 year old girl
named Talia who had been, there was an attempted abduction of Talia. And they, they concluded,
these police officers concluded, not based on the testimony of the villagers. Okay. They concluded
that the villagers were being assaulted by river miners with jet pack technology. Now, if you know
anything about river miners and you've spent time in the Amazon jungle, you know, that that narrative
is absurd. Case closed. It's absurd. And everybody ran with it. The Peruvian media was all over this
thing. Took it very seriously until the jet pack minor narrative went out. And then everybody bought
it hook, line and sinker. Everybody, the Peruvian press, the American press. I even watched a segment
on News Nation where they were like choking around like, Oh, those pesky miners with jet packs. Like,
it's those guys. Obviously they're trying to drive the villagers off their land. And it was absurd.
Who owns jet packs, let alone miners? Okay. It was absurd. That's absurd. I, I,
none of these people who are saying this had ever encountered a Peruvian river miner. I have. And
they don't, they don't, they certainly don't have jet packs. They're not Tony Stark. They're,
no, they dump a bunch of mercury in the water, kill everything and then drudge the bottom on these,
on these, on these rusted out boats that can barely, you know, move. And, and, uh, they don't have any
money and the whole thing was absurd. It was absurd. So at that point I thought, okay,
I gotta go. Cause this, this is bull crap. It's not jet pack miners. So my, my passport came back
and I didn't have any more excuses. So I said, all right, I'm going to, I had a little window of
time, like a week before, right up against my, my Guatemala trip with my son. Uh, and so I tagged my
friend, Doug Thornton asked him if he'd go with me. And Doug is a, was an infantry Marine and a,
a DHS, uh, a special operator. So, um, uh, Doug is a great guy to go with. And so, uh, I organized
this, this expedition. I, uh, I chartered a riverboat and I made contact with the village first. And I want
to thank, um, the ufologist, Ronnie Vernet, the Brazilian ufologist. He put me in contact with the
village. And, uh, in fact, with the kid that had the young man that had filmed some of these,
the footage that went viral, his name was Christian. He was the school teacher. And I got in contact with
Christian and Christian and I began a dialogue. And, and, uh, what I did was he wanted me to record
a message, uh, on, uh, WhatsApp in regard to my intentions. I want to come to this investigation.
And, and, and he played that recording to the Apu, the chief of the village and his elders.
And then in response, I got an official invitation to go from the Apu. And, uh, I was told that,
uh, I was told that the villagers were in dire straits, that, uh, if there was any way I could
help, that would be great. Also, like I'm, I'm free to come and do whatever investigation I want,
but also, you know, they're, they're running out of medicine and stuff like that. So, uh, I contacted
some associates of mine, specifically some of the men from Conduit Church, some of these awesome dudes
over there who, who, who wanted to help me fund this thing because I wanted to, I now wanted to
sort of go on an, uh, um, an aid mission too, to, to restock, resupply them medical supplies and
stuff. And we did. So we went to San Antonio de Pinto Yaku on this chartered riverboat. By the way,
all of this is in a YouTube video on my YouTube channel. And we, we brought supplies, the Apu and
some of the guys from the village met us in Iquitos and went up, like escorted us up the river.
It took a couple of days to get up the river. Um, you go up the Alto Nanai and then you go up the,
you go up the Nanai river and then you go up the Pinto Yaku from there. And when I arrived to the
village, I was, I'd been in a lot of these villages, you know, Peru. And this is the first time I was
greeted by, you know, a small army of men with loaded shotguns. And they were there
cheerfully receiving us, but they were armed, right? All of them were armed. And this is how
they were always, since the incursions had been happening, they were doing patrols. The men were
not sleeping at night. They were, they were sleeping during the day and then patrolling at night.
And, uh, they hadn't been going out to their farms and, and, and they, they were, it was just,
um, they were traumatized. So we unloaded all the, all of the, uh, provisions that we brought
them. We also brought them in addition to food and medical supplies. We brought them, um, some
technology. We brought them some night vision goggles with recording capabilities so that they
could see and record the phenomenon. We brought them a thermal binoculars. We brought them, um,
high powered flashlights and we brought them really good radios so that, you know, so that they could
better protect their village. And, uh, and I also went with, um, I hired a couple of, uh, active duty
Navy jungle commandos to go with me, uh, proving guys. And so, um, we disembarked and, and were greeted
by these villagers and they, they brought me into their tambo, which is their, like their meeting
place. Government have built, have built this thing there. This was San Antonio Pinto Yakuza. It's the
Kitu people. And they're a very old, uh, community, the very old, one of the oldest communities in the
region. And this is sort of one of their last outposts. And this is one of the last, it is
like the last outpost of civilization before just a vast untracked wilderness, Amazon jungle.
So the government had put a, uh, communications outpost there, which means the villagers had
internet. So they had satellite internet. So these, when I say villagers, they're not people like in,
you know, grass skirts with blow, with blow guns. They're, they're more modernized villagers and
they all have cell phones. You know, they watch Marvel movies and stuff sitting in the tambo at
night. So, um, they received us, uh, uh, very, um, enthusiastically. They did a traditional
Ikitu dance for us. It was really cool. Um, and then we began our investigation in earnest. And,
um, I started to go around with the Apu, the chief, to go to the different areas where they had
encountered the phenomenon and to interview people. And, um, I'm trying to encapsulate this.
So the first thing I, I came to understand was a lot of people in the village had encountered this
phenomenon. It wasn't like one or two people. A lot of them had seen the phenomenon and they were all,
many of them were traumatized. So like a lot of PTSD and basically what they were encountering was
the way that these incursions would begin was it'd be nighttime, always at nighttime, always after
dark. And they would see like two mini flying saucers hovering in the air, right? Just these
little saucers with a series of lights around the bottom. And that's how they knew the incursion was
about to happen. And then these two little saucers would go fly into the jungle and then land. And
then shortly thereafter, they would see two individuals sneaking into the village. And these
individuals would be dressed head to foot in black armored bodysuits with helmets. They were
described as very much like the green goblin from the Spider-Man movie. Yeah. With the, with the,
you know, because he had that helmet, but he had like kind of the almond shaped eyes with the yellow
almond shaped eyes. And he uses the, the craft. He flies on the craft. Yeah. Yeah. So that's how,
what they were saying. It's like the green goblin, but without like the big, you know, grin on the
helmet. They would stand on the craft. Yeah. Yeah. And so what the little flying saucer
things that they saw turned out to be circular hoverboards. And, and these guys were dressed in
black armor bodysuits and their eyes, they had these almond shaped tinted eye lenses on their
helmets. Some said yellow, some said green, night vision. I don't know. And, uh, and they were very
tall. Everyone said they were taller than me. I'm six one. And some people I would go like,
this tall, this tall. Some people were like this tall, like, you know, seven, seven, seven and a
half, eight feet tall or whatever. Um, so, uh, basically, you know, calculating some exaggeration
in there, you know, they were probably six and a half, seven feet tall, conservatively based on
what the villagers told me. So, um, the, these individuals, uh, they shot some of them at point blank
range with shotguns, 16 gauge, uh, birdshot. It had no effect. They were literally here,
the BBs dinking off of their armor. And when one guy said he was confronted, one of these guys
confronted him while he confronted one of these assailants at night. And this particular guy was
dressed in a silver suit and he was so adamant. He's like, I know all the other people are saying
black, but what I saw, the guy was silver head to foot. And he said, I shot him at point blank
range with a shotgun. And in the blast, the shotgun, he could hear the, the, the BBs dink
off the armor and it knocked the guy back on his butt. And by the way, when he shot him,
the guy was hovering, not on a hoverboard, just off of his boots. They had these two circular
discs on the bottom of their boots that emitted a light and they could hover. So he was floating.
He said he was floating about a meter off the ground. I shot him. He fell back on his back
from the blast and then pop right back up and just like zoomed away. Um, a lot of the villagers
saw these guys. So a handful of them shot at them. Uh, one of the villagers said that he, he saw
a larger disc hovering in the sky. He put his flashlight on it and he saw two guys, the silhouettes
of two of these armored guys together, both of them on one of, on one circular disc. Uh, so sometimes
there was this one guy and they're like surfing on them. And, um, and so in addition to the,
to the black armored body suits, these assailants, uh, that, that technology and the hoverboard
technology, it's clear that there was also advanced aerospace vehicles involved because more than a
few villagers, one guy drew it on an acrylic chalkboard for me, saw an almond shape, uh, rather
a acorn shaped craft, but like prone, like on its side. Wow. And they all just, they all drew the
same thing. They all drew it for me. Uh, all the ones who told me about this, they drew it in the
dirt for me, or I had them draw it in the dirt for me, or I, or the one guy drew it on the acrylic
chalkboard. And I've got that on film. They all drew the same thing. And some of them saw close
encounter, like, like 40 feet in the air above their hut. Some people describe it as matte black
hovering silently, no propellers, no propulsion. Remember these people are watching all the same
movies we are on their phones. They know what airplanes are. They know what helicopters are.
These aren't like primitive, like I said, uh, natives. And one guy said, the guy who drew it on
the acrylic chalkboard said that he was pulling up his nets at night. And as he was doing that,
it was like, he says, like somebody turned the lights on or the sun suddenly came up
and he looks up and 30, 40 feet above him is one of these craft almond shape. Um, I keep saying
almond shape, acorn shape craft. And he said, but this one was translucent. It was like, it had a mesh,
a transparent mesh. He could see the mesh, like looking through a screen door and he saw
two guys inside of it, two people or beings or something inside of it. One in the front,
one in like the belly of it. And it projected a light down on him and it, and it had these little
stubby protrusions and they opened up and there was like a series of blinking lights and then they
folded back in and it's, and it started to move off. And he said, when it started to move off,
there was sort of a low frequency hum. So you have, not only you have these armored assailants
on these hoverboards, you have advanced aerospace vehicles, um, unconventional technology being
deployed in the Amazon, Peru, the, uh, Alto, Alto Nanai region, various different villages. Now,
well, why are they called face peelers? Uh, because, because the, the, the indigenous people,
if you ask them who these assailants are, half of them will say they're aliens. Half of them will
say they're face peelers. And what they mean by face peelers is there's, is the, the, the, the face,
face peeler legend goes back to the eighties, like the mid eighties. And it, it doesn't go further
than that. Um, and they say that these, they call them gringos started showing up with technology
and it's sort of like the boogeyman, the, the, the, the wives, I mean, the mothers and fathers
would tell their children, don't go out at night. The face peeler will get you because every now and
again, there'd be an attack by face peelers and the, the cadaver of the person would go missing.
And then they would show up later without a piece of their face gone or their whole face.
And sometimes their organs harvested. Um, so some villagers think these are gringos like CIA,
you know, whatever that's, you know, everything CIA to people out there. So, um, they probably
thought I was CIA, but, um, so, uh, there, there was the, the most important incident happened with
this, one of the most important incidents with this 15 year old girl named Talia. She was almost
abducted. That's why the, the police went out there. They had to go out there because there was
an attempted abduction, uh, kidnapping. So they had to go investigate. So, um, we interviewed Talia.
I, I, the first time I saw her, she was in the village, in the middle of the village, uh, during
the evening, everybody was out, you know, all the men were playing soccer, the women were playing
volleyball and she was sitting by herself against a wall. The Apu pointed her out to us and me and Doug
just were sort of, we didn't really want to approach her. We didn't want to freak her out. And she's just
sitting there kind of smiling, watching the, the people play, you know, volleyball and soccer,
just sort of sitting by herself, smiling. She looked over, she saw us and instantly she,
she started to tremble. She just started trembling and she froze up and she's just freaked out. And
she took her hair, she had long hair, she took it and moved it over to the side of her face. So we
couldn't see her face. And she just sat there trembling. And, and the Apu brought her father over
and we said, Hey, we'd love to interview Talia, but obviously she's very scared. So he went over
to her, tried to convince her to talk to us. She did not want anything to do with us. She associated
us with her assailants. But, um, the father told us, Hey, here's where I live. Come back over
tomorrow morning. I'll talk to her. You guys just come and I'll bring her out to you.
Um, and so that's what we did the next morning. Long story short, um, we were standing in, in,
in this guy's backyard. He brought Talia out to us to talk to her. And as soon as she saw,
she started trembling again and crying, severe PTSD. And she had a scar right here. And, uh, so we,
I interviewed Talia and she told me a wild story. I mean, um, I didn't really have the time to tell
it right now, but she, there was an attempted kidnapping of her by these assailants one evening.
And there's a lot of details that goes into this, but they, they, they captured her in her backyard.
They, on, they landed on hoverboards. That's how it began. She, she, she, she was poking at a piece
of fruit in the evening, just before, just after sundown or as it's getting dark, the fruit hit the
ground. She bent over to pick it up and she felt this gust of wind. And she looks over and it's one
of these guys, assailants, head to foot and black armored body suits, right? It just, it's just, it's
one guy he's surfing on this hoverboard and they all go like this when they tell me they're like
surfing. And the guy comes, there's a little golly. He comes up the hill hovering and lands the board
right behind her and grabs her from the behind, from behind, grabs her mouth and grabs her. And
then another guy, same thing, comes surfing up the, from the golly, lands in front of her, grabs her
feet. And then they both lift her off the ground. And she said, when they, when they, after they
landed, they reached down and touch something on their boot to engage the technology, lift it off
the ground. And then they hovered her, carried her behind this chicken coop, this thatched roof chicken
coop. And there proceeded to, without going to all the details, to attempt to cut her face off.
They took out what, what we think was a, like a laser scalpel. And they began at first, they put
some cream on her face, which numbed her face. First, they shot something up her nose with a syringe
and she became disoriented. And then they put cream on her face and took out this late, what we think is
a laser scalpel and began to make the incision. And in fact, she heard them speaking. One, one of them
she referred to as the gringo because he sounded like me, she said, and the other one sounded like
a Peruvian. So, and when they're getting ready to do this, they're putting the cream on her face
before they start making the incision. One of them said to the other, be careful, be careful. Don't
put too much on her face. It'll ruin the flesh. And she said that what, what she thought they meant
was it was, she heard them saying something about how it makes it difficult to separate the,
the skin from the, you know, from the flesh beneath it. Um, so then they proceeded to make the incision
and she started just one last effort to, to, to break loose. She started to push up the helmet
on the guy behind her and he let go of her to pull his helmet down. He didn't want her to see him.
And when he let go of her, she screamed and everyone in the village was already in a state
of vigilance. This wasn't the first incursion. So they're all sitting on their porches at night
with their guns and their flashlights, getting ready to start doing patrols. So when she screamed,
they were on scene, her brother and, and, and people who lived near her were on scene within,
you know, very short order. And they saw Talia laying on the ground in a state of disorientation
and the two assailants, they were dragging her by the hair actually at first. And they were trying
to lift her off the ground to take her by her hair. And the one guy said, you know, let her go. We,
we can't take her or something like that. And they dropped her. And then the other people came on the
scene. Talia remembered that part that she was being pulled by her hair. And then when the others.
And you show in your video, the laser incision and it's crazy.
So when the other villagers arrive, uh, they see the assailants hovering on the, on the discs
and they got their flashlights on them and they went right up through the canopy.
Wow.
And I could tell you many other such incidents.
So what, what does this have to do with Michael Herrera? Who's this UFO whistleblower?
Well, very, very, very quickly.
Indonesia.
Okay.
So very, very quickly, um, I need to make sure people understand these incursions didn't just
happen in remote villages in the jungle. They also happened in the city of Nauta. 36,000
inhabitants, hardened target with the Navy presence, Peruvian Navy presence, militaries,
helicopters. Okay. It's not miners with jetpacks trying to drive people off of the land so they
could mine the water, the river. That's not what this phenomenon is. The fact that the incursions
were happening in Nauta absolutely, uh, debunks that, that narrative. So the Michael Herrera
thing, I think what we're looking at is, and, um, and Michael's a friend of mine and, uh,
he, uh, had a, as everyone knows, I won't, I won't retrace his story, but, um, he encountered
a disc, a large disc in Indonesia.
Yeah. It was an eight gone craft that was blacker than black. And he was apprehended by
these people that weren't special forces, but had super advanced technology, some paramilitary
group. And they were, they seemed to be escorting these psionic assets on board this like alien
reproduction, like this exotic manned craft. They were engaging in human trafficking.
That's what it seems like. Very simple terms. Exactly.
So, so the, the connection there is nefarious people, paramilitary organizations with advanced
aerospace craft, using it for the most, for the most abominable things imaginable, including,
uh, including, um, human trafficking for whatever purposes, harvesting psionic assets, which they
do. In this case, peeling flesh off it. In this case, peeling flesh, but I think they were using
the pace, the face peeler phenomenon as a cover. For what? Something else that was going on. And very,
very quickly, there was an operation happening, a joint operation happening in Peru that had some
crossover when, when these incursions were happening in the jungle. It was called Resolute Sentinel.
And it involved, it involved, uh, basically every military agency we have. The Marines were there
in Peru, the Air Force, the Navy. That's not a coincidence. The, the Space Force was there,
the Coast Guard, uh, and they were running joint operations, training operations with the Peruvian
military, uh, Uruguay, uh, I think Ecuador, Brazil, the UK was involved. It was like...
So what would the face peeling be a distraction from?
I don't know. But, you know, I always wonder if, if that, if that Resolute Sentinel was a cover.
Wow.
Either, uh, I'd like to think it's, it was a cover for some sort of, um, benevolent operation
happening to try and drive these guys out or capture them or something. I don't know.
I hate to think it was, I hate to think that we were experimenting with something out there.
I mean, that would be awful.
I, I hate to think that and I don't want to think that, but, um, or is there some sort of, um,
third party in possession of some subcontracting, uh, apparatus underneath these, uh, aerospace
contractors who've maybe have gone rogue?
Some nefarious global breakaway.
Exactly.
Yeah.
Is that what we're looking at here?
On that sinister note.
And there's a whole lot more to be said of this. We're out of time.
Yeah.
Look at my video on YouTube, the face people.
Yeah. Well, we'll, we'll, we'll cut parts of it in and, but this was amazing, Timothy. I really
appreciate your time, man. This was a blast and, uh, love the way you think. And, uh, we got to run
it back because we, I think we just did like four hours and 45 minutes or something like that.
Yeah.
So, man, it was my pleasure. You do just amazing work and, um, just keep going.
Oh, thanks, man.
You're awesome.
Likewise. Let me get you to the airport.
Let's get out of here.
We'll be right back.