What do you call it when a retired Air Force general, one who once ran the most notorious
lab in UFO history, vanishes from his house in broad daylight?
The general was involved with the Pentagon's most advanced aerospace research.
When the NASA material scientist behind a breakthrough rocket engine alloy disappears
30 feet from her friend on a hike.
She was right behind them, 30 feet behind them, and then she disappeared.
And one of MIT's top plasma physicists is gunned down outside his own front door.
This many top scientists getting killed or going missing in just under a year looks like
a major red flag.
Who were the first people the Israelis killed in Iran when they went in?
The first thing you do is kill your scientists.
It's the kind of thing that sounds like the Chinese science fiction book, The Three-Body
Problem.
A world where scientists don't just make discoveries, but become the front line of a war they don't
even know they're in.
A world where the future rests on some of the most important minds on Earth.
And those minds start disappearing.
Except here, the names and the people behind them are real.
Cassius went missing after taking lunch to her teenage daughter at a cafe in Taos Plaza.
Some of them were very important people, and we're going to look at it over the next session.
What we're looking at might not just be geopolitics in the dark or pressure coming from nation states,
but from an unseen force shaping our timeline from somewhere above it, and a hidden struggle
over who gets to control humanity's next leap.
Or maybe none of these cases are connected.
It's really sensitive stuff, and I'm not a big believer in coincidences.
So tonight we're following the trail through missing scientists, murdered physicists, defense
world gatekeepers, in this strange shadowland that forms wherever advanced knowledge becomes
too dangerous to leave walking around.
There's a state that researchers called hypnagogia, that threshold between waking and sleep where
the brain is doing something genuinely unusual.
The kind of thing that comes up in remote viewing accounts or other out-of-body experiences.
And honestly, some of the most fascinating conversations I've had on this show.
Since moving to Austin, sleep is something I've thought about a lot more, mostly because
I'm not really doing it.
That is, until recently.
I used to sleep on whatever mattress I'd had for years, and it was clearly not helping me
get the sleep I need.
Then I did a comprehensive search, and I learned that most mattresses are kind of lame.
And a total insomniac friend of mine told me that he tried Helix, and it fixed all of his
issues.
Helix is the mattress of the future.
They have a sleep quiz that matches you to the right mattress based on your sleep position,
your body type, and whether you sleep hot or cold.
I got matched with the Helix Midnight.
It has a cooling cover which I know is going to matter a lot in these extremely hot Austin
summer days.
When I started using it, the change hit immediately.
I'm waking up feeling like I actually recovered overnight.
For someone who does four- and five-hour interviews, sleep is maybe the most important thing for
me to dial in.
Ask any health or biohacking expert, and it's the number one thing that impacts the rest of
your life.
Helix has 20-plus mattresses, free shipping, a 120-night trial, and a lifetime warranty.
And Helix's Midnight Luxe was ranked best overall mattress by both Forbes and Wired.
Thank you so much to Helix Sleep for sponsoring today's episode.
Visit helixsleep.com slash jessemichaels to take advantage of their spring savings event
and get 20% off site-wide, and 20% is a lot when it comes to mattresses.
Again, that's helixsleep.com slash jessemichaels, michaels with no A.
The trail begins in Albuquerque, New Mexico, in the shadow of Sandia Mountains.
It's February 27th, 2026, a late Friday morning on Quail Run Court.
Neil McCaslin, a 68-year-old retired Air Force general, is at home in a quiet neighborhood
at the edge of the Cibola National Forest.
A repairman sees him at the house around 10 a.m.
Then, about an hour later, around 11.10 a.m., his wife leaves for a medical appointment.
At 12.04, barely an hour after that, she's back home.
But her husband is gone.
Left behind are his prescription glasses, his phone, which had been switched off, and his
smartwatch.
All the things that would make him trackable in the 21st century.
But what's missing is a red backpack, his wallet, and a .38 caliber revolver with its
holster.
Not the best combination.
At 3.07, his wife Susan reports him missing, and the official police investigation begins.
In a newly released 911 call, she tells the dispatcher he's been gone for about three hours.
I have some indication that he must have planned not to be found.
She said he changed his clothes, and appears to be on foot, since none of their cars or bikes
were missing.
She also tells dispatch that he's been dealing with some medical issues, and that both of
them were seeing a doctor for anxiety, lack of sleep, and short-term memory problems.
In fact, it was the same doctor she had seen earlier that day.
But Susan chalked the health issues up to garden-variety things that you face in old age.
She never thought that Neil would actually act in a way to harm himself.
Saying if his brain and body keeps deteriorating, he didn't want to live like that.
But it seemed to me that was just a, man, I hate how this is going kind of thing.
A comment like that would naturally raise concerns about self-harm.
But whether that was a real risk or just a throwaway comment on an off day, we don't
actually know.
When the police asked about the weapons, she said that her husband had a gun safe with
multiple pistols and rifles, but at that moment, couldn't tell whether anything was actually
missing.
Although now we know that one of his .38 calibers was, in fact, gone.
The next day, a silver alert goes out.
This is the kind of statewide alert issued when authorities think a missing person might be
disoriented or cognitively impaired.
New Mexico state statute doesn't require any kind of formal diagnosis.
Given what Susan had already told the police, that was enough to trigger it.
But even with those reported issues, McCaslin still doesn't fit the profile of a man who
just wandered into a canyon.
Investigators say he's still highly intelligent and capable.
Friends say that the week before he disappeared, McCaslin cycled 60 miles.
He hiked those very foothills.
He biked them.
He knew every trail.
This wasn't a man losing his bearings, but the kind of guy who could out-ski most millennials.
This was also a town he knew by heart.
McCaslin once commanded the Phillips Research Site at Kirtland, an Air Force base notorious
for hosting advanced weapons research right nearby.
He wasn't a stranger to this place.
It was basically his backyard.
His wife would also issue another statement, saying McCaslin had some risk, but not from dementia.
He was not confused and disoriented.
But a clear head didn't make him any easier to find.
The Bernalillo County Sheriff's Office said that they had surveillance footage from both
ends of his street and still couldn't confirm his direction of travel.
They made public appeals for doorbell cameras, dashcams, GoPros, anything.
If you have any information where McCaslin may be, contact BCSO's Missing Persons Unit.
Within the span of a week, the search expanded from the Sheriff's Office to the FBI's Albuquerque
Field Office to the Air Force Office of Special Investigations, New Mexico State Search and
Rescue, Albuquerque Mountain Rescue, horseback teams, three types of search dogs, drones, helicopters,
and neighborhood canvassing.
And despite living in an era with enough cameras to catch almost every delivery on the block
in which he lived, no footage of him ever surfaced.
Police accessed his electronic devices and searched his usual hiking spots, like the
Elenic Lagos area into the Domingo Baca Canyon.
But there was still no trace of him.
After weeks, all they could find was a gray Air Force sweatshirt a mile east of his house.
And even after testing it, they couldn't confirm it was McCaslin's.
So we're talking about a regimented, physically active military vet who vanished from his house
without leaving a single digital or physical fingerprint behind.
That alone is strange.
But it gets stranger once you understand who McCaslin actually was and the world he came
out of.
General McCaslin, his disappearance was discussed.
UAPs were discussed.
So I don't think this story is going away, Jesse.
This was a man who spent his career deep in the black world of American defense.
When you read his official Air Force biography, you realize he had access to things that the
rest of us aren't even supposed to know exist.
The foundation for that kind of clearance started when he graduated from the Air Force
Academy, earned a Ph.D. in Astronautical Engineering from MIT on a Hertz Foundation Fellowship, and
later studied at Harvard's Kennedy School.
He went on to lead the Space-Based Laser Project Office, served as vice commander of the Space
and Missile Systems Center, was the Materiel Wing Director at the Air Force Research Lab's Space
Vehicles Directorate at Kirtland, and spent part of his career in the National Reconnaissance
Office, the world of black, off-the-record satellites.
His career spanned everything from directed energy, to space weapons, to nuclear oversight.
You probably get the point.
This was a man who could out-credential most presidents, and probably had more access than
them, too.
And there are two jobs on his resume that matter more than the rest.
From June 2009 to May 2011, McCaslin served as Director of Special Programs at the Pentagon,
in the Office of the Undersecretary of Defense for Acquisitions, Technology, and Logistics.
The title is a mouthful, but according to the official Pentagon training documentation,
that office oversees acquisition special access programs.
These programs are the ultimate category of secret black projects.
In fact, they account for about 75 to 80 percent of all special access programs in the Department
of War.
These are the programs built to protect the crown jewels.
Extremely sensitive research in the process of building something, like a next-generation
weapons system, or a craft that doesn't officially exist.
This is where sensitive technology moves from theory, to prototype, to something that the
military can actually fly.
And if you're wondering where UFO reverse engineering programs would possibly hide, this
is the place.
In the classified world, McCaslin's office was the motherlode.
His Wikipedia page goes a step further, claiming that the role made him Executive Secretary of
the Special Access Program Oversight Committee, the body that reviews and approves every single
special access program in the Pentagon.
But that's not even the most interesting job on his resume.
From 2011 to 2013, McCaslin commanded the Air Force Research Lab, AFRL, at Wright-Patterson
Air Force Base, overseeing a $2.2 billion science and technology portfolio, one of the largest
research operations in the entire Pentagon.
advanced material science, future weapons, and of course, exotic propulsion.
And if you're familiar with UFO lore, you also know that Wright-Patterson isn't just
famous for Project Blue Book.
It's the alleged home of the Roswell crash debris.
I called Curtis LeMay and I said, General, I know we have a room at Wright-Patterson where
you put all this secret stuff.
Could I go in there?
I've never heard him get mad, but he got madder than hell of me.
Depending on who you believe, this place houses some of the most exotic materials in the history
of the U.S. government.
It's the place where they get studied, stored, reverse-engineered, and obsessively hidden from
public view.
That's not even a conspiracy.
This is the place during World War II where the U.S. would reverse-engineer advanced Nazi
tech.
And General Neil McCaslin ran the entire thing.
But what really put him on the radar of UFO world is that his name showed up somewhere
no one expected.
In 2016, WikiLeaks published the hacked emails of John Podesta, Hillary Clinton's campaign
chairman and one of the most powerful political operatives in Washington.
Buried in that email dump is an email from Tom DeLonge to Podesta.
The subject line, General McCaslin.
DeLonge writes,
He mentioned he's a skeptic.
He's not.
I've been working with him for four months.
I've just got done giving him a four-hour presentation on the entire project a few weeks ago.
He tells Podesta that McCaslin just has to say that out loud.
Because he is very, very aware.
Because he was the man in charge of all of this stuff.
When Roswell crashed, they shipped it to the laboratory at Wright-Patterson Air Force
Base.
General McCaslin was in charge of that exact laboratory up to a couple years ago.
He not only knows what I'm trying to achieve, he helped assemble my advisory team.
He's a very important man.
DeLonge was after UFO disclosure for the American people.
That's the whole point of To the Stars Academy.
General McCaslin being involved in those early efforts is a big deal.
Some people try to dismiss Tom DeLonge and say that he was never in touch with Neil McCaslin.
After all, these leaked emails were never publicly confirmed.
But even his wife Susan would come to acknowledge that McCaslin was caught up in the Russian hack
and had less contact with Tom after the emails were released.
Key word here, less, not zero.
And she's implicitly admitting that they were in close contact previously.
In fact, in that same email batch that leaked, a calendar notification shows that Susan herself
accepted a Google Calendar invite for something called a DeLonge-Podesta meeting.
So at minimum, McCaslin and his wife were in the room for conversations about UFO disclosure.
We're not talking about a 4chan thread here.
We're talking about Podesta's actual inbox.
And as for Susan McCaslin, she has a quite impressive background herself.
She's a PhD astrophysicist, a colonel in the Air Force Reserve.
She was a NASA astronaut semifinalist and had stints at both Boeing and Raytheon.
She might even have her own clearance history.
After McCaslin disappeared, she told the press that he only held commonly held clearances since
retirement.
Maybe.
But a man who spent his career this deep in the black world likely saw the full portfolio.
And you don't really unsee that.
Susan later made a statement on Facebook.
She wrote,
Neil does not have any special knowledge about the ET bodies and debris from the Roswell
crash stored at Wright-Patt.
Though at this point, with absolutely no sign of him, maybe the best hypothesis is that aliens
beamed him up to the mothership.
However, no sightings of a mothership hovering above the Sandia Mountains have been reported.
Maybe this is just a woman holding it together with dark humor while the internet tears her
life apart.
But it's undeniable that the phrasing is odd.
She doesn't say Roswell material doesn't exist at Wright-Patterson.
She just says McCaslin doesn't have any special knowledge about it.
An event that, mind you, has been reported on ad nauseum in the open source world.
So she might just be saying,
there's nothing that Neil McCaslin knows about Roswell that you, the public, don't already
know.
Now look, any reasonable person should be hesitant to parse or speculate on the words
of a grieving wife.
And Susan and Neil deserve all of our thoughts and prayers.
But also, to any reasonable person, these words almost feel like a cipher to decode, an
invitation to speculate, just a little bit.
And the statement ended up provoking just that.
They spurred a lot of public speculation.
If anything, the internet theorizing went into overdrive.
I do think that there are secrets that obviously will not be released because we have technologies
that other nations don't.
and just see the superiority of our forces right now with Iran.
Had McCaslin been quietly folded into some continuity of government program or taken into
protective custody in preparation for the war with Iran?
Had he been taken by a foreign adversary that understood exactly how valuable he was?
People in UFO world associate McCaslin with the Majestic 12, an elite and top secret presidential
advisory panel dating back to Truman and Eisenhower that deals with the UFO topic.
There are a lot of reasonable questions as to whether this Majestic 12 committee ever really existed.
But perhaps the person deepest on the UFO truth, at least from the government perspective
that we know about over the last 70 years, is a guy named Colonel John Alexander.
And at one point, he admitted that the Majestic 12 was basically just a cover for continuity
of government programs.
People in the military-industrial complex, where if the president and his direct cabinet
were incapacitated, they would take over.
To be honest, McCaslin sounds like he squarely fits that profile.
Theories around his disappearance kept multiplying.
And the timing of all of this didn't help either.
Are aliens real?
Uh, they're real, but I haven't seen them.
In the summer of 2025, the mainstream Italian magazine, Let Espresso, published an article
from a confidential source.
It claimed that President Trump was wrestling control of special access programs away from
the Pentagon and under the command of the White House, a move that supposedly sparked tensions
between military leaders and some of the president's advisors.
The article goes on to mention Project Preserve Destiny, a program involving communications
with non-human intelligence housed under the National Security Agency, or NSA.
The program involves some of the most bizarre protocols and has some of the most profound
implications of anything we've ever covered on this show.
Just listen to the experience of Air Force Sergeant Dan Sherman.
This is what he was told the program was about.
The genesis of it was in 1947, we came in contact with an alien species, and in 1960, they
started a project, it was called Project Preserve Destiny, and it was designed to genetically manage
fetuses, human fetuses, so that they would have the heightened ability to do this particular
thing that I was going to school for.
My mother was one of the selected targets, or whatever you want to call it.
And on the night of February 19th, 2026, Trump announced on Truth Social that he was directing
the Pentagon and other agencies to begin identifying and releasing government files related to aliens
and the UAP phenomena.
Trump is always shooting from the hip.
You don't really get the sense that that post was planned.
And you have to think, if a UFO legacy program does in fact exist, they were thinking deeply
about their most important personnel.
Eight days after that announcement, McCaslin vanished from his neighborhood.
I'm not going to pretend I know what this means, and I'm not saying that Trump's announcement
is the reason he disappeared.
But the timing is a data point.
There could be a few reasons why that timing is important.
Neil McCaslin, I mean, you have to wonder the timing.
President Trump saying, you know, I'm going to release these files, and then six days later,
Neil McCaslin goes missing.
If McCaslin was involved in these programs and felt he could be implicated in any way,
the release of these UFO files could have been a pressure point.
Maybe enough to make him crack and disappear into the wilderness.
This also could have explained the deep anxiety leading up to that moment.
Maybe the intense hiking and biking was to relieve stress.
What many online are saying is the most simple explanation for McCaslin's disappearance is
that he walked into the Sandia foothills with his gun, and that whatever was in his head
after a lifetime near the most secretive programs in the country simply became too much to carry,
a burden too great to bear.
The fact that he changed his clothes before leaving, making it harder to identify what
he was wearing, adds to that theory.
But after weeks of searching terrain that experienced teams covered repeatedly, they haven't found
a body.
So the opposite could also be true.
This was a man who was already involved with early disclosure efforts.
McCaslin wasn't hiding from transparency.
If anything, he was working toward it.
And that makes him quite dangerous and a liability to the people who don't want disclosure.
To them, this is the last person you'd ever want to put on the witness stand.
He was a man who saw behind the curtain and knew exactly what was hanging there.
Harvard lawyer and civil rights activist Danny Sheehan, the constitutional lawyer behind the
Pentagon Papers, recently went on the Third Eye Drops podcast with my buddy Michael Phillip
and described what he calls the association.
There has arisen an insurgency group that have occupied extremely high positions in the Defense
Department, inside the Central Intelligence Agency, inside some of the private aerospace corporations,
and inside the military services, okay?
And I happen to know who they are, okay?
And what they've done is they've formed an association.
And they're working to try to drag the program back into the government.
This is a covert circle of 24 retired high-ranking officials from the DOD, CIA, and private aerospace.
A secret brain trust quietly working to drag classified UAP programs back into the light
of government oversight and towards transparency.
They're all retired.
And they all took their Rolodexes and credibility with them.
So did McCaslin have his own little black book?
Was he one of those 24?
We don't actually know.
But he does fit the profile.
Retired, credentialed, connected, and sympathetic to disclosure.
And I've got their names too here.
Wow.
Right here.
Are those names private?
They're not public at all.
Okay.
They're not public at all, but there's 24 of them.
After McCaslin hung up his uniform in 2013, his wife described him as a man winding down,
hiking the foothills, enjoying a quiet life in the desert.
Technically, that's all true.
Dialbud power for 24 hours.
End of day comes our shower.
But that's not the full story.
In fact, after leaving his post in government, he's listed as a founder of DBE Consulting,
a New Mexico national security consulting firm tied to James Tegnellia, the former deputy
director of DARPA and the director of the Defense Threat Reduction Agency.
This agency, also known as DITRA for short, is the Pentagon's agency for countering weapons
of mass destruction.
But it also might have a thing or two to do with UFOs.
The person in charge of collecting all of the information from DITRA dealing with extraterrestrials
and, as he put it, quote unquote, little green men, happened to sit next to me at my computer
terminal and began pulling all of the documents on my system and the systems in our SCIF.
This consulting firm wasn't just two old colleagues starting a fishing club.
It represents two aerospace graybeards with connections way too deep to ever really walk
away, advising clients across the Pentagon and Department of Energy.
Make of that what you will.
In 2019, he joined the board of trustees at Riverside Research, a nonprofit with hundreds
of millions of dollars in defense and intelligence work on the books.
He was also the director of technology at ATA.
Applied Technology Associates.
One of those aerospace firms with a deliberately vague name working in sensitive areas in space
systems and directed energy.
That doesn't sound like a quiet retirement to me, but that's exactly the kind of person
who makes a very specific set of people very nervous.
A potential whistleblower.
Operating in the dangerous margin between intelligence agencies and private contractors.
Two groups with their own distinct methods of making problems disappear.
And if you're in the business of making problems disappear, you make sure you give the public
a story they can wrap their heads around.
This is the Fixer Handbook 101.
Which brings us back to a detail that doesn't get enough attention.
Just because McCaslin's gun is missing doesn't mean he was the one who took it.
Think about it.
If you wanted to stage someone's disappearance to read like a probable suicide, what would you
take?
You'd take a gun.
Not their phone or smartwatch.
You'd leave everything trackable with a GPS chip.
But take the one item with an obvious narrative attached to it.
Ultimately, who knows what happened to McCaslin.
What we do know is that a man who knew more about America's most classified science programs
than about 99.9999% of our population vanished from his house without tripping a single camera.
And as of today, despite 700 homeowners canvassed, search parties, drones, helicopters, FLIR sweeps,
K-9 units, and the FBI, we have next to nothing.
No confirmed sightings.
No scent trail.
He's just gone.
Like a ghost.
For one of the most intensive searches in recent New Mexico history, the absence of evidence
is bizarre.
But it might be a data point unto itself that points to someone who's sophisticated, who
knows how to work the blind spots.
And McCaslin isn't the first to vanish.
Congressman from Tennessee, Tim Burchette, has been trying to get answers himself, but claims
that some of our intelligence agencies are actively stonewalling his attempts to investigate
why our top researchers are disappearing at such a high rate.
He told the Daily Mail that the numbers seem very high in these certain areas of research.
I think we'd better be paying attention, and I don't think we should trust our government.
I had a t-shirt on my BirchitforCongress.com website that said more people believe in UFOs
than believe in Congress, and it sold out.
So, I mean, there's something going on out there, brother.
But while Burchette was looking for answers in Washington, the internet was doing its own
digging.
After his story broke, an online manhunt zeroed in on a potential smoking gun, an ex-account
called TMB Spaceships.
The account posts about plasma propulsion and spacecraft systems, but hasn't posted since
February 27th, the day McCaslin disappeared.
I looked into it.
Its account claims that in 1991, its owner was attending the University of Texas as a
U.S. Air Force butter bar electrical engineer, which is slaying for a newly commissioned second
lieutenant.
Except McCaslin reached second lieutenant on May 30th, 1979, and by April 1991, he had reached
lieutenant colonel.
His official Air Force biography also puts him in Los Angeles from 1988 to 1992, not Texas.
The account also mentions a brother-in-law who spent 40 years in navigation and started
working for Texas Instruments in the 1950s.
But the only McCaslin brother-in-law we could actually verify doesn't fit that profile.
Based on these posts, the user behind the account doesn't appear to be McCaslin.
While the internet was busy trying to unmask this ex-account, the real story was hiding
in plain sight.
Today's episode is sponsored by Incogni.
Something that comes up a lot when I talk to UFO whistleblowers, physicists, and researchers
who work on sensitive projects is how carefully they have to manage their digital footprint.
Most people have no idea how much of their personal information is sitting on sites they've
never heard of.
Personal phone numbers, addresses, family members' names, all collected without your knowledge
and sold to anyone willing to pay for it.
That's what got me first using Incogni about a year ago.
They go after data brokers directly and get your information removed immediately.
Not just buried, actually deleted.
And they keep following up until it's confirmed.
The feature I find most useful is custom removals.
If you find your information on some random PeopleFinder site, you paste the link into your
dashboard, and their privacy experts immediately handle the takedown.
You get unlimited submissions, and they completely eliminate the back and forth you'd usually
have to deal with to get your information removed from these sketchy websites.
Take your personal data back now with Incogni.
Use code AmericanAlchemy at incogni.com slash AmericanAlchemy for 60% off an annual plan.
Again, that's 60% off if you sign up with our code today.
I'm also including a link in the description.
When you dig into the $2.2 billion science and technology portfolio McCasland oversaw at
the Air Force Research Lab, you'll find a thread that leads somewhere specific.
And that thread is metal.
A super alloy of metal, co-invented by another missing scientist.
Monica Jacinto Reza
Monica worked in one of the most brutal corners of propulsion science.
An age-old limitation had kept advanced rocket propulsion pinned down by the same ugly problem.
If you want to get heavy satellites into orbit, you need a high-pressure, oxygen-rich environment.
The metallic alloys strong enough to hold the engine together in these situations would go up in
flames. And the alloys that didn't catch on fire were too weak to trust with the guts of an engine.
So the U.S. military needed to find a sweet spot. But nobody could find one.
So we were forced to rely on the Russian RD-180 engine for sensitive national security space launches.
This meant that during the Cold War, we were literally stuck buying defense hardware
for the most sensitive missions from our biggest geopolitical rival.
The stalemate finally shattered in the 1990s thanks to the hard work of Dallas Hardwick and
Monica Reza at the Rockwell Science Center. They engineered a nickel-based alloy tough enough
to survive the crushing pressure, but stable enough to not go up in flames or fracture in an oxygen-rich
hellscape. They named this supermetal Mondaloid. The first three letters of each of their names
fused into one. By 1999, the Air Force Research Laboratory, or AFRL, began co-funding their work.
The same Air Force Research Laboratory that was later headed up by Neil McCaslin.
Monica told Space News that over the next two decades and after multiple Air Force and NASA contracts,
the metal she created was eventually scaled into a family of super-alloys, Mondaloid 100 and 200,
each engineered for different temperature and pressure conditions.
This was the vital national security hardware that would allow us to stop relying on Russia.
Fast forward, and Mondaloid ends up in kerosene-fueled AR-1 engines,
Rocketdyne's U.S.-built replacement for the Russian RD-180. Then, in May of 2011,
none other than Neil McCaslin came to Wright-Patterson as the new commander of the Air Force
Research Laboratory while the Mondaloid program was still active. And Monica's co-inventor,
Dallas Hardwick, who had been at Wright-Patterson since the year 2000, was right there alongside him,
embedded in the lab's materials directorate until her retirement in 2012. This was the exact
place where Mondaloid 200 was co-developed. In fact, a National Academies report shows the
Mondaloid partnership was shared between the Air Force Research Laboratory and Monica's team at
Pratt & Whitney Rocketdyne, which later became Aerojet Rocketdyne. The Air Force knew that mastering
materials like Mondaloid could shape the future. And at Wright-Patterson, cutting-edge science has
long been rumored to blur into the unexplained. But there's a long and much weirder history of
exotic metallurgy coming out of Wright-Patterson. And this is where the story goes somewhere familiar.
Some researchers connect Mondaloid to a specific lineage of exotic metal that goes all the way back
to the alleged Roswell crash of 1947. In an interview with journalist Bob Pratt, Jesse
Marcel Jr., the Army Air Force intelligence officer at the Roswell crash site, described some of the
debris as thin and foil-like. And when he held a lighter to it, it didn't burn. The theory goes that
whatever was recovered at Roswell eventually became a classified R&D seed program at Wright-Patterson's
Air Force Research Lab. And over decades, that seed inspired families of advanced alloys designed
to mimic or exploit the same impossible properties. Shape recovery, extreme strength-to-weight ratios,
burn resistance. Not chemical clones of the Roswell metal, but descendants of the same research tree.
You have to admit, it's a bit bizarre that Wright-Patterson had a contract with Battelle Memorial
Institute in 1949, studying nickel-titanium alloys, long before the material became associated with
memory metal. Memory metal extremely similar to what Jesse Marcel described, just two years after he
reportedly handled it. Then fast forward to the 1960s at the Naval Ordnance Laboratory, and the world was
introduced to nitinol, an alloy that remembers its shape. It was seen as a breakthrough in modern
metallurgy, but for anyone steeped in Roswell lore, it looked eerily familiar. Now, Mondeloy lives in a
very different metallurgical neighborhood. Nitinol is about 45% titanium, while Mondeloy has only small
amounts of titanium, about 1-4%. And if you look at the actual science behind Mondeloy, the exotic metal
metal theory hits a wall. Monica's patents for Mondeloy mentions Hanes-214 and Monol alloy K-500.
So is Monica's superalloy some kind of Roswell starship derivative? Maybe not. But who's to say
these exotic metal lineages didn't have a little outside inspiration along the way?
You have to admit, the optics are bizarre. A scientist co-invents a superalloy inside the same research
portfolio McCasland oversaw, and now they've both vanished? If you look at the world they came out of,
intelligence agencies have warned for decades that foreign agents target America's space and defense
world. McCasland was practically a walking hard drive, not for a single piece of knowledge,
but for the vault in his head. The same way Monica's value wasn't just Mondeloy, it was the person behind
it. A mind capable of solving one of the toughest problems in American rocketry is capable of solving
the next one too. So let's go back to June 22nd, 2025, when the woman who taught us how to tame fire
fire, vanished. The search is on for a 60-year-old woman missing in the Angeles National Forest.
Monica Reza was last seen near Mount Waterman yesterday at about 9 a.m. The LA County Sheriff
Department's Crescenta Valley Station and Montrose Search and Rescue have been working around the clock
on this one. Search and Rescue scoured the area for eight days by land and by air, but found nothing
other than Monica's beanie, which photographs from the day show was tucked into the hip belt of her
pack. The visor was recovered about 400 yards off the trail the day after her disappearance.
When no other evidence surfaced as is protocol, the synthetic aperture radar mission was concluded
and the investigation was handed off to the Homicide Bureau, the missing persons unit. But Monica's
community had already mobilized, organizing volunteer groups, including expert mountain rescue teams,
who began searching the areas outside the search and rescue perimeter and would continue to search
by land and by drone when the official search and rescue mission was called off. Hikers have been
known to survive for two to three weeks in the wilderness at times, but the weeks wore on and the
volunteer exhibitions kept going out every few days. Hope of rescue dimmed, but the goal was to at least
recover Monica's body. The organizers begged for volunteers to keep deploying until Monica's
birthday in December, six whole months after her disappearance. The weeks turned into months and
still no sign of Monica. She had vanished without a trace. That fateful June morning, Monica was well
equipped with a backpack, hiking boots, hiking pants, and plenty of water. It's still unclear if she had her
cell phone on her. Some theorized she could have been attacked by a mountain lion or bear, but no
dens were found in the area. No remains. The San Gabriels are mountain lion country. The terrain is
extremely rugged. There are many giant boulders and cave-like shelters that could obscure Monica from the
view of rescuers. Still, multiple civilian searchers who descended the ravine nearest to Monica's last
reported location, described the terrain as steep, but not steep enough to be fatal if someone fell.
Something about her disappearance feels off. If someone had wanted to kidnap Monica, it's conceivable
they could have intercepted her on the trail and led her to a car parked along a different section of
the highway. We may never know if her disappearance was just a tragic twist of fate, a crime of opportunity,
or something much more nefarious. Beyond her invention of the Mondoloi, the heat-resistant
coating for interiors of rockets and satellites that allow for entry and re-entry into our atmosphere,
most importantly, we want to honor Monica's life. The outpouring of prayer, support, and resources from
her family, friends, and colleagues demonstrates how deeply she is and will continue to be missed.
The last entry on the volunteer Facebook group for Monica's search and rescue efforts was on
November 18, 2025. 150 days after her disappearance, the group was still planning a recovery expedition
that week. As disturbing as Monica's disappearance is, four days later, another woman disappeared.
Back in the day, I used to chug coffee like I was prepping for a quantum jump, but then I'd crash like
my nervous system got slingshotted through a kaleidoscope. Anxiety spiking, aura flickering,
and REM sleep never met her. It was like drinking battery acid on an empty stomach. Then I found
Mudwater. It doesn't fry my circuits or my synapses. I use Mudwater's original blend over ice. It still has
a little bit of caffeine, but it's stacked with adaptogens and nootropics like L-theanine,
chaga, lion's mane, cacao, the whole earth squad to keep you naturally energized and to ensure that
you don't wake up with the morning scaries. One sip of Mudwater and my cells report for duty.
Two sips and boom, I'm plugged into the fungal starfleet. All systems go. So are you ready to
make the switch to cleaner energy? Head to mudwater.com, that's M-U-D-W-T-R dot com, and grab your
starter kit today. It's M-U-D-W-T-R dot com. Right now, our listeners get an exclusive deal up to 43%
off your entire order, plus free shipping and a free rechargeable frother when you use code
Jesse at checkout. That's right, up to 43% off with code Jesse, that's J-E-S-S-E, at mudwater,
M-U-D-W-T-R dot com. After your purchase, they'll ask you how you found them. Please show your support
and let them know we sent you.
It's been nearly a month since anyone has seen Melissa Casillas. Her stepdaughter says a doorbell
camera showed Casillas walking a couple miles away with a backpack, and she was last seen walking on
a highway in Taos County about a month ago. It was June 26th. A family friend even saw her walking
along the highway. He turned around to see if she needed help, but then all he saw was a blue truck
driving by. No Casillas. Her family thinks she got into that truck. Her family says her personal
belongings are all still at home, including her phone, which had been factory reset.
This time, an hour from Los Alamos National Laboratory in Ranchos de Taos. Melissa Casillas
is a 53-year-old administrative assistant at Los Alamos National Laboratory, one of the most
secretive research sites on Earth, and of course the original home to the Manhattan Project,
where the first atomic bomb was developed under Oppenheimer.
On the morning of June 26th, 2025, around 6.15am, Melissa dropped her husband, Mark, off at the
campus. He worked at the lab as a superintendent, and said he watched Melissa swipe her badge at the
gate. But instead of heading to work, Melissa drove an hour back home, telling her daughter
Sierra. She'd forgotten her badge and was going to work from home instead. Sierra didn't think
anything of it, and left for her own job. Around 12.30, Melissa dropped off lunch for her daughter
at her work. Everything seemed normal, but around 1.30, Mark got a call from Melissa's boss. She never
showed up at work. He texted Sierra, who sent a text to her mom, and it was quickly marked as read.
But by 2.30, her second text wouldn't deliver at all. Around 2.15, doorbell cameras caught Melissa
walking along State Road 518 in a turquoise shirt, blue jeans, and a maroon sweatshirt around her waist,
heading in the direction of Carson National Forest, about three miles from her house. Back at the house,
her daughter came home to a locked door and Melissa's car in the driveway. Inside, she found her mom's purse,
wallet, keys, and both her work and personal phones. When she picked one of the phones up,
she realized it had been factory reset. A check she was supposed to cash was sitting there too,
next to a few dollar bills. Her daughter searched through her things and realized she might have
taken a toothbrush, a hair iron, and other personal items. A witness later reported that around the same
time Melissa was seen on surveillance footage, they saw a blue Dodge truck following her. They also
said she was walking like she was hurt or intoxicated. The family later disputed it,
saying that the witness described a woman in a white shirt, not turquoise, which was what Melissa
was wearing. Either way, Melissa was gone. When her family, Sierra and Mark, compared notes,
the stories didn't match up. Melissa told her daughter she came home because she forgot her badge,
but Mark said he watched her swipe in with it. Either one of them was wrong,
or Melissa wasn't telling the truth. After going through her things, Sierra realized that
her mother was under enormous pressure. On an interview with Dateline, she said that there
was a lot crumbling down on her that we didn't know about. Melissa was also feeling financial
stress. Her husband said that after their daughter Sierra was in a bad car accident,
there was supposed to be a settlement, but it fell through. Her 2022 GoFundMe mentions that
the accident left her family with medical costs most could never fathom. As Sierra and her father
started piecing things together, they began suspecting Melissa might have left on her own.
And when you look at the items she took, like a toothbrush and hair straightener,
it tells us a few things. Abductees don't usually take their hair straighteners,
and a suicidal person doesn't care about frizzy hair. This behavior describes someone who might be
expecting to go somewhere with running electricity, a mirror, and maybe even someone to see.
The factory reset phones left at home are another clue. If she had left voluntarily,
she might have wanted to wipe her message history and make herself harder to track down.
The Los Alamos connection, of course, put Melissa on everyone's radar. And even though administrative
roles can overlap with classified material, we don't know what her position entailed.
And when you add in the confusion about the badge, the factory reset phones, the personal items she
took, and the financial stress, this starts to look like someone who made a decision to disappear
on her own terms. Maybe she saw something she wasn't supposed to at the lab. And her phone and
hair appliance were a neat cover story for somebody who didn't want her to speak out. Whatever happened,
Melissa's still missing, and her family is still looking. Her parents have set up a GoFundMe,
offering a $5,000 reward for any information that brings her home. But not every disappearance
near a sensitive facility is foul play. The evidence looks like it points somewhere more
tragic and personal than a sinister conspiracy. We're including her because she deserves to be
found, but we're not including her as evidence of something darker. For that, we have to look 700 miles
west at what was happening under the stars just outside Los Angeles.
A man shot and killed three days ago at his home in the Antelope Valley community of Lano has been
identified as Carl Grillmayer. He was a Caltech scientist. Colleagues say the 67-year-old made
groundbreaking discoveries in astronomy and will be greatly missed.
On February 16, 2026, about 30 miles northeast of Waterman Mountain, where Monica Reza disappeared,
another colleague from Caltech and JPL would meet an equally tragic and suspicious end—the great
astronomer Carl Grillmayer. In the small, unincorporated community of Lano, tucked away
near the Los Angeles and San Bernardino County line, a world-class astronomer had built his own
observatory on a remote stretch of land. He chose to set up shop in the secluded Antelope Valley,
20 miles east of Palmdale, precisely because of how thinly populated it was. Carl Grillmayer wanted
the darkest night skies possible, with the least amount of light pollution. Carl Johan Grillmayer,
born in Calgary, Alberta in 1959, dedicated his life to studying galactic astronomy in distant planets.
His work focused on mapping the structure of the Milky Way, identifying stellar streams,
remnants of smaller galaxies, or clusters torn apart by gravitational forces. These incredibly
faint, stretched out ribbons of stars, drift through our Milky Way, and tell the story of what was left
behind. Modern science sometimes suffers from hyper-specialization, but Carl Grillmayer did not.
Within astrophysics, he was a renaissance man, a polymath, with research interests at every scale.
From the research of our own solar system, to giant galaxy clusters, to the search for extraterrestrial
life. Grillmayer discovered the Lethe Stream, a vast river of stars yanked into the Milky Way from
nearby globular clusters. Using the Sloan Digital Survey, or SDSS, Grillmayer tracked subtle disturbances
in the paths of these stellar streams, leading to key insights into dark matter, a mysterious missing
mass, which forms a cosmic glue that holds galaxies and their clusters together. Stars, galaxies,
planets, and matter as we know it are only 5% of the observable universe. Think of them as the foam
on an incoming wave crashing on the beach. Dark matter forms much of the rest of the ocean.
A vast halo of dark matter envelops the Milky Way. Its immense gravity would disturb the path of incoming
stellar streams by tugging on them and changing their paths. And by tracking these changes,
Grillmayer was able to make profound insights into one of the universe's biggest mysteries.
What is most of it made out of? Through his comprehensive study of stellar streams,
Grillmayer helped reshape our understanding of how galaxies evolve. And his work with exoplanets was
arguably even more profound. Using the Spitzer Space Telescope, Grillmayer did pioneering work
studying the atmospheres of exoplanets, breaking down light passing through distant worlds to search
for molecular fingerprints that tell us what they're made of. In 2007, Grillmayer was part of the team
that discovered the first ever instance of water vapor in an exoplanet's atmosphere. Today, the techniques
he pioneered are proving pivotal in the scientific search for alien life, as the same capabilities
can now probe the atmospheres of habitable planets for biosignatures, footprints of living ecology
altering the planet's chemical balance. His colleague at Caltech, Sergio Faiardo Acosta,
described his approach to exoplanets and galactic structures as truly detective work.
Carl Grillmayer was an extremely renowned scientist, and I would say he still is because
his legacy will keep on. And it becomes the consensus reality in conventional astronomy that
we're not alone will owe a lot of that paradigm-shattering insight to Dr. Grillmayer's groundwork.
But Grillmayer also studied celestial bodies much closer to home. He worked closely with NEOWISE,
an instrument which serves as planetary defense. You heard me right.
NEOWISE could be the first line of defense against humans going the way of the dinosaurs.
So Grillmayer had as front line of view as you can get when it came to the potential for Earth's
extinction. He's published extensively, and his research has earned him a number of accolades,
including NASA's Exceptional Scientific Achievement Medal in 2011. Recently, Grillmayer had begun work on
a new project, testing new instrumentation at Caltech's Palomar Observatory to monitor for
meteor impacts on the Moon's surface during an upcoming lunar eclipse. Another colleague,
collaborator, and lead scientist, Joe Maciero, said,
It is a really exciting project, and I know Carl was looking forward to seeing what we could learn
about the near-space environment from that. It made perfect sense that someone so passionate
about the night skies would build a home outfitted with his own observatory. And what makes no sense
is why a neighbor would seemingly stalk him on his property in December and return to kill him in
February. On December 20th, 2025, according to sheriff officials in court records, Carl Grillmayer
called the police to report someone trespassing on his sprawling lot in Llano. Deputies were dispatched,
and when they arrived, they found 29-year-old Llano resident Freddy Snyder wandering the rugged
landscape nearby, carrying a loaded unregistered rifle. Snyder claimed he was just headed to the post
office and carried the weapon for self-defense against wild animals. But the LA Times uncovered
Snyder's property records, indicating the post office was in the opposite direction of his and
Grillmayer's home. The sheriffs arrested Snyder on a felony weapons charge and booked him at the
Palmdale Station Jail, where he was accused of attempting to escape before his court appearance.
When Snyder showed up at court, the judge told him to complete a gun safety course,
citing his lack of past criminal record and an unnecessary prosecution's law as the reason for
his leniency. Snyder was released from jail on his own recognizance. Things calmed in the new year,
at least temporarily, until another 911 call came in on February 16th. At 6.10am, deputies responded to
a 911 call for assault with a deadly weapon. Carl Grillmayer had been shot on his porch. Paramedics
pronounced him dead at the scene. While the deputies responded to the 911 call at the Grillmayer residence,
another call came in. A carjacking had occurred just down the road. Freddy Snyder was arrested for
the carjacking and was subsequently linked to Grillmayer's shooting. Snyder, the man who was
released from custody for lacking a criminal record, was now charged with several felonies, including
burglary, carjacking, and murder. This time, his bail was set at just above $3 million. Investigators have
yet to uncover a motive, and they've found no evidence that Snyder and Grillmayer were acquainted.
No one has an explanation for why this man suddenly went on a crime spree that began and ended with Carl
Grillmayer. And Freddy Snyder's arraignment was postponed from March 26th to April 29th, so it may take
many months to uncover just what happened here. Could Grillmayer have stumbled upon something he
wasn't supposed to? Was Snyder being controlled by darker forces? Was he just a patsy or an extension
of something deeper? Recently, Dr. Grillmayer had been working on the revolutionary Vera Rubin Observatory,
an observatory which saw its first light mere months before his untimely death. The Vera Rubin Observatory is
one of the largest scale surveys of the sky ever undertaken. It produces over a thousand images
every night, covering the entire southern hemisphere from horizon to horizon, and it promises to
revolutionize the search for interstellar objects. Currently, we've only ever detected three objects
confirmed to be entering the solar system from beyond. But astronomers estimate Vera Rubin will discover
50 by the time its run is over. It will show us our own solar system in unprecedented detail.
On its first act of night, it revealed over 2,000 previously undiscovered asteroids. Here's where
things take an interesting, albeit very speculative, turn. In 2017, we discovered Oumuamua, the first ever
interstellar object to visit our solar system. It had some very strange properties, especially the way it
accelerated without any visible cometary tail, leading past American alchemy guest and Harvard
astrophysicist Avi Loeb to speculate that it may be a spacecraft or alien artifact. It was given the name
Oumuamua because it means in the Hawaiian language, a scout, a messenger from far away. All the proposals
that were put on the table to explain the anomalies of Oumuamua invoked a rock of a type that we've never seen
before. With Rubin now online, we're poised to discover many more Oumuamua's, which is why Vera
Rubin is now motivating mainstream SETI researchers to start scanning our solar system for more anomalies
which could be alien spacecraft or probes. If our solar system is in fact filled in extraterrestrial
spacecrafts and artifacts from visiting civilizations, Rubin is perfectly poised to pick them up. But there's also
a big limitation. All of Rubin's imagery has to be approved by the Pentagon. This is not a conspiracy
theory. It's a publicly known fact as reported in this article from the Atlantic. Every image gets reviewed
by the intelligence agencies before the scientific community is allowed to see it. As the Atlantic article
reports, a government agency would chip in five million dollars for the construction of a dedicated network
for moving sensitive data. Each time the telescope were to take one of its 30-second tile images of
the sky, the file would be immediately encrypted without anyone looking at it first and then sent
to a secure facility in California. Next, an automated system would compare the image with previous images
of the same tile. It would cut out small postage stamp pictures of any new object it finds,
be they asteroids, exploding stars, or spy satellites. It would filter out the postage
stamps that might depict secret US assets, and one minute later, send all the rest together with
their coordinates to an alert service available to astronomers worldwide. This level of intense
intelligence community oversight over what you might expect to be a conventional astronomical tool
is not unprecedented. A much smaller all-sky survey called PANSTARS, the same one which discovered
Oumuamua, underwent massive censorship from the Air Force, with swaths of imagery redacted or blacked out.
Astronomers complained that these redactions often got in the way of their work. Now what if you were to
spot a UFO on one of these things? Of course the publicly stated reason for this has nothing to do with UFOs,
and everything to do with classified spy satellites and military space assets. Most of the time this
is probably true, but it does have other implications. Past American alchemist Dr. Beatrice Villareal
discovered a possibly vast population of unknown objects orbiting the Earth. She found tens of
thousands of transients, light reflecting mirror-like objects orbiting the Earth. And she found them on
astronomical plates from 1949 to 1957, before Sputnik or any American satellites were up in space. She
also found them on astronomical plates from the Palomar Observatory, the same place associated with Carl
Grillmair. Villareal is currently working on replicating her results. And if I had to guess,
I think we're going to find some interesting corroboration for them.
I've been working with transients for a while. I think a lot of people know about this transient
work. We have been looking for like multiple transients and images. Sometimes you can see
multiple of them appearing and vanishing within half an hour. So if there truly is a population of UFOs
surrounding the Earth, the Rubin telescope, Grillmair's pet project at the end of his life,
would certainly catch them. But again, anything it sees would have to get a Pentagon stamp of approval,
before ever reaching the general public and scientific community. Now this is definite
speculation, and I want to make the disclaimer that there's no direct evidence suggesting this.
But the question has to be asked. Did Grillmair potentially see something in the Rubin data
that wasn't meant for public release? He might have seen something classified,
but why would he want to report on that? If he saw something more anomalous, it would be hard to
tell him in good faith as a scientist to not tell the public. We may never know,
but Dr. Grillmair's targeted killing leaves many questions unanswered. Snyder's bizarre lenient
treatment, the disappearances of General McCaslett, Monica Reza, and Melissa Casais are all notable
because of the access they had to top-secret intelligence and technology produced at our nation's
premier space science and defense facilities. The murder of Carl Grillmair, if premeditated and
intentional, would represent a terrifying escalation in this attack on science. A mind like Grillmair's
doesn't come along very often. A senseless act of violence is always a tragedy, but when the
expertise of an astronomer like Carl is wiped off the planet, we can leave no stone left unturned. Which
brings us to another shocking and senseless act of violence that took out another of the world's
preeminent scientific minds, this time an expert on nuclear fusion. Nuno Felipe Gómez Lurero was born
in 1977 in Visu, a city in central Portugal. Even as a little boy, he always knew he wanted to be a
scientist. In a 2018 MIT profile, Nuno recalled how everyone else wanted to be a policeman or a fireman.
He couldn't quite place the origin of his scientific interest.
He followed that passion to Lisbon, where he received his undergraduate and master's degree
at the Instituto Superior Tecnico in Lisbon. Nuno then went on to attend Imperial College in London,
earning a doctorate in physics in 2005, with a dissertation on tearing modes in plasma.
After graduating, Nuno arrived in the United States to join Princeton University as a post-doctoral
researcher at the Plasma Physics Lab in 2005. From 2007 to 2016, Nuno worked in a laboratory for the UK
Atomic Energy Authority and as a researcher at the Plasma and Nuclear Fusion Institute in Portugal.
In 2016, Lurero returned to the United States, joining the faculty at MIT as a professor and fusion
scientist. I'm Nuno Lurero. I'm a professor at MIT. My main appointment is in nuclear science and
engineering. He flourished at MIT and by 2022 became deputy director of MIT's largest lab, the Plasma Science
and Fusion Center, which is an umbrella research center at MIT for all the plasma and fusion-related
activities that we do on campus.
And in January 2025, President Joe Biden presented him with the Presidential Early Career Award,
the highest U.S. government honor for young scientists.
To say Nuno was a renowned physicist would be a massive understatement.
He was a leading expert in plasma physics. The work Nuno was conducting at MIT was attempting to
solve the hardest problems in nuclear fusion.
Problems that would unlock our capabilities in clean fusion power,
potentially solving the world's energy crisis forever.
For those unaware, nuclear fusion would be the ultimate clean energy dream,
bringing the sun to the earth and powering our whole society.
No fossil fuel pollution or Chernobyl-style meltdown necessary.
Wielding fusion power would dramatically reduce the human need for fossil fuels.
And with that, we might be able to avoid a lot of the geopolitical escapades we're seeing happening today.
But there's one great challenge. Plasma is a chaotic soup of charged ionized gas,
which behaves in wildly unpredictable ways. To contain it, and to force the atoms to fuse,
demands a special magnetic field, one which binds the plasma up into just the right geometry,
and under just enough pressure to force the atoms to merge, despite the immense repulsive force
between them. There are many challenges to nuclear fusion, but perhaps the greatest
is the problem of the containment field. It is no simple task, but it's where Nuno Lurero excelled.
His research was especially focused on one of the greatest challenges in plasma containment fields,
magnetic reconnection. Consider the loops of plasma we see on the sun. Plasma gets trapped
in arcs of opposite magnetic force. It usually gets trapped in tubes of electromagnetic energy,
hot particles rising out of the sun's surface and falling back in. Sometimes, like a rubber band
that's been stretched too much, it snaps. The field lines break. All the energy stored in the field
bursts out as the particles heat up and accelerate out. Then the field reconnects. This process causes
solar flares and coronal mass ejections, the kind of events that could one day fry our entire grid
with an electromagnetic pulse, or EMP. Nuno was a real blue sky researcher,
studying the phenomenon of magnetic reconnection itself.
But his work had extremely practical applications, because just as reconnection causes flares from the sun,
it's also a major factor in our attempts to bring the sun's power down to Earth, and do so in the form of
real nuclear fusion. Giant donut-shaped tokamak reactors use powerful magnets to contain superheated plasma,
and magnetic reconnection is one of the greatest obstacles to sustained nuclear fusion. Just like plasma
ejections from the sun, often with fusion, a leak gets created, leading to rapid cooling and pressure loss.
This effectively stops the fusion process dead in its tracks. Nuno Lurero was one of the world's
experts in understanding the intricacies of exactly how and why these magnetic reconnection leaks happen.
We don't know if Nuno came close to solving the problem of magnetic field line breaks. But we do know
he was probably as close as anybody. And at 47 years old, it's safe to say he had many impressive
decades of discovery and invention ahead of him. Except on December 15th, Dr. Nuno Lurero was gunned down
inside his Brookline, Massachusetts home.
Nuno Lurero was a husband, a father, an award-winning scientist, and expert in his field.
He was shot in the foyer of his apartment while his wife, mother, and daughters played a card game inside.
The only other person who saw his killer was his 12-year-old daughter, who first answered the door
for what she thought was a delivery man. Later, authorities would report that Claudio Manuel
Neves Valente, the Portuguese national and top suspect in the shooting at Brown University that
had occurred just two days prior, was likely also Nuno's killer. In some ways, this seemed very plausible.
Nuno and Claudio had both studied physics together 20 years ago at Portugal's Instituto Superior
Tecnico. Physics programs are tight-knit. They're also highly competitive. The men certainly knew each
other and were part of the same graduating class. But Nuno was actually an average student in undergrad,
whereas Claudio was tied with another student for top of his class. Claudio had his heart set on
MIT for graduate school. But as a surprise to everyone, he didn't score very well on his graduate
school admissions test, making MIT a reach. He ultimately didn't get in. Claudio Valente was
accepted to Brown University instead, but felt let down by a lack of academic rigor in their physics
program, insisting his classes were too easy, covering material he'd already learned in undergrad.
Claudio was described as egotistical and combative by his classmates at Brown.
He only made it a year into the program before taking a leave of absence. Eventually, he dropped
out of the program entirely and returned to Portugal. That year, he posted a disgruntled note online.
Happy now? And some now believe Valente harbored deep resentment for his former classmate,
Nuno Larreiro, whose massive success would have been assault in the wound.
Back in Portugal, tail between his legs, Valente worked at an internet company called SAPO, or SAPO.
His colleagues described him as highly competent and rigorous, polite, but aloof. His closest friend
at work, Sergio Bastos, who worked with him for seven years, insisted Valente was an extraordinary
professional. He did things that few people were capable of doing, but admitted that he was very
lonely. I think one of the great regrets he had was that he couldn't create his own family,
Mr. Bastos said. He had few social skills, and I don't think he had any girlfriends in the years we
worked together. One day in 2013, Valente reported to work. He declared it would be his last day.
He turned in his laptop, and he was never seen again.
Bastos tried in vain to reach out, but at this point, no one from Valente's former life could make
contact, including his own family. In 2017, Valente applied for and was awarded a visa to the United
States. He settled in Miami, Florida, where authorities are still trying to piece together
how exactly he spent his time. What we do know is that for the past three years,
Valente rented a storage unit in Salem, New Hampshire, and returned to Providence numerous
times to conduct surveillance on the Brown campus. Investigators eventually traced Valente to Boston
as early as November 17, 2025. By late November, he had checked into a Boston hotel and began making
repeated trips to Providence. A janitor at Brown saw a masked man matching Valente's description
inside the Barris and Hawley Engineering Building on November 28 and again on December 1. On December
1, Valente rented a blue-gray Nissan Sentra with Florida plates. That car was seen repeatedly around
Brown between December 1 and December 12. The picture was clear. This was pre-operational reconnaissance.
Valente executed his plan on Saturday, December 13, 2025. He barged into an open lecture hall in the
Barris and Hawley Building, the home of the physics department where students were taking final exams
before their winter holiday. Around 4 p.m., Valente opened fire with a 9mm pistol, killing two students
and injuring nine others. Valente would leave a confessional video behind. It was filmed in his
storage unit as a massive federal and state manhunt was still underway. He confessed that he had spent
six semesters planning his attack at Brown. After the shooting on December 13, Valente successfully
evaded law enforcement for two full days, using a burner phone with a European SIM card, as well as
swapping out credit cards and the license plate on his rental car, his identity remained a mystery.
Valente might have gotten away with his crimes, except for the fact that he had one more act of
violence planned. At some point between Saturday and Sunday, Valente drove back to Boston. And on
Monday, December 15, Valente spent the day pacing around Commonwealth Avenue. Maybe Valente saw
Lurero as a representation of everything he couldn't amount to, a successful academic, a family man,
a leader in his field of physics, a successful emigrant to America. This may have just been a
modern physics-based rendition of an age-old Shakespearean play. But still, there's something
both strangely calculated and apprehensive about Claudio Valente's actions leading up to his confrontation
with Lurero. Authorities have much more information about Valente's whereabouts in Providence prior to
his Brown shooting. After that, he kind of goes dark. And for the rest of Saturday and all of Sunday,
Valente seems to drop off the map. On Monday, December 15, Providence police were still circulating
surveillance clips from Brown. They were also still interviewing survivors. The shooter had not been
identified. That same evening, at about 8.30 p.m., Lurero was shot at his home on Gibb Street in
Brookline, Massachusetts. Earlier that day, the familiar Nissan made its first appearance parked on
Babcock Street around 8 a.m., five or six blocks from Lurero's home. Then, starting around 1.20 p.m.,
police say security cameras recorded a masked person at different points along Commonwealth Avenue.
Nuno reportedly got home from overseeing PhD-qualifying exams at MIT that day around 6 p.m.
At 8.23 p.m., a camera records the suspect, now masked and wearing a vest over his darker clothing.
At 8.30 p.m., the doorbell to Lurero's apartment rings repeatedly. His youngest daughter opens the front
door and peeks into the foyer. She sees through the glass a man standing inside of the building,
but on the other side of the foyer door. Her description of the man's clothing is mostly in
line with the footage revealed, but she adds that the yellow vest he wore had some gray stripes.
There are a few discrepancies in her observations compared to the footage seen of the suspect that
day. She even describes the shooter as having short facial hair, which suggests that he's not wearing
a mask. And according to her, he's also wearing a winter hat and carrying a cardboard package about
the size of a dictionary. She thinks he's a delivery man because the package has a barcode on it.
Lurero's daughter returns to the living room as Nuno replaces her at the front door to deal with the
visitor. The whole family hears gunshots and rushes to Lurero, who is wounded in the upper left chest,
upper abdomen, right thigh, and has a graze wound through his left thigh. The daughter sees the
shooter run to a blue or gray car parked across the street. At 8.35 p.m., the cameras outside a Boston
University Police Department record a Nissan operated by someone wearing a HiVise vest.
Minutes later, another camera records the vehicle heading out of the city.
If we're to believe that the shooter was Valente, it seems clear that once Lurero was shot,
he immediately went into hiding. He switched the rental car's plates to an unregistered plate from Maine,
then drove to his storage facility in New Hampshire. Investigators said Valente entered that
facility about an hour after the Brookline shooting. The Department of Justice transcript of the videos
that Valente later recorded in that storage unit adds a very grim layer to the story. In these
recordings, Valente said he had planned the Brown attack for a long time. The language Valente uses
implies that both of the attacks were intentional, but it still leaves the reason for targeting Lurero
maddeningly vague. Yes, the two men had studied in the same university in the 1990s, but there's no
evidence of a recent dispute, direct contact, or a concrete grievance tied to the Brookline attack.
A second anomaly is the mismatch between planning and execution. Valente seems to have surveilled
Brown repeatedly. He would return constantly to the same building. He rented both a car and storage unit
in advance. Yet his own post-crime confession depicts the actual Brown shooting as totally botched.
He said he never wanted to do it in an auditorium. He even suggested that people could have escaped
via an emergency exit. He also complained about his eye injury and described the whole thing as,
quote, a little incompetent. A third anomaly is the timeline gap between the two attacks.
Where exactly was Valente in the roughly 48 hours before Lurero was shot? Where was he staying?
How did he locate Lurero? How could he even be sure Lurero was home? Nuno had only just returned
from a trip to DC. Was he being tracked somehow? Valente's videos hint that the second slaying
was also intentional, but not how far back the planning went. Detectives arrived on the scene to
find Lurero distressed but consciously alert. As he's transported to the hospital, one paramedic
says he doesn't say anything. She believes he was in shock. He answers questions by shaking his head.
But at the hospital, he was able to provide his name and information. If Lurero had recognized his
possibly unmasked killer as his former classmate, would he have said anything? Tragically,
Nuno Lurero went into surgery that evening, but did not survive. He was pronounced dead the following
morning. In the days that followed, they spoke to the MIT professor's family and colleagues,
and they said that there was no threat present, and they still have no motive.
Everything about this case is shocking, but particularly Valente's combination of caution
and sloppiness. He went to great efforts and lengths in Providence to wipe any trace of his movements,
keep his identity hidden. But then he arrives in Boston and paces back and forth in public locations
that would obviously have security cameras. It almost seems as if he was having cold feet.
Or maybe he was awaiting instruction. Subliminal or conscious instruction.
As we've covered on this show, the horrifying ability to program assassins is remarkably easy,
and it's been demonstrated by governments globally and employed to take out targets at the highest
level. What remains unresolved is why Lurero was chosen, what exactly happened in the two days
between the Brown massacre and the Brookline attack, and whether Lurero had been a long-standing target
or simply became one after the Brown shooting was already underway. What we do know is that Nuno Lurero's
loss is devastating. He wasn't just the head of MIT's Plasma Science and Fusion Center. Nuno was
still an active professor, training the next generation of top scientific minds to push us
farther in harnessing the power of our sun and creating clean energy on Earth. He was twice awarded
the MIT Department of Nuclear Science and Engineering Outstanding Professor Award. He was given this for the
beloved courses that he taught, both Intro to Plasma Physics and MHD Theory of Fusion Systems. MHD,
or magnetohydrodynamics, also could have just as sensitive implications as nuclear fusion. It's the
less focused on aspect of Lurero's work. And these are called the magnetohydrodynamic equations. They're
hydrodynamics, but now there's a magnetic field, so you refer to this as magnetohydrodynamics. Some believe
that it could lead to a whole new paradigm in flight and propulsion. The point is, an attack on Nuno was
an attack on the future of science. There's no other way to say it. To put it simply, Nuno was the tip
of the spear on sustained, clean, widespread nuclear fusion energy. Could that be why someone wanted him dead?
This brings us to a strange coincidence we have to bring up when discussing Nuno Lurero's murder.
Breaking news out of Brookline, an MIT professor shot and killed. He was shot several times in the foyer
of his Brookline home. Just two days after Nuno's death, one of the top privately funded fusion
companies, TAE Technologies, announced a massive merger with a surprising publicly traded company. TAE would
merge with none other than Trump Media and Technology Group, the company behind Trump's social media
platform Truth Social. The deal was announced on December 18th, 2025. Lurero died on December 16th.
The announcement didn't coincide with any decisive technical breakthroughs. Nonetheless, this combined
entity was suddenly valued at around $6 billion. TAE is a private long-running experimental company.
Their mission is to build aneutronic fusion reactors using hydrogen boron fuel to make
commercial nuclear energy. But just like all fusion enterprises so far, they have yet to produce net
energy or commercial power. TAE is still pre-revenue and pre-product in its core mission.
So why is any of this relevant? Well, there are a few key competitors in the race with TAE to produce
commercial nuclear power. One of their biggest competitors is a company called Commonwealth Fusion Systems.
Commonwealth Fusion Systems is a company that emerged directly from the Massachusetts Institute
of Technology. Its founders built their work on decades of MIT's institutional research. The MIT
Plasma Science Infusion Center collaborates closely with the company and contributes fundamental plasma
physics essential to its reactor design. And Nuno Lurero was the director of the Plasma Science
Science Infusion Center at the time of his death. So the head of research that directly supports
Commonwealth's aim of stable nuclear energy was assassinated on his doorstep.
We want to give you some context on exactly where this happened. The shooting was on Gibb Street in
Brooklyn.
A shot and killed at his Brooklyn Hall.
I'm walking around. I got children in the playground right around the corner.
Authorities say the Portuguese professor died at a hospital this morning.
And two days later, one of Commonwealth's biggest competitors announces a merger with a sitting
president's publicly traded company. Does that mean anything? I'm not entirely sure,
and I genuinely don't want to insinuate anything. But I also think it's dogmatic and unreasonable to
say that the timing isn't odd. Again, there are reasonable explanations for this merger. Most analysts
say that any fusion company will need the support of the federal government to bring this nascent,
unproven, and extremely costly technology out of the laboratories and onto the power grid. It's simply
too cost and infrastructure intensive and would involve a complete overhaul of our current grid
system. There are other power players in oil and gas who have an interest in TAE. A great example is
Chevron. Ultimately, the question remains, what lengths would the power players in energy go to shore up
their survival and dominance. There's clearly a race to control the technology that could determine
the future of energy, aerospace, and intelligence in our modern world. And Nuno Lurero's research was
at the heart of it. I think on any given day, it's tempting to go for the low-hanging fruit,
be a little more ambitious, and tackle the really hard problems.
It would hardly be the first time scientific talent tied to strategic technology seemed to attract
a shadow of danger. In the heart of the Cold War, as America raced to build Reagan's Star Wars missile
shield, something deeply sinister began happening to the scientists building it.
It's a story so rich and intriguing that if it were fiction, it would likely be a bestseller,
because all of the dead, almost two dozen to date, worked in Western Europe's defense industry.
You might not know that Star Wars, also known as the Strategic Defense Initiative,
was actually a joint effort between the United States and some of its key allies, like Great Britain.
Between 1982 and 1990, 25 engineers and computer scientists, all working for GEC Marconi,
on some of Britain's most classified defense projects, all died, one after another.
I call upon the scientific community in our country, those who gave us nuclear weapons,
to turn their great talents now to the cause of mankind and world peace.
And each case was so bizarre. They consistently defied rational explanation. A 24-year-old jumped from a
suspension bridge. His body was then found with mysterious needle puncture wounds in it. A 26-year-old
allegedly drove his car away from a tree with a rope tied between his neck and its trunk,
decapitating himself. And the coroner called it suicide. A Ministry of Defense consultant was found
in his flat with his feet bound, a plastic bag over his head, and a rope coiled four times around his
body. This was ruled an accident due to quote-unquote sexual misadventure. A senior radar scientist loaded his
car with extra petrol cans and drove it at full speed into an abandoned cafe. Another was found
electrocuted in his garden shed, wires attached to his body, a handkerchief stuffed in his mouth.
Open verdict. One man simply disappeared during a research experiment at a reservoir and turned up
months later in Paris with no memory of how he got there. The British government investigated nothing,
held no inquiry, classified the files, and to this day, not a single person has ever been charged.
Was it the KGB, MI5, or something else entirely? Nobody knows. The case is officially closed,
yet also unsolved. This is just one anomalously condensed example. Time and again, when scientific
minds get closer to unlocking new facets of our reality, or get too close to the crown jewels of
defense, they seem to be removed from the conversation. Take the disappearance of Mexican
neurophysiologist and psychologist Jacobo Grinberg, who vanished in 1994 just after his biggest discovery.
That space wasn't empty, but rather filled with a massive energy matrix he dubbed the lattice.
How we see the world was based on our tether to this matrix, and those with the honed ability to
synchronize their cognition with the lattice would be able to bend the hologram to their own designs,
just like Neo in the Matrix. Grinberg had seemingly stumbled upon something foundational,
and then he was never seen again. After convening with some top scientific minds in the year prior,
his lab was cleared out, and his records were erased. The only thing left behind was a single
chilling note. If you understand the system, you disappear.
Speaking of disappearances, we'd be remiss if we didn't mention one of the most famous
disappearances in modern aviation, tied to the scientific realm. On March 8th, 2014,
Malaysia Airlines flight MH370 took off from Kuala Lumpur with 239 people aboard.
Somewhere over the South China Sea, its transponders stopped transmitting.
Malaysian military radar later showed that after going dark, the plane made an unexplained U-turn,
flew for another several hours in the wrong direction, then vanished from the earth so
completely that despite the most expensive search in aviation history, only a small number of debris
fragments believed to be from the MH370 crash have turned up alongside the coasts of Africa and a
handful of Indian Ocean islands. And around that disappearance, a wild theory took shape.
It's centered on alleged drone footage and a companion infrared video.
Researcher Ashton Forbes claims that these videos show MH370 over the Nicobar Islands being encircled by
three fusion-powered plasma orbs that generate a spinning wormhole teleporting the plane westward,
likely toward the Maldives or Diego Garcia, as part of a covert military black program operation
targeting high-value engineers.
Now, I want to be super clear. I don't know what to make of these videos. Impressive people from the
intelligence and military world have told me they are very fake. And that, for example, they've never
seen thermal infrared imaging on these sorts of systems in full color. But there's another
narrative that gets slept on and doesn't require any belief in UFOs zapping an airplane out of the sky.
Among the documented passengers on the MH370 flight were 20 engineers from Freescale Semiconductor,
an American semiconductor company that had just announced new products including devices relevant
to radar and electronic warfare for defense market applications. The employees included mostly
Chinese and Malaysian specialists whose work involved the kind of microchip technology
that sits at the intersection of civilian computing and military applications.
Some researchers believe that this is what made the group valuable, not just as passengers on a missing
plane, but as carriers of highly specialized scientific expertise. If those engineers were in fact tied to
the future of military microelectronics, then they represented a goldmine of technical knowledge for the
next generation of defense technology. In any case, it's not the first instance of a mysterious
aircraft malfunction claiming the life of a top scientist.
Itzhak Bentov was a self-taught inventor and scientist. Born in Czechoslovakia during World War II,
he escaped Nazi Germany to Israel. Once there, he helped invent the country's first rocket despite
lacking formal science training. But his true passion lay in unpacking the mysteries of consciousness,
which he believed was made up of vibrating, harmonious atoms. His theories helped shape the
foundation of the CIA's gateway process, a protocol developed by consciousness researcher Robert Monroe
in Virginia to achieve ascended states in consciousness and possibly even astrally project.
Bentov also consulted with the Stanford Research Institute and worked closely with many of the
people in the U.S. forming the CIA's psychic spy program, Stargate.
Bentov's life was tragically cut short at 55 years old when American Airlines Flight 191 crashed shortly
after taking off from Chicago O'Hare Airport, claiming the lives of all crew and passengers on board.
Many researchers in parapsychology and consciousness say that Bentov was as close to the truth or a theory of
everything in consciousness that you could get. He also had deep ties with American and Israeli intelligence.
He was even a close associate of Andrei Puharic, who was one of the earliest architects of MKUltra,
the CIA's mind control program. Bentov's extremely dense and almost indecipherable book about consciousness,
Stalking the Wild Pendulum, has become a cult classic. And many people who research him say the same things about
him that they do Grinberg. If there is a matrix, this guy might have found out how to control it
and how to get out. But not every scientist on this list was lost in a single catastrophic moment.
Some seemed to fade from view and get marginalized as their work moved deeper into the classified world.
Take Ning Li, a Chinese American physicist in Huntsville, Alabama, known for her radical work on
superconductors and gravity control. Working with her colleague Douglas Torr, she proposed that cooled
type 2 YBCO superconductors might produce tiny gravitomagnetic effects, a theory that pointed towards a
possible path to gravity control technology. After leaving the University of Alabama and receiving
Defense Department funding, she largely vanished from public view, with rumors that her work had
disappeared into the classified defense world. Her story took an even darker turn in 2014, when she was
struck by a car on the University of Alabama campus and suffered permanent brain damage. She later
developed Alzheimer's disease and died on July 27th, 2021, leaving behind one of the more haunting
stories in gravity research. A physicist who chased gravity, vanished into secrecy, and never really came back.
And then there's the story of John Norseen, a former Navy pilot, weapons designer, and neuroengineer at
Lockheed Martin, who is known for his work in biofusion, biometrics, neuroweaponry, and information security
concepts tied to neural pattern recognition and human-machine integration. He talks about brain prints, the
idea that we have fingerprints, but you might also have a unique kind of, you know, electromagnetic signature, just like iris or whatever.
Yeah. One close friend described his work in even darker terms, saying the weapons he designed
involved manipulation of the mind, ideas that pushed into territory we'd never now categorize
as cognitive warfare. You said that John Norseen, you spoke to John Norseen, and he was at Allagash
in the 19, in 1976, in August, when you guys were there and experienced your abduction.
He read our report to the ranger that same day. And what did he say he was doing there?
He said he was doing a TTR, tag, trace, retrieve, exercise with a subcutaneous device that they
were testing that they could monitor field agents. You know, if we tell them like blood pressure,
heart rate, that sort of stuff. Norseen died while on business for concurrent technologies,
on September 27, 2007. Exactly what happened remains unclear.
Norseen's story brings us back to the larger pattern, because this is bigger than just one man
or one strange death. Again and again, the people working closest to powerful,
secret scientific knowledge are the ones who seem to become the most vulnerable.
So where does this leave us? With the realization that even our own government,
the most powerful entity on earth, seems unable or unwilling to fully protect the very people
building its future. Or because every case points to the same explanation. For example,
General Neil McCaslin's case seems eerily possibly connected to Monica Reza's.
The killing of Carl Grillmare seems possibly of the same variety as what happened to Nuno Lurero.
But ultimately all of these cases could be isolated.
Sometimes the explanations for these things involve extreme human irrational emotion.
But sometimes they involve foul play. Whether it's homegrown black budget cleanup crews willing to kill
anyone who gets too close to their proprietary technology. Or foreign adversaries taking out
experts to hollow out American brainpower before the next big war. The real crown jewels aren't the
weapons or the hard drives, but the minds, the judgment, the intuition, and the years of trial and error
that most people never see. You can steal documents or hack a server, but if you really want to shortcut
the future, you steal the person who already solved the problem.
We like to imagine the black world as restricted hangers and test sites.
But the most valuable assets in the world still get up in the morning and drive to work.
Maybe there's an even stranger possibility hovering over all of this. One that moves beyond terrestrial
politics and into the highly speculative realm of exo-politics.
Relations between Earth and other intelligences that average citizens might not even know exists.
During the Bush administration, key players in the federal government were urged to read the Chinese
science fiction novel, The Three-Body Problem, written by a power plant engineer, Shi Jin Lu.
It's about trisolarian extraterrestrials forced out of their own unstable solar system and headed for Earth.
The trisolarians systematically monitor, mess with, and sometimes even kill human scientists at the
frontier of human ingenuity. These are usually people working on nuclear, plasma, and particle
accelerator physics. Sounds kind of familiar. Basically the scientists that control the rules of reality itself.
So why was the upper echelon of the American government reading this book?
Why did a presidential advisor named Harold Malmgren, who worked directly with JFK, LBJ,
Nixon and Ford, and who was briefed on UFOs? Why did he tell me that this is how the non-human
intelligences operate? By tracking the frontier of human innovation?
They were opposed to anything which threatened their control.
So it's almost like the UFOs are more, it's not just the atomic connection, they're generically
attracted to the tip of the spear as far as tech development. That's at the heart of it.
Yeah. Why was Harold's daughter, Pippa, who was on George W. Bush's National Economic Council,
tasked with reading The Three-Body Problem? And if connecting missing and dead scientists with aliens
sounds super far-fetched, I get it. But it's worthy asking yourself why UFOs so very often
seem to cluster around the very technologies that define strategic power.
They show up at nuclear sites across the United States and the world.
I've personally interviewed many whistleblowers who've worked at these bases who claim this.
Robert Hastings, the author of the great book, UFOs and Nukes,
has talked to almost 170 of these people.
There was even a UFO crash right next to Brookhaven National Labs. In case you're not aware,
Brookhaven houses a very powerful particle accelerator called Cosmotron.
Witnesses of the UFO crash claimed that the wreckage was cleaned up and taken to the lab.
This isn't just an American phenomena. Russian General Vasily Alekseyev said that UFOs would show up
when they transported sensitive scientific technology. The Soviets have records around
UFOs showing up around their national labs and nuclear sites. Which brings us back to the strange
question of why so many government officials were framing all of this problem. Maybe the
three-body problem was hiding truth in fiction.
There's an apocryphal story and truthfully I don't know how much weight to put in it. But it's
absolutely wild. It involves former President Barack Obama and Pearl Jam lead singer Eddie Vedder
drunk around a campfire. Eddie presses Obama on the true nature of reality. He wants to know how the
world really works at the highest level. He senses that there are things going on above his head.
Obama's answer? Read the three-body problem.
I've had a lot of conversations where people have asked me to do a video essay commenting on these
missing scientists. I went into this investigation unsure of whether any of these cases were linked
at all. And honestly I came out feeling like on a human level they're mostly not. Perhaps with the
exception of Monica Reza in McCaslin. Maybe it represents forces operating on levels higher than
human clearance systems. Many people forget that science itself is weird. There's a long history of
quote-unquote demons in science. Written about extensively and eloquently by former Harvard professor
Jimena Canales. Whether it's Heisenberg downloading matrix multiplication at Algoland. Dirac staring at
the fire at Cambridge and downloading the Dirac equation. Pauli dreaming up the architecture of
the hydrogen atom. Or Descartes having a series of his own prophetic dreams. If we were to apply
scientific scrutiny to the process of scientific discovery itself, it might begin to look less like
conventional science and inductive logic and more like revelation or something received.
Maybe entities higher than humans on the food chain are both inspiring and at times
stagnating science. What we do know for sure is that where there's truth, there's violence.
This goes back to Socrates and it's historically been the case with religious mystics. And if you think
religious truths are worth dying for, and that science and religion meet at some omega point,
then maybe this is all true for science too. Because if science really is brushing up against something
deeper, the questions underneath this pattern start to get very dark. But whether the forces at work
deleting these scientists are human or something stranger, the cost is the same. The people closest to
the edges of what we know. The ones rewriting the rules of physics, scanning the sky for threats we
can't see yet, and unlocking the science that shapes the next century. These are the ones we keep losing.
Their minds were the prize. They were the ones taking us into the future and they are now disappearing.
The search continues and the list is growing.
One of them is Alabama-based scientist Amy Eskridge. She was openly studying anti-gravity technology when
she died in 2022. Her death was deemed a suicide by a self-inflicted gunshot wound, but she warned
friends ahead of time that her life could be in danger. I don't believe that she killed herself. I
just can't because I spoke to her four hours before and she told me time and time again, I'm not going to
commit suicide. I am not going to have an accident. If there's something suspicious about my death,
it's because it is.
If you're still watching, you're one of the first to hear about this. We just dropped a new limited
merch collection. Two tees, one off-white, one vintage black, plus hat. The design has a timeless
retro-future feel. You can wear it every day. If you've been watching the show lately, you've probably
already seen me wearing it. This is a limited run, so when it's gone, it's gone. Head to
AmericanAlchemyMerch.com to grab the Believe drop today. And while you're there, the Cowboy
UFO-T is a fan favorite we always keep in stock, along with the Atomic Age design.
Thank you all so much for following and supporting the show.
Thank you all so much for joining us.
Thank you.