This might be the craziest American Alchemy episode of all time.
In the video you're about to watch, we reveal some extremely hardcore details about how UFO programs actually work.
Spoiler alert, it involves rounding up people from third-world countries who have psychic capabilities to systematically summon or lure in UFOs.
It also involves electromagnetic pulse weaponry used to down these crafts.
And of course, it involves reverse engineering the technology.
What you end up with is a parallel reality, a breakaway technology chain, and the ability to hide all of these things in mountain and undersea bases all over the world that are sometimes jointly operated by non-humans and humans.
But before we get into that, we've got to back up and report on the latest UFO news.
Because the government isn't talking about any of these darker details we'll get into in this video.
But they are beginning to admit that UFOs are real.
And we have come a long way.
I mean, even Neil deGrasse Tyson is now admitting that all of this stuff is probably real.
When these people of high rank started reporting, I said, all right, I have to jump in here.
On May 8th, 2026, the Department of War released hundreds of UFO-related documents, video, and audio.
With President Trump ordering the release of government files related to ET life in UFOs, posting a very pointed message to the American people.
The Department of War's UFO release webpage already has 500 million hits on it since then.
That is more than the entire population of the United States.
If you haven't already seen the drop, it's not the vault we were hoping for with an alien autopsy tape, pictures of historical crash retrievals like Roswell, or a little gray in a freezer at Wright-Patterson.
The release was pretty vanilla.
It was more like a UFO starter pack.
A lot of the documents in this drop weren't even newly declassified despite being presented that way.
They'd been hiding in plain sight for ages.
Now, they're just getting a stamp of approval.
Again, if that's what it takes for the academic and scientific consensus to shift,
and to convince people like Neil deGrasse Tyson to admit this stuff is real,
then they weren't doing science in the first place.
They were just waiting for establishment institutions to make it acceptable for them to look into this stuff.
On the other side of this issue, a lot of people are asking, why now?
Is this some sort of narrative distraction from more prosaic but darker trends in Iran, around Epstein, or whatever else?
Because the timing and the motivation of this UFO data dump does seem cynical.
And I'm sure it is.
I'm sure it is a distraction from Epstein, Iran, and all sorts of other problems we have.
And yet, a lot of these podcasters and independent media are now flipping on UFOs entirely, calling it a PSYOP.
This is also not good first principles thinking.
UFOs can be very real, of serious consequence to the nature of reality.
And they might also be getting used as a distraction.
Those two things aren't mutually exclusive.
Someone can tell you to look at the moon and pick your pocket, but that doesn't make the moon fake.
Give the people some blurry videos they have no hope of making sense of,
drown the truth out in static, and call it transparency.
Release a poorly curated batch.
Don't separate the wheat from the chaff.
And if something draws a bad reaction, find some way to stigmatize it after the fact.
If people react well to the drop, continue to inch forward.
But the release of this new information wasn't entirely meaningless.
And it's especially hard to laugh off in one particular place.
Space.
You see, this whole drop puts NASA, our premier civilian space agency, in a bind.
Because they've been playing dumb about their own astronauts seeing UFOs,
and they've been gaslighting the public since their inception in 1958.
NASA is not a place that's going to hide its head in the sink.
That's kind of harder to do when the Department of War, the Pentagon itself,
is now admitting that these astronaut sightings were actually unresolved.
Astronaut Gene Cernan, the last man to walk on the moon,
experienced bizarre flashes, distant blinking objects,
and even getting hit with blinding flashes of light in the dark while he slept.
Like a train coming at you, only with a flash.
Gene goes on to insist, something is out there.
And Houston says,
We don't doubt it, Gene.
Now this is all very serendipitous,
because I just got back from Japan,
where I spent a lot of time with a NASA historian there,
named Takanao Jowson.
Jowson happened to be a very close friend of Gene Cernan's.
And then he went on to reveal something absolutely mind-blowing to me.
Why are you sure?
Really?
Pretty wild, and I don't think to the skeptics out there
that Takanao Jiao-sen was coordinated at all with the Pentagon.
But as Houston said, we don't doubt it, Gene.
What you know if you watch this show
is that things like this happen all the time.
Disparate data points from around the world,
all corroborating the same UFO truths.
You see, the government wants a slow and steady disclosure drip,
but at American Alchemy, we want to speed things up.
Maybe the best way to expose the real UFO truth
isn't in this Department of War data dump,
but in a sci-fi book written by whistleblower
and former American Alchemy guest, Jake Barber.
It's so blatant and in your face and so real,
it doesn't register as exciting, you know, in that format.
Who is Jake Barber, you ask?
He's a pilot, former Air Force,
racy black belt, and he's an all-American badass.
On paper, he was an Air Force aircraft mechanic,
but that was just a cover.
He held a NATO top-secret security clearance,
deployed on presidential support missions,
hunted war criminals in Bosnia,
and later slipped into the shadows as a contractor
flying UFO crash retrievals as a helicopter pilot.
And according to Jake,
one of those crafts that he retrieved
seemed to be alive,
with a consciousness of its own attached to it.
And for a few terrifying moments mid-flight,
that consciousness possessed him.
Jake was the black hand of an unnamed aerospace giant.
He won't say who, but here's a clue.
Look, man, if you took two guesses,
you'd get both of them right on the first try.
There you go.
When I interviewed Jake,
his claims were so wild and so ahead of the curve
that most people's brains just bounced right off them
and into the comments section
to roast Logan Paul's cameo instead.
And what happened there is kind of the point.
Jake's novel is called Sentinels of Aether,
and it's written by a ghostwriter
under the pen name Alva Douglas.
I'm linking the manuscript
in the description of this video.
This was a novel deemed so dangerous by the Pentagon
that they spent six months
reviewing just 20 pages of the book.
They escalated it to subject matter experts
in classified special access programs
and came back with seven pages of redactions.
And that was just from 10%
of the full 120,000-word manuscript.
Why would the Pentagon redact fiction?
Maybe it's because it wasn't.
The best-kept secrets don't need to be classified.
They're just too insane to be taken seriously.
They're self-stigmatizing.
So when the truth is just too strange,
you disguise it as fiction.
In this episode,
we want to get into exactly
how the Black UFO program actually works.
I'm talking about disclosure at a whole new level,
hidden in plain sight.
Aerospace programs recruiting psychics
from third-world countries.
In fact, they are often drugged, microchipped,
and used like human joysticks
to fly these UFOs.
I'm also talking about underground bases
hidden all over the world.
And I'm talking about holograms and nanotechnology
used to create entryways into these mountain bases
that only open up for certain people
with certain biosignatures.
And finally, I'm talking about protocols
that can help anyone, you included,
attract and see UFOs.
And maybe call one to your bedroom window.
Protocols that the government has been exploiting
in hidden programs for decades.
So what's the real secret
that the Pentagon doesn't want you to know?
The ability for any person
to connect to this phenomenon
or attract it like a human antenna is real.
The big secret isn't a mothership.
It's you, your own human nature
that's far more magical
than the happy accident
of random atomic interactions
we're told about in school.
If anything, that worldview
of materialist reductionism,
that's the PSYOP.
So keep your eyes peeled
because tonight we're going inside the book
the Pentagon doesn't want you to read.
We'll decode what's real,
what's fiction,
and what's hiding
five miles east of Coyame, Mexico.
Today's episode is sponsored by Incogni.
Many of our guests are scientists,
researchers, and engineers
working on some of the most exotic technology
with implications that could change
the course of history.
And for people exploring the nature of reality,
privacy is a prerequisite.
People aren't paranoid.
They're just operating in spaces
where what's findable about them
actually matters.
They want to reduce their online footprint
as much as humanly possible.
Most people have no idea
how much of their information
is already out there.
Phone numbers, home addresses,
relatives' names,
all sitting on sites
you've never even heard of,
collected without your knowledge,
and sold to anyone willing to pay for it.
That's what got me using Incogni.
They go after these sketchy data brokers directly
and get your information deleted,
not just
And they keep following up
until removal is confirmed.
And you can see all of this cleanly
on their dashboard.
The feature I find most useful
is custom removals.
If you find your information
on some random people finder site,
you paste the link
into your Incogni dashboard,
and their privacy experts
handle the takedown immediately.
You get unlimited submissions.
So take your personal data back now
with Incogni.
Use code AmericanAlchemy
at Incogni.com
slash AmericanAlchemy
for 60% off an annual plan.
Again, that's code AmericanAlchemy
at Incogni.com
slash AmericanAlchemy.com for 60% off.
Take your online privacy back today.
Before we hit play on Sentinels of Aether,
we need to roll the tape back on Jake Barber.
We were running operations, let's say,
more attuned for the UAP.
Because before there was ever a manuscript,
there was an operation.
Jake worked for a private company
embedded inside legacy aerospace.
Need to know operations.
No questions asked.
But Jake's routine missions
for his employer
gradually evolved
into something more ominous.
He was sent on what looked like
a high-stakes scavenger hunt,
tracked down some missing
Panasonic Toughbooks,
ruggedized laptops
meant to endure extreme environments.
And it's believed on these Toughbooks
was highly sensitive information
that was evidence to CR programs.
Sensor data and video footage
that might be classified
and incriminating proof
of UFO crash retrieval operations.
We received human intelligence
that gave us the intel package
we needed to pursue
where we thought
the first set of Toughbooks might be.
A recovery team was sent
and we found the Toughbooks.
I'm not going to say where.
And we returned them to our employer.
The Toughbooks were missing the hard drives.
We then set out to recover the hard drives.
Our human asset led us
to another location
high in the Sierras,
which was a glacier lake.
And the hard drives
were sealed in a steel container
like 25 feet underwater.
Don Paul Bales,
a 25-year military
and law enforcement veteran,
later confirmed
that he worked under Jake
on this same operation.
Technically, I did not work for them.
I worked for Jacob.
And by the next mission,
something felt off.
He was given a new intel contact,
new coordinates,
a new chain of command.
The whole operation
had a different fingerprint.
When his team finally reached
the target location,
an ambush was waiting.
The next mission we went out on,
I'll just tell you that
shots were fired
and we called bullshit.
And that's when we began
to backtrack
and set out with our own effort
to find out exactly
who we were working for
and what they were interested in.
From an insider leak,
we now know that the programs
documented on these Toughbooks
used temporary flight restrictions
to clear the skies,
lure UFOs in,
and bring them down
with EMP weaponry.
For the uninitiated,
EMP means
electromagnetic pulse.
It's basically
the electromagnetic fallout
you would experience
with a nuke
without the nuclear blast.
But it gets even darker.
Apparently,
civilian aircraft
had also been taken down
after entering
this restricted airspace
with the bodies
and wreckage disposed of.
If even a fraction of that
was sitting on those Toughbooks,
they were a massive liability.
Not only did Jake's employer
want to destroy the Toughbooks
with evidence of crash retrievals,
they also wanted to destroy him.
The plausible deniability button
that people at the top
can hit
in order to protect themselves
would sever us
as the hidden hand.
So Jake does
what any good operative does
when the mission burns.
He burns it back.
He and his teammate
turned their special ops spy craft
back against their own employer
and indirectly,
the UFO legacy program itself.
Jake's weapon of choice
isn't a gun.
It's a manuscript.
And DOPSR,
the Defense Department
pre-publication review,
is the system designed
to silence him.
For most people,
it's a muzzle.
But Jake turns it
into a Trojan horse.
He teams up with a ghostwriter
and begins crafting the manuscript,
then slices it into 20-page chunks
and feeds them to DOPSR.
The first round took six months
and came back
with seven pages of redactions.
Instead of killing his story,
the redactions only served
to confirm it.
You see,
Jake used the redaction process
backwards
as a discovery tool.
Normally,
you know it's classified
and you avoid it.
But Jake submitted material
he suspected was classified,
then watched
what the Pentagon blacked out.
By drip-feeding chapters,
he could see which lines
made the Pentagon flinch,
adjust,
probe,
and slip real facts
about the UFO legacy program
into the public domain
under the camouflage
of fiction.
The manuscript
becomes a Trojan horse.
The Pentagon's own bureaucracy
becomes the delivery mechanism.
And buried in the pages
is a trail of breadcrumbs
hidden in plain sight.
For most readers,
it's just a thriller.
But for those who know
what to look for,
it's a cipher
waiting for the right eyes
to crack it open.
And the clock starts ticking.
Out in the badlands,
just north of Kuyame, Mexico,
Earth looks a lot like Mars.
Mesas ripped sideways
from tectonic violence.
Rust and bone-white rock layers
streak down canyon walls.
Boulders sit in bizarrely
impossible stacks
like a Martian sculptor
played Jenga with geology.
There's no light pollution here.
No highway glow.
No city haze.
When the sun drops,
it's just you,
the desert floor,
and the whole galaxy
staring back at you.
Which means if you don't
want to be seen,
this is the perfect place
to disappear.
Welcome to Enigmatic Kuyame,
population 1,230.
On paper,
it's a sleepy border town.
But ask around,
and it's Mexico's Roswell.
And that's not hyperbole.
It's literally the title
of a book
by researchers Noe Torres
and Ruben Uriarte,
who both documented
decades of strange activity
in the area.
Locals constantly talk
about colored lights
that wink in and out
around the mountain peaks.
Little orbs and square objects
that seem to come
out of the landscape itself.
And then there's the big one.
In 1974,
Kuyame became the setting
for one of the strangest
crash stories on record.
A mid-air collision
between a small Mexican plane
and a UFO.
A Mexican recovery team
raced to the site
but never came back.
According to the leaked report
that surfaced in the 90s,
the whole Mexican team
ends up dead.
And the mystery object
is airlifted out
by U.S. forces.
If you're imaginative,
you might wonder
if Kuyame wasn't
just a crash site,
but has long been a sandbox
for clandestine ops.
Perfectly isolated,
with weird geology
very good at hiding doorways
to things
that aren't supposed
to exist.
The locals,
they don't talk
about the lights anymore.
And if you ask
too many questions,
you might find out why.
Alex McEwen, Tier 1 Operator.
11 years in America's most elite units.
Tonight, he's alone.
Escorting two dozen refugees
through jagged desert terrain.
Women and children
who will die
if he doesn't get them
to extraction.
They're early,
and his team
is still behind him somewhere.
Extraction without the unit
wasn't the plan.
H1, I copy.
What is your 20?
Alex hits them
with a code
that's known
as a verbal IFF,
a code only people
on this classified op
should know.
Matchbox.
He gets the right answer,
so he waves
the refugees forward.
But here's what Alex
doesn't know.
These refugees
weren't just lucky enough
to have a Tier 1 escort.
Someone very powerful
wanted them here.
Barber claims
that some of these
Black Aerospace programs
had a very specific need.
People untouched
by modern civilization,
often from
Third World countries,
psychically uncorrupted,
and displaced people,
refugees,
victims of natural disaster,
they're perfect.
No passport,
no paper trail,
no one who'd know
if they went missing.
Fed into a UFO legacy operation
that most people
will never hear about.
All the program would need
is a reason for them
to disappear
that no one would question.
A natural disaster
works just fine.
So does border crossing.
So does geopolitical conflict.
That's when Alex sees it.
A second helicopter,
even bigger,
carrying a steel
Konex shipping container
with a mini-split HVAC unit
bolted to its roof,
slung beneath the chopper
like a coffin on a hook.
According to Barber,
this is how they moved them.
These refugees
aren't being rescued,
they are the cargo.
Three figures materialize
from the dust.
They move fast,
efficient,
predatory.
Alex knows immediately.
These aren't friendlies
coming to help.
Their gear is a Frankenstein
mashup of high-end helmets,
comms,
and lightweight armor.
One guy's pants
are tucked into
his Converse All-Stars.
Does this sound at all
like military to you?
Two men beeline for him
as the third heads up a hill
and shoulders a rifle
aimed at Alex's skull.
And then something happens
that chills Alex's blood.
They call him by name.
Alex!
His stomach drops.
That's when things go sideways.
They rip the rifle from him
and break it down
like a pit crew
before tossing it.
Don't even fucking blink, bro.
He's outgunned three to one
with a rifle pointed
directly at his head
from elevation.
They blindfold Alex
and zip-tie his wrists.
One of them pulls out
a strange handheld device,
something like a bioscanner.
He sweeps Alex with it
from head to toe.
A wand hunting for trackers
and biometric chips?
These guys are professionally trained,
not random desert smugglers.
He doesn't have it.
Man one steps close.
Man three holds the high ground,
rifle steady.
Man one raises his hand,
gives a silent signal,
and somewhere above,
a trigger is pulled.
A 7.62 round tears through Alex's right shoulder,
clavicle pulverized,
shattering bone and flesh.
A second signal and a second shot.
His throat explodes,
drowning in his own blood.
A third signal.
Third shot.
His face is obliterated.
His body drops back,
cold, lifeless,
face to the stars.
Or what's left of his face,
that is.
The entire universe of Alex McEwen
blinked out like a dying star,
sudden and violent.
Children bury their faces.
Some of the women don't look away.
It's almost as if they've seen worse.
Alex McEwen,
tier one operator,
patriot,
now just a corpse
in the Chihuahuan desert.
He believed he died serving his country.
But the men who killed him
were clearly serving something else.
Cut to Pope Air Force Base,
North Carolina.
We're inside
Joint Special Operations Command,
or JSOC,
their operations center.
Everyone's frozen.
The Secretary of Defense himself
is on the other end of the call.
And he is not happy.
Dale, what in the fuck
just happened out there?
General Dale Steinmaker,
commander of Joint Special Operations Command,
is wondering the exact same thing.
Uh, Mr. Secretary,
do you have agency guys
in Coyame, Mexico?
Why the fuck would I?
Everyone's at war.
Nobody should have been
in goddamn Mexico.
But the drone feed
tells a different story.
Someone just took out
an entire special mission unit
on JSOC's watch.
The Predator drone
had caught the whole ugly scene.
Alex's execution,
the refugees being loaded
into the shipping container,
and now the helicopters
lifting off into the desert,
human cargo in tow.
Are you suggesting
this is blue on blue?
Black on block, sir.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
The difference here matters.
Blue on blue is friendly fire.
Tragic, but explainable.
Black on black is a nightmare.
Covert operators
killing covert operators.
Shadow versus shadow.
Whoever did this
wasn't supposed to be there.
The thermal signatures
of six bodies
cool in the sand.
The combat controller
called for air support,
but bled out
mid-sentence.
All right, Vector F-18s
out of white sands.
I want every eye in the sky
on those helicopters.
Wherever they're going,
we're going there first.
Within minutes,
satellites pivot over Koyame.
Half a dozen airborne assets
spin up in Vector South.
Restricted Area 5107,
the largest military installation
in America.
3,200 square miles
of nothing but sand and secrets.
This is where they detonated Trinity,
the first atomic bomb.
July 16th, 1945.
Since then,
it's been a war game's wasteland.
Eagle One and Eagle Two.
Top Gun graduates
yanked off a training mission
and thrown straight
into the real thing.
Eagle Flight,
what is your loadout?
Sorry, gang.
We're fast, but not fatal.
Negative for ordnance.
How about a show of force instead?
Translation?
Scare the hell out of them
and force them to land.
Just don't kill them.
They want answers,
not corpses.
Five miles out,
the helicopters dropped
into a descent.
They sink below the canyon walls
and vanish.
Back in the war room,
the radar blip blinks out.
They lost radar contact.
Radar is line-of-sight technology.
Terrain blocks it.
Fly low enough,
hug the Earth tight enough,
and you disappear.
In skilled aviation circles,
this is called
nap of the Earth flying,
and these pilots know
exactly what they're doing.
Eagle One drops to 8,000 feet.
Night vision goggles on.
Scanning.
Bingo.
Tally 2.
Two helicopters,
and beneath the bigger one,
still spinning on its cable,
the container full of human cargo.
Eagle One calls them out
over guard frequency 243 megahertz,
the international emergency frequency,
and orders them to land.
Copter flight of two
with the external load
east of Coyama in Mexico.
This is a United's Navy F-18.
You are instructed to land immediately.
But the helicopters hold course,
refusing to ID yourself
and ignoring a Navy intercept.
Ballsy.
If this part is true,
we know more about
where to knock
and who to use
the Freedom of Information Act on,
NORAD under U.S. NORTHCOM,
JSOC through U.S. Special Operations Command,
plus the Navy.
And we know what to ask for.
Incident reports and air defense logs
on unknown aircraft
in the Koyama Corridor in 2004
that ignored guard frequency 243 megahertz
and blew off a Navy intercept.
Something I've noticed
doing this show for years
is that the biggest ideas
usually hinge on one strange specific detail.
Gary McKinnon describing a spreadsheet
of non-terrestrial officers.
Hal Puthoff explaining
why CIA remote viewers
tested their abilities
in deep waters on submarines.
Diana Pasolka realizing
that the Vatican Observatory
knew more about UFOs
than met the eye.
These are key details
that completely change
how you understand someone's story.
And if you're not capturing
those details,
they're gone.
I've been getting into
Plod Note Pro lately
exactly for this reason.
Because the same thing happens to me
outside the studio too.
I'll be walking around
thinking through something
a recent guest said on a podcast
and suddenly,
a connection clicks
between that and something
another guest said
two years earlier.
This is one of the clearest examples
I've found personally
of the real utility behind AI.
This product is ridiculously easy to use.
One press to start recording
and then I press it again
to highlight a moment
I want to come back to.
It will take comprehensive notes for you
about everything that transpires.
You can also add text notes or images
so it's not just raw audio
floating around somewhere.
Then when I get back home,
Plod turns everything I've said
into an organized summary
and I can actually ask questions
about what I recorded.
I can ask things like
what was that connection I made
between Thomas Townsend Brown
and time travel?
Or what was that thing I said
around the 10 minute mark
about Bob Lazar?
And Plod will pull the answer
directly from the recording.
That's the difference.
You're not just saving audio.
This isn't your average AI note taker.
You're building a searchable archive
of your own thoughts.
As you can see,
the Note Pro is credit card thin,
has up to 50 hours of battery,
and it handles both in-person conversations
and phone calls
without switching modes.
So head to plod.ai slash alchemy
to learn more.
That's P-L-A-U-D dot A-I slash alchemy
and use code ALCHEMY10 at checkout.
Thanks so much to Plod
for sponsoring today's episode.
But back to the story.
After the intercept doesn't work,
Eagle One decides to get their attention
the old-fashioned way.
But as he lines up the pass,
something's wrong.
The gorge dead ends into a mountain
so massive it eats the stars.
1,500 feet of vertical rock.
No way around,
no way over,
no escape.
So what is this?
A suicide run?
Then everything goes wrong at once.
In the war room,
the drone feed dies.
At the same time,
Eagle One's cockpit goes black.
Flight controls, dead.
Engines, dead.
200 feet from the ground,
at near supersonic speed,
the jet becomes a dead weight.
He has milliseconds to choose.
Ride the coffin into the mountain
or punch out at speeds
that can rip human bodies apart.
The math is ugly.
In an homage to the first man
to ever eject from a cockpit
at supersonic speeds,
he double grips the handle
and pulls.
8,000 feet above,
Eagle Two can't breathe.
His oxygen system is dead.
So are his generators.
He rips off his mask,
fighting through his own
electrical failure.
Systems flicker back online.
He looks down.
The jet's gone,
but the helicopters are still flying
straight at the face
of Mount Mexico.
Nice one here with your barrel in.
The mountainside starts to pixely.
It dissolves from 3D to 2D to nothing
as the helicopters slip through
and vanish from one world into another.
Entering a massive chamber
made of stone and steel beams.
Outside, the electromagnetic force field
re-energizes to the illusion
of solid rock.
To the outside world,
it looks like they vanished.
But inside, they've just arrived.
Home.
Call it a black site,
a breakaway base,
or something worse.
We don't have a name for it yet.
What we do have is a body count
that shouldn't exist.
And a story that leaves
more questions than answers.
An elite American operator
executed in the desert
by unknown forces
using U.S. authentication codes.
A JSOC mission
burned from the inside out.
A weapon system
that can surgically blast drones
and F-18s
with an electromagnetic pulse.
Missing refugees,
human beings,
loaded into a shipping container,
ferried by unmarked helicopters
across the desert,
and chased by U.S. fighter jets
to a holographic mountain in Mexico
that isn't a mountain,
but a door.
And behind it,
a secret underground facility.
The fact that the general
is asking the secretary of defense
if another agency
is running an unsanctioned op
in Mexico
tells us their worst fear.
The enemy isn't foreign.
It's domestic.
But it's not under normal
chains of command.
And if that's true,
then this isn't just a botched mission
in the Koyame Desert.
It's the tip of something
much bigger.
So who's really running this show?
And how deep does this
parallel world actually go?
A real hero.
June 12th, 2023.
The National Press Club event
in Washington, D.C.
After years embedded
in covert crash retrieval operations,
Jake attends
a National Press Club conference
hosted by Stephen Greer.
Thank you.
Stephen Greer is notorious
for getting in touch
with people on the inside
of the UFO Legacy program
and helping draw publicity
to their stories.
Usually, he's going
for the most disgruntled defectors.
Jake shows up at the event
and is there to red team
the whistleblowers.
We were actually sent there
on behalf of our employer
to look for whistleblowers
that we were trying to
basically report to the FBI
and get arrested
because at that time,
I was in this weird place
between becoming a whistleblower
or rounding up the whistleblowers
and shutting them up.
Essentially, figure out what they know,
do a threat assessment,
and report back to headquarters.
Somewhere out there
are a few missing
Panasonic Toughbooks
loaded with highly sensitive material,
and Jake thinks one of these guys
might be about to spill
what's on them.
Then, Michael Herrera
takes the stage.
Herrera was a Marine
with the 31st Marine
Expeditionary Unit.
He described a 2009 mission
in Indonesia,
a civilian evacuation
following a catastrophic
earthquake and tsunami.
Sounds kind of familiar, right?
In 2009, my unit,
which was the most decorated
infantry battalion
in the entire Marine Corps,
which was 2nd Battalion,
5th Marines,
was called in to do
humanitarian assistance operations
out in the Philippines,
which was Operation Kitsana.
His unit was flown deep
into the jungle
with no comms,
no signal,
and no civilians.
His six-man team
pushes to high ground,
to a hill thick with vegetation,
and that's when they see it,
a craft.
And right there
was something that stuck out
like a sore thumb,
especially with jungle terrain,
things like that,
you know,
vegetation,
very green stuff,
was something that stuck out
so well.
It's always going to be
basically imprisoned in my mind
for the rest of my life,
and it has been for 14 years,
was something that was rotating,
and it was transitioning
between colors
like a light matte gray,
as well as a dark matte black.
So in between,
that's what it kept,
and it was very smooth.
You can see that the craft here
actually had,
it was roughly about 300 feet.
And the reason why I know this
is because
you could fit three of the helicopters
that we flew in on
underneath this craft.
300 feet across,
octagonal matte,
or what he describes
as Vanta black.
It's so black
that it almost looks
like dark matter,
like light itself
isn't interacting
with this craft.
It hovers just above the canopy
with a subsonic hum.
Before they can process
what they're looking at,
they're intercepted.
An eight-man paramilitary unit,
no insignias,
no IDs,
moving in fast,
rehearsed,
and ready to kill.
They disarm the Marines,
scan them with a bioscanner,
and hold them at gunpoint.
The message is clear.
You were not supposed to see this,
and if you talk,
we will kill you.
I know what you're thinking.
The Indonesian jungle
sounds a lot like
the Mexican desert.
While this is all happening,
Herrera sees some trucks roll up
with shipping containers
and HVACs mounted on top.
He assumed they were moving drugs,
but hearing Michael Herrera's testimony,
Jake knew better.
He had the missing piece
of Michael's puzzle.
I have no first-hand experience
with that operation,
nor direct contact
with anyone involved with it.
I know of that type of operation.
I know of that craft.
I know of those containers.
He'd seen those containers before.
Those units that they used
are consistent with the workstations
we use when we're out on the range.
There are many split HVAC systems
that are used up there.
And they weren't hauling drugs.
They were hauling people.
Kids.
There are operations OCONUS
outside the continental United States
where prospecting for psionic assets
takes place,
and they're highly coveted.
And the interesting thing is,
is I hear in those programs
that there's something valuable
about the life experience
in third-world countries
in that it seems as though
people that live a simpler life
and are outdoors more
and have less contaminants
in their food and their drugs
and in their culture
seem to be a little bit better
at disassociating
and heightening their intuition.
Remember the refugees
from Jake's manuscript?
Those were psionic assets
being funneled into programs
that don't exist on any budget.
People being forced
into heightened states of consciousness
in order to summon UFOs.
How in the hell do you get
like the humans?
And they say,
oh no, it is natural disasters.
They said actually, sadly,
the unaccompanied minor crisis
and the caravans
that just had like kind of
unaccountable swaths of humans
in Central America
running up through the Darien Gap
and across the U.S.-Mexico border.
And then they said the Ukraine war.
Jake knew Michael Herrera was legit.
I saw a good Marine up there
when I saw Mike.
I saw a brother in arms
doing his best
to be put now
with a microphone in his face
in a fucking suit and tie
in Washington, D.C.
when he's cut out
to be carrying a saw
through the jungle.
And now he's doing his best
and he's an honest, good guy
and I wasn't going to let him hang.
So instead of continuing
to red team Michael
and run counter intel on him,
he decided to join forces.
We know that the CIA's
Office of Global Access
is rumored to coordinate closely
with JSOC and NEST
or Nuclear Emergency Support Teams
for UFO crash retrievals.
We also know that the Department of Energy
has protective forces,
elite units with legal authority
under the Atomic Energy Act
to move and guard
highly sensitive material
outside the normal DoD chain of command.
They're described as elite fighting forces
that operate in all combat environments.
The protective forces here
are recruited by private companies,
but trained and commanded
by Defense Nuclear Security,
a program under the Department of Energy's
National Nuclear Security Administration.
Were these the guys
who threatened Herrera in the jungle?
We don't know,
but it sounds like
from the lack of insignias
and mismatched uniforms,
it's likely some Black World paramilitary
belonging to a private defense contractor
and one that's designed
to be completely untraceable
and confuse anybody it runs into.
So if you're running
an unacknowledged Black World hit squad,
where do you park it?
You need more than a base.
You need a mirage.
And these are the last words
he told me.
He said,
Jim,
we have things out in the desert
that's 50 years beyond
what you can comprehend,
and he knows I can comprehend
a hell of a lot.
So what's going on here?
Let's start with the obvious theory.
It's just a hologram.
We know that the military's been flirting
with holographic warfare
for decades.
In 1999,
reporter William Arkin
wrote an article about
a 1994 Air Force concept
for a holographic projector,
massive 3D illusions in the sky,
intended for PSYOPs.
As a side note,
people should deeply investigate
this tech tree,
especially as it concerns
normal UFO sightings.
The problem here is
a partial mountain-sized 3D hologram
visible from multiple angles
is an insane power bill.
You're talking brutal energy requirements
just to fake a rock.
And yet,
the lore runs deep.
Billionaire UFO enthusiast
Robert Bigelow
says that Bob Lazar
described a holographic book
at S-4 Area 51
that's like an alien Kindle.
Bob's story
is so much more in-depth,
so much more detailed,
like that book.
Tell people about the book?
It was some kind of a holographic book
that as you opened up the pages,
whatever the stories were
became a hologram.
Stephen Greer talks about
a whistleblower
who allegedly saw Raytheon
projecting UFO-like craft
as a part of a false invasion scenario.
Here is the Raytheon Triangle
at Fort Irwin.
That is man-made.
Wow.
And the guy who saw it
in detail,
because he picked up some night skips
he was told not to,
saw that there was this one
and then they were holographically
projecting several others.
Wow.
This could be used
in a false alien invasion,
you know,
like a hoaxed invasion.
And then that later,
he and his wife
got abducted
by this thing.
Yeah.
And tortured.
Whoa.
And it was Raytheon.
Then you have whistleblowers
like Randy Anderson,
who says he was taken underground
at Crane Naval Surface
Warfare Center
in Indiana
and shown a metallic gauntlet
with a crystalline screen.
And above it,
symbols that looked
almost holographic.
I'm looking at it
and it almost looked
like a mirage
type of effect.
And above that display screen
were these hieroglyphic symbols
that I started to see appear.
The projection appeared
integrated into reality itself,
far more advanced
than normal holograms.
So advanced hologram tech?
Maybe.
But Koyame does get hammered
by thunderstorms
during monsoon season.
And a giant mountainside light show
feels like the last thing
you'd ever want
riding on perfect weather.
One glitch
and your billion dollar cover
is blown.
So that's a lot of faith
to put into a hologram.
So what if it's something
that seems like a hologram
but isn't?
Back in the day,
I used to chug coffee
like I was prepping
for a quantum jump.
But then I'd crash
like my nervous system
got slingshotted
through a kaleidoscope.
Anxiety spiking,
aura flickering,
and REM sleep
never met her.
It was like drinking battery acid
on an empty stomach.
Then I found mud water.
It doesn't fry my circuits
or my synapses.
I use mud water's
original blend over ice.
It still has a little bit
of caffeine,
but it's stacked
with adaptogens
and nootropics
like L-theanine,
chaga,
lion's mane,
cacao,
the whole earth squad
to keep you
naturally energized
and to ensure
that you don't wake up
with the morning scaries.
One sip of mud water
and my cells report
for duty.
Two sips
and boom,
I'm plugged into
the fungal starfleet.
All systems go.
So are you ready
to make the switch
to cleaner energy?
Head to mudwater.com
that's M-U-D-W-T-R
dot com
and grab your
starter kit today.
It's M-U-D-W-T-R
dot com.
Right now,
our listeners
get an exclusive deal
up to 43%
off your entire order
plus free shipping
and a free
rechargeable frother
when you use
code JESSE
at checkout.
That's right,
up to 43%
off with code JESSE,
that's J-E-S-S-E
at mudwater,
M-U-D-W-T-R
dot com.
After your purchase,
they'll ask you
how you found them.
Please show your support
and let them know
we sent you.
So what if it's something
that seems like
a hologram
but isn't?
What I'm talking about
is a little technology
known as foglets
or utility fog.
Now we have to add
an asterisk here.
This technology
is theoretical.
So let's treat this
as a thought experiment.
Imagine robots
the size of glitter,
roughly 100 microns,
that don't just build things,
they become things.
Billions of tiny robots
lock arms
in 12 directions
to form objects
on command.
Then dissolve
and reshape
into something
completely different.
Remember the liquid metal
Terminator
from Terminator 2?
That shape-shifting assassin
that could morph on command?
Nanotechnology foglets
could make that real.
And that's not just
sci-fi fan fiction.
In 1989,
scientist Dr. J. Storrs Hall
pitched the concept
of utility fog,
an active polymorphic material
made up of trillions
of foglets
that link together
to form solid,
programmable matter.
In 1993,
he doubled down on it
with a paper
that was published
at a NASA conference.
Here's how it works.
Each foglet
is armed
with its own
extremely rudimentary
nanocomputer
and can talk
to its neighbors.
They can share power,
data,
and rearrange themselves
into almost anything.
A mountain
should be pretty easy.
Hall claims
you could actually
push this technology
to the point
of creating
a virtual world around you.
You'd essentially
get Star Trek's holodeck,
one that could actually
cut you
and make you bleed.
That's a direct quote
from him.
All of the stuff
you want
out of a material,
an intelligent
morphing material,
can be done
simply by expanding
or contracting
the material
and controlling
that at a scale
that ranges
from seconds
to milliseconds.
Unlike holograms,
foglets have
a physical presence.
They could be
your magic carpet,
push you on a swing,
shield you,
slap you,
or even become
your best friend
if you really
want to get weird.
You could punch
a foglet mountain
and break your hand,
but program it
to recognize you
and open sesame.
They're essentially
programmable matter,
solid or permeable
on demand.
They could fake
the gritty feel
of sandstone
and layered rock
by dialing in
just the right
micro-vibrations
for your skin
to read as solid stone.
But there's a catch.
In Hall's original design,
his foglets
looked more like snow,
not ideal for mimicking
a desert mountain.
But in interviews
and other technical write-ups,
he says his design
could be enhanced
with light-emitting antennae
to match color
and optical properties
in real time.
Add that upgrade,
run the foglets
in pixel mode,
and the outer skin
basically becomes
a 3D TV screen,
blending into
whatever you want it to.
Now look at how
the story describes
the mountain's behavior.
That's our next big tell
that we might not be
dealing with
a simple hologram.
As the helicopters
are about to collide
with the mountainside,
its 3D appearance
transitions to 2D,
then pixelates
into nothing.
If upgraded foglets
exist,
and that is a big if,
we are admittedly
engaging in extreme
speculation here.
So you should accept
that caveat.
But if they exist,
this is the behavior
you might expect to see.
As the helicopters close in,
foglets would start
shifting formation,
half their arms
staying locked
in lattice formation,
while the rest
drop out of rock mode
as the mountainside
dissolves into flickering
patches like pixels
on a screen.
From the cockpit,
it would look like
a 3D mountainside,
flattening into a weird,
shimmering 2D skin
that breaks into pixels
and dissolves
as the helicopter
passes through.
The low-frequency pulsing
in the crew's headsets
is another clue.
It's not ambient sound,
so one possibility
is strong radio frequency
emissions bleeding
into their radio gear,
a glitch that's known
as audio rectification.
If foglets were adapted
for the real world,
they'd likely be upgraded
with wireless,
real-time communication
for swarm coordination.
So imagine trillions
of foglets moving
in coordinated waves,
unlocking, shifting
antenna arms,
and cycling their
electrical states.
That kind of swarm
could generate
the strong radio emissions
and an audible pulsing
you'd hear in your headset.
A hologram wouldn't
do any of this.
Remember, in the novel,
the drone and the F-18s
suddenly lose power,
while the helicopters
slip right through
the mountain, untouched.
In theory, if the mountain
is really a trillion
little foglets,
each spec with its own brain,
sensors, and comms,
they could act like a living
electromagnetic warfare system.
With each cubic inch
packing 16 million processors,
they could jam
specific signals,
bleed power from drones
while leaving others untouched,
and run friend or foe codes
so only approved aircraft
get a clean pass.
returning helicopters
could transmit the right codes
to slip through,
giving everyone else
power failure
and a not-so-gentle escort
into the dirt.
Now, this mountain
in Sentinels of Aether
could also be pure fiction.
But crafts vanishing
into mountains
is a documented phenomenon,
especially in places
like the Uinta Basin.
If something lets objects
slip through
what looks like solid rock,
we're probably beyond
conventional technology
and already playing
in the Black World sandbox.
Foglets are just my best guess,
but they aren't some
wild stoner fantasy either.
The DIA has openly mused
about programmable matter
for camouflage and invisibility.
In the 1990s to 2000s,
the idea of smart dust
caught fire among
sci-fi nerds everywhere,
including some feds at DARPA
who began funding research
on millimeter-scale
autonomous sensing
and communication nodes.
While utility fog
is still theoretical,
the building blocks
were active research areas
back then.
By 2001,
DARPA was demonstrating
smart dust in field tests.
By 2004, MEMS,
or Microelectromechanical Systems
technology,
had matured significantly.
Publicly, we know
about DARPA's smart dust
and creepy biohybrid
insect cyborgs,
but in the Black World,
we have no idea
what exists.
Hall himself,
again the creator
of this concept,
has warned that
a lot of the work
needed for real nanotech
got actively suppressed,
which is why we're
a bit behind
on Star Trek replicators
and nano assemblers.
And let's not forget
about the Invention Secrecy Act
of 1951.
This lets Uncle Sam
classify and bury
both government
and private inventions,
including patent applications
in the name
of national security.
If something like
utility fog exists
in a classified program,
filing a patent
would amount to disclosure.
So there's a reason
no patents exist.
The whole point
of special access programs
is to keep
these capabilities hidden.
You wouldn't telegraph
that you've solved
molecular nanotechnology.
If you want to keep
something a secret,
you don't file.
And then you have
Ben Rich,
former head of
Lockheed Skunk Works,
saying things like,
we already have the means
to travel among the stars,
but these technologies
are locked up
in black projects
and it would take
an act of God
to ever get them out
to benefit humanity.
Anything you can imagine,
we already know
how to do.
Rich even claimed,
we have things out
in the desert
that are 50 years
beyond what you
could possibly comprehend.
If you've seen it
on Star Wars
or Star Trek,
we've been there
and done that.
He also admitted
that there are people
in the intelligence world
who want this
breakthrough technology
to stay in the black forever.
And he's saying this
in 1995,
the same era
Hall is pitching
utility fog to NASA.
So if Rich is right,
then by the early 2000s,
the public was still
gawking at smart dust
while some special access
program buried
in the desert
might have been playing
with full-blown
programmable matter,
the kind of tech
that could absolutely
fake a mountain.
Just look at what
Ross Coulthart
and his sources
have said
about Bradshaw Ranch
in Arizona.
There is a portal
in the United States.
In fact,
I suspect there are multiple.
But this particular portal
is in a highly guarded facility
that is used
under the U.S. Forest Service cover.
There are men
with guns
who patrol it
and there are witnesses
who have seen
people walking
into literally
a wall.
So we have craft
moving in and out
of a mountain.
We even have people
walking through walls.
Now let's talk psionics,
the psychic summoning
of UFOs,
Jake Barber's secret sauce.
We're told,
and there's a whole movie
made about it,
debunking the idea
of telepathy
and psychics
and psionics.
And yet you've only
got to read
the CIA gateway documents
in the CIA files
and they show that
that's actually not true.
Yes.
That essentially
everybody took it
very, very seriously.
Jake Barber told Herrera
that the paramilitary unit
he encountered
was transporting
psionic assets,
people with special
intuitive abilities.
What is real
is the ability
to go into something
like a meditative state
and summon UAP
and pilot UAP.
That is real.
That's 100% real.
Wow.
I have to process
that for a moment
because that is just
the most extraordinary claim.
He calls them P3s
or psionic predisposition potential.
These aren't
your average recruits.
He personally sees it
less like human trafficking
and more like elite recruitment
into specialized programs.
Although admittedly,
reading a lot of these stories
makes me pretty concerned
about human rights violations.
So when these P3s
or psionic assets
are recruited,
what do they actually do?
Jake describes them
as intuitives,
trained like assets
in remote viewing,
telekinesis,
and the whole psychic toolkit.
All of this is honed
through specific protocols.
Their job is to tap
into what he calls
the consciousness field.
Think of it
like a cosmic
worldwide web,
full of information
everywhere,
all the time,
invisible
until you access it.
A P3 is the receiver,
the Wi-Fi antenna.
According to Jake,
there are two main
attraction methods.
Machine-based systems,
signals or energy systems
that act like a beacon
or dog whistle.
After we turn on
the dog whistle,
UAPs literally come to us
day after day.
Or our manned-based systems,
trained psionics
projecting an invitation
through the field,
essentially calling to
whatever's monitoring it.
To train a psionic asset,
you have to shut down
the overthinking brain
and let intuition run point.
Children are naturally
better at this
since they're usually
more intuitive.
Basically the plot
of Stranger Things,
psychic kids being tested
at Department of Energy
National Labs.
Jake's consciousness-based
attraction method
is very similar
to Stephen Greer's
coherent thought sequencing,
the core technique
in his CE5 protocol.
It's a meditation-based
invitation system
built on a similar premise,
consciousness as a
communication channel.
Now I know Greer
can be polarizing.
At times he can be
self-aggrandizing
and just plain wrong
about a whole lot.
But he's stayed
remarkably consistent
on this one thing
for decades.
And his contributions
to UFO disclosure
are incontrovertible.
His system is all about
non-local consciousness
and laser-focused thought
with love and peace
as the carrier signal.
You basically run
a cosmic Google Maps
in your mind's eye,
zooming in
with mental imagery
until you've dropped
a pin on your exact spot.
According to Greer,
the craft picks up
on a directed
coherent thought signal
as clearly as a radio
would pick up
on an electromagnetic signal.
Remember the words
of Lockheed's Ben Rich,
who said exotic propulsion systems
work the same way ESP works.
All points in time and space
are connected.
Mind, body, and craft
integrated as one.
Here's the basics
of how it works.
Coherent thought sequencing
is like sending out
your address
by visually guiding the craft
to your location
through your mind's eye.
You're essentially
remote viewing space
and then zooming in
on your physical location.
It actually even helps
to use Google Earth beforehand
to accurately visualize
aerial shots of your location
so your mental zoom-in
is razor sharp.
Here are the basics.
Sit down.
Close your eyes.
Breathe.
Now zoom out
and expand into space.
The stars shimmer
as you scan the star field,
remote viewing the cosmos.
In a galaxy not so far away
is our very own
spiraling Milky Way.
Push in on a twinkling dot
on its arm.
Flash forward
to our solar system.
Eight planets orbit the sun.
Earth lights up.
Dive towards our planet Earth.
Continents come into view.
North America.
The United States.
Your state lights up.
Pin drop your city.
Zoom in over your town.
Drop into a God's eye view
of your neighborhood,
street,
the roof you're under,
and finally,
your exact spot.
Down to the chair
you're sitting in.
You are the pin drop
on their map,
broadcasting into the cosmos
like a laser pointer.
In this model,
UFOs are directly coupled
to their observer's consciousness.
You're linking
to both the ship's mind
and its navigation system
and feeding it
a visual vector
it can lock onto.
Optionally,
if you have a legal,
safe line of sight
and no aircraft
in your sky,
you can tag your location
with a low-power laser
into the star field overhead.
Never shine a laser
at aircraft
or anywhere near
their flight path.
That's a federal crime.
So if you use this technique,
use it responsibly.
I would also add
that your internal state
before trying this
is incredibly important.
If you're going
through a rough time
or you have any sort
of ulterior motives,
you will probably get burned.
Those negative emotions
inside of you
might get amplified
by the contact experience.
Calling these things
into your purview
can be very dangerous.
As with all of this stuff,
there's a left-hand path
and there's the right way
to do it.
But in its best instantiation,
the idea is
by extending
your consciousness outwards,
you become a lighthouse.
You can essentially invite
and lead the craft to you.
When done in teams,
again with a good vibe
and intention
associated with it,
you can amplify the signal
through collective focus,
multiple minds,
one address.
It's kind of like
a synchronized love beam
blasting straight
into the fabric of space-time.
But here is where
it gets dark.
There's just no way
to put lipstick on this pig.
Jake personally remembers
an incident transporting
a craft where his consciousness
was disrupted,
possibly because
a psionic asset's consciousness
was stuck inside the craft,
or because the craft itself
had a consciousness
that connected to him
while flying it
to its drop point.
There are some
potential issues
that can happen
if the psionic asset
is still connected
to the craft.
I hooked up.
As I'm flying back
to the drop site,
I'm like completely overwhelmed.
I'm like bawling my eyes out,
flying a helicopter
at night,
like trying not to run
into mountains and shit,
and I'm like,
oh my God,
this is not good.
I just felt like
I was in the presence
of my mother.
It was like a feminine energy
that was loving and sad,
and I don't know what it was.
In leaks passed to the pseudonymous
researcher Joey is not my name
in 2023 by Michael Herrera,
relayed to him through an insider
we can now safely assume
is Jake Barber
before he went public,
he paints a very grim reality.
While psionic assets
are taught how to communicate
with ET
and interface with ET tech,
they're also chipped
with a small tracking device
and given a lot of heavy drugs,
because you have to be
in a very positive,
calm,
happy mental state
in order to do it.
After several years
of this experimentation
and drug use,
a lot of these people die
or slip into a coma.
These people are essentially
treated like biological equipment,
maintained and then replaced
when worn out.
Historically and on the inside,
the term sometimes informally used
for psionic assets
at these sites
is pink assets.
They've essentially been treated
like experimental human meat.
I'm sure many of these programs
are run differently,
some might be far more ethical
than others,
but let's just call a spade
a spade here.
As Jake has explained,
psionic flight doesn't come
without risks
and it gets weirder.
Allegedly,
any random member
of this unacknowledged
special access program
can't just hop in
and fly a UFO
if he's not psionically gifted.
He'll get the silent treatment.
The craft won't talk to him.
It simply won't show up.
According to this leak,
in order to fly
some of the ET craft,
it has to be done
through consciousness.
A black group pilot
can't fly an ET craft directly
if he doesn't have
the psionic abilities.
So they devised a way
to connect a psionic person
to an advanced
brain-machine interface
where the pilot
can control the machine
to control the person's intentions.
And in turn,
control the ET craft.
The psionic asset's mind
turns into a psychic joystick.
So this is where things
get even weirder
and more multi-layered.
There's a pilot
behind this psionic asset
that flies the UFO
through the psionic asset,
using the psionic asset's brain
to route the UFO,
commanding it
through a machine
which converts those commands
into neural patterns
in the psionic's brain,
the craft's readable language.
The psionic asset
becomes a biological interface,
a human drone
wired into an exotic control system.
No psionic equals no flight.
Pretty insane, right?
Except the black world
has been hinting
at this for years.
Let's go back again
to Lockheed Skunk Works CEO
Ben Rich,
who allegedly compared
advanced propulsion
to ESP,
or extrasensory perception.
Instant, nonlinear connections
across spacetime.
And then there's
UFO whistleblower Don Phillips,
also tied to Lockheed Skunk Works,
saying that UFOs
are a full-body connection
and that humanity
has the quickest computer
built into them.
Humanity has the quickest
computer built into them
than any man-made computer
can ever approach,
and that includes
the Cray computer.
Phillips also riffs
on the Firefox movie's
mind-controlled helmet.
Firefox,
the most devastating
killing machine
ever built.
The weapon system
is one of the most
advanced ever conceived
with a thought-guided,
thought-controlled arsenal
on board the plane.
Think your commands.
Steer with your eyes.
Fire with pure thought.
And then there's
Philip J. Corso,
who claimed to be
at the Pentagon
in the 50s,
doling out UFO materials
into the civil
or private side world.
He claimed the technology
ended up in places
like Bell Labs.
But he and his son,
who has spent time
with past American
alchemy guest Danny Sheehan,
have talked about
a helmet with which
you could steer
a UFO with your mind.
The fact that the UFOs
appear to be navigated
telepathically,
for example,
and that the craft
have built into it
some kind of an AI capacity
to respond telepathically
to the control
of the pilot.
Now that's pretty far out.
Thanks to leaps
in data signal technology,
it might be reality.
For Lockheed's Don Phillips,
it's proof that technology
is finally catching up
to the fastest,
most powerful processor
in existence,
the human mind,
on certain dimensions
involving intuition,
still miles ahead
of any machine ever built,
even with large language models.
So one Lockheed insider
calls the human body
a supercomputer
that can command aircraft
with thought,
while another says
exotic propulsion
works like ESP.
Suddenly,
Jake's story
doesn't sound so crazy.
But there's more proof
Jake Barber
isn't out of his mind.
His story would have made
a lot of sense
to John Norseen,
a former Navy pilot
turned neuroengineer
and weapons designer
for Lockheed Martin.
This is a man
who is funded by NASA
and DARPA
for mind-reading research.
In 1999,
Norseen published
a report on biofusion,
a system he later described
involving brain-computer interfaces
that convert thoughts
into commands.
No joystick or buttons.
You just think
and the aircraft moves.
According to a man
named Doug Pasternak
who interacted with him,
Norseen believed
that a pilot
could fly a plane
by merely thinking.
Basically,
no delay,
no latency.
For example,
when you say
write 090 degrees,
the computer maps
the pilot's electrical pattern
in the brain
and turns the pilot
090 degrees.
And if there's a mistake
and the pilot
processes 080 degrees,
the helmet
catches the mistake
and injects
the right number
into the pilot's mind.
Electromagnetic waves
straight to the dome.
This is the tamest part
of Norseen's work.
His theory describes
systems that could
push your brain
into any target state.
Aggression,
calm,
focus,
ecstasy.
I'm sure there are
tons of implications
for this work
for CIA mind control programs
like MKUltra,
but let's stick to UFOs.
According to his colleague,
Duncan Lurie,
Norseen theorized
that every thought
leaves an energy
dispersion pattern.
He called it
a brain print,
like a fingerprint,
but for cognition.
Intent,
emotion,
fear,
joy.
Each one has a pattern,
not a static image,
but something more
like a posture,
a configuration
your brain holds
that produces
an action or state.
So if thoughts
or brain states
leave patterns,
how exactly
do you capture them?
As Norseen explained,
think of your hand
touching a mirror.
It leaves a fingerprint.
That's what
biofusion does.
It maps these brain prints
using mathematical models.
Just like you can find
one person in a million
through fingerprints,
you can find one thought
in a million.
He wanted to build
a full dictionary
of these brain prints.
The system learns
what your brain looks like
when you want to turn left,
speed up,
tilt,
and stop.
It doesn't just read you.
It maps you.
In theory,
if you know the math
of a brain pattern,
you can potentially run it
back into the brain
and get the same state
or feeling.
You can think of biofusion
like a brain-computer interface
on steroids.
Now here's where
it gets interesting.
A technical write-up
by Autonomous019
cites an internal
Lockheed Martin R&D report
by John Norseen
called
Biofusion Reflexive Control
in Neuroergonomic Integration
and Adaptive Cockpits.
According to Norseen's citation,
that report was funded
under the contract
N66001.
I'll spare you
the rest of the numbers.
This is the same contract
that NASA describes
as an Aviation Weather
Information Systems project.
And that N66001 prefix
traces back to the Navy's
Space and Naval Warfare
Systems Center
in San Diego,
today known as
the Naval Information
Warfare Center.
So it appears
we have a NASA-Navy hybrid
and not too far
from where the Nimitz
Tic-Tac sighting
occurred in 2004.
Looked on a small
saw-white Tic-Tac object
with a longitudinal axis
pointing north-south
and moving very abruptly
over the water.
The same sighting
that Ross Coulthart
swears involved
a Lockheed craft.
I now know categorically
that the Tic-Tac
is Lockheed Martin technology.
On the surface,
John Norseen's work
looks like it somehow
made it into a NASA
weather contract.
But it lines up
with a mirrored
Lockheed Martin document
from around 2000
that lists his
Biofusion R&D report
with the same contract number.
Multiple independent references
all point to the same thing.
Norseen's Biofusion
Neurocockpit work
was riding under that contract.
I guess if you had a project
that involves flying UFOs
via mind control,
it makes sense
you might bury it
inside a weather program.
By the early 2000s,
Norseen's work
basically vanishes
from public view.
And not long after,
he does too,
under very strange circumstances.
Shortly before a planned lecture
at the Naval War College
in Newport,
he emailed colleagues
a cryptic line
about his future talk.
He had sent me an email
and said,
and some of the other people
from Ann's,
and he said,
listen,
I'm giving a lecture
on my latest research
at the Naval College
in Newport.
Do you want a VIP pass
to come and attend it?
And I was like,
oh yeah.
So he said,
okay,
I'll get it all set up.
And then at the end
of his email,
you know,
he was into,
I forget what the term
is for this kind of
use of language.
Semiotics.
Semiotics, yeah.
He was really into that.
And at the last sentence
in his email said,
Nor,
he said,
I RV'd the upcoming
lecture,
John not heard
nor seen.
Whoa.
And I remember calling Ann
and saying,
hey Ann,
what the heck
does this last sentence mean?
John not heard nor seen.
I know he's in the
semiotics and stuff,
so, you know,
not nor seen
is his last name,
but John not heard
nor seen.
And then just like
two weeks after that,
he was found dead
in a motel room.
Jesus Christ.
So that was some sort
of code where it's like
he remote viewed
his own death.
He remote viewed it
and he wasn't there.
And this was code
to say he's not heard
nor seen.
Yeah.
I mean,
what else could that mean?
Oh my God.
Nor seen was gone,
but the kind of work
he was doing wasn't.
And roughly 20 years later,
they resurface,
but in a different form.
Enter Lockheed Martin
engineers Charles Chase
and Gerald Jonas
with a patent called
Cognitive Enhancement
Using Feedback.
I've personally had
the pleasure of meeting
Charles Chase
and think he's a genius.
And this patent
might sound boring
on the face of it,
but it's not.
It's describing
a closed loop system
that reads your brain waves,
compares them
to a target brain state,
and then hits you
with light,
sound,
or electromagnetic pulses
until your brain
is nudged
towards that target,
like a tuning fork
for the human mind.
It's essentially
an extremely sophisticated
version of biofeedback.
I've asked Charles Chase
and he doesn't know
nor seen,
but you have to admit
it is pretty interesting
that there is a lineage
pointing to the same company
and the same sort
of control loop.
Measure your brain,
compare it to a target state,
stimulate it,
and remeasure it.
And then there are
other people at this company
up to the executive level
that are talking about
flying UFOs with your mind.
So it looks like
Norseen's adaptive cockpit ideas
could be the prototype.
Looks like the weather project
grew some teeth.
In multiple interviews,
including with me,
the consciousness is activated
through heightening intuition
and lowering intellect.
Barber describes
consciousness craft interfaces
that sound impossible.
But here's the documented R&D
showing this technology
has been actively developed.
Whether it's been successfully
integrated with exotic
propulsion systems,
we don't ultimately know.
But the technical capability
Barber described
isn't necessarily science fiction.
It's just Lockheed Martin,
circa 1999.
And by 2018,
that same basic dream
of humans interfacing
directly with machines
was no longer buried
in obscure papers or patents.
That year, DARPA launched
a program called N3,
Next Generation Non-Surgical
Neurotechnology.
DARPA's official program brief
openly talks about
building bi-directional
brain-machine interfaces
for military use,
including for things like
control of unmanned
aerial vehicles.
One of the teams
that advanced in N3
was led by Battelle.
And if you've done
any deep research
on UFO legacy programs,
you know that
Battelle Memorial Institute
is all over it.
According to Battelle's
own 2020 press release,
their team progressed
to phase two of the program.
They were working directly
with the Air Force Research Lab,
Carnegie Mellon,
and others on a system
called BRAINSTORMS,
which stands for
Brain System to Transmit
or Receive
Magneto-Electric Signals.
BRAINSTORMS
uses nanoscale devices
injected into the human bloodstream
and guided with magnets
into specific areas of the brain
as part of a system designed
for bi-directional neural interfacing.
So by 2020,
you don't just have vague patents
and R&D rumors.
You have DARPA openly funding
a nanoscale injectable
brain-computer interface
with the Air Force Research Lab's
involvement
that could be a stepping stone
towards warfighters
eventually interfacing
with aerial vehicles.
Or it could simply represent
an advancement
in that capability,
which was established
years before.
Now for a different track.
Stay with me here.
In 2016,
the Navy filed a patent
under inventor
Salvatore Pais
for what they called
craft using an inertial
mass reduction device.
The patent describes a craft
that manipulates
high-energy electromagnetic fields
to achieve exotic propulsion,
a setup that requires
precise, real-time control
of its own field geometry.
You need something
that can sense
its internal field configuration,
and how it interacts
with the surrounding environment
and adjust in real time.
Something faster
than a joystick.
Faster than a keyboard.
Something like a mind.
What you won't see
in the open record
is the obvious next step.
Plug those worlds together.
If Jake Barber is right,
that missing link
lives in special access programs
that don't get patented at all.
So to recap,
Layer 1.
Lockheed develops
and patents
brain-to-machine interfaces.
Layer 2.
The Navy patents craft
that require
electromagnetic field manipulation.
Layer 3.
Psionic assets.
Human intuitives
jacked into exotic craft
through neural interfaces,
translating thought
into propulsion.
I'm not saying
that we have a verified
Salvatore Pais saucer
in a hangar
synced to a psionic asset
with that exact setup.
I am saying
that Barber's psionic pilot story
sounds wild.
Until you look at the R&D lineage
and realize
every piece of that stack
is already sitting
in white papers,
patents,
and weather contracts.
So far,
we have a fake mountain,
drugged psychics,
and spacecrafts
that only fly
if you plug
a human mind into them.
What's next,
do you ask?
The moon's fake,
clouds aren't really clouds,
birds are surveilling us?
Yeah,
DARPA's R&D portfolio
does not make that
less creepy.
Zoom out of Koyame
and you'll see a pattern.
Mountains,
paramilitaries,
and vanishing crafts.
It starts to look
less like random
campfire stories
and more like puzzle pieces.
Take Sedona,
Vision Quest capital
of America,
the land of crystals
and trust fund shamans.
Famed for its
Martian landscape
and vortex spas,
it's all very
eat,
pray,
love.
But once the sun
sets behind the red rocks,
the vibe starts to shift.
The notorious Bradshaw Ranch
is ground zero
for Sedona's
high strangeness.
There's even a book
about it called
Merging Dimensions
involving a rumored
portal on the ranch,
massive cargo planes
descending towards mountains
where nothing exists,
and lights shooting
out of canyons
as if the landscape
itself is alive.
There are constant claims
of strange activity
at Bradshaw Ranch
in Secret Canyon
with reports of guys
with military-style guns.
No surprise,
the ranch was sold
to the U.S. National Forest
for climate research
in partnership
with the Department of Energy
and Oak Ridge National Lab.
Nothing to see here.
Whispers of a rumored base
near Secret Mountain
aren't new.
Journalist Ross Colthart
went to Sedona
and came back a believer.
I am in no doubt
whatsoever, Jesse,
that there is a deep
underground military bunker
that was built
in the 1950s
under Secret Mountain.
That's what it's called.
It's the hilarious thing.
It's named Secret Mountain.
It's called Secret Mountain.
Unbelievable.
And that's not all.
Outside of consulting
multiple on-site witnesses,
Ross personally witnessed
anomalous activity
around Secret Mountain.
And if you looked
at a particular place
over Secret Mountain,
you would see
this big orb
being escorted
by helicopters
rising from behind
Secret Mountain.
and we watched
at 1.30 in the morning
and sure enough,
up comes this beautiful
golden orb.
Gigantic.
It's not every day
you see orbs escorted
by Blackhawks
like a presidential motorcade.
But zoom in a little
and look closely.
You'll find something else.
Investigators digging
into rumors
of underground facilities
near Secret Mountain
and Bradshaw Ranch
kept hitting
the same anomaly.
A tunnel,
geophysical surveys
and magnetometry
by Terra Exploration Group
showed a straight,
man-made tunnel
roughly 50 feet
in diameter
running like
a hidden artery
from Secret Mountain
to Bradshaw Ranch
to the front gate
of the Clarkdale
Cement Plant,
which John Bradshaw
claims used to be
the biggest employer
in town
and was guarded
and fenced
like a military site.
And there's
massive amounts
of electrical power
going into
the ground
under Bradshaw Ranch.
And we didn't put this
in the feature-length film
that we put to air
on Primetime,
but it runs
in the full-length interview
with Paul,
my friend.
He did a ground-penetrating
radar check
on the road
around Bradshaw Ranch
and we found
a 50-foot-wide
reinforced steel concrete
highly visible
on ground-penetrating radar.
Literally just under
the ground.
Whoa.
If you think this is
beyond belief,
underground military bases
exist across the United States.
They are called DUMs
or Deep Underground
Military Bases.
Richard Sauter
wrote an amazing book
about them
that I recommend
you check out.
There are also reports
of hikers near Sedona
walking into something
out of a black op fever dream.
Armed Men in Black,
Insignia-free uniforms,
M16s in hand,
standing in the middle
of Coconino National Forest.
These guys aren't militia.
They don't match any unit
anyone can identify.
And this isn't just Sedona.
This exact same ghost force
keeps popping up
in other hot zones
across the United States.
Head northeast
to Skinwalker Ranch
in Utah's Uinta Basin,
and the vibe shifts
from moonstones
to pure dread.
This place doesn't
want you here.
The Ute tribe
won't even talk about it.
They call it
Cursed Ground,
the path of the Skinwalker.
And if you spend
any time on the ranch,
you start to understand why.
Drones malfunction,
helicopters lose power,
equipment dies.
I am transfixed on
that tacky room.
For all intents and purposes,
I'm in that room.
And so I just,
I said out loud,
okay, this is stupid.
And then I said,
all right,
if you got something
you want to show me,
show me.
If you got something
you want to tell me,
tell me.
What the hell?
I live in?
That's creepy.
UFOs don't just
fly over Skinwalker.
They interact and descend,
vanishing into mesas
like ghosts
passing through walls.
Sound familiar?
Owner Brandon Fugel
openly describes
Blackhawks circling
with no transponders,
shaking the house,
running constant surveillance
We had a situation
above the triangle
where we were
launching rockets,
of course,
one of numerous occasions.
And the prominent
UAP,
Unidentified Aerial Phenomena,
ends up appearing.
And then what happens
within minutes following,
the Blackhawk helicopter
comes right over the mesa,
descends over the property,
and just hovers
right over the south field.
He also described a time
where a UFO dropped
down from the sky,
entered the east field portion
of the ranch below a helicopter,
and then exited from a mesa.
Does it look like it comes
from right there?
It came out of the mesa,
right there.
Wow.
That is unbelievable, gentlemen.
During all of this,
drones and other sensor equipment
malfunctioned.
Previous Skinwalker Ranch owner,
Robert Bigelow,
tells another story
about a UFO flying
lazy figure eights
at low altitude,
then shooting straight
into a mountain.
And so they stand there
and they're watching this,
and then it deviates
dramatically,
and it shoots off
at low altitude
right into the mountain itself.
But there's no explosion.
It's just gone.
In another case
near Skinwalker Ranch,
he describes a similar craft
doing the same thing,
shooting straight into the mountain
as if the stone
was a doorway.
If we zoom out,
it gets even stranger.
During the CIA's
remote viewing program
in 1973,
psychic spy Pat Price
described a massive
underground base
inside Mount Hayes, Alaska.
It had advanced technology,
consoles,
personnel that looked
like military.
He named three more bases,
Mount Perdido in Spain,
Mount Iñangani
in Zimbabwe,
Mount Zile
in Australia.
Years later,
Joe McMonigle,
another extremely talented
remote viewer,
was given the same coordinates
blind.
He saw the same mountains
with the same underground
command centers,
and then he saw
something else.
The bases were connected
like nodes of a network,
and when he remote viewed
Mount Perdido in Spain,
he saw how it was built,
not by non-human intelligence,
but by us,
helicopters,
cargo crates,
human personnel
moving materials
into the mountain.
Is it really possible
to see through
someone else's eyes
or sense through
their senses?
Actually,
we're not sure
exactly how it works,
but it is possible
to report on the position
or place that they're located.
Once a private company
has reverse-engineered
enough non-human technology,
its capabilities
can leap decades
or centuries
ahead of our own military.
At that point,
you're talking about
a parallel civilization
with its own cities,
its own private armies.
In physics,
we won't discover
for another century.
People seem to disappear
on all of these mountains.
The mountains contain
geomagnetic anomalies.
UFOs appear,
often coming in
and out of the mountains.
The mountains almost feel
like an air pocket
of a different consensus reality.
As my friend
and legendary UFO researcher
Richard Dolan might say,
a breakaway civilization.
And this is the real takeaway.
After years of researching
this stuff myself,
people always want to know
how I shake out
on what's actually going on
with UFOs in the government.
This is the stuff you get into
that's just hard to talk about.
It's hard to say
with a straight face.
Jointly operated
human and non-human bases
with entirely insulated
and separate chains of command.
I know that sounds nuts,
but think about it another way.
Name me a topic
other than UFOs
with this much
circumstantial evidence,
but nothing concrete
and definitive.
So much smoke,
but no fire.
The control system
around this stuff
has to operate
parapsychologically.
They have to have
next-level abilities
to cover themselves up.
And if anyone
is in charge of disclosure,
they are.
This is the truth
behind some of these
missing scientist cases.
And it's the reason
why certain technology trees
involving gravity manipulation,
nanotechnology,
fusion,
and free energy
tend to hit dead ends
or get softly enveloped
by bizarre shell outfits.
The tech going nowhere
in the civilian world,
but getting siphoned
into the black.
And think about it logically.
To think that
non-human intelligence exists,
but hasn't infiltrated
governments and private
aerospace is maybe
just as crazy as believing
in non-human intelligence
in the first place.
You can't really be open
to one and completely
closed off to the other.
If this is at all real,
then of course,
the government
can't just disclose it.
It's probably gonna get
spoon-fed to us in fiction.
How else do you prepare
a world for the idea
that the mountain
on the horizon
might not be a mountain
at all?
So yes,
maybe Jake Barber
didn't land another egg
as he predicted
when I interviewed him.
We hope to do
a demonstration
and invite key members
of the public
from institutions
and demonstrate this
and maybe even get
something to the ground.
And his attempts
to recreate legacy
UFO efforts
in a friendly,
open-source way
in the form of
a private company
called Skywatcher
seems like it's
hit some snags.
But what if,
in the tradition
Tom DeLonge established
with his book
Secret Machines,
Jake designed
this manuscript,
The Sentinels of Ether,
to encode the real truth
in fiction
and then go on
to use the Pentagon's
own review process
and redactions
as authentication.
If just two chapters
of this Sentinels of Ether story
that exists today online
triggered a firestorm
of black ink,
what is hiding
in the rest?
What was redacted?
If this sounds like fiction,
then good,
because that's exactly
where they've been hiding it.
In plain sight,
wrapped in stories
we were taught
not to take seriously.
And maybe that's the point.
A reality this shattering
can't be announced.
It has to be drip-fed,
encoded in movies,
buried in books,
disguised as entertainment
until we're ready
to see it
for what it really is.
We don't need
a billion-dollar
black budget,
psionic handlers,
or brain chips.
We have the hardware,
we have the brainwaves,
and we have a love beam
they can't jam.
Eight billion biological antennas
walking around
on the surface
of planet Earth.
Homegrown receivers
capable of connecting
to a field
the black world spent
70 years
trying to monopolize.
Because there's a far
more radical thesis
than
they're hiding UFOs.
It's more like
they're hiding us
from ourselves.
The technology
isn't in the craft,
it's in human neurology,
and in the human spirit.
And they've spent
70 years making sure
that we don't figure
that out.
Non-human intelligence
doesn't need
a press conference
at the White House.
They've been making contact
through back channels,
indigenous tribes,
secret societies,
occult practitioners,
psychonauts,
lone religious monks,
or just some kid
sending coherent love beams
out his bedroom window.
Sooner or later,
something might pick up.
In the words of Jake Barber,
we're not alone.
The skies aren't classified.
Your conscience
can't be redacted.
I encourage us all
to look upward
and look inward
and to become
the best versions
of ourselves quickly.
We need you.
A new era awaits.
Until next time,
I'm Jesse Michaels
and this is
American Alchemy.
This next advertisement
is for us,
American Alchemy.
Come work with us.
We are looking for
a highly competent producer
and operator
who can own workflows
end-to-end
and has a strong
editorial eye.
We definitely have
a preference for applicants
who were fans
of the show prior.
As you know,
if you've been watching
the show,
there's a whole set
of references
and there's a whole world
that we kind of swim in
that can be hard
to kind of ramp up on.
Experience with YouTube
specifically is also preferred
but not required.
If anything,
we're just screening
for general competence.
We want somebody
who's a little type A
but also open-minded
and deeply understands
and is fired up
about the vision
and mission
for American Alchemy.
And of course,
we want you to have
your own intrinsic
and organic interest
in the nature of reality.
Responsibilities will include
interfacing with the most
epic guests in the world,
helping shape
the editorial schedule,
working on a bunch
of YouTube stuff,
and helping just increase
the output and general
operational efficiency
behind American Alchemy.
Basically,
we want to turn this thing
into a well-oiled machine.
I've been doing
a lot of this stuff myself
since we've started.
I book all my guests,
I do all my research,
and I'm realizing
that some of these
logistical minutia
is not necessarily
my happy place.
I like to spend time
learning,
meeting people,
and going deep
on the content.
So if logistics
and operations
is your strong suit
and you're passionate
about subjects
and content like this,
please reach out.
Submit your applications
at apply
at jessymichaelsmedia.com.
Again, that's
apply at jessymichaelsmedia.com.
Submit your project
at jessym Edge.
I'll see you next time.
Hello.
Peace.
Woo.
Woo. Earth.